<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="mturk">
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Supporting the French proposal</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The meeting of the committee took place in the parliament house under the chairmanship of the committee chairman Mushahid Husain Syed, in which they proposed to the government to send a delegation, with representatives of all political parties apart from humanitarian aid to Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="3">After the meeting, speaking to representatives of the press, Mushahid Husain Syed said that the committee welcomed the proposal given by France, in which it was stated that Israel calls an immediate ceasefire and allow humanitarian work among the affected people of Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Calling the Israeli attacks on Palestine, a crime against humanity, he said that all countries should derogate these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mushahid Husain made the double standards of the countries of the world a target of his attack, and said that why are those who speak against terrorism, quiet about the Israeli attacks on Palestine?</seg>
    <seg id="6">The chairman of the standing committee of external affairs in the senate also targeted the leaders of Muslim nation who were taking a quiet stance on the matter of Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that the committee expressed hope that the newly elected American President, Barack Obama would speak to the Muslim nation, within his first 100 days of his government, to bridge the gulf forming between American and the Muslim nation.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mushahid Husain Syed said that the gap formed between Muslim nation and the West should be filled by taking not only sudden steps but also by solving long standing issues like that of Kashmir and Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The minister of foreign affairs, Malik Imad told the committee that he was going to Saudi Arabia to attend the meeting of the foreign ministers of the governments of Islamic countries.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This sudden meeting was called as a result of Israeli attacks on Palestine. He said that he was aware of the Palestinian matter and at present, the government was in contact with the premiers of other countries.</seg>
    <seg id="11">minister of state for foreign affairs has said that the issue of Palestine should be resolved in accordance with the resolutions of the United Nations.</seg>
    <seg id="12">two journalists from Arab countries also joined the conference and they told about the latest situation in Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="13">in Islamabad, students of the International University demonstrated protest against the Israeli attacks on Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="14">the protesters were holding banners and placards having anti Israel slogans written on it.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">abstention from dieting in order to avoid Flu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This research from the American Scientists have come up after the experiments on rats.</seg>
    <seg id="3">in has been proven from experiments that rats put on diet with less calories had less ability to resist the Flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="4">research has proven this old myth wrong that its better to fast during fever.</seg>
    <seg id="5">according to the scientists one should eat a lot during fever.</seg>
    <seg id="6">the researchers from the Michigan State University say that the rats on dieting had less power to resist the infection and their chances of dying had increased whereas rats on normal diet had better resistance against the Flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to Professor Elizabeth Gardner, people who do dieting will not be effected with flue sooner but also they will take more time to recover from it.</seg>
    <seg id="8">she also said that those people who have taken the flue vaccine should also avoid dieting during few months of winter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'first nuclear experiment was done in 1990'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Thomas Reid who has worked in the Lever national laboratory of America as a Weapon designer, has written this book with the help of the Ex director of technical intelligence at Las Elmos national laboratory, Dani Stillman.</seg>
    <seg id="3">this book was titled, 'Nuclear Express: political history of bomb and its proliferation' and both writers have claimed that which ever country first made a nuclear bomb either stole the nuclear secrets of another country or they had the support of another nuclear power.</seg>
    <seg id="4">in an interview with US news, Thomas Reid said that in 1990 during Benazir Bhutto's rule, China experimented Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Thomas Reid said that based to many reasons, he has a belief that China had experimented Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="6">the reasons include the design of the bomb and some information retrieved during talks with the Chinese scientists.</seg>
    <seg id="7">he further added that this was the reason that in 1998 only in a span of two weeks and three days, Pakistan was able to carry out nuclear experiments as a reply to Indian nuclear experiments.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Thomas Reid reminded that in 1961 Russia suddenly carried out a nuclear experiment and besides possessing the bomb for a long time, it took 17 days for America to carry out nuclear experiment.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He further said that in May 1998, the atom bomb that Pakistan tested was made with a lot of care and Pakistani scientists were completely trusted for it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">When Thomas Reed was asked this question that China supplied atomic technology to Pakistan so he said in his answer that India is a mutual enemy of Pakistan and China.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that its evidence is also present that Dr. Abdul Qadir Khan has used the Chinese model. Later the documents received from Libya also confirm this.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Another question that is it common to do nuclear experiments mutually. Then he said that Anees Sonway openly performed a nuclear experiment in the desert of Nevada for Britain.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said that we also predict that Israel also has access to the results of this experiment.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Thomas Reeds was also asked if China is continuing nuclear proliferation?</seg>
    <seg id="15">On this Thomas Reeds said that China has been supplying raw material, instructions and the design to a nuclear facility of Iran in its city Asfahan.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Apart from this, China has also provided Iran with an enrichment plant in Kheeraj.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He said that China had been providing nuclear technology to Iran, Rome, Pakistan, Egypt, Libya and Yemen via North Korea.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Year 2008 the most successful for Madonna.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This show was organized around Madonna's album 'Hard Candy' and it also included Ukrainian gypsy band and Justin Timberlake's one or two songs.</seg>
    <seg id="3">An old racing car was also showed on the stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Celine Dion's show in year 2008 was the second best show from revenue point of view in which two thirty six million dollar's were made.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Canadian show 'Taking Chances' visited twenty four countries where as Madonna visited only seventeen countries which was her first tour in last eight years.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The director of shows of both singers was Jimmy King, who also organized the tour 'Reunion' or 'Spice Girls'.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Madonna has broken her own record in 2006</seg>
    <seg id="8">In 2006 in 'confession concerts' she made one ninety three million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Polestar has declared Bon Jovi third most successful singer who had made one hundred and seventy million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bruce Springsteen has made one hundred and sixty million dollars and he stands fourth, and Police stood fifth by making one hundred and twenty six million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="11">According to this magazine in year 2008 very few people in North America had attended concerts and musical events and only those people participated who were willing to buy expensive tickets.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In America, there was an average increase of eight percent in the price of one ticket. In Madonna's show, the most expensive ticket sold was of 350 Dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The editor of Pollstar magazine, Gary Bongiovanni, said that given the economic environment, the year 2008 was a good year for musicians.</seg>
    <seg id="14">He predicted that the year 2009 would be a good year for Springsteen and U2, whose albums were to be released this year.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ban on Joint Education: Taliban</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The local Taliban of the Hafiz Gul Bahadur faction, in the chief province, Miran Shah and other provinces of North Waziristan have distributed a pamphlet in which the government and semi-government institutes in which boys and girl are given joint education were warned.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the pamphlet, it was stated that if the joint educational institutes were not closed by the 5th of January, action will be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It was stated in the pamphlet that making identification cards for women, either for government aid or for other educational reasons would be forbidden, and that women would be disallowed from going to identification offices in all provinces.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The local Taliban's announcement of the forbidding of women from making identification cards was made at a time when about 200 women had submitted their forms in North Waziristan for identification cards in the identification offices for the sake of the Benazir Income Support Program.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to the locals, the pamphlets issued by the local Taliban was read out loud on the loudspeakers of all the mosques in North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">However, the letter did not state whether there would be a ban on separate girls educational institutions or not.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the pamphlet, after this announcement, if woman gets caught when out to get education or get her ID made, she and her family will be given a legitimate punishment.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Besides this, in the area of Bannu, the police says that a tunnel of gunpowder was blasted on Sunday on Bannu Mir Insha Road, from which one pedestrian died and one was injured.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Injured was admitted in Bannu civil hospital.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Target Killing: More dead bodies found.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police, on the morning of Sunday, two dead bodies were found from the areas of the main Mangora, Green square and Sohrab khan square, in which their heads were separated from their bodies.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The deceased were told to be related to Frontier core and the police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">An eye witness said that a letter was also found near the dead bodies in which there was a threat that who ever picks up these dead bodies before 11 in the morning, he is responsible for his own death.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Locals say that the dead bodies were lying the market until 11am but later the security officials picked both the dead bodies and transferred them to the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="6">There has been a dangerous rise in the target killing during the last few weeks in the main city Mangora and the surrounding areas.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In which local citizens including women and security officials are being killed</seg>
    <seg id="8">according to local sources, more than thirty people have been killed to date in these kind of incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="9">so far no organization has taken responsibility of these killings.</seg>
    <seg id="10">the spokesman of the local Taliban in Swat Muslim Khan told on Saturday that the dead bodies found on Friday included those of his fellows and also included the dead body of the Taliban commander in Deolai, Rafiullah.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Muslim Khan said that Rafiullah was under custody of the security forces for the past one and half month.</seg>
    <seg id="12">he had said that the local taliban send notice before killing any one. On the other hand common citizens are worried about these incidents in Mengora.</seg>
    <seg id="13">according to the local people, a large number of security forces are deployed in Mengora but despite of this the attacks on the citizens are ever increasing.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Musical tribute to Benazir from Bakhtawar.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A rap song (a modern style of music) in Bakhtawar's voice has been posted on youtube as well.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This 5 minutes long song contains pictures and video clips of Benazir.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Eighteen years old Bakhtawar is a student at the Edinburgh University.</seg>
    <seg id="5">she has great interest in poetry and singing.</seg>
    <seg id="6">it is said that apparently after the appreciation from her mother she had started singing songs as a hobby.</seg>
    <seg id="7">while paying a tribute to her mother she has said that she was an intelligent and beautiful lady, she did every thing with style.</seg>
    <seg id="8">regarding the 27th December incident she said that she the bullet was fired at her temple, she left us at the age of 54 and left three children amongst residuals.</seg>
    <seg id="9">the whole nation is hopeless without her and she is still in everyone's heart.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bakhtawar is the second amongst Benazir's children after 20 years old Bilawal.</seg>
    <seg id="11">she has been taking interest in music from early days.</seg>
    <seg id="12">it is said that before her mothers return to the country with reference to a journalist friend she has expressed a will to meet the Grammy award winner music director and rapper Puff DD. but this meeting could not take place.</seg>
    <seg id="13">translation of Bakhtawar's poetry was published by some Sindhi news papers as well but her voice is being heard for the first time through You Tube.</seg>
    <seg id="14">some workers and followers of Benazir Bhutto have started preparing CDs of Bakhtawar's rap song.</seg>
    <seg id="15">on the other hand, the spokesman of Pakistan Peoples Party, Farhatullah Babar has confirmed that the poetry and voice in the song on Youtube is of Bakhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="16">he told over the phone from Islamabad that its a tribute by a saddened daughter to her brave mother, and it is also being telecast by the government TV network as well.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar has said that his party has not decided yet to distribute the CD's of the song by Bakhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="18">He said that few years back a fake account of his young Chairman Bilawal Bhutto Zardari was made on Facebook which was closed later on.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani : Information Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Federal Minister for Information and broadcasting Sherry Rehman while confirming, through and SMS sent to BBC, the citizenship of Ajmal Qasab just added that further investigation is being carried out.</seg>
    <seg id="3">before this the Advisor to Prime Minister for Interior Rehman Malik had denied his Pakistani citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="4">he had said that no record for Ajmal was found by the citizen record keeping institute, NADRA.</seg>
    <seg id="5">there is no information on this latest statement that on what basis the Government has changed its stance on Ajmal Qasab's citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, according to the foreign office spokesman, Ajmal Qasab's citizenship has been confirmed by the interior ministry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">earlier BBC Urdu service and some other newspapers and TV channels have told that Ajmal Qassab belongs to Farid Kot town of the Okara District in Province Punjab.</seg>
    <seg id="8">however the government had been denying it.</seg>
    <seg id="9">it has not yet been established that this Ajmal Qassab does belong to Farid Kot or some other place.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Rockets fired from Lebanon, bombing in answer</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">the Israeli Army and Police official have told media correspondents that 4 rockets were fired on the Israeli territory from Lebanon out of which one fell in the Neharia town of northern Israel which injured two people slightly.</seg>
    <seg id="3">in answer to the rockets fired from the Lebanese territory, the Israeli artillery has bombed Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="4">its is not clear that this attack was carried out by Hizbullah or the Palestinian groups active in Lebanon are behind it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Lebanese government says that it is also trying to figure out who is behind these rocket attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">BBC correspondents have declared that this as a very dangerous turn in the reigning situation in the region.</seg>
    <seg id="7">BBC's editor for Middle East Geremy Bowin has said that due to these rocket attacks is the danger of the war spreading out has increased.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Over the past few days, it was been feared that the military operation in Gaza may extend further north, along the Lebanon- Israel border</seg>
    <seg id="9">and there on Wednesday night, the Israeli Air Force conducted sixty air raids on Gaza Strip.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Israeli Army, these attacks targeted Hamas's Police Force's offices, underground tunnels, weapons' caches, rocket launching sites and Hamas's armed personnel.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Apart from air raids, Israel Army's and Navy's artillery continued shelling Gaza during the night.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The Palestinian Authorities said that a mosque was destroyed during the air raids on the Gaza city.</seg>
    <seg id="13">According to unconfirmed reports tanks from Israeli Army, aided by the helicopters from the air, have advanced towards the area of Khan Younus.</seg>
    <seg id="14">During this conflict of now twelve days, around seven hundred of Palestinians, which include a large number of women and children, have died.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Whereas on the other side twelve soldiers from the Israeli Army have also been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Israeli Security Forces have confirmed that a high ranking defense official, Amos Gillad is going to Cairo to settle the terms for seize-fire.</seg>
    <seg id="17">A delegation from Hamas is also going to Cairo to conduct parallel talks with the Egyptian diplomats.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Apart from this, the leader of the Palestinian Authority, Mehmood Abbas, is also reaching Cairo on Friday.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">My heart is broken, return my kidney.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Richard Batista says that eight years ago, he had gifted his wife Dawnell his kidney, to save her life.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to AFP news agency, it is Dr. Batista's statement that his wife has repayed him for his gift by cheating him and having relations with another man, and now she wants divorce.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Dr. Batista said, during an interview to a local newspaper, Daily News, that her love affair has put a hole in my heart that still exists.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Dr. Richard Batista's lawyer, though Dr. Batista is demanding his kidney back, but he actually wants a monetary compensation for the kidney.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He will give his stand about his wife in front of a judge within the next few days.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">140 year old, 9 kilo weighing lobster free</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">'George the Giant Lobster' was captured from the sea two weeks ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Seafood company of the city had purchased it for a hundred Dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">And instantly started using the lobster photos for his publicity.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Although, "PETA" a group working for animal rights demanded to release the lobster. As a result of which it will be released in the Sea.</seg>
    <seg id="6">George was caught in Canada from the sea after which he spent 10 days in the city crab and seafood company tank.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The age of lobster can be told by its weight.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Restaurant's manager Keith Walanty says that their purpose was not to hurt the lobster at all. And to keep him in the tank was to provide entertainment to the customers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Engrid Newkurk from the animal rights group PETA says that restaurant's decision is worth praise and an example for those who want to keep these precious animals in the tank or want to eat them by boiling them alive.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Search of girl with the help of a cell phone.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When the officials heard of Nataly Maltais, the police and firefighting forces of the city of Acton, Massachusetts came in to action.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Officials discovered the right location of the girl using the GPS on her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Although with the google street view , it was found out that the girl is in a motel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">a week ago Natalie's grandmother Rose Maltois Natalie took her from her legal parents' custody.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Ethol's police chief Timothy Anderson told BBC that she said she would never give Natalie back and then she left the state.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Police contacted Miss Maltois but when as per promise she did not send Natalie back, the Police decided to search for Natalie through her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="8">since 2005 there is a regulation in America that the cellular companies will provide location for 67 percent people in a range of 100 meters and 95 percent callers in a range of 300 meters.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on a visit to India.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">this is Hamid Karzai's second Indian tour in last five months.</seg>
    <seg id="3">it is expected that during his meeting with Prime minister Manmohan Singh he will discuss after effects of the terrorist attacks in Mumbai.</seg>
    <seg id="4">during this visit he wants to express the feeling of his people and solidarity with India over the Mumbai terrorists attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">during Karzai's visit, besides extremism, bilateral trade will also be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">discussion on bilateral cooperation to counter extremism between both countries is also expected.</seg>
    <seg id="7">during his last visit to India, president Hamid Karzai said that terrorism will not be let into the relations between India and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">he also said that both India and Afghanistan are facing challenges of terrorism and merciless killings.</seg>
    <seg id="9">peace and stability in both countries, region and whole world is beneficial for everyone.</seg>
    <seg id="10">we understand this reality that both countries and the whole world can only join hands to face this curse of terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="11"></seg>
    <seg id="12"></seg>
    <seg id="13"></seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2"></seg>
    <seg id="3"></seg>
    <seg id="4">Ajmal Qasab is now in police custody, and it is being hoped that the police will file a charge sheet against him before January 24th.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ajmal Qasab does not have any lawyer to defend him.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In a letter written to the Pakistani government, Qasab asked for legal aid.</seg>
    <seg id="7">India has give Pakistan proof of the involvement of Pakistani extremists in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Pakistan has accepted that Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani civilian.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the police case, Ajmal Qasab and his partner Abu Ismail killed 6 police officers including ATS chief Hemant Karkare, Additional Police Commissioner Ashok Kamte and Encounter specialist Police Inspector Vijay Salaskar, after which they fled with their squad car, which was later recovered near DB Marg, Gurgam Choupati.</seg>
    <seg id="10">During police action, Ismail Khan died and the police captured Ajmal alive.</seg>
    <seg id="11">No lawyer was appointed yet, to follow Ajmal's case.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The lawyer chosen by the government, from the legal aid cell, Dinesh Mota refused to accept the case on moral reasons.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Two lawyers pulled out their names after protests and opposition by the people of a political group.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Constitutional Amendment; Committee to be formed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After addressing a seminar on environment change, he told media representatives that for this sake, the parliamentary meeting will take place in which a committee will be formed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that until now, to complete the 17th amendment, the constitutional amendment bill was presented by the Joint National Movement to the National Assembly, whereas other political parties have also presented their constitutional bills in this regard to the parliament.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the Pakistan Peoples Party has also send all the political parties a rough version of the 17th amendment and the committee would analyze their version.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In answer to a question, he said that the parliament would decide the balance of power between the President and the Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Prime Minister said that the Parliament has the complete right to take any decision.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In answer to another question, he said that in getting the former President retired General Pervez Musharraf to leave his post, apart from the role of political parties, the former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Pakistan Peoples Party, Benazir Bhutto also played an important role, by forcing the global brotherhood to remove the uniform of President Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that the elected Vice President of America, Joe Biden was a supporter of Pakistan and democracy, and that the president honored him in return for his services with the Pakistani Crescent.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Replying to a question about the Indian governments warning of breaking all ties with Pakistan, after the Mumbai incident, the Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Geelani said that the leaders are under extreme pressure from the public, which is why they issue such statements.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Protest against the removal of journalists</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Tuesday the organization of journalists, RIUJ held protests in front of the Islamabad Press Club of journalists and newspaper workers against media owners and the government about the news channel and newspapers removing many of their employees.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking to the protesters, senior member of Pakistan's biggest journalist organization, Federal Union of Journalists,  C.R. Shamsi said that the politicians who used to protest with us till yesterday on the streets, today they have become rulers and are sitting in the parliament. Fearing a certain lobby of the media owners, they are not doing anything for the rights of the journalists.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the newspaper owners who speak of human rights have made their offices punishment houses and beggar camps, where despite earning millions of Rupees per year, the workers are given meager wages and by removing hundreds of them, they are killing them economically.</seg>
    <seg id="5">An example of this is in front of us of the worker of a private TV channel, Channel 5, in Lahore, who committed suicide over not getting his salary for four months. And even today, due to being unfairly removed or not getting salaries for months, many workers are leading very difficult lives.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that there should be firm steps taken against the TV and newspaper owners, and the journalists should put a protest camp in front of the parliament to get their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="7">C.R. Shamsi criticized the governor of Punjab, Salman Taseer, saying that employees were removed from his Urdu Newspaper 'Aaj Kal' staff, without prior notice.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wheras Junah daily, Khabrein daily, Channel 5, Burns Plus TV and Aaj TV have removed dozens of workers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Speaking to the protestors, the General Secretary of PUFJ said that today, throughout the country, journalist organizations are observing a black day against the removal of journalists and newspaper workers, whereas journalists will go to the parliamentary session wearing black bands on their arms to get back their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Mazhar Abbas, in 50% of the Pakistani newspapers and TV channels the workers and journalists were being exploited, where they work without any agreement.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that till now, more than 200 journalists and workers have been removed from newspapers and TV channels, while it is being feared that the owners will remove hundreds more in the present year, making an excuse of the present financial crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas has said that the journalists' movement will continue unless, the dismissed workers are restored, implementation of the seventh wage board responsible of determining the wages of employees of news papers and release of salaries of TV channels and newspaper employees' blocked since many months.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">cabinet of eleven members have taken oath.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">new cabinet includes six ministers from anti, ex prime minister Sardar Atiq Ahmed Khan, Muslim conference group, two from Pakistan Peoples Party, two from Peoples Muslim Conference and two from the Mutahida Qaumi Movement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">the eleven members cabinet also includes a female member as well who belongs to the anti Atiq Muslim Conference group.</seg>
    <seg id="4">the ruling coalition has said that an expansion will be made in the cabinet next week, and it is expected that a dozen more ministers will be added to the cabinet. note that earlier this month Sardar Atiq Khan was dismissed from the prime ministry through vote of no confidence and Sardar Yaqoob was elected as the new prime minister.</seg>
    <seg id="5">the departments of these ministers will be announced later on.</seg>
    <seg id="6">during the oath taking ceremony, the workers of Pakistan Peoples Party raised slogans in favor of ex prime minister Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">3.5 million users effected from the virus.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">discovered for the first time in October 2008, this virus known by the names like Confecker, Down and Up and Kido.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Microsoft had released a patch to tackle with this virus but despite of that almost 3.5 million computer and memory sticks have been affected with it.</seg>
    <seg id="4">the experts say that the number of effected computers can be a lot more.</seg>
    <seg id="5">to handle this, the users need to use Microsoft's MS08067 patch.</seg>
    <seg id="6">according to Microsoft, this virus which infected millions of computers, locates the services.exe file in windows and then enter gets into its code.</seg>
    <seg id="7">afterwards, this virus turns into a DLL type of file into the System folder of the windows.</seg>
    <seg id="8">it also creates the name of this file as well.</seg>
    <seg id="9">then changes the registry details of the windows.</seg>
    <seg id="10">after getting activated, this virus creates a problem which rises as an http server and changes the restore point of the system.</seg>
    <seg id="11">afterwards, it downloads the files from the maker's website.</seg>
    <seg id="12">according to Microsoft, this virus has infected computers in different countries of the world.</seg>
    <seg id="13">these countries include China, Brazil, Russia, India, America and Britain.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'The Demand for a Quick Report on Indian Information'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In an interview with the representatives of the media, after a meeting of the Home Ministry, he said that the given by India</seg>
    <seg id="3">information will help in investigation in these regards.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that Pakistan was a sovereign nation and about the investigation on the information received from India, no country's</seg>
    <seg id="5">dictation wuld be accepted.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that apart from the information received from India, they was gathering other information as well.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The internal advisor said that the executive institutions have taken 124 members of practically non-existent groups into custody, solely on the basis of the fear of a reduction in peace.</seg>
    <seg id="8">And if any evidence is found against them, action will be taken against them, while innocent people will be freed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In an answer to a question, he said that no arrested person would be handed over to India, and that action would be taken against such individuals according  to Pakistani law.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that action would be taken against these individuals according to the law of the FIA.</seg>
    <seg id="11">while answering a question he said that the Indian law enforcement agencies have collected information about people involved in Mumbai attacks in 42 days therefore the world community including India will give some time to Pakistan to investigate on these informations.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He reiterated this offer from the government that a joint investigation team be made to investigate the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="13">it should be clear that a 3 membered investigation team led by additional director general FIA which is   of Mumbai attacks from India.</seg>
    <seg id="14">investigating on informations provided to Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Pakistani High commissioner in India Shahid Malik has met president Asif Ali Zardari in which it was cleared that if any person or group from Pakistan is found involved in Mumbai attacks, he will be dealt in accordance with the national laws and no one will be handed over to India. whereas the Indian leadership is putting pressure on Pakistan to extradite the people involved in the incident to India.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Any thing is possible in America'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mr. Obama will take oath as the 44th president of America on 20th January.</seg>
    <seg id="3">while standing on the stairs of the building built in memory of 16th American president Abraham Lincoln and addressing a musical concert</seg>
    <seg id="4">Mr. Obama said that America is facing the most bitter challenges since many generations and he is hopeful that America will take care of it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Abraham Lincoln put an end to slavery in America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But at the same time Mr. Obama said that it will take time to solve problems that are facing the country and it is a tough road.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But nevertheless, I am hopeful that the dream of the founders of this country will live.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America, besides the wars of Iraq and Afghanistan, is fighting a great economic downfall.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Unusual steps are being taken for the ceremony of the oath taking.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Management thinks that 2 million people will attend this ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="11">America has a public holiday on Monday as on this same day the great leader of human rights Martin Luther King was assassinated.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Martin Luther King was black.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A tribute to Martin Luther King, The decision of doing work.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Martin Luther King was murdered in 1968.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barrack Obama paid tribute to Dr. Martin Luther King and told Americans to work together to fulfill the promises of this nation.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Here, in Washington, preparations are being made for an unprecedented gathering of the public, for the oath taking ceremony by the new president on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is believed that near 2 million people will gather in Washington to watch the historic oath of presidency by the president.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama started Monday by visiting a medical center in North Washington, where he met with injured American soldiers. After this, he visited a home for the homeless, and painted a wall.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Speaking to journalists, Barack Obama said: "After the present crisis which we are facing, and the difficulties that many people are undergoing, we cannot sit quietly".</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that Martin Luther King spent most of his for the people.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Barack Obama said: "Today, we are remembering and respecting him, so it is not a day for us to stop and think. It is a day for us to act".</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that the ceremony on Tuesday would be on the same path as that of Martin Luther King's 'My Dream' speech, to hear which many thousands of people gathered, in 1963.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In this speech, Martin Luther King said that the day will come when people would not be preferentially treated based on their color.</seg>
    <seg id="12">BBC's Mathew Price said that you can call it the patching up of history, that Martin Luther King Day came twenty four hours before the first black president in American history would take the oath of office.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In many of the southern states of America, Barack Obama's presidency is the interpretation of Dr. Martin Luther King's dream.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">was the additional political agent.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The additional political agent was kidnapped ten days ago from south Waziristan by unidentified masked men.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Sources say that the agent was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer faction of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the local government, around 4 o'clock in the evening, Tuesday, the Additional Political Agent of South Waziristan, Aamir Latheef was brought to Wana Scouts camp, by a group of tribals.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, they did not reveal who had kidnapped the additional political agent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, the locals are saying that the political agent was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer faction of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Aamir Latheef was kidnapped when he was going from Wana to Tank.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On the 11th of January, 2009, seven masked men kidnapped the additional political agent, Aamir Latheef, along with his driver, from the tribal area, Karkandah of South Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the government agent, the kidnappers first disarmed the guards, and after that they seated the additional political agent in another car, and took him away from there.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the local government, after the kidnapping of the additional political agent, security forces guarded all the check posts in South Waziristan and semi-tribal areas, and the people coming and going were searched thoroughly, and from the previous one week, the rulers have placed economic restrictions on Wana.</seg>
    <seg id="11">on 8th of December 2008, Assistant political agent of north Wazirastan Asmatullah got kidnapped when he was going from Mir Ali to Bannu to enjoy his Eid vacations. Few days after this two people including Tehsildar Amanullah were killed by unknown maskers in north Wazirastan.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Victory of a British hacker in the court.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">a 42 years old British citizen has admitted that he had hacked an American military website.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gary is a patient of asperger syndrome. it should be kept in mind that an asperger syndrome patient has the obsession to do similar kind of tasks.</seg>
    <seg id="4">his lawyers say that if he is handed over to America then he will commit suicide.</seg>
    <seg id="5">however the government officials say that their are very less threat regarding Gary's health.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Lord justice Morskey and Mr. Justice Simon while announcing the decision said that Gary is permitted to file a review petition in a British court.</seg>
    <seg id="7"></seg>
    <seg id="8">He added that the secretary of interior has noticed this issue.</seg>
    <seg id="9">but the government prosecutors say that the secretary of interior had used his authority.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Gary has never denied hacking of the American military website.</seg>
    <seg id="11">in 2001 and 2002, Gary hacked American computer system which caused a loss of eight hundred thousand dollars to the American government.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Gary hacked 97 computers including that of American Navy and NASA.</seg>
    <seg id="13">However Gary says that he did not do dis with bad intentions but he was just looking for information about aliens which he thought the American government had kept secret.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Gary's mother Janice Sharp has said that she is happy with this decision.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Gary's lawyer has said that its the right decision.</seg>
    <seg id="16">This case has been continued since 2002 and finally a right decision has come up.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Kashmir: two Hizb Commanders killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Colonel Acharya, spokesman of the northern command of the Indian Army deployed in Jammu, told BBC: on a reliable information, troops from 24 rashtria rifles and Jammu Kashmir police besieged the place in batihaas jungle in tehsil Gandwa of the Doda district where the armed extremists were hiding.</seg>
    <seg id="3">they fired at the army and in retaliation two extremists got killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Correspondent say that among the two terrorists killed, one was also Zahoorudding, the district commander of the banned group Hizb-ul-Mujahideen active for the last 12 years in the area, who was a specialists in bomb blasts.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The other with him is identified as Sajjad Hussain, who according to the army , became associated to the extremists since the last year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Acharia, the operation is still going on in the mentioned area of the jungle because according to them there is a possibility of presence of more extremists there. Army said two Kalashnikov were found during the first step of the operation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Yesterday, the head of the province police, Kuldeep Kumar Khudda, by announcing the statistics of the year 2008,  has declared this year the most peaceful year until now.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that in November and December during 7 stages of assembly elections, no torture was done.</seg>
    <seg id="9">More than 1350 candidates participated in these elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Be clear that Hizb-ul-Mujahideen is active in Jammu Kashmir for the last eight years.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Hizb-ul-Mujahideen declared one sided cease fire in July 2000 for the first time after which Indian government and Hizb commandos had a talk.</seg>
    <seg id="12">But the cease fire was over in only 15 days.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Later many senior commandos of Hizb-ul-Mujahideen were killed in different operations.</seg>
    <seg id="14">on Thursday, the Pakistan's famous daily The News has said regarding the extremist groups existing in the Pakistani administered Kashmir, that Lashkare Taiba and Hizbul Mujahidin have decided to review the Kashmir policy.</seg>
    <seg id="15">it should be clear that both the organizations had a policy that the Kashmir dispute should be resolved through an armed resistance.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Dera Bugti: blast over the gas pipeline</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Police officials say that the 18 inches diameter pipeline going from Lui gas field to peer koh was blasted.</seg>
    <seg id="3">this pipeline goes towards the Sui plant.</seg>
    <seg id="4">meanwhile, Sarbaz Baloch, presenting himself as a representative of the banned Baloch republican army has accepted the responsibility of the blast on behalf of his organization over the telephone.</seg>
    <seg id="5">fourth pipeline has been blasted in four days.</seg>
    <seg id="6">on Friday an 18 inches diameter pipeline was blasted in Dera Allahyar whose repair work was continued till Sunday morning.</seg>
    <seg id="7">General Manager of Sui Southern Gas in Quetta, Mushtaq Siddiqui has told that supply from this pipeline will resume in the afternoon.</seg>
    <seg id="8">this pipeline reached Quetta through Sibbi.</seg>
    <seg id="9">there is a severe shortage of gas in Quetta, Ziarat and other surrounding areas for the past three days, where on one hand snowfall is continuing and temperature has fallen below the freezing point and on the other hand heaters and stoves are out of gas.</seg>
    <seg id="10">moreover in Dera Bugti city, there was a motorcycle blast on the mall road but police told that there was no loss of lives in this blast.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Adminstrator for Jamaat Al-Dawa.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The central headquarter of Jamaat Al dawa is in Muridkay almost 25 Kilometers away from Lahore.</seg>
    <seg id="3">the center includes hospital, schools and student hostels.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Law minister for Punjab, Rana Sanaullah has said that the posting of administrator in Jammat al Dawa center is to make sure that the social work being done over there is not affected.</seg>
    <seg id="5">the leader of Jamaat al Dawa Hafiz Saeed's son in law Khalid Waheed has told that for the supervision of the hospitals, schools and other welfare organizations a high government official has been appointed and according to him the number of police troops have also been increased.</seg>
    <seg id="6">the Security counsel of the United Nations have imposed sanctions on Jamaat al Dawa after which the Federal government of Pakistan have stared an operation across the country against Jamaat al Dawa and have put leaders including  the leader of the Jamaat Hafiz Saeed in House-Arrest.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Khaqan Babar belongs to the DMG or District Management Group.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Hafiz Khalid Waheed has told that on Sunday the Commissioner of Lahore Khusro Pervez Khan along with police and civil administration came to the Taiba Center and inspected its different parts. Khalid Waheed has disapproved the appointment of the administrator in the center of Jamaat al Dawa and said that due to the actions of the government, the number of patients in the hospitals and children in the schools of the center have already decreased.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Here according to a press release by Jamat-ud-Dawa, party's chief Hafiz Saeed has written a letter for the General Secretary of United Nations, Ban Ki Mon, and Committee for Taliban, in a reques is made to cancel the restrictions on the party made by the Security Council.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It says in the letter that the one sided decision of the Security Council on banning Jamat-ud-Dawa is unfair. And Jamat-ud-Dawa has no relation with terrorism but it is busy in the activities of charity.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Edhi on the aid mission of Gaza.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After going through many steps of receiving permission required to enter Gaza, he has only been successful in reaching Egypt from New york.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said while talking to BBC Urdu service from Qahira that he has still not reached Gaza because Egypt and Israel has created many obstacles.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that it has been 8 days since I am here but I still have not received the permission to enter Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I am currently in Qahira and hopefully will get permission to go to Gaza</seg>
    <seg id="6">He told explaining that: "First I was given only 7 days visa to go to Gaza and later on my insisting, Pakistani officials helped me and had it extended for one month but on this condition that I will go to Gaza only once that is single entry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that he has his son and daughters with him and they want to do charity work in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">I have brought some money.</seg>
    <seg id="9">A one million dollar check has been given to Red cross of Egypt and ten thousand dollar cash is also given in order to send aid to Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">four more ministers in the cabinet, total of sixty three</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">four new federal ministers include two from Mutahida Qaumi Movement and Two from Jamiat Ulamae Islam Fazalur Rehman Group.</seg>
    <seg id="3">president Asif Ali Zardari took oath from the new ministers.</seg>
    <seg id="4">in the oath taking ceremony, the Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani and members of cabinet were also present.</seg>
    <seg id="5">after the inclusion of four new ministers to the federal cabinet, the number of Federal ministers, ministers for state and advisors has reached a total of sixty three.</seg>
    <seg id="6">two minister from MQM include Farooq Sattar and Babar Ghouri whereas ministers from Jamiat Ulamae Islam Fazalur Rehman Group include Azam Swati and Molana Ataur Rehman.</seg>
    <seg id="7">the departments of these ministers have not been announced yet.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Farooq sattar is the convener of MQM whereas Babar Ghouri is a senator from MQM whose term wil expire on tenth March.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Azam Swati was elected as a free senator and is considered to be one of the richest senators.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Moulana Ata-ur-Rahman is a member of National Assembly and also Moulana Fazal-ur-Rahman's younger brother.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Remember that, four statesmen holding posts in important ministries are not the members of the national assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Note that the cabinet was expanded on 3rd November, 2008 with 22 new ministers and 18 national ministries. So, at that time it was thought that the members of MQM would also be included but due to disagreements on the distribution of the ministries, MQM stayed away.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bolochistan, Blasted Pipeline</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police, this is a 18 inch diameter pipeline which  connects different wells of Parekoh and meets Suyi gas pipeline. This was blasted my some unidentified men in early morning.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Apart from this, yesterday, well number 3 near Suyi had been totally destroyed by a blast and also a gas pipeline near Dera-allayar was also damaged due to a blast.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Militant organization Baloch republican army's spokeperson, Saryaz Baluch accepted the responsibility of these blast on the behalf of his organization.</seg>
    <seg id="5">As the year 2009 started, the was increase in violent incidents in Baluchistan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">This month, till now, several gas pipelines have been blasted.  Also, Attacks on trains and on people belonging to the Punjab region have also increased.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Though the Prime Minister of Baluchistan, Nawab Aslam Rayisani, has expressed concern over such activities and ordered the police to exchange information from intelligence agencies, but,stopping such incidents has not been possible yet.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Approval of package of 819 billion dollars for economic revival.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">No member related to the Republican party did not vote in favor of this plan of President Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Members of the republican party said that the economic plan is very expensive and will not prove effective.</seg>
    <seg id="4">240 votes were drawn in favor of this package in the members assembly where as 160 were drawn against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This plan of economic revival will be presented next week in the Senate where the ruling Democratic party has very little majority.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Danger is being expressed that great opposition from the republican party may not make it easy for Senate approval.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After the approval of economic revival plan from the members assembly, Barrack Obama insisted on the members that this important plan should not come between the political disagreement.</seg>
    <seg id="8">President said that this plan, for which he was hopeful that it will act as the law by next month, will prove to make a peaceful atmosphere in the country. Due to which trade will enhance in America.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to this plan, common people and business men will be relieved of loan from 275 billion dollars and 540 billion dollars will be given for roads, bridges, 10,000 schools, unemployment allowance and research for new technology.</seg>
    <seg id="10">BBC writer Richard Luster has said in Washington that Barrack Obama intended to introduce a new political culture by putting back the political disagreements but discussion this Economic Package has once again made political pillars sore.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Republican party members in the assembly declared the bill proposed from the government, a waste of government money. And said that this will not help in creating new vacancies.</seg>
    <seg id="12">They insisted on the bill proposed by their party in which attention has been given to relaxation in taxes.</seg>
    <seg id="13">They said that through their package, less investment can create more chances of livelihood.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They said that instead of construction plans, relaxation in taxes can create more number of vacancies instantly.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bitterness among Israeli president and Turkish Prime Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Rajab Tayyab Erdogan almost shouted at Israeli President and said that many people's blood have been shed in Gaza. And he  felt sorrow watching that people can actually clap on the reason of this military action from Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Erdogan said that "I think you are using such words to erase your guilt and that in a high voice. But you killed people and I am remembering those children who were killed near the shore"</seg>
    <seg id="4">Shamoon Parez said that Gaza's pain is not Israel, It is Hammas who has founded dangerous dictatorship there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A correspondent of BBC from Davis says that nothing like this has been seen before in an international economic forum.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Although later Erdogan said that he respects the Israeli president and also his age due to which he did not shout at him but what he was saying was miles away from truth.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Turkey is one of the few Islamic countries which have diplomatic relations with Israel, but for the last few years there has been tension between them.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The attacks were not planned in Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Speaking to Indian news channel, NDTV, Wajid Shamsul Hasan, said that the report of the Pakistani investigations into the Mumbai blast will be prepared soon.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the attacks that took place in Mumbai, last Novemeber, more than 170 persons were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">India claims that the responsibility for the attacks belongs to the extremist group, Lashkar-e-Taiba.</seg>
    <seg id="5">India also said that Pakistani 'state factors' were guilty in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After the Mumbai attacks, the relations between the two countries were affected.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The high commissioner Wajid Shamsul Hasan gave his first statement about the report of the Pakistani investigations, from which it becomes evident as to what is within the report.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wajid Shamsul Hasan said that as far as investigation has gone, Pakistani land has not been used.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It must be some other place, not England either.</seg>
    <seg id="10">these are the two places (Pakistan and Britain) about which I was worried.</seg>
    <seg id="11">India and the international community has created a lot of pressure on Pakistan to take actions against the culprits of the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Wajid Shamsul Haq said: we are not trying to cover it up.</seg>
    <seg id="13">we believe in taking action based on facts.</seg>
    <seg id="14">the world will accept our investigations.</seg>
    <seg id="15">we will try to satisfy India over the results (of the investigation)</seg>
    <seg id="16">while defending the delay in the investigation is Pakistan he said that it takes time to collect, understand and check these kind of stuffs.</seg>
    <seg id="17">The High Commissioner Wajid Shamsul Haq said that it took 45 days for India to present its dossier.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A black man elected as the republican leader too.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">in the sixth round of elections in the Republican party, Michael steel has won who received 91 votes out of 168.</seg>
    <seg id="3">During the  election for the position of chairman of the party, Katen Dawsen, candidate opposite to Steel, was given 70 votes. Whereas, former chairman Dunken abdicated from the competition in the second round.</seg>
    <seg id="4">People say that from the five candidates who stood for the position of the chairmanship of the republican party, Michael Steel was considered the most conservative among them.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After his win, Michael Steel said in his speech "We are saying to our friends and enemies together, that come with us but those who will cause problems in this, be prepared to separate from us." Michael Steel is from Maryland where he has also been the Deputy governor.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He got famous in 2006 when he stood for a seat in the senate.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But after loosing in the senate elections he was appointed as the chairman of one political conservative committee of the party.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Now after being selected as the chairman of the party, the efforts of the republican party campaign in the entire country will be under his supervision.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He fought elections for this promise that he will give the party a new cause. And that he will use a new technique to join conservative supporters to the party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Indian claims presence of Lashker-e-Tayyaba and Josh-e-Muhammad in Jammu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">There are news of presence of terrorists in  the Poonch Tribal area of Jammu</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the official sources, police and army surrounded the area and started the search on receiving secret information.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this a fight started in which four militants, two soldiers and one policeman were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the sources, fights were going on until the last news. And in this area, militants associated with Lashker-e-Tayyaba and Josh-e-Muhammad are present, for which more army has been sent to fight them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">During this, chief minister, nominated by the involved officials, Omer Abdullah met with the governor and he directly gave the news of the selection of the Assembly leader from his party national conference.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Congress, the ally of the National conference also informed the governor of the advocacy of Omar Abdullah.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Omar Abdullah will take oath as the chief minister of teh sate.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Remember, national conference became the biggest party by gaining 28 seats in the assembly of 87 members in the current state elections. Keep in mind that separatist parties boycotted the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Congress, which secured 17 seats, accepted to form coailition government with the national conference.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Today party workers welcomed Omar Abdullah with great fanfare on his arrival in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On this occasion, Omar Abdullah says that he will play his role in making the talks possible between Indian government and separatists. Although this is not possible until the elections in India and formation of the new government.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Role of EU for peace in the Middle east.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">from official point of view, the role of European Union is decisive in the peace efforts to stop the war in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">according to Brussels' official stance, the efforts of Schwarzenberg delegation or Sarkozy were equally helpful in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="4">European Union's spokesman Amadeu Altafaj has said that every such effort is adorable which is helpful in sending the European Union's message to the opponents of the war.</seg>
    <seg id="5">it seems alright as far as the official statement is concerned.</seg>
    <seg id="6">but in reality the European Union is portraying a very disappointing picture of the internal tensions.</seg>
    <seg id="7">as the head of the Union, Czech republic's role is even weaker than before.</seg>
    <seg id="8">an on top of that the internal issues have made is helpless.</seg>
    <seg id="9">on the other hand the French president Sarkozy is behaving like if he is still the president of the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Whereas France has completed its presidential tenure of six months.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Sarkozy wants to play a leading role and he is capable of it but he does not have the permission to do it.</seg>
    <seg id="12">the most funny situation is faced by the French foreign minister Bernard Kouchner.</seg>
    <seg id="13">he is part of a delegation which is headed by the foreign minister of Czech republic Schwarzenberg.</seg>
    <seg id="14">the problem is that both foreign ministers are issuing contradictory statements over the Middle East war.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Schwarzenberg says that Israel has the right for self defense whereas Kouchner says that this cannot be considered as a war for self defense. moreover Germany has sent its special ambassador to Middle East. Unless the European Union does not show unity based on common stance, it can not succeed on the diplomatic front.</seg>
    <seg id="16">its proof is the Israeli behavior which does not care about the efforts for reconciliation from the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="17">this is a golden chance for the European Union to do something since America due to the policies of George W. Bush has already failed in the Middle East.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Financial Crisis: Suicide of a billionaire German industrialist.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Adolf Merckle, a resident of Sawabia in Southern Germany left a huge business group behind him.</seg>
    <seg id="3">but a short while ago, common German citizens did not know much about it.</seg>
    <seg id="4">when he had to negotiate with 30 banks who lent money to his industrial group, he became the topic of the headlines and he could foresee the murky future of the Merckle group.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Merkle group had to face a loss of a few hundred million Euros due to the arrival of the financial crisis after it bought shares in the German car manufacturing company, Volkswagen.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Financial institutions then refused to give it the new 700 to one Billion Euro loan it needed on an immediate basis, so Merkle went into deep pressure.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Some time before that, the same bank was prepared to give it the immediate loan that it needed, but Adolf Merkel had got to this position from being a small producer, to having a yearly turnover of nearly 30 billion Euros, so he could not bear to lose his capitalistic powet.</seg>
    <seg id="8">After the death of his father, when Adolf Merkel took over his family business, he developed it quick, putting it on new lines.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He called his company Ratiopharm, which is a very successful and large pharmaceutical company in Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Until a while ago, the value of this business was between 5 and 6 billion Euros, and it still earns about 8.1 billion Euros a year.After the superb success of Ratiopharm, Merkel group started buying many other institutions which included construction supply manufacturing companies like Hydelburg Cement to car manufacturing companies like Kassbohrer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The number of employees of the Merkel group around the world is near 100,000 and its foundation company, the pharmaceutical Ratiopharm always had special importance.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Adolf Merkel has said many times in his life: "It has been four generations since I started making medicine.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Now the management of this group is in the hands of my children and I hope that the mangement of this company will remain in my family for a few hundred years.</seg>
    <seg id="14">After the suicide of Adolf Merkel, banks have sanctioned 400 million Euros in floating loans for his group, but under the condition that VEM will have to sell Ratiopharm so that it could improve its financial conditions in the long term.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Like this, after the death of Adolf Meerklay, the Meerklay group will not remain the same as it was.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Crime rate among the immigrants in Germany.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the fresh statistics, crime rate among the immigrants from 2004 to 2007 is</seg>
    <seg id="3">Reduced from 9.22%</seg>
    <seg id="4">to 4.21%</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Joachim Herrmann, the interior minister of Baweria province, this is apparently a positive change.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said: "It is important to note that the number of foreigners getting German citizenship is increasing.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Therefore this should also be mentioned in the statistics that even though the criminal is German but his background is foreign.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Herrmann said that his province will take this in to account when gathering statistics in 2010.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Besides Baweria, Hamburg is also thinking in the same lines.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Senator for foreign affairs from CDU, Christoph Ahlhaus has said: "When research is done in a scientific manner, the man can not pre-decide its results but it is based on the facts and figures that come out as a result of the research.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Ahlhaus diverted the attention to a research report from the anti crime's provincial office which was prepared in 2006 and according to this report in Bergdorf, a part of Hamberg, it was investigated that out of all crimes happening there what percentage have the involvement of foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="12">results showed that the foreigners here have</seg>
    <seg id="13">the crime rate was less as compared to the crimes allover the province.</seg>
    <seg id="14">in contrast when in 2006 a survey was done on crimes in youth in Berlin, it came up that young people having foreign background had a percentage of .44</seg>
    <seg id="15">was 7 percent</seg>
    <seg id="16">However, other political parties of Germany for example, SPD, Environmentalists organization Greens, and leftist organization Linkspartei were against this proposal that while collecting facts and figures regarding crimes, this should also be inquired that which German citizen has a foreign background.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">We want quick evacuation of troops from Gaza: Olmert</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Ehud Olmert has stressed that for complete evacuation of the army, a future and permanent ceasefire agreement is inevitable.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamas and Israel declared ceasefire on Sunday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Islamic militant group Hammas while announcing one week cease fire, has asked the Israel army to leave the Gaza strip within one week and to finish the barricade on the Gaza strip.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On other side, the leader of Hammas Ismail Hannan has said that Israel has been given victory from God in the Gaza war.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that in Gaza war, Israel has not been able to succeed to achieve its purpose.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Before that, in the city of Egypt, Sharm Al Sheikh, a conference was held of Arab and European countries on Sunday. In which Israel was asked to evacuate its army from Gaza instantly.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It was decided in the conference that soon an international aid conference will be held for Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="9">German chancellor Angela Meerkal also attended the mentioned conference.</seg>
    <seg id="10">At least 1300 Palestinians and including 10 soldiers, a total of 13 Israelis were killed in the war lasting for three weeks between the militants of Hammas and Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the other side, Palestinian President Mahmood Abbas has insisted on the formation of national government in the areas of Palestine.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A video message for Germany from Al-Qaeda</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this 30 minute video message, a man wearing a black turban with a covered face and holding a gun, is giving a message to the German Government.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This man is introducing himself as Abu Talha and speaking in German language.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Arabic sub-titles of this video message are also there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">on the side of the screen is the logo of Al-Qaida and the date written in the video is October 2008.</seg>
    <seg id="6">in this message it is said to the German government that after deploying such a large number of troops in Afghanistan this country is thinking that it will not be attacked, if it's not ingeniousness then what else?</seg>
    <seg id="7">introducing himself as Abu Talha, this man however did not threaten to directly attack Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="8">the number of German troops amongst the Allied NATO forces in Afghanistan is around 3500.</seg>
    <seg id="9">last year the German parliament has approved a bill to send one thousand more troops to Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">this is the first message to Germany from Al-Qaida.</seg>
    <seg id="11">having a critical eye on terrorism related issues, the famous expert Mikhail Luders says regarding this message: "the recent suicide attack on the German embassy in Kabul is a proof of the fact that we should take it seriously in any case.</seg>
    <seg id="12">for the past few years Al-Qaida has been issuing video messages on internet and there have been attacks as well after such messages.</seg>
    <seg id="13">On Saturday,the militant organisation, Taliban took responsibility for the suicide attacks that took place outside the German embassy.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Many German newspapers and thinkers are looking at this attack in connection with the Al-Qaidah message.</seg>
    <seg id="15">"They are targeting Germany"</seg>
    <seg id="16">Fundamentalist Muslims are viewing the German Afghan policy in a negative and critical manner.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They accuse the German government of following an extremist policy, not only in Afghanistan, but also in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Because of this, they are considering German as their target, more and more.</seg>
    <seg id="19">In the meantime, the German government claims that the German secret agencies had knowledge about this video, even before it came to light.</seg>
    <seg id="20">The German joint crime control organisation is busy studying the video.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama has taken the position of American presidency.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this setup, let alone the American public, the whole world has different hopes about Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Now when Barack Obama is receiving greetings from all over the world on becoming the president of America, the expectations from him are also rising.</seg>
    <seg id="4">in this reference, the German Chancellor Angela Merckle has expressed confidence in the American president.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I am sure that based on the friendship between Federal Republic of Germany and the United States of America, we can resolve all the issues faced.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Russian prime minister Viladimir Putin has said that Obama appears to a serious and open hearted man this is really a good news.</seg>
    <seg id="7">although the policies of former American president George W. Bush have been facing criticism.</seg>
    <seg id="8">however, his regime is appreciated for promoting China to play a more constructive role internationally whereas China has said about the new American president that he will have to work for stronger military relations between both countries.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Active in German city of Bochum, Chinese political expert Kusuay Wu says:</seg>
    <seg id="10">"in this reference, I am sure that in coming weeks and months, Obama and his team of economists will put immense pressure on China to have a more flexible and competitive to market exchange rate for the Chinese currency.</seg>
    <seg id="11">former American regime has also improved on relations with India.</seg>
    <seg id="12">how far Obama can take these relations, Christopher Raj, Professor of American Studies in New Delhi says on this: "now we have come closer in strategic partnership, however, Obama can not bring an overnight change.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In a message sent to Obama by Pope Benedict, he also stressed upon the need to create an environment of peace and mutual help in the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">State elections in Israel</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This is the first important election in this war ridden country since 2005.</seg>
    <seg id="3">For the state elections, more than 14,400 contestants have entered the arena for 440 seats.</seg>
    <seg id="4">To maintain peace and safety during the elections, 800,000 police and soldiers were posted in Iraq.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Fearing that some bomb blast or terrorist attack might take place on this important day, all the borders of Iraq were sealed one day in advance, i.e. on Friday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Apart from this, the airport was closed and restrictions were placed on public trasnsport.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to reports, due to the restrictions on public transport, there was no traffic on the roads of Baghdad, and children were seen playing football on the roads.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the present Iraqi elections, the security arrangements will tell, on one hand whether or not the local security agencies will be able to take over the country after the return of the American forces from Iraq in 2011, and on the other hand, political analysts are using this as a test as to what extent the public is prepared to bring change to the country in democratic ways.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The state elections are being held with help from the United Nations and almost 800 international supervisors are overlooking the elections.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Youm e Ashura; Youm e Ashura was observed with reverence and fervor in the whole of Iran commemorating the great sacrifice of Syed-us-Shohadaa Hazrat Imam Hussain (AS).</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency reported that in all major and minor cities including Tehran, the capital city of Iran, the mourning of Syed-us-Shohadaa Hazrat Imam Hussain (AS) was observed with veneration and devotion. A large number of believers attended these mourning gatherings and processions, paying their condolences to The Prophet (S) on the martyrdom of his family members. Today the whole of Iran is grieved and sorrowful on the great sacrifice of the Prophets Grandson Hazrat Imam Hussain (AS) in the field of Karbala. The believers recollected the great sacrifice of Syed-us-Shohadaa Hazrat Imam Hussain (AS) in the field of Karbala and took part in gatherings and processions on a large scale.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Retreat of Israeli soldiers from Ajleen province of Gaza, unmatched forbearance of Palestinian soldiers.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Urdu service of Mehr news agency, even on the 16th day of the fight between truth and falsehood in Gaza, there was beastly bombing by the Israel on the city population  of Gaza, by the use of air, land and naval attacks, due to which 880 people have died so far.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Among the martyred are 275 innocent children, who have slept in the lap of death, smiling at the deception of the leaders of Arab countries and of so called human rights organisations.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Today, the always ready to die, Mujahids of Ajeen province have defeated the Israeli army, with the power of faith and martyrdom, and a show of amazing forbearance and steadfastness, tightening the collar of life, around the necks of the Zionist enemies.</seg>
    <seg id="5">If it were not for the deception of Egyptian president, Hasani (not) Mubarak, the brave and loyal Hamas Mujahids would have defeated Israel a long while ago, but apart from the Israeli siege, the Egyptians have also placed Palestinian Muslima under siege, which is the saddest story of Arab history.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Here, the Saudi Arabian and Jordanian governments are giving the Israeli government political and economic support, and are helping Israel by deceiving the helpless Muslims of Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barack Obama: America will use a new policy towards Iran.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report from Mehr news agency, the newly elected president of America, Barack Obama told ABC news channel, in an interview with them, that they would take a new approach towards the Iran dilemma.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama said that Iran would be a very big challenge for the American government</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that they are in a dilemma with regards to Palestinian Islamic organizations Hamas and Hizbullah's support of Iran and Iran's nuclear enrichment program.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But he will not retain the policy of present American president George Bush, with regards to Iran, but would adopt different policies for Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama said that he would make his actual goal completely clear, while stressing on the hope for mutual respect and dialog.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Barack Obama has mentioned in the past that no prerequisites will be set with regards to dialog with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the interview , he expressed the hope that his government would take quick policy decisions on Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Regarding the Middle East crisis, Obama said that he would form a special team</seg>
    <seg id="10">which will start working on establishing peace in the Middle East from the 20th of January.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush, unable and disliked president Bush accepted his mistakes and crimes in his last press statement.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency related from Associated Press that the American president George Bush, in the last press conference of his term, accepted numerous of his mistakes and crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking during the press conference at the White House, President Bush said that though newly elected president Obama has the feelings of well wishing, still, the biggest challenge facing Obama would be to prevent possible attacks on America.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the completion of the Iraq mission and social security reforms were his mistakes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush said that whatever he did, he did it for the sake of protecting America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Upon being asked various questions about the Israeli inflictions on Gaza, President Bush said that Israel has the right to defend itself. According to him, Hamas does not have the right to defend itself and Hamas should not do anything to Israel, and like America, the whole world should choke the oppressed rather than the oppressor.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The incapable and despicable president of the United States said that Hamas should not be given weapons either, while America is providing Israel the worlds most destructive weapons. Israel is using American weapons to massacre Palestinians and Bush also praised the Israel supporting Arabs, calling them the friends of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Bush expressed shame at some of the crimes going on in the Abu Ghraib and Guatenamo jails.</seg>
    <seg id="9">People are opining that cases should be filed against Bush for his war crimes, and that the organisations which manage to do this will have done a great service to humanity.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Iranian President Ahmedinejad expressed sorrow over the silence of the Arab leaders.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by Mehr News Agency, the Iranian President Mahmood Ahmadinejad criticized the Arab leaders silence on the Israeli inhumanity and oppression on Gaza, expressing his sorrow.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmadinejad said, expressing surprise over the Arab countries and their leaders silence over the beastly acts of Israel, that Israel is subjecting the Palestinian public to a holocaust. They are making the Palestinian children, women and civilians targets of their barbarianism, and the Arab leaders have not even given one statement.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmede Nejad has called upon all the Arab countries to unite against Israel and to save the oppressed Muslims of Gaza Israel's harm and tyranny.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ahmade Nejad; Saudi King should clarify his stance on the  genocide being done in Gaza by Israel.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the report by MAHAR/MEHR news agency, President Ahmede Nejad in his message to the Saudi King Malik Abdullah declared that the silence on the human genocide in Gaza and muteness on the murder of innocent children and women by  the Muslim King of Saudi Arabia is a reason that  is encouraging of the enemies of Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmede Nejad has said in his message; You should show your true stance on Gaza and declare support for the oppressed, so that the enemy's efforts of planting differences in the Islamic block should fail.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmede Nejad has said in his message; You know that for the last 19 days Israel is bent upon human genocide, murdering innocent children, subjecting homes, mosques, schools and hospitals to barbaric bombing. The Zonist Regime is brutally murdering the unarmed Muslims in Gaza. In situations like these, silence on the part of leaders like you is only encouraging Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Ahmede Nejad has told Malik Abdullah that even non- Muslim countries like Valenzuela and Bolivia have taken concrete steps against Israel and that he is expected to take better steps.</seg>
    <seg id="6">President Ahmede Nejad told the Palestinians that success will be at their feet in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">and Oppressed will win over the oppressors and thats Allah's promise.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090116.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush; Terrorism is still a threat to USA.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">MEHER/MAHAR news agency has copied with reference from the German news agency that the US President while addressing his successor Barak Obama and the nation in his farewell speech, said that though the US is safer than it was seven years ago but the threat of terrorism still looms over USA.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Bush said that the enemy terrorists are waiting patiently to attack America, and they have a strong determination to attack America so America should never be unaware about its security.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The American President ignored the hurts and suffering of the hundreds of thousands of Palestinians in Gaza, and defended his policies saying that America is still the biggest supporter country of independence. However commentators do not accept the reality of the unpopular president's remarks, as America is neither a supporter of freedom, nor a supporter of human rights, but rather it is the most mischievous country in the world, which not only supports a blood thirsty country like Israel, but is also directly involved in its crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Israel, openly kills children, women and civilians and the American president is congratulating them. This is the American humanity and freedom which the world is seeing in Gaza and other places.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Usama Hamdan: Presence of army in Palestine continues</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by Mehr News Agency, the Hamas leader in Lebanon, Usamah Hamdan told French News Agency, during an interview, that the one sided ceasefire from Israels side is against the comprehensive international efforts for a ceasefire. He said that as long as Israel is present in Gaza, a one sided ceasefire is meaningless.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that the one sided ceasefire was an unsuccessful effort of Israel to escape defeat. Hamdan said that if Israel wants long term peace, it will have to accept Hamas's conditions as well as end this siege.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The Hamas leader in Lebanon made it clear that if Israel tries a one sided ceasefire with its army remaining in the Gaza belt, there will be resistance against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Addressing a one way conference from Beirut, the Usamah Hamdan called for the European countries to break ties with Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Hamas leader said that the increasing numbers of the martyred and injured will only increase our determination.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He told the Palestinian public to stay firmly rooted and resist the enemy like a boulder.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Taliban have killed six people in Pakistan's tribal area of north Wazirastan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">meher reporting agency copied with reference to rueters that taliban have killed 2 Afghans and 4 Pakistanis over accusation of espionage in Pakistan's tribal area of north Wazirastan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">according to reports, on Tuesday morning locals found four dead bodies from tehsil chowk in Tehsil Mir Ali, who were shot dead.</seg>
    <seg id="4">whereas two dead bodies were found in capital Miranshah who were thrown in the market of a Bazaar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Letters written in Urdu have also been found near the dead bodies in which it is claimed that the dead were involved in espionage.</seg>
    <seg id="6">also, two weeks earlier, in Miranshah, capital of north Wazirastan, two Afghanis were killed over accusations of espionage.</seg>
    <seg id="7">over last twelve days, fifteen people have been killed over charges of espionage for America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">it should be clear that during last six years more than a hundred people have been killed in South and north Wazirastan on accusations of espionage. Taliban are accused of being involved in these murder cases.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barak Obama is expected to undersign the closure orders of the infamous Guantanamo bay prison.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr reporting agency has copied through sources that today the American president will sing the orders of the closure of the infamous Guantanamo bay prison.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The new American president, Barack Husain Obama started working on his campaign promises at the surface level.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this regards, President Obama called for making a plan on calling the army back from Iraq, while the American president will sign an order today, to close the notorious Guatenamo Bay jail.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is being expected that President Barack Obama will probably sign on the order today, through which the Guatenamo prison will be closed within one year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Apart from this, the White House is expected to revise suspected terrorism investigation methods and ban ill treatment of prisoners during interrogation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President Barack Obama started to fulfill his election campaign promises from his first day in office, and first of all started by taking steps towards making the actions and working of the government transparent.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Experts say that the American president has started making efforts to save the falling image of America throughout the world, but that would be difficult for it, because as long as it will keep supporting the blood thirsty Israeli government, it can not be expected to do anything good. Therefore if America wants to save its image, it will have to stop its support of Israel and have to disassociate itself from Israel's crimes.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tony Blair stresses upon the need to include Islamic organization, Hamas in the talks</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr news agency quoted from the Britain newspaper, The Times, that former Prime Minister Tony Blair stressed upon the need to include Hamas in the talks, to bring about peace in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the newspaper, Tony Blair said that it is important that a path be found for bringing Hamas into the Middle East peace process. Blair criticized the Bush administration for speaking only to Mahmood Abbas and ignoring Hamas. It should be clear that the western countries have realized the democratic and organizational powers of Hamas and are calling for bringing them into the talks, whereas previously they used to consider it a terrorist organization. A terrorist organization which is trying to defend its country and struggling to save its own house from the clutches of others. Whose house and country have been in the hand of the occupying Israeli government for 60 years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Murder of Balochistan merchants in Karachi, Complete strike in Quetta</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Due to the death of four merchants from Balochistan in Karachi, a complete strike was in effect on Thursday against it, in Quetta and some other places.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this period all business centers remained closed, whereas traffic was also less than normal.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The protesting strike was called by the 'Anjuman Tajiran Balochistan' (Balochistan Trade Union), Pushtunkhwah Milli Awami Party and the Jamiat-e-Ulama-e-Islam. They accused the Karachi police of having openly fired at these merchants, when they were going by car to their vehicle showroom on Tariq road.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The president of the Anjuman Tajiran, Abdur Raheem Kakad demanded that the guilty police agents should be arrested and action should be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, the stand of the Karachi police about this incident was not immediately clear.</seg>
    <seg id="7">All four of the dead merchants were from the border city of Chaman.</seg>
    <seg id="8">A large amount of security was provided by the government during the strike, and police officers were posted throughout the city, at important locations.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A senior commander of Hamas was killed in Israeli attack.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In an air attack by Israel, a senior Hamas commander was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This is the second death of an important Hamas figure, in the week long Israeli attacks on the Gaza belt.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Officials of Hammas have said that Abu Zakaria Al Jamal was killed on Saturday in his palace located in North of Gaza city.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Scholar Nazar Rayyan of Hammas was killed  in another aerial attack by Israel on Thursday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Residing in Rome, Hammas's exiled leader Khalid Mashal has expressed taking revenge and threatened Israel with a ground attack.</seg>
    <seg id="7">There are thousands of soldiers and tanks of Israel placed on the border of Gaza and they are waiting for fighting orders.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America has appealed for a cease fire. But has said that decision of fighting on Gaza is based on Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="9">American President George Bush, on his weekly radio speech, has accused Hammas of excitation to aggravate violence. And has adjudged their rocket attacks on Israel as terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He has said that America is working on cease fire. But one-way agreement will not be accepted.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Three dead bodies found in the Northern Waziristan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani security officials have said that three dead bodies are found in the tribal areas of Northern Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">There is doubt that Taliban have killed them by giving them death sentence.</seg>
    <seg id="4">These dead bodies are found near the main city Meran Shah of northern Waziristan. And with them, such notes are found in which these men are blamed to be American spies.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officials said that probably one of the bodies is of the man who was kidnapped last week.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the other two bodies damaged with bullets are of Afghan inhabitants.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Israeli attacks on Gaza continue on the 10th day</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A Palestinian child injured in the Israel missile attack.   Israel ground army is fighting with the troops of Hammas in the entire area of Gaza strip where as Israeli aerial army continued attacks on the area's of militant groups on the 10th day.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The defense minister of Israel, Ehud Barack, said on Monday that they will continue the army operation until the people of Southern Israel are safe from the rocket attacks of Hammas.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Although, besides the attacks of Israel, the rocket firing is continued from the side of Hammas in which four people including three local citizens are killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Leader of Hammas, Mahmood Zuhr on monday insisted on his friends to demolish the Israeli Army and target local Israeli residents.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But one official of Hammas said that they plan to send a delegation to Egypt on Monday to think about the current violent situation of their party.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In Gaza one Palestinian woman injured. Medical sources in Gaza said that during the last 10 days almost 530 people have been killed and these also include those 11 civilians in which at least there were five children.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Israel, in a ground attack, has reported one soldier killed and 10 more injured.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Israel has stopped journalist, to do reporting on the military action, from entering Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">the elected vice president of America, Joseph Biden has reached Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">the Foreign Minister welcomed the American Vice President.</seg>
    <seg id="3">the elected Vice President of America along with his delegates have reached Islamabad  or Friday on a tour to Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Foreign Minister Shah Mehmood Qureshi and higher officials of the American consulate welcome them.</seg>
    <seg id="5">American senator Lindsy Graham is also accompanying Biden in this visit.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Press officer of the American embassy Luo Fentern told voice of America that the elected vice president will discuss different regional issues with Pakistani officials but he restrained from giving more details.</seg>
    <seg id="7">sources from Foreign office say that apart from government officials, Joseph Biden will also meet the Chief of army staff General Ashfaq Pervez Kiani.</seg>
    <seg id="8">it is expected that apart from bilateral and global issues, war on terror related issues will also be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Joseph Biden was awarded Hilal-e-Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After arriving in Islamabad, Joseph Biden met with President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="11">During the meeting the president presented him with Hilal-e-Pakistan on playing an important role in forming close relations between Pakistan and America.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Please have it cleared that last year Joseph Biden, together with Senator Richard Lugar, introduced a Bill as a chairman of Foreign Affair committee, favoring the increase in  America's foreign army provision to Pakistan in the coming 5 years by 3% to a total of 5.7 billion dollars.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Joe Biden played an important role in removing the previous president Parvez Musharaf, Prime Minister Gilani</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Yusuf Raza Gilani and Joe Biden ( File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="3">Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Gilani has stated that America's Vice President candidate Joe Biden has played an important role in making Parvez Musharaf leave as Army Chief of Staff. And Joe Biden has also helped a lot for democracy in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Yusuf Raza Gilani made this statement during a talk with the press in Shipyard, Karachi.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He said that Joe Biden is Pro-Pakistan or supports Pakistan. And he, as a chairperson of Foreign Affair Committee of American Senate, presented a bill of 15 billion dollars aid for Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On protesting against missile attacks done by American investigating jets, Prime Minister Pakistan said that Pakistan has no agreement with American government on permitting such attacks and according to him, this is a matter of Pakistan's despotism therefore they can not permit attacks of these kind on any condition in the country's premises.</seg>
    <seg id="7">he also expressed a hope that after the succession of the new American government, change will come to the American policy as well.</seg>
    <seg id="8">(File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="9">Yusuf Raza Gilani has said that the government has successfully separated taliban from ordinary tribesmen but the drone attacks have proven to be very harmful to the efforts of the government and the terrorists once again join hands with the local tribes.</seg>
    <seg id="10">he said that the international community agrees to this stance of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Prime Minister added that if reliable evidence is provided, then the Pakistani Forces will operate itself in its own territory.</seg>
    <seg id="12">prime minister yusuf Raza Gilani repeated his stance over Mumbai attacks and said that if India provides evidence, then investigation will be carried out on its basis and if there is any proof of someone's involvement, he will be dealt according to the laws of the country.</seg>
    <seg id="13">while answering a question about Rehman Malik's tour to Britain and his meeting with the MQM leader Altaf Hussain, the Prime Minister said that Rehman Malik went to London on his approval.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Quetta, four policemen including DSP killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">File Photo</seg>
    <seg id="3">on an important highway of Quetta, Saryab road, firing by unknown people killed four policemen including DSP 'Deputy Superintendent of Police".</seg>
    <seg id="4">On Monday morning, a jeep carrying two DSP's one Sub Inspector and two constables was traveling towards the police training center when two people sitting on a motorcycle near the degree college on Siryaab road started firing at them without any provocation, resulting in the death of Sub Inspector Mehdi, Constable Sibghatullah and Nasrullah died on the spot, while DSP Hasan Ali died upon reaching the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hospital sources say that the other injured DSP Ghulam Muhammad's situation is also critical, and he has been shot in the neck and the head.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After the incident, the police have surrounded the area, but as of yet, no one has accepted responsibility for the incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The death of another Indian software engineer in America</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Another software engineer belonging to Andhra Pradesh has been shot and killed by unknown attackers.</seg>
    <seg id="3">26 year old Akshay Vishal of Secunderanadwas shot two days ago by unidentified assailants in the state of Arkansas. Vishal died in the hospital while undergoing treatment two days later.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was an employee of Satyam Computers and was providing services for Falcon Jet Airways in America.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In the last one year, seven students from Andhra Pradesh have been killed by American anti-social elements.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The rise in the deaths of those going to America for higher studies and employment from the state has increased the worries of the thousands of families whose children are in America.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It should be known that America is preferred in Andhra Pradesh for higher studies and brighter futures.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the statistics of American consulate in Chennai, 100,000 American visa applications are received from India, from which the majority i.e. 40% is from Andra Pardes.</seg>
    <seg id="9">During this time, the provincial government started trying to bring the dead body of the deceased to Hyderabad.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">America should stay alert for Enemy's attack: Bush.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">President Bush has insisted America on being alert for enemy's attack in his last weekly speech on radio.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Bush has that even today, America's biggest threat is another attack from the terrorists. He has warned that enemies of the country are waiting patiently and are ready to attack again.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Retiring president has said that America should never be ignorant of its safety.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush has also expressed best wishes for the next President Barrack Obama, who will take his oath on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Newly elected President Barrack Obama shed light on the historical importance of his oath taking ceremony in his speech on radio on Saturday.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that this ceremony is a tradition in which transfer of the power from one leader to another in a peaceful way is also highly related to the American greatness.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mr. Obama reminded that in the entire world, there are many who can not even imagine that their leaders will retire from their positions without violence and shedding of blood.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Meeting in Raiwind between Sharif Brothers and Federal Minister for Interior; Political and security issues were discussed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The largest opposition party in the center and the ruling party in Punjab, the Pakistan Muslim Leagues leader Nawaz Sharif and Federal Minister for Interior Rehman Malik met in Raiwind on Sunday; the meeting was also attended by the Chief Minister of Punjab Shahbaz Sharif.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to local media, Rehman Malik brought a message from the leadership of Pakistan Peoples Party.</seg>
    <seg id="4">But talking to journalists after the meeting, Rehman Malik did not mention any details about this matter and only stated that he came to talk about building consensus on political issues and to brief the PML(N)s leadership on the aftermath of the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He said, I informed them about the steps which have been taken so far.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Dont forget that the major crackdown was done in Punjab by the Punjab Government and the team which I have formed now will also require help from the Punjab Government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Rehman Malik said that the media is not briefed every day but messages are exchanged with PML(N)s leadership on daily basis. On the other hand, Pakistan Muslim League spokesman, Pervaiz Rasheed, also refrained from talking about any of the political issues and only stated that Rehman Malik had told everything which was important.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be noted that the Interior Minister met with the Pakistan Muslim Leagues leadership at such a time when 20 Nazims belonging to PML(Q), the opposition party in Punjab, held a press conference with Governor Salman Taseer. PML(N), while dismissing the objections of the Nazims against steps taken by the provincial government objected to the involvement of the Punjab Governor, member of Pakistan Peoples Party, in this matter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Speech of Obama is pleasing for Pakistan: President Zardari.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">While welcoming the inaugural address of American President Barak Obama, the President of Pakistan Asif  Ali Zardari has said that the  mutual interest and to encrouage relationship  among muslim world shown by him is pleasing for Pakistan and its people.</seg>
    <seg id="3">in a statement issued on Wednesday, he said that reiteration of high moralities and values from the American president is a hope for a better future for the people of the world.</seg>
    <seg id="4">president Zardari stated that there is no doubt that there is a great pressure on America to join the world community to find ways of peace, prosperity and complacency.</seg>
    <seg id="5">it should be clear that president Obama after taking the oath for his designation said on Tuesday in his opening speech that  America wants development in relations with the Islamic world which should be based on mutual benefits and respect for each other.</seg>
    <seg id="6">he told the people of poor countries that America will work with them so that there is social development and reduction poverty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Obama nominated a special representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">former ambassador for United Nations Richard Holbrooke has been nominated as a special representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Holbrooke played a vital role in peace agreements in Bosnia Herzegovina.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Holbrooke said that he is ready to be an advisor to president Obama on Afghanistan and Pakistan issues.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He clearly said that this is not an easy task.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that both countries have entirely different history.</seg>
    <seg id="7">George Mitchell has been selected for Middle East who will try to revive the Arab Israel dialogue.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mitchell is an Ex-minister and he had played an important role in establishing peace in northern Ireland.</seg>
    <seg id="9">while talking at the state department today, he said that the situation in the Middle East is very vulnerable, complicated and dangerous.</seg>
    <seg id="10">But despite of this America will not step back from the efforts for peace over there.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghanistan: Voters' registration in danger.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Election commission of Afghanistan that due to concerns over security, it is delaying voters' registration is some areas in south.</seg>
    <seg id="3">in southern Afghanistan the voters' registration had to be started this week for the upcoming presidential election.</seg>
    <seg id="4">but the commission has told that unless the security situation does not improve, voters in few areas of province Hilmand will not be able to get registered.</seg>
    <seg id="5">in those parts of South, repression has increased from last year, where the rebel talibans have increased attacks on Afghan and international forces.</seg>
    <seg id="6">meanwhile, the Afghan and international forces have said that during the night, between Wednesday and Thursday, they have killed at least 28 militants during fights across Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">NATO has said that their army has destroyed 22 fighters during air and land attacks on Eastern province Khost near the border of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Before that, Afghan Ministry of Defense stated that in the same province, Afghan army killed 8 rebels and injured two.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is not clear whether Afghan officials have mentioned the same incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090123.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Two missile attacks in Waziristan, at least 18 people killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistan authority has said that at least 18 are dead in the 2 ambiguous American missile attacks in the North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the officials, American jet fired three missiles near a house in the area Mir Ali of north Waziristan, killing 10 people in that house.</seg>
    <seg id="4">according to the local officials, there were 5 foreign fighters in those who were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This area is considered the center of the Taliban and Alqaida's fighters.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After a few hours of this incident, southern waziristan was also attacked with a missile, in which at least 8 people died.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Apart from disagreement of Pakistani government, after the mid of the last year, there have been almost 30 missile attacks in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The present attacks were the first attacks since President Barack Obama took office.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The Bush government was avoiding to take acceptance for or deny the attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="10">On Friday, suspected American spy planes dropped three missiles in the tribal region of North Waziristan. Until now, five people have died.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The dead could not be identified.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to initial reports the missile attacks were on a house, in the locality of Mir Ali.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It should be known that these are the first missile attacks on the tribal regions of Pakistan, since Barack Obama became president.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">In the state of Sarhad, the officials have rejected the demand of putting a restriction on girls education.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the state of Sarhad, the officials have rejected the warning to put a restriction on girls education, by the Taliban soldiers, saying that this announcement is against both law and Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On Sunday, the education minister of Sarhad state, Sardar Husain Babar added that the government will never allow such efforts to succeed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that it is the effort of the extremists that the children of our region remain deprived of education.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words: "These people try to secretly blow up schools and frighten the boys and girls"</seg>
    <seg id="6">Talking about the environment of fear and insecurity, he said that the local government knows well and wants it to be known that no force can stop the spread of education in the land of the Pukhtons.</seg>
    <seg id="7">One day ago, the Taliban soldiers, led by Moulana Fazlullah had demanded the banning of girls from studying in Swat's educational institutions from the 15th of January.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Despite the military activity going on in Swat, during the last one and a half years, about 150 educational institutions were destroyed by the militants by the use of explosives and arson.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Due to the destruction of these educational institutions, thousands of girls and boys were deprived of the facility of education.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Strict security arrangements in India on Republic Day.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The 60th Republic Day is being celebrated in India on Monday. On this occasion, strict security measures are being taken and thousands of soldiers were posted throughout the country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On the occcasion of Republic Day, during the army parade in New Delhi, weapons, planes and other military equipment is displayed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Officials are saying that the security arrangements include anti aircraft missiles and sharpshooters and that police will be deployed to watch the roads of the parade. American President Barack Obama congratulated India on the occasion.</seg>
    <seg id="5">And he also wished Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, who had undergone a heart operation on Saturday, a speedy recovery.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Please note that yesterday Indian police had claimed to kill two suspected Pakistani fighters near New Delhi after an encounter.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to local government police had recovered AK47 rifles, grenade an some papers from both persons. Which indicates that they were probably from Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Police is also investigating this matter that whether these two persons belong to the banned organization 'Lashkar-e-Taiba' which was involved in last November year's Mumbai attacks.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tea: A good cure for breast cancer</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a new research, drinking three cups of tea every day</seg>
    <seg id="3">the chances of breast cancer is reduced by more then one third  in women less then 50 years old.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In a research conducted in MOFT center of Florida America, it has been told that women with less then 50 years age that have breast cancel onco</seg>
    <seg id="5">gets the chances of breast cancer reduced by 37 percent who drink tea three cups a day.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The research shows that the aged women dont get any effect from drinking three or more cups of tea a day.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The researchers think that the tea contains such elements that are effective against the special type of onco in the breast cancer (that effect the women younger then 50 years age)</seg>
    <seg id="8">in the Moft Cancer Center situated in Tampa city of the State of Florida, a research was carried out on 5 thousand women who had taken the treatment for breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Their ages were between 20 and 70 years.</seg>
    <seg id="10">the experts compared their medical record and life pattern with that of women who were safe from breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">the experts also found out that on a particular type of cancer, Lobular, tea had shown a great effect and it reduced by 66 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="12">almost every tenth patient of breast cancer suffers from this type of it.</seg>
    <seg id="13">this type of cancer is more dangerous because it deep inside and is usually diagnosed when it has already spread to a great extent.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Experts say that by taking at least three cups a day regularly, the danger of breast cancer can be reduced in young women.</seg>
    <seg id="15">they say that making tea a regular drink in daily life can cause great resistance in the body against breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="16">in Britain, every year, almost 40 thousand women are diagnosed to have breast cancer.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Afghan war is the greatest challenge faced by America : Gates.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">American defense minister Robert Gates has said that the war in Afghanistan is the biggest military challenge faced by America.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gates will give a briefing today to the Senate and Parliament over the strategies of the Obama regime on Afghanistan and Iraq wars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Gates told the Armed Services committee of the Senate that fight is not the only solution to the Afghanistan issue. But he added that in order to secure several areas, sufficient number of troops is not there, and the Talibans take advantage of that to carry out their activities.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">why reduce exercise with the age?</seg>
     <seg id="2">new research</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="3">exercise at any age is good for health.</seg>
    <seg id="4">it energizes your heart, reduces the cholesterol level, helps in keeping the weight low, helps in preventing diabetes and slows down the process of Alzheimer or dementia.</seg>
    <seg id="5">unfortunately the ability to exercise reduces in many people with the age.</seg>
    <seg id="6">experts say that exercise keep our body and brain active however age can affect it.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the American Medical Association, several health related problems can arise by not doing exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Dr. Pattricia P. Leka of Maya clinic Minnesota says that increase in age is a big reason for being handicapped from exercise and less physical activity.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Dr. Patricia teaches medicine at Mayo clinic.</seg>
    <seg id="10">She headed a research regarding heart diseases and man's ability to do exercise in older age.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Team of doctors used high frequency sound waves to observe the performance of heart.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In which heart's activity of pumping blood and its contraction and relaxation was studied.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Researches focused their attention on the right side of the heart, which is the main part of pumping blood.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They came to know that with increase in age, problems increase in the relaxation action of heart.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Dr. Patricia says with increase in age, problems occur in the activity of relaxation of heart and with increase in age, this effects the ability to exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Dr. Garvin Ken was part of this research</seg>
    <seg id="17">He says that we were surprised to see that it has an effect  and it confirmed that bad exercising ability is very much related to the heart relaxing activity.</seg>
    <seg id="18">some times blood pressure can cause disorders in heart's functions and heart diseases.</seg>
    <seg id="19">if the doctor and the patient work in tandem in this regard, then they can take advantage of the benefits of exercise even with the age.</seg>
    <seg id="20">a detailed report in this matter is published in a magazine of American Medical Association.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">No chances of an immediate war with Pakistan: Indian Army chief</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Indian Army Chief General Deepak Kapoor has said that there are no chances of an immediate war with Pakistan how ever we are always ready to defend our country and sacrifice our lives for it.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He has accused that despite of commitments and international pressure on Pakistan as a result of Mumbai attacks, the infrastructure of terrorism is not only existent but also proactive in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">he said this while talking to the correspondents in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Indian Army Chief was on a one day tour to the valley of Kashmir in order to analyze the overall security situation in New Delhi administered Kashmir and preparation of armed forces on the borders.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He was asked a question, that according to the media reports Pakistan has rejected the evidence provided from India regarding the Mumbai attacks, what were his thoughts about it.</seg>
    <seg id="7">General Kapoor said that the decisions of peace or war matters are taken by the political leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Talking about the presence of the skeleton of terrorism on the land of Pakistan,he said allegedly, that India will fight against such circumstances who are ready to destroy peace and weaken India.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He said that there are around 7 to 800 fighters present on the land of Indian Kashmir from which almost 50% are foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="10">General Deepak Kapoor said that only with the betterment in the weather, the efforts of encroachment between Pakistan and Kashmir under its government can be increased.  Although India has increased security on the boarders.</seg>
    <seg id="11">They have refused to the possibility of reduction in the number of army soldiers in Indian Kashmir by stating that one can not compromise over the country's security.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May God answer the world's prayers and may Barrack Obama be beneficial for the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Though there is not much hope, but we shall see how the relationship between America and Pakistan , effected by this change, are in our favor.</seg>
     <seg id="3">That what will Mr. Barrack Obama give to the world in the name of Martin Luther King's dreams.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The oath taking of Obama as the president of America, whose part of the name is also Hussain, is where historically important in all the ways, is also a great challenge for the history.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Not only for his own self but also for those who supported him with all their hearts.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This challenge will also be for the white majority as it is not easy for them to accept that a colored man is ruling over them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here, South Asia, specially Muslims who have expectations from them, should remember that he has been elected as the president of America. And Obama should remember that President of America is actually the President of the entire world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After a moment, a man whose brothers and sisters from his generation were brought to America from their countries as slaves and whose sweat and blood have strengthened the roots of the most powerful country of the new era, today a representative of this racially discrete nation will be called the 40th President of this very America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have expectations from this one man.</seg>
     <seg id="3">People who love him, have to have unreal expectations from him.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If Obama succeeds to an extent in reducing the hatred among races and religion in the world, so this will be a win for people who love him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What will be its effect on South Asia and can a meaningful change be expected in the American policy regarding this matter?</seg>
     <seg id="2">How will this change effect the relationship between America and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4">Dear, whether it is Obama or some one else, the decision of the policy of the entire world is done by Jews lobby of  billionaires, influencing, powerful and effective people.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And as far as Pakistan is concerned, after the series of recent Bombay blasts,the offensive reaction of India, America and Israel is in front of everyone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even for a while, after Pakistan was formed, the managing of Swat was left to the Ruler of Swat, which had it's own army and law.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They surrendered their rule to the government of Pakistan according to a treaty.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But it's sad that our governments have treated Swat like a step mother.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There has been no increase in the number of schools in Swat, since the rule of the Ruler of Swat was finished.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Nor was there any interest in the construction and development over there.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The number of girls receiving education in the present rule is many times less than their number in the previous rule.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Sarhad state of Pakistan, the local Taliban have been targeting the educational institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The most schools were destroyed in Swat province, of which the majority were girls schools.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Not only this, but the Taliban have announced the prohibition of girls education in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thousands of boy and girl students are being deprived of education.</seg>
     <seg id="5">what do you think, by stopping girls' education, what the Taliban want to achieve?</seg>
     <seg id="6">why has the government failed to stop these illegal activities so far.</seg>
     <seg id="7">what do you think the government should do.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the question should be that what ISI and Pakistani Agencies will get.</seg>
     <seg id="2">because the people of Swat have now understood this game that the army is there to serve the Taliban and not to kill them, otherwise how can five schools be bombed in a single night and that during the Curfew. How come people can be beheaded during the curfew and hanged in the center of the crossing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">when the writ of the government is not being let implemented, how can the government succeed in stopping these illegal activities?</seg>
     <seg id="2">now the question arises that having an armed force, armed with modern weapons, modern technologies and intelligence system, why the government can not control these few Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">the only answer is that there is a hidden hand over their head, that neither their arms end nor they are apprehended.</seg>
     <seg id="4">result of the discussion is that Taliban with their wrong steps are making it easier for the imperialists.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">fifteen years before the war was continued in Afghanistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">ISI used to control the Taliban when there was the opposition from the Northern Alliance, which was supported by Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Then, suddenly the situation changed and Taliban's works came to light.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And ISI also got an offer of Dollars from America, so the previous friend became an enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now the situation has changed but the war is still going on and those supporting them in Pakistan are still Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Until man realizes what is wrong and what is right, he continues to make mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For instance, when a thief goes to steal something, if he realizes at that time that stealing is wrong, it is a curse and it will bring punishment, and he fears Allah, that person will not steal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Similarly, as long as Israel does not realize that it is doing wrong, and spilling the blood of the innocent, and it will receive punishment for that, it will continue to play Holi with the blood of the innocent people in Gaza.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Greetings</seg>
     <seg id="2">The question is that, is war, armed resistance and terrorism the solution to problems?</seg>
     <seg id="3">If not, then what is the magic recipe that will bring out a solution to the problems?</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is true that war and extremism do not solve problems, but rather it puts 'blessings' in them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Palestine, Afghanistan and Iraq should adopt the same model for their development, that Nelson Mandela had used in South Africa.</seg>
     <seg id="6">That is, to struggle character wise and politically, more than in an armed manner.</seg>
     <seg id="7">From the Kashmiris taking part in the elections, it looks as if they have accepted this view point.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the third week of Israeli attacks on Gaza and the number of deaths have gone close to a thousand.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Despite worldwide diplomatic efforts, to date, a ceasefire was not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">According to another report, since the start of attacks, on the 27th of December, 90,000 Palestinians have left their homes and moved towards safer locations.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here, aid groups have accused Israel of being careless about Palestinian children, and said that a whole generation of Palestinian children will be victim of grave psychological and emotional difficulties.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What should happen?</seg>
     <seg id="7">how is permanent peace possible in Gaza?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Click here for details</seg>
     <seg id="9">(Please note that due to increase in number of comments, only the reviews typed in Urdu will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="10">for this press Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard to select Urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Taliban should be given a chance</seg>
     <seg id="2">basit, Peshawar</seg>
     <seg id="3">Please wakeup, if the Taliban start doing the real Jihad, then who will kill the innocent people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Who will burn down the girls' schools?</seg>
     <seg id="5">who will do kidnapping for ransom or if ransom not paid then blame people of being American agents and hang them on the towers?</seg>
     <seg id="6">these Taliban have brought such damage to Islam that no nation or religion has ever brought.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pashtoon Rore</seg>
     <seg id="8">Kohat, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">if the whole Muslim world just give a joint threat to attack Israel, you will see that how upset will its father America be.</seg>
     <seg id="2">and immediately not only talks on ceasefire but ceasefire will really happen as well.</seg>
     <seg id="3">but what can be done, where should our Muslim leaders bring the courage from.</seg>
     <seg id="4">someone tell Ahmed Nayad to take the first step as he is very popular for his bravery at the BBC forums.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the responsibility of peace and human rights not only lies on Arabs and the Muslim world but its and obligation on the whole world to raise their voice against tyranny.</seg>
     <seg id="2">this unfortunate incident is Bush's worst sin so far.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Just like in Pakistan and India before 30th June or the end of the fiscal year, the government institutions are looted, the American regime just before its end have given a green signal to Israel to do what ever it wants.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">on one hand America says that effort will be made for ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, the United Nations is passing resolution after resolution, but action-wise, neither have done anything. There is only one meaning of this, and that is that the even the United Nations is openly in favor of destroying the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All Muslim countries should immediately end their membership in the United Nations, and should establish their own global organisation.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We have many examples of where only promises and resolutions of America and the United Nations are seen, but the harm is only done to the Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What is the use of these vain efforts if BBC does not want to publish anything?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Where have all the rules of journalism been buried? When blood, specifically of Muslims, is spilled, the monster of unbiasedness gets onto BBC's back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">which considers itself the standard bearer of truth.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Forget about breaking something on its own, the height of heartlessness is that it does not even publish comments</seg>
     <seg id="5">from Muslims</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The only difference between you and the Jews is that they call themselves Jews and martyr the Muslims, and the likes of you stay among Muslims, call yourselves Muslims and cause Muslims..</seg>
     <seg id="2">[syja786]</seg>
     <seg id="3">For a long time on BBC forums, sometimes suicide bombing and other times terrorism in India was used to target a certain sect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The favorite word of these Anti-Islamic discussions was Extremism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You can get a very good idea, about who an extremist is, from the above discussion in which, writing against Iran was almost considered blasphemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When will our muslims understand that Anti Christ can not be fought with swords.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Looking at unarmed people in the bombing of Israel, what shall one do other than crying?</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the basic fault is of this turmoil and massacre which by naming Jihad, we try to blacken the beautiful face of Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When majority of Palestinians accepted the existence of Israel then why did Hammas need to fire those rockets on Israel and made suicide attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Attitude of the both the sides is against humanity.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The role of UN and the USA was again seen as favoring towards the injustice of Israel.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah give muslim nation the understanding of becoming  united. Ameen!</seg>
     <seg id="2">and the real terrorists should be given the noble prize for this painful movement against terrorism, after all they are doing the real work.</seg>
     <seg id="3">otherwise, is this large scale terrorism possible without the support of some big feudal and everyone knows who these controller are.</seg>
     <seg id="4">so in this situation, in common terms it is called DADAGEERI which means do what ever you can.</seg>
     <seg id="5">That it even hits you hard on the head and does not even let you cry.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">medicines for injured, and coffins for the dead are being supplied by the Arab leaders and asked that</seg>
     <seg id="2">Should the Israeli attacks take place?</seg>
     <seg id="3">this is the actual problem that the leaders of Muslim countries including Saudi crownprince are in a false sleep, neither they have an army nor any plan for defense and just by providing aid they think they have fulfilled their responsibilities.</seg>
     <seg id="4">they should take immediate measures against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="5">for example stopping the supplies of petrol to European countries and America but alas they</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salam to All brothers and sisters!</seg>
     <seg id="2">I believe that in this time of difficulty, telling Hamas to stop their struggle for the sake of peace is an injustice to thousands of widows and hundreds of thousands orphans, and it is similar to considering them defeated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If Israel and its supporters are at the height of their Pharoahism, soon Moses will be born within their house, as this is the rule of nature, as the steps taken by America and Israel have acted like a fertilizer in growing suicide bombers among the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Which these power intoxicated elephants are not realizing.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Abu Abdullah, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Hamas and Israel should reconcile so that this bloodshed comes to an end.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Muhammad Sarfraz, Paris, France</seg>
     <seg id="3">Absolutely true.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Lets suppose that Hamas is really the righteous one and they have waged Jihad against the tyranny to become successful in the divine court, even then they should at least realize that if good brings harm to the people then it is of no use</seg>
     <seg id="5">Those who claim to love God, his Messenger, and their religion; it becomes an integral part of their faith to love humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">So after muslims, all believers who are living on this earth should be wiped out according to the command of Allah?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najibur Rehman Psycho, *Lahore* [P@KI@N]</seg>
     <seg id="3">no there are no orders to destroy but to invite them to come to Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">but Jihad is ordered against those who do conspiracies against the religion.</seg>
     <seg id="5">these people should be fought with unless they stop these conspiracies - but this doesn't mean at all that one should wear a jacket and blast himself at a gathering.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">brothers, the only end to the killer of innocent children is destruction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">but I ask my friends that the Israelis who did not have a place to shelter in past have become so strong today that they don't listen to any one, this is because the Jews are united.</seg>
     <seg id="3">there are no Shea's and Sunnis, there are all just Jews and they have developed everything in every field.</seg>
     <seg id="4">in contrast, what is the condition of 55 Islamic countries?</seg>
     <seg id="5">they are behind in every field and they have become so helpless that the enemies are killing them and they are waiting for the death.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">it is essential that all Muslim countries unite and prepare a strategy against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Feroz Magsi, Jhang, Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">and there is no better strategy, that recognize Israel, learn modern education and means of progress and let the world live in peace and harmony.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Muslims have plenty of land and means as well.</seg>
     <seg id="5">the need is of proper use.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">this first most disappointing factor is that Hamas and Alfateh could not unite.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Great leaders like Yasir Arafat and Sheikh Yasin were killed in an organized manner in order to weaken this brave nation which is doing Jihad for the Aqsa Mosque and this was impossible without removing Yasin and Arafat from the way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">the world is witnessing that how Palestine had been scattering  after the death of these two leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and how the Jewish lobby gradually kept strengthening its grip.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">in 1974 a Pakistani prime minister was so worldly trusted that first time in the history he manged to gather all the Muslim leaders under one roof with hundred percent attendance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">today on his 81st birthday, is it a very difficult task that the whole nation promise to not only keep unity in its lines</seg>
     <seg id="3">also, while eradicating the differences between other Muslims,  its (The formation of Islamic common wealth) mission will be carried forward</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">its a monster that has gripped Palestine for half a century.</seg>
     <seg id="2">this monster has many faces.</seg>
     <seg id="3">many times this monster criticizes itself from its own but different mouth to divert the pressure and attention of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and its other mouths are eating humans in Iraq, Afghanistan, Iran and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">this monster is most unhappy with Islam because it knows that whenever it will be kicked out that will be through Islam, Muslims, the perfect religion of Muslim and Practical Islam as the history tells that Islam has put giants like Abu Jehl on the right path.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">bombing from Israeli fighter planes on Gaza has continued  since 27th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="2">more that 3 hundred Palestinians have been killed in these attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="3">after the Arial attacks, Israeli tanks and armed vehicles have reached the Gaza border with complete preparation for a ground attack.</seg>
     <seg id="4">through a unanimous resolution in an emergency meeting of the security council, the United Nations has demanded Israel and the Palestinian authorities to ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="5">however the Israeli authorities say that they will continue operation in Gaza until they make sure that rocket attacks on Israel have stopped.</seg>
     <seg id="6">in your opinion, is this claim of Israel true that it's doing all this for defending the sovereignty of Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="7">is the world community playing its role in such situation?</seg>
     <seg id="8">does this aggression has an indirect relation with the coming elections in Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="9">can any improvement be expected in the situation in Middle East after the succession of the newly elected American president Barak Obama.</seg>
     <seg id="10">(Kindly note that due to the increase in number of reviews, only those typed in Urdu will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="11">for this press Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard to select Urdu)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Palestine will forever remain a sacred place for Muslims and its protection is a must for us.</seg>
     <seg id="2">and we should also remember that it is also our Qibla e Awwal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel and India have to vanish one day since these countries are made to be broken and God will surely torment these disbelievers. Sajid Sadiq, Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="4">"when the night of loneliness can be passed by tearing down</seg>
     <seg id="5">when an affliction can be avoided with only prayers" (Nawabzadah Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC publishes these kind of comments after deep search.</seg>
     <seg id="2">after all a neutral impression is to be maintained.</seg>
     <seg id="3">although the news from BBC are usually correct but the real thing is the style of the news.</seg>
     <seg id="4">what should be pointed out and what news should be given less importance.</seg>
     <seg id="5">etc. etc.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="7">in this art now a days the Pakistani electronic and print media, specially some Urdu newspapers and columnists are no more behind anyone, who cheat in the coverage of the increasing extremism and terrorism or in the "grudge of Muavia" written on them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">has said that the United Nations which apparently talks of Human rights and peace, but when it comes to grimness and coercion over Muslims the only words coming out of its mouth are that Hamas should stop the attacks. how long this hypocrisy will continue.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why there is so much atrocity on Muslims. If people like America leave backing up of Jews then Allah Almighty had said that this nation will live a shabby life and this nation can never live a right life. So if Americans you have courage then leave backing up of them and see then their fate of life.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">So-called writers and murderers in name of peace should understand that peace in the world can only and only be obtained through giving justice not through genocides.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If any nations can be perished through genocide and results of choice can be obtained then after actions of Hitler, existence of Jews and their uprising was impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As poet says.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Atrocity is atrocity, it vanishes when it rises.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Blood is blood, clots when drop.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now who will tell whom what is terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Is this comes in terrorism, why? because own pain is only felt.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Other people are not humans or blood of Muslims is so cheap or color of these innocent's was not red?</seg>
     <seg id="4">And now why there is no condolence message coming from anywhere?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I saw Bombay blasts operation like this fire was in my own house. Can not see the sorrow of mankind. And can anyone not see this sorrow? Alas if Muslims would think as one.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Dead bodies on the road, helpless injured and innocent faces soaked in blood, how shall we condemn, I can not find words!</seg>
     <seg id="2">I feel like crying over the helplessness of the Muslims that on one side people are being killed in India so the rest of the world comes over Pakistan without any proof and asks to perform operations otherwise we will do it ourselves!</seg>
     <seg id="3">And on the other side, Israel is killing generations of muslims in front of everyone and the world is silent. This is unbearable!</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is delay but not NEVER in the house of God and only then will this darkness shed. Then</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the presence of America, danger to the integrity of Israel is a joke.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Considering elections, the rulers should do such activities for people's support. There is no doubt in this specially when countries like Israel exist. Rest talking about Barrack Obama, then history is the witness that no American leader has gone against the policy and nor will do it. Regime, whether black or white, is a regime.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The debate going on in the forum makes it clear that every one is sad on Benazir's death but as a politician, one can not ignore her mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This talk requires debate that whether Benazir gave her life for democracy or for power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If democracy was so dear then  why was it left in 10 year dictatorship of Musharaf until American clearance and the deal.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir did not come to Pakistan when the stratocracised public needed her, unfortunately she came at a time when her acquittal from her cases and her supremacy was promised.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">when each and every historic personality is being accused, there is no one to say any thing over this.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="3">few things are ignored thinking that nothing can be done of them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">another reader.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir/Sir probably you should not only study Pakistan's history but that of 4 friend and 7 other countries, may be you would agree with Psycho's point of view.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tariq Ayaz</seg>
     <seg id="7">'those who don't have a good nature can't be corrected through training'</seg>
     <seg id="8">living green in the water made the reflection of the wheat plant look like a cypress.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Britain never let them unite and established the Hindu-Muslim conflict which was later on brought up by Sir Syed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">psycho</seg>
     <seg id="3">how brutal is our nation, not only we are blind while writing odes on ourselves and our parties but now we are picking, accusing and criticizing every historical scholar and no body is there to say any thing over this.</seg>
     <seg id="4">enough of development that we have made.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="6">few things are ignored just by thinking that nothing can be done of them. Just like a donkey can not become a scholar by just loading books over it.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">although after the Mumbai attacks, there has been a setback in the dialog between Pakistan and India, however Pakistan and India should continue these dialogs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">if we talk of war then it will bring loss of humans from both sides.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India says that the man caught in the Mumbai attacks is a Pakistani citizen and he has also written a letter to Pakistan in Urdu but on the other hand when India initially apprehended this extremist, they said he is a great engineer and afterwards he was declared as a 4th grader; point to be noted.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First of all Mary Christmas to Mr. Bhana and to all the Christian brothers of the forum.</seg>
     <seg id="2">greeting to all friends of the Forum: Mr. Psycho, A. Raza, sister Sana, sister Shahida and Mr. Akram.</seg>
     <seg id="3">we do not want the flames of fire but flowers of peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">War itself is a problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">will war give solution to problems.</seg>
     <seg id="6">it will bless with fire and blood.</seg>
     <seg id="7">will give hunger and exigence.</seg>
     <seg id="8">therefore wise humans</seg>
     <seg id="9">its better to avoid war</seg>
     <seg id="10">in yours and ours yards</seg>
     <seg id="11">its better that the glim keeps lightened</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the India-America relations have deepened and India knows that when the time comes, America will openly betray Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">this is also the old history of America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">in case of and Indian attack, America would get its goals and the expense would be on India as well.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan should make a clear statement that we shall not attack first but if we are invaded then there will be no peace, reconciliation and ceasefire until India is completely destroyed or occupied even if we ourselves get destroyed in doing so.</seg>
     <seg id="5">this is the Islamic history.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">even before this resolution the Pakistani public and army had given the message that they wanted to give.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Indian efforts for achieving diplomatic and military benefits as a ransom for the Mumbai attacks are making it more clever that effected and that is why in contrast to the initial strict reaction the world community has relaxed its pressure now.</seg>
     <seg id="3">while ignoring India's unnecessary bobbery, the satisfaction of the United Nations and the appreciation from the Interpol chief over Pakistan's efforts is a "Side Effect" of India's overwhelming diplomacy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">there are no two opinions over this that it is a heinous act.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But the question is that when thousands of Taliban attacked the house of Pir Samiullah, where and what was the Pakistani army doing at that time?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Should the army not be accountable for what they have done over the past one year?</seg>
     <seg id="4">How many Taliban are killed by the thousands of shells fired by mortars and cannons everyday?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I appeal to the I.S.I that for God's sake, stop monitoring the Taliban and let us live in peace in our heavenly hometown Sawat.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And stop this phony operation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">That day is not far when a resolution about Pakistan's military intervention will be passed by United Nations just like the bill which was passed against Jamat-ud-Dawah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Riaz Ahmad Farooqi</seg>
     <seg id="3">The extremists of our country and their supporters themselves are constantly providing all evidences and justifications required for instigation of action against them, and God forbid, the day when such a resolution is passed, in all likelihood not a single voice would be raised in United Nations, in our favour.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And supposing there is a delay in the enactment of this resolution, then considering the example of America, a superpower will come forward to take over on its own resources.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We are not aware and familiar with the character and achievements of Pir Sami-ullah and what his activities were.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Maybe he was not a revolutionist.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Like the deadbodies of Comrade Che Guevara, Nawab Akbar Khan Bugti, Doctor Najeebullah and thousands of other revolutionists have been subjected to dishonour at the hands of the enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are deathless even after being dead.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But here an international game is being played. Here ferrocity and animosity is created to do the ruling.</seg>
     <seg id="6">So there can be reason created that if we are not here then these vandals and animals can come take over the government.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the name of religion, activities of these so called Islam lovers is highly condemned.</seg>
     <seg id="2">America sees the torture of these extremists but instead of being sad on these faithless activities, they easily name them as tribal culture.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The reason for these faithless activities, sometimes given in the name of tribal culture and other times in the name of Islam, is not something done by a person with a heart.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, people of our army are with these people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">That is because when they change destination, it takes time. But to catch them, forget about getting there on time, even if they are on the spot, they leave from there.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are they so brave that they keep 50-70 people hostage and our army just watches it as spectators?</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are also men of God and so is our army.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is very clear that there is fishy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">instead of promoting God's blessing and merciful nature, discussing various disastrous and lesson gaining occurrences to create an air of fear and terror in the name of religion was being seen. And besides the event of hanging the dead body, their literature and books like "what will happen after death" also create fear and terror.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And these people are using this fear and terror as a shield for the purpose of world power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wiso!</seg>
     <seg id="4">Like you have scared the world from the fire of hell,</seg>
     <seg id="5">You yourself have become the reason of fear.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It comes as a surprise when it is said that this was not done by a Muslim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We are either unaware of our history or we choose to not know about it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who burnt the closed door of the Prophet's daughter on the refusal of oath after the Prophet (PBUH) passed away and how took her husband by the rope in his neck?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Did they come from abroad?</seg>
     <seg id="5">was the attack of Yazid's forces on Medina not the act of Christians and the Jews?</seg>
     <seg id="6">without accepting reality neither the motives can be diminished nor correction can be made.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">O' BBC please stop this dual-headed policy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">better than this topic the super hit title: Shoe-ing of Bush fair or unfair?</seg>
     <seg id="3">'should have been</seg>
     <seg id="4">Tahir Choudhry, Japan</seg>
     <seg id="5">please show some modesty, a human pulled out of his grave and hanged over a pole just because he raised his voice against the oppression, and you are concerned about the topic of the box office.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the success of, operation Sherdil and across the border operation Lion heart, depends on the fact that in whose favor is the opinion of general public.</seg>
     <seg id="2">this act is of American and Pakistani agencies and Peer Sahab is a victim of this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">all discussions on this forum will now be anti Taliban since the secret agents have successfully joined Taliban and they are doing what can change the public opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I only want to ask that when this body was hanging for a whole day, what was the army doing? Are they only there for targeting the public. They even report something like this 'Bombing on Taliban residences, a shell falling on a house kills two children and their mother'.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Did they not know about this mistake?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Or were they watching the show?</seg>
     <seg id="4">We fold our hands and request them to please, for God's sake, stop this game.</seg>
     <seg id="5">After all, there is a ruler above you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Whether the question asked by BBC is understandable or not, it is saddening to see the lack of perspective of the writer. For instance, no one asked what the army of 30,000, in Swat went there to do.</seg>
     <seg id="2">That the bodies of the Taliban who helps the army is left hanging on poles throughout the day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Whatever the green footed Pakistani government did with the Swat public, the media, including BBC did not do good by keeping the world ignorant about the reality.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Pakistani Army is putting up a drama.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Every child in Swat is saying that this is a bloody drama.</seg>
     <seg id="6">For God's sake stop this drama.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These Talibans have tarnished the Muslim image.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If in the whole world true Muslims don't call these terrorists as Muslims then how come these elements are able to live in the lands of true Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Those who become shameless, can't do hard labor they pick up guns and become the members of terrorist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Islam did not spread on the point of a sword or barrel of a gun.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Feel the shame.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Its need is neither in any religion nor in any customs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All media including BBC gives thier views about taliban and tribal areas by different resources</seg>
     <seg id="3">But nobody knows what the actual situation is. It is we who know about it because we are tribals.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In short this is a game in which CIA, RAW, MUSAD, and our own ISI is involved.There is nothing like taliban or tribal people, they are the negative elements created by these institutions who are spoiling the name of Islam, Taliban, Religous institutes, Pukhtoon nation and Tribals.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The heads of Muslims have hung from shame over this action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I salute the leader of MQM, Althaf Husain, and the leaderships of ANP and PPP, as they have spoken against this cancer, i.e. the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This cancer was given birth to by Zia-ul-Haqq. He has gone, but he has destroyed Pakistan as he went.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But I have hope that the present government will eradicate this cancer.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the Mumbai attacks, India had said that there was the hand of some Pakistani extremists behind the attack.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan refuted these claims and said that it would help India in investigation in every possible way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India said that they have given Pakistan a list of the suspected extremists which India wanted.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now, Pakistan said that the Jaish-e-Mohammad leader, who is included in the list, Moulana Mas'ood Azhar, is not under house arrest, and that the government of Pakistan has no information about him.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Previously, the President of Pakistan, Asif Ali Zardari had rejected the idea that western intelligence agencies and the Indian government had provided Pakistan proof about the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">President Zardari said regarding Ajmal Kasab, that it is not yet proven that he is Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="7">meanwhile, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has warned Pakistan that its relation with India can not improve unless its land is being used for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="8">and in a latest development, the Indian cricket team has cancelled its tour to Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="9">should these political instances affect over the sports?</seg>
     <seg id="10">what do you see as the future of Pakistan and India relations.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Neither America will break Pakistan nor India.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan will be broken by Pakistanis themselves.</seg>
     <seg id="3">what do you expect after so much provincialism, sectarianism, and Mullaism.</seg>
     <seg id="4">although Jinnah also did not do good to the Muslims of India and it has been proven with time.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Yasmin, Chicago.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Madam, if Mr. Jinnah's vision was followed, neither the cancer of provincialism, sectarianism, and Mullaism had spread in Pakistan nor the Muslims in India had undergone such behavior.</seg>
     <seg id="7">but it's our fault that we could not bring up a leader like his stature.</seg>
     <seg id="8">if we can not care for our heroes, then</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">this region has great capabilities.</seg>
     <seg id="2">god knows when we'll understand and the region will progress with the blessing of unity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">in both countries the enemies to peace like Mullas, Pandits, Taliban, Shiv sena, RSS have been raised.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and the evil powers don't want this region to progress therefore these countries are controlled like puppets.</seg>
     <seg id="5">can you imagine what status will this region of Pakistan, India and China will have in the world.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Pakistan is under persecution from God that these thieves, bandits and criminals have been imposed as leaders of the nation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">may Allah protect our country from any harm, Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">but Sir, open your eyes to see the surrounding situation and ground reality, you will figure out how far American forces have penetrated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">moreover, the internal affairs don't seem to be good, as you can see the circumstances in NWFP, Balochistan and in Karachi in Sindh.</seg>
     <seg id="4">in this situation the country needs such a leader who can unite us as one nation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">O Allah bestow your mercy upon us.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Account to my understanding, a final war is inevitable.</seg>
     <seg id="2">this is enough of it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">now it should be do or die.</seg>
     <seg id="4">this problem can not be solved through these acts of insincere dialogues.</seg>
     <seg id="5">and not through small scale terrorism in each other's country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">after all, Europe got settled after the final world war.</seg>
     <seg id="7">and if this world war had not taken place, then these countries, just like Pakistan and India, would have been clattering.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Almost all of our political parties agree on this matter that these terrorist and denominational activities should be terminated from the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But our army rule does not seem sincere in this matter. On one hand, American and Europe are made to believe that we are with you on this war against terrorism and the other hand, we also help Taliban secretly.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We have to think now and decide our direction and only choose one way. Thank you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no doubt in this that majority of the members of Jamaat-ud-Dawa are the members of Lashker-e-Tayyaba, who joined  the party  named Jamaat-ud-Dawa Pakistan after Lashker-e-Tayyaba was invalidated.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Although these members preferred subsidiary activities and now after India's great persistence, The United Nation has invalidated it also and Government of Pakistan is continuing the crack down against them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, it is better if Jihadi groups leave religious extremism and continue religious and subsidiary activities.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Terrorist groups present in Pakistan, who support professional criminals and the heads of those Mullahs are those who call Pakistan the land of destruction and what not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And now they are doing everything to destroy Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In reality, they do not even deserve to be called Human beings, let alone Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Without cleaning Pakistan from these evil doers, the country's existence will be in jeopardy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can we still afford to think if we should ban these mutinous or not?</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this world of callous leaders, there is no place for those whose work is only to kill.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This news breaks my heart to pieces.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What kind of world is this where it is hard to live for one who takes the name of one major pillar of Islam,  religion of Allah.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Non-Muslims can kill Muslims but when Muslims even try to take revenge, all our hypocrite leaders together with all the non-muslim world treat people with the true and right pain of religion just like our great leader Hafiz Saeed is being treated today.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">India in impunity of Bombay attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan relation are bitter. Better relationship as a result of last few years between the two countries have been jolted  greatly.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India has always held the military and non-military groups in Pakistan responsible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And bringing relationship back on track is being conditioned by operations against these groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">For as much, Indian security departments have held Lashkher-e-Tayyaba responsible for the Bombay attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this case, name of Jamat-ud-Dawa has come in the front many times.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the first time that relation between both the countries have worsen due to a terrorist activity in India</seg>
     <seg id="8">In December 2001, after the attacks on Indian Parliament, these two neighbors were on the brink of war.</seg>
     <seg id="9">After that, in 2002 Lashker-e-Tayyaba was banned and included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Now Jamat-ud-Dawa, about which Security analysts say that it is in reality a new face of Lashker-e-Tayyaba. Restrictions on the party are being requested.</seg>
     <seg id="11">In your opinion, should this group be banned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Should Pakistan do decisive operations against extreme activists on its land?</seg>
     <seg id="13">By banning Jamat-ud-Dawa, can  current Pak-India crisis be over?</seg>
     <seg id="14">crisis be over? and how important is it to close down the armed groups to keep constant peace between both countries?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Security Council of the United Nations has banned Jamat-ud-Dawa. After all what proof does the security council have to decide this so quickly?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Does the Security Council always show this type of urgency against the Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is what they call a slow complainant and a fast witness.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If you look at it, even India has become an unsuccessful state.</seg>
     <seg id="5">whose intelligence, army and security institutes failed, and were forced to dance at the fingertips of a few terrorists for 72 hours. And India wants to put the blame for its inability on Pakistan, to fool the whole world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When one disbeliever dies, there is hue and cry in the whole world. Why these double standards?</seg>
     <seg id="2">To a non political, religious and social organisation of our dear country---</seg>
     <seg id="3">Furqan Farooq, Faisalabad</seg>
     <seg id="4">As long as our Prophet (PBUH), the Awliya Kiram and the Sufis continued to teach people the lesson of love and respect, the religion of Islam would spread and prosper with peace.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Muslims have also advanced in every field.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But when there was a rise of Mullaism in the religion, there was a division of people into Muslims and Kafirs, and new avenues of mischief were opened, which were not known to the world previously.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salam- Please do it with pleasure but act at your own.</seg>
     <seg id="2">do not do it under American pressure.</seg>
     <seg id="3">if India is aggrieved, it should provide the evidence.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why doesn't it give it?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And why it accuses us of every thing?</seg>
     <seg id="6">there are extremist groups and organizations in India as well, why don't they put sanctions on them?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are we the only terrorist in the world?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What India is doing in Kashmir, what is that?</seg>
     <seg id="9">What Israel is doing, what is that?</seg>
     <seg id="10">the truth is; we are the first Nuclear Muslim State and why; this is the main issue.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is now in the last stages.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Kamran Hassan, ABU DHABI</seg>
     <seg id="3">Your talk touches the heart and circumstances also seems to be such</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now American magazines are very boldly printing the new map of Pakistan and all these sanctions seems to be the part of this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">American are not slowly but now very swiftly tightening there grip over Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">We must remember that in these circumstances,if we as a nation does not display unity and solidarity then if Bangladesh can be created,anything else can also happen.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Terrorist attacks should be condemned to the maximum, whether they are on the Mumbai Hotel or the Marriot Hotel in Islamabad or in Palestine.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Similarly, terrorists should be hunted down irrespective of their nationality and whether they are Pakistani, Indian, American or Israeli.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now the question is that every day terrorist attacks take place in Pakistan, hundreds of people die but the Pakistani officials along with the rest of the world stay silent.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Wasnt the attack on the Marriot Hotel an act of terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="5">then why-</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">hale to the advisor for interior Rehman Malik, how brave and bold has the gentleman become.</seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">not only this, but according to BBC Mr. Malik has denied this impression with intensity that the arresting of the terrorists have been carried out under 'someones's pressure'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">wow, all praise to the Almighty!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">whether having the ability or not or to say that I don't want.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We, the Pakistanis are fighting whose war.</seg>
     <seg id="3">and why we have our own interests which we shall do our best to protect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">No one has  a right to interfere anyone's national affairs.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The colonial system is apparently not there.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If people expect justice, or demand that an external united court be established, respect democratic institutions, and not help any dictator or army man, there will be peace in the third world, including Pakistan, which I think is not acceptable by those calling for unity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As such, Pakistan is always following the goals set by Europe and America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This happens, despite the opposition of a majority of the Pakistani population.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And this causes more opposing feelings.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If they trust America and the United republics, then let them leave the style of new populations, and let them work on those lines, upholding the sovereignty of the state.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan has the ability to arm and disarm.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Pakistan Occupied Kashmir, security forces captured a proved camp of practically non-existent Lashkar-e-Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Since the Mumbai attacks, pressure is increasing on Pakistan to act against the extremist organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India's accusation is that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
     <seg id="5">It is their claim that without a doubt, the extremists who carried out the Mumbai attacks used Pakistani land.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In the meanwhile, officials in Peshawar claim that the lot of trucks which carry supplies to the united forces in Afghanistan was burnt by unidentified armed people, because of which more than 50 trucks were destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the second attack in Peshawar on NATO and American supplies in the last 48 hours.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In the meanwhile, Pakistan captured an established camp of the almost inexistent Lashkar-e-Taiba. Previously, lots of efforts were carried out to try to disarm armed groups all the way from Karachi to the tribal regions, which included giving compensation to those who returned their weapons and even ascertaining them that no action would be taken against them.</seg>
     <seg id="9">The situation is telling us that the efforts undertaken in the regime of General Ziyaul Haqq, after the previous Soviet Union's interference in Afghanistan to get rid of the armed groups that formed as a result of the resistance that started through American and Saudi funding, and to bring an environment similar to that before 1980 were not successful.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The question is what does Pakistan want to do?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Does Pakistan have the ability to do so?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Click here for details.</seg>
     <seg id="14">(Please note that since there is an increase in the number of comments, only those comments typed in Urdu will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="15">For this, press alt+shift on on-screen keyboard and select urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I ask only one question from flag holders of humanity.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If you kill their children and they bring necklace for you, this is impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4">And question from you that from islamic studies to western eastern studies, say any logic, argument and philosophy give permission to kill innocent civilians including praying men, laborers and poor workers of different occupations, in revenge of American attack?</seg>
     <seg id="5">If answer is in no then you have instant need of correcting your point of view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">People were armed, at that time their was a danger that Russia will turn toward Pakistan after Afghanistan, therefore people were armed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now when there is danger that America will overrun Pakistan through passage of Afghanistan of which American president had said out in his election campaign then why should we unarm these people?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Only because America or India army don't have to face any civil resistance after defeating Pakistani army?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Yes, if anyone of them is involved in any destructive actions then Pakistan should act against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">But it is sad that the fact that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved proves India's claim that Pakistan is guilty in this.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeebur Rahman Syco, Lahore</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even if we accept that Lashkar-e-Taiba is guilty, it is still not correct to blame the Pakistani government.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And another question is that were these terrorists not supported by an Indian governmental or non-governmental agent?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are terrorists only born or prepared in Pakistan, and not in any other country of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post63" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As for Lashkar-e-Taiba, the present terrorism is in no way connected to it.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It must be remembered that Hafiz Saeed is the first 'Jehadi leader' who called the Taliban actions 'mischief'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I am sure that the Taliban effect is a inseparable result of American plans, and hence every person who can stand in the way of Taliban must be removed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Despite the support of the whole nation, the fact that Zardari and co. took action against the Lashkar is a clear sign of their frigid and kiss-up nature.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To stop the project that is running on Saudi-American funding, they must be requested themselves to regather, for God's sake, the filth that has polluted our society.</seg>
     <seg id="2">One should also protest against them that according to what ethics, America and Saudi Arabia distributed dangerous weapons and named Jihadis but in the reality spread the virus of hateful literature and culture. Due to which slaughter houses were open in our country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the threat of attack from India, announcement of the Pakistani Army that they will divert their attention to India by removing the army from Afghanistan and the announcement of Taliban that they will take care of the Afghan border, America stumbled badly. And tried its best that India should attack Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This shattered the confidence of America in the area.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Although India did not even threatened nor it has the guts to.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And the rest was taken care of by the attacks of Taliban or American posts.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Thus it was proven that without the support of Pakistan and its army, America can not do anything.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Karachi is Pakistan's business and economic center and Dubai of the less privileged areas.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Hundreds of thousands do not return empty handed from here. But since the law was enforced on the western borders, Karachi has taken all the attention.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now they are looking to kidnap this city.</seg>
     <seg id="4">For the first time Pathan's are called Pashtoons. They are made to fight by making them strangers to each other. Although the need is to be united.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One solution to the problem is that the Urdu speaking learn Pushto or the Pushto speaking learn Urdu, or its better that everybody learns English.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You must be thinking its a funny suggestion, but don't you think the cause of the conflict is also funny?</seg>
     <seg id="3">that the cause of the torture would be language?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir in my childhood I had actually given the same suggestion many times to my friends ,which included people from every religion and rhetoric groups, but my friend people used to laugh over these suggestions.</seg>
     <seg id="6">at that time, these rhetoric and religious differences were not that live and powerful but they were boiling inside.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">its hard to understand that what is happening and why?</seg>
     <seg id="2">are these the signs of the judgement day?</seg>
     <seg id="3">what are these innocent and innoxious people being killed for?</seg>
     <seg id="4">the reason is in front of everyone, ones who want to break Pakistan into pieces are active and those who do all this neither belong to any religion nor a country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whether it is Karachi or Bombay, our homes are burnt with their own lamps( we  have destroyed our homes ourselves)</seg>
     <seg id="6">When the government comes, they just change names of the places to build a name for themselves. Just like these days airports, roads, buildings are all named Benazir.</seg>
     <seg id="7">What has happened in Karachi, is this what Benazir means?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When Bombay attacks were at their peak, the failure of efforts of RA to initiate turmoil in Karachi proves this that in the past political elements working on the payroll of RA have now resigned from their posts.</seg>
     <seg id="2">unjustified killing of Pashto speaking hard workers and Indian threats have awaken sleeping Pakistanis from Karachi to Khyber.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Where reaction full of patriotism of all political, religious, lingual and national parties have taught diplomatic manners to India, at the same time they have also given American planners one more chance to think.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">MQM and ANP are responsible for the turmoil in Karachi and management is showing self interest.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Management can control the situation in 1 hour but it is being given wind on purpose.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Pressure of political parties on police and rangers keeps them from doing the operation.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Talks of getting united are only limited to statements, political parties should let go of their self interests and work for the interest of a common man.</seg>
     <seg id="5">until there is pressure on the administration, these kind of incidents will keep taking place.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I think these people are the biggest terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">and foreign powers are definitely involved in this but no one knows who they are?</seg>
     <seg id="3">but alas that if these incidents were in any city of NWFP, then what would the government have done over there, but since its not in NWFP, the government seems to be helpless.</seg>
     <seg id="4">the government should operate here and save a large and very important city of the country from terrorism</seg>
     <seg id="5">otherwise Pakistan will face a huge financial crisis.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC Urdu is also not writing the truth under pressure and Pakistani media's condition is already weak.</seg>
     <seg id="2">the whole truth is there on BBC English.</seg>
     <seg id="3">one solution to the problem is that either Urdu speakers should learn Pushto or Pushto speaking learn Urdu or better if every body learns English.</seg>
     <seg id="4">you will definitely take is as a funny suggestion but don't you think the cause of the conflict is also funny?</seg>
     <seg id="5">that language is the reason of violence?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There was another story of cruelness recorded in Karachi, terror of which was being felt by every citizen for a long time.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Wherever one could do something, he did everything. Reports on the media are 50% of what has happened here in four days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Stayed awake in the last four nights and still afraid.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Who evacuated hotels, killed cobblers peanut sellers.</seg>
     <seg id="5">causing depredation on Super highway and cutting off ears of the innocents are all not aware of the punishment of Allah, which will catch them one day.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In your opinion, what are the reasons of this sudden disturbance?</seg>
     <seg id="2">(BBC)</seg>
     <seg id="3">Placing in front of us the heart struck attacks of Bombay, we certainly do not have to dive to find the reasons for this disturbance in Karachi. But there is one simple and easy reason that this disturbance was the result of spilling of blood subconsciously.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is evident that if some one will knock kneed with the father, it is not unusual for the son to get out of control.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the blood of the loyalists of Liaqat Ali Khan also belonged to the same place but to eliminate Mr. Psycho's misunderstanding I am writing this verse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">we will also repeat our elders' traditions</seg>
     <seg id="3">we made it by sacrificing lives and will save it by doing the same</seg>
     <seg id="4">Faizan Tauseef Siddiqui</seg>
     <seg id="5">it is very disappointing that whole country is at stake and we are fighting with each other.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mr. Siddiqui, I request if wikipedia.</seg>
     <seg id="7">see Liaqat Ali Khan, you will will find out that he belonged to a noble Punjabi family from Karnal in Punjab.</seg>
     <seg id="8">due to his steps for the migrants, today the migrants consider him as one of them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">there is always a reaction to every action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">one can afford on oneself but.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Ejaz Aiwan</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sir, before you gather a huge crowd very quickly, I should tell you that you are finding the open memento of the real gangster activities these days on the walls of Karachi in the form of wall chalking and posters.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We have been tolerating both kinds of actions.</seg>
     <seg id="6">These thugs did not even forgive Pakistan and the founder of Pakistan, they did not face any reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="7">On the contrary, we are writing our hearts on the chest of Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One Muslim League N was left, even they made a draft of the 18th amendment and gave it to People's Party.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Before this, MQM and Muslim League Q have made and submitted a draft of the 18th amendment in the National Assembly and the Senate.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Till now it seems that drafts of the 18th amendment is a political trick and no one is sincere in getting this amendment approved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the reason why  no one has made a fuss in the assembly or senate floor in the favor of this amendment nor has forced the assembly to approve this change.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It seems like that after submitting the drafts of 18th amendment, these parties have done their part that is they will be able to say this tomorrow that we submitted the draft, government speaker did not take any action.</seg>
     <seg id="6">MQM coalition partner of government, Muslim League N an underhand ally of government and Muslim league Q the party to approve the seventeenth amendment then how is it possible that these parties can be sincere to approve the disapprove amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="7">its just like writing your name amongst shaheeds by just putting color on yourself.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Peoples Party anyway is not in a hurry to dismiss the seventeenth amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="9">How would one think of getting his own hands cut.</seg>
     <seg id="10">as long as Zardari is the president, seventeenth amendment is not going to be cancelled.</seg>
     <seg id="11">this is an opinion of a majority in our survey and so is the truth.</seg>
     <seg id="12">if the seventeenth amendment was to be cancelled then Zardari would never had become the president.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Now he is even more powerful that president Musharaf as along with being the president he is also the chairman of the Peoples party.</seg>
     <seg id="14">as long as he is the president, the seventeenth amendment will remain intact.</seg>
     <seg id="15">in order to cancel the seventeenth amendment, the political parties will first have to dismiss president Zardari from the presidency.</seg>
     <seg id="16">neither MQM wants this nor other parties.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Most elders of our family belonged to labor class.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And when we in our childhood we used to see our uncles doing strenuous labor it gave birth to this desire in our heart that God protects us from strenuous physical labor.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To seek refuge from it we wrote a letter to the editor of daily Amroz and asked what should we do after matriculation exams that we dont have to go through strenuous physical labor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Editor in his reply wrote that we should become a doctor or an engineer and should opt for such and such subjects to study.</seg>
     <seg id="5">From the beginning we were inclined toward engineering and also in metric we opted for technical drawing instead of biology.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But at the time of admission in FSC elder brother insisted on doing FSC in Pre Medical and become a doctor.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We hardly studied biology for a month and when we couldnt understand a thing we swapped biology for Mathematics.</seg>
     <seg id="8">It means that the fear of strenuous physical jobs made us to become engineers and now we are well placed among many the youth of our family and for this we are thankful to God</seg>
     <seg id="9">This we remembered when we were trying to lift carpet from our old house with our two young sons.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It was not even 30 minutes for us working that our younger son said Dad it feels like I am not born for this job.</seg>
     <seg id="11">We said if it is true then study hard like us and free yourself from physical labor.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Son started saying that I am studying and will complete my studies but I cant do this work .</seg>
     <seg id="13">Three of us somehow managed to finish the job and got back home.</seg>
     <seg id="14">What it means is that when a man decides the destination no matter what were the motives behind this no one can stop him from getting it.</seg>
     <seg id="15">But if you dont even know what you have to do then God be with you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is said that do not say bad about the dead. But what shall we do, we see only bad things in Benazir even on her first death anniversary.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir, for her selfish purpose, crushed the independence movement of the Sikhs after giving the list of their names who were fighting for freedom on one hand and on the other gave India the chance to keep its full attention on Kashmir after them helping to suppress Punjab Movement.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Tug of war between Benazir and Nawaz Sharif rule is part of the history, which has pushed the country back many years.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir continued to give negative comments on Kashmir and the nuclear program after being exiled.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Benazir violated the London agreement with Nawaz Sharif and made a deal with General Musharaf.</seg>
     <seg id="6">during her rule, Benazir gave a free hand to her husband to make as much money that is why he is known as Mr. Ten percent.</seg>
     <seg id="7">during Benazir's rule his brother got killed but his murderers are still safe from any punishment.</seg>
     <seg id="8">besides being a woman herself, Benazir avoided fighting for women's rights.</seg>
     <seg id="9">just like Benazir did her politics over her fathers dead body, similarly her widower is doing the same over her dead body.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Benazir came into power twice but she could not punish her the culprits of her father's political murder even she couldn't register a case against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">it has been 37 years since East Pakistan separated from us but look at the extreme of senselessness of our people and leaders that we never celebrate the mourning day.</seg>
     <seg id="2">what should have happened instead is that we should have celebrated 16th December as a didactic day and take such measures that this kind of incident don't take place again.</seg>
     <seg id="3">on this day we could send greeting to the people of Bangladesh and try to bring them closer to ourselves again.</seg>
     <seg id="4">the rulers would reopen the Hamudur Rehman commission reports and discuss the reasons for the separation of East Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They used to make arrangements to bring back the Bahari's stuck in Bangladesh and send them presents to raise their spirits.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But we lack feelings now. We are not even aware if someone dies in our neighborhood.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We do not care about our brothers and sisters because we have become selfish.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Even if a great accident occurs, we are busy in our daily routines of life from the next day.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Only if East and West Pakistan could be one together just like East and West Germany was united once again.</seg>
     <seg id="10">We can be one again if we both sacrifice for each other and come out of the hole of selfishness.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But this wish does not seem to be granted in the near future.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When it was announced in the news today that the Governor of the American State Illinois was arrested for corruption charges</seg>
     <seg id="2">and when the State Congress started getting ready to remove him from the position of the governor as soon as possible, then there is this one American companion who has a close watch on the circumstances of Pakistan, boastfully claimed to us that this is what we call democracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In America, even the higher level people can not transcendence the law.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and there is your country Pakistan whose president has been elected after dropping of corruption charges.</seg>
     <seg id="5">my sense of humor woke and I said that what's wrong if a governor got arrested in America, in Pakistan, once we arrested the Prime Minister overnight and hanged him and the second time we exiled one.</seg>
     <seg id="6">tell me when it happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan sent off the lawbreaker with guard of honor from the presidency, tell me when did such thing happened it America?</seg>
     <seg id="8">In Pakistan, the Chief Justice was suspended in such a way that besides the public support he has not be restored so far, did it ever happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Holder of a fake degree was made the minster for health in Pakistan, did it ever happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="10">after hearing all this the American went down laughing and then conceded defeat.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">in this picture, president Zardari is smiling despite of being surrounded by the Americans from all four sides.</seg>
     <seg id="2">it looks from his smile</seg>
     <seg id="3">He is thinking that America is supporting his government but he is forgetting that a year ago they were with Pervez Musharaf.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This picture has been taken as it was a family gathering</seg>
     <seg id="5">A photo like this was never published in the papers before; one president with three American officials.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It seems the American involvement in Pakistan has increased and more than one official is needed to do the job; or they are not relying on their new puppet the way they relied on the one before him.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This could also have been arranged keeping in mind the stories of President Zardaris breach of commitments.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If it had been a sensible ruler, at least he would not have been grinning during the photo session and he would have had a subservient and embarrassing look on his face.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If the principle of democracy is applied on this picture then Present Zardari is in minority.</seg>
     <seg id="10">In democracy, majority rules the country and the picture reveals the actual rulers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The scenic Swat valley is also called the Switzerland of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The governments policy so far is to engage in talks besides the use of force.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the use of force is achieving nothing other than strengthening the Taliban and increase in public sympathies for them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">what needs to be done is that the government, instead of using the power, should eliminate the causes of the issue.</seg>
     <seg id="5">by eliminating the causes Fazlullah and Taliban will automatically finish.</seg>
     <seg id="6">the Sharia bill proposed by ANP will become the solution of the problems of Swat to a great extent.</seg>
     <seg id="7">But besides implementation of the Sharia, the government will have to give more attention to the economical issues.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">from the early steps of General Musharaf, it looked like the nation has got rid of the incompetent politicians, but the lust of power changed all his plans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">all the hopes were from the participation in the "war of terror", he had started considering himself as immortal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">those steps which were expected, all broke-off.</seg>
     <seg id="4">as soon as Bush's era came close to an end he started worrying about the end of his rule and in that bewilderment, he made a deal with the thieves.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Even then General Musharaf could control the Army but never know what's happening to the present government.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Either its Bajor or Swat, the army does not control terror but bombs the "Enemy" public; along with loss of lives and wealth if you make the enemy a mentally sick, then aren't we the Enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Swat, the strongly affected part of Sarhad state, despite the continuity of military action for over one year, the situation is still going from bad to worse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On one side, the government is only reiterating the passing of a reproachful resolution in the national assembly. On the other side, the Taliban's illegal radio FM channel is having much more influence in the region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the third side, the common man considers it safest to listen to the one who actually has control over the region.</seg>
     <seg id="4">During the action of the security forces, there were claims of destroying the fundamentalists by the bombing of gun ship helicopters and cannon houses, but despite these destructions, the Taliban only became more powerful, and according to an estimation, their control over Swat increased that much percent more.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a result, on the one hand the government is not ready to accept defeat, and on the other hand the Taliban is stronger.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Who is stuck in  between? The poor civilians.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is said in Swat, that someone asked what kind of people are the Taliban were, so he got the answer, 'They are very good, as they are protectors of the religion and they fight against the enemies of Allah and the religion'.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Then he asked how the army was, so he got the answer, 'They are very good, as they are the protectors of the country and they fight against the enemies of the country'.</seg>
     <seg id="9">He then asked who the enemies of the religion and the country were, so he got the answer, 'We civilians'.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I am wondering how the Pakistani Army will fight the Indian Army, when they couldn't control a small faction of the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They could not track the illegally set up FM channel of the Taliban, which I believe was very easy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But still, the FM channel is spreading poison with all vigor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the girls schools, now boys schools are being destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Curfews are called so that the Taliban can move around easily.</seg>
     <seg id="6">During curfew tonight, eight trucks entered the outskirts of Mengorah and formed barriers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The question arises as to how they got there despite the curfew.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The army could kill Akbar Bugti in his house, but salutes the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="9">For God's sake, can someone explain to the army to save the poor public from the grip of the Taliban and prove that the Army can defeat any enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">You say that mostly blood is spilled in the world because of religion. Tell me today, if there was no religion, would all this killing not take place?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are Punjabi, Pathan, White, Black, Mahsood and other tribes the result of religion?</seg>
     <seg id="3">No! No way! Sir, religious is what teaches that no one is black or white, punjabi or muhajir otherwise if religion was not present, then half world would have vanished for the war between white and black and other half fighting over the status and sect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Actually, religion gives moral teachings to the man. And binds him that he is not here on his own choice but the creator of the universe has sent him here. And he should spent his life according to his rules.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a muslim, I have total faith that Islam is complete way of life and a true religion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After living in London, for many years I used to ask wellness of my family over the telephone every morning. Although many did not even call once to find out how we were. Then I realized that they do not even tolerate our phone calls so we stopped calling.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Living here in France for the last two years, I have also felt the same thing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Do not know why people expect us to call.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A resolution passed about Iraq in a few hours, Darfar has absolutely no problem in sending peace army.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Bombay attacks were condemned in no time and banning dubious groups is only a matter of a few hours.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And where death is dancing, we are doing consensus.</seg>
     <seg id="4">O caretakers of international peace! life is finishing here!</seg>
     <seg id="5">is it really being waited to diminish.</seg>
     <seg id="6">so that any again no aggrieved could even think about using a weapon of mass destruction like the stonebow to gain his own rights.</seg>
     <seg id="7">when a father is running carrying his beloved sons dead body, even then your hearts don't pinch you with pain?</seg>
     <seg id="8">If not then you don't even deserve to be called human being.</seg>
     <seg id="9">but you are a black mottle over the name of humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">so atleast this has been proven that this region has also been a homeland for Jews for centuries.</seg>
     <seg id="2">ideally these two nations should have lived in harmony but since their strings are in Western and Arab hands, so without their will peace can not prevail in this region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">and now even Iran wants to fight its proxy war from here.</seg>
     <seg id="4">even if the Israeli operation stops temporarily, it will start again any moment after any incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC's own country has its interests related to America and Israel and this is why while taking cover of enlightened moderation, it has started a series of blogs or Jewism and doing a biased propaganda.</seg>
     <seg id="2">BBC is only completing a formality, and its goal and intent is only to gather well wishes.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I request the moderator to publish this comment of Fidwi, so it be known that at least a little bit of affinity towards truth is still remaining in BBC</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thank You.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I don't know who wrote this story or how this story came to being, but one thing is for sure, in every age, draculas have been drinking the blood of innocent people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In every age, wars have been fought and blood has been spilled.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the surprising thing is that this 21st century man, who considers himself civilized, is quiet over this ruthless open massacre.</seg>
     <seg id="4">How could I not feel that whatever is happening is presenting a very ugly picture of mankind.</seg>
     <seg id="5"></seg>
     <seg id="6">Well wisher, Sajjad Alhasnain, Hyderabad, Deccan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At this time, including Derah Gahzi Khan, summer showers are taking place throughout the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">here is a poem according to the weather, enjoy the weather along with this poem.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These rains are with your presence.</seg>
     <seg id="4">if it rains, its spring</seg>
     <seg id="5">if it stays then its peace</seg>
     <seg id="6">sometimes comes without a reason</seg>
     <seg id="7">at times spread over day and night</seg>
     <seg id="8">sometimes very noisy and sometimes very quiet</seg>
     <seg id="9">These rains are with your presence.</seg>
     <seg id="10">in a memory, at a night</seg>
     <seg id="11">to a buried ash</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sometimes it was such, that the wind put it out.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Sometimes it burnt itself.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Sometimes each drop seems sorrowful.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Even these rains are from you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All these rulers are going to run away carrying a suitcase. What is it to them, whether the country lasts or not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whether the public sells scrubs or takes lemon peels and scrubs the temple bells with them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">For one, our media is also corrupted, like our leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It's goal is only to extract money from the government, and nothing else.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As for the public, they are ignorant. To speak about them is the biggest ignorance.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Yesterday afternoon something surprising happened.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All police are running here and there, but don't ask about illegal parking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What's more, NYPD traffic was not in the state where it could look at illegally parked vehicles.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Something like this happened, that a plane of the US Air really became a ship and landed in the Hudson river.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Until now, we only now that terrorists are of the descendants of geese.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Yesterday was perhaps historic cold, in New York.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The temperature does not fall this much.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Even my jaws started hurting from my half an hour walk outside.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Imagine, how the people who jumped from the plane into the river would have felt.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It is a matter of happiness that all people were safe.</seg>
     <seg id="11">And it was sad that the companies plane drowned during this financial crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="12">I went by West Side Highway to New Jersey, watching all this, and I saw that Southbound was blocked, but what did I still do?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Yes, I got stuck in the same rush on the way back.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Thankfully, in my one hour trip, the way had opened at least a bit, so I was able to get the 56th street exit.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Otherwise, I had not taken the previous two exits, seeing the lines waiting at them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Makki, My Pakistan: Well, Congratulations, Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ammar: Of course, believing women</seg>
     <seg id="3">Shaguftah: Well, Congratulations, Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sarah: I have slaughtered two chickens and how they are slaughtered, Jahanzeb has already mentioned.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Apart from this, there is no other way.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At this farm, one has to get his own meat done,, including removing the skin.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Basim: .Net might take some to repair.</seg>
     <seg id="8">what happened on the forum?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Linko</seg>
     <seg id="10">in order to work with Listen to Blog, see it in Fire Fox.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Duffer: same to you, Eid Greetings to you.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sir please use Fire Fox.</seg>
     <seg id="13">the snow will vanish.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">we unnecessarily kept thinking of these Taliban of Swat as indelicate but who were only unhappy over women's education.</seg>
     <seg id="2">they kept expressing their grief by demolishing a women's school and college somewhere every day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">but just like other ideas, this idea did not also come true, according to this report by CNN, today on the sacred day of Monday this Taliban gang of Swat have blasted a boy's school.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Swat, The Taliban has destroyed a boys school.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The girls schools were already destroyed, acting according to the famous English saying "Ladies First". I do not know why people are still bent on calling the Taliban uncultured and barbaric.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Another thing that becomes clear from this is that the accusation against the Taliban, that they are against girls education, is not true.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Rather, Masha Allah, they are against education altogether.</seg>
     <seg id="8">May Allah give these Mujahideen more power, and the evil government</seg>
     <seg id="9">which is let loose on us, may He help them in uprooting them.</seg>
     <seg id="10"></seg>
     <seg id="11"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">just a while before this, the wedding of a dog with a girl took place.</seg>
     <seg id="4">look at that groom.</seg>
     <seg id="5">humanity is still a rarity in the twenty first century.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">it is the era of computers and its involvement is ever increasing in every sphere of life.</seg>
     <seg id="2">many people have many reservation over this increasing involvement of computer, for example, in financial matters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">where use of credit card bring ease to life, it also gives better control to law enforcement agencies over your private life.</seg>
     <seg id="4">so now only through your financial matters like through your credit card, you can be located.</seg>
     <seg id="5">and in future when use of real currency will reduce to a great extent, its benefits will increase more and more.</seg>
     <seg id="6">similarly in the world of crimes, instead of playing with the dangers of robbing a bank, the credit card information is stolen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">similarly computers have become the source of friendship.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Social networking sites, like Orkut, Facebook and Myspace are at first level of acceptance.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But do you not think that the more we are following these social networking sites, the further we are getting from people in real life?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Similar are the match making websites, where your desires are matched with others desires and you are shown a list of the people who match with you.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But can you lead a life with a person who is just like you?</seg>
     <seg id="12">I can not, and that is why the spouse is called the better half,</seg>
     <seg id="13">because he/she will get rid of the faults within me.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Perhaps I received a lesser share of wisdom.</seg>
     <seg id="2">From childhood, I thought of everything as being true if it was told by an elder.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the same way, I was convinced that my father knew the answer to every question in the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I was even ridiculed a lot on this</seg>
     <seg id="5">But only that seemed true which was plausible.</seg>
     <seg id="6">I was always perplexed at the need of telling a lie.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Even suffered in this part of my age because of this</seg>
     <seg id="8">So I tried to keep the lies at a minimum.</seg>
     <seg id="9">I refrained from giving false hopes to others particularly with Allahs name</seg>
     <seg id="10">And only say God willing when it was my wish that the work was to be done</seg>
     <seg id="11">Besides Allah knows what is there in the hearts.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a disgusting problem which rears its head due to the ignorance of the religion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to both our religion and the law in Pakistan, infants should remain with their mother.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Their father is responsible for their maintenance allowance and he can meet them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">then when they become mature, they live with whom they wan to live.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You are right that the actual problem are the relatives who misguide.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">feudalism has overshadowed our deeds.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Even here is thinking is prevailing that there will be more partners in father's property so it is resisted, although this act of the father is commendable should be imitated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">here these restriction regarding making of relations have created many evils in the society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">concept of remarriage of a divorced or a widow is getting rare.</seg>
     <seg id="5">due these unnecessary beliefs and tradition the family system is facing disarray.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">in our society, if a wife of a 50 or 55 years old man dies or a husband of wife passes away and they remarry, then why it is not appreciated?</seg>
     <seg id="2">there is a Pakistani uncle near us whose wife died a good 10 or 12 years ago, now after getting all his children married when he married a widow, his own children have gone against him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, this is religious right, what do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="4">What type of mentality is the 'while we are there, no one can take our mother's place', kind of mentality?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion the children of this person should think that after having married all the kids, is there anything wrong in his marrying a widow?</seg>
     <seg id="2">This way the widow gets a caretaker and uncle also gets someone who will take care of his home.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because his children would certainly be busy in their worldly affairs and would not be having time for him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The reason for this is ignorance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Tomorrow if their wives refuse to look after them, when they are old, what will they do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is a result of the force of society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When people begin to make fun of such a family for doing something like that, children start to feel ashamed of their father's second marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Though they should face the environment and say that their father's action is in perfect accordance with Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is the curse of our society, which we are facing for the last 40-50 years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is acceptable for a wife that her husband does unlawful actions but she does not let him marry another woman.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If its in her power, she will not let him do so even after she dies.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Destroys her afterlife along with her husbands'.And also lets spreading of the immorality in the society.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Nothing happens with singing about Islam. We actually like what our traditions and cultures are.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For example, keeping girls from getting education and fear of love marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And about your question, when sir instead of bringing his wife home, goes to someone else's wife so the dependents just make a fuss for the show and stay quiet and satisfied. ( yeah, later the relatives of the wife get angry)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Indian subcontinent, we accepted Islam centuries ago but we could not let go of this illiterate thinking and always thought of culture and tradition as more valuable than Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Considering man's 2nd marriage as ridiculous, divorce as denigration, divorced as untouchable, love marriage as dishonor and considering a man marrying an older women is dissimulation of the women is only the result of this way of thinking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And over all, by copying the western world, we are declaring the religious and veil as old fashioned.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Accepting Islam was easy, getting rid of this way of thinking is very hard.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Allah grant us all spirit and courage for this.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Amen</seg>
     <seg id="7">Writing Urdu was never so difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Century passed writing such little writing</seg>
     <seg id="9">Know that little is much.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Allah Hafiz</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Ameer Taimoor in his book "I am Taimoor" writes that i found this secret in my life that if leader of any Army is in front line then that Army will never lose.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But here situation is else.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To say that Common people are there to die for us if we die then martyr</seg>
     <seg id="4">if someone from common people dies then murder</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May peace and blessing of Almighty be upon you.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I was coming back to my shop after the Isha prayer tonight, a man who was sitting in his car waved at me and called.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I thought that probable this man has lost his way or wants to ask something, I stopped as his whole family was sitting in the car.</seg>
     <seg id="4">he asked me if I could speak and understand Arabic, I said no problem, you tell me what's up?</seg>
     <seg id="5">he started telling that he has come from Riyadh and here in Medina someone picked my pocket, kindly help me. I said please go away brother, since such an incident has already taken place with me that I gave this man 12 riyals so that he could reach Riyadh, but he started doing the same after moving a little farther.</seg>
     <seg id="6">I was furious, I cursed him and threatened him of the Police, then he ran away.</seg>
     <seg id="7">this is the situation of Muslims now that even for begging we ride our cars along with our families and make at least 2 to 3 thousand a day.</seg>
     <seg id="8">However there is a clear Hadith (SAAW) that the upper hand is better than the lower hand since the lower hand is the begging one and the upper hand is the giving one.</seg>
     <seg id="9">May Allah bless us and make us true Muslims (Amen)</seg>
     <seg id="10">Wassalam</seg>
     <seg id="11">Javed Iqbal</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Wife of famous singer Adnan Sami, reached a police station in Bombay accusing him of torturing her.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The police station suggester her to contact Court.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Adnan Sami's wife Saba Guladari submitted a plea against her husband that Adnan Sami tortures her continuously.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and treats her inhumanely.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now this has exceeded her tolerance limit therefore a case should be recorded against Adnan Sami.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Police instead of recording a report suggested that she should contact the court by saying that this matter is not what comes under police control.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In your opinion, is the accusation of Adnan Sami's wife on him is correct?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What if this accusation is an attempt of tarnishing the name of Adnan Sami?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Let us know of your comments regarding this matter.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Adam Sanghar, Mehr.</seg>
     <seg id="2">as far as allegations are concerned, anyone can post it on someone else.</seg>
     <seg id="3">nothing comes before prestige.</seg>
     <seg id="4">however may be the relations between Adnan Sami and his present wife, he left his respectful life and went to India to make money and now this fame has caught him badly.</seg>
     <seg id="5">this is a consequence of his own deeds.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Washington...</seg>
     <seg id="2">top American officials say that president Obama will take strict stance over Afghan president Hamid Karzai.</seg>
     <seg id="3">in the new American policy over Afghanistan, there is more emphasis on war than development.</seg>
     <seg id="4">officials say that Hamid Karzai is considered to be a hurdle in achievement of American goals Since in his government, there is corruption, drugs business has increased and Taliban are regaining their power.</seg>
     <seg id="5">American officials say that people, who are putting more pressure on Hamid Karzai to do more, include vice president Joe Biden and President Obama's representative for Afhanistan and Pakistan Richard Holbrooke.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that this good administration was noticed after the President Bush left, who used to have a video conference with Hamid Karzai after every 2 weeks and used to emphasize on the role of America in Afghanistan and the development of its city departments.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Officials say that Obama management will work with the state leaders as a backup with the main government.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Officials say that they will emphasize Hamid Karzai on fighting against corruption</seg>
     <seg id="9">Hamid Karzai faces new elections this year. And it is not clear as yet that Obama and his companions will favor his presidency or not.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Is this statement, of the American officials, a forecast of change in American policy regarding Afghanistan?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Is this era of Hamid Karzai ending?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What are your thoughts in this matter?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the series of three one-day matches between Pakistan and SriLanka, Srilanka defeated Pakistan with 2-1.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan defeated Srilanka in the first one-day match although Srilanka won in the next two matches.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In this third one-day match, the nation's team performance was very poor. They worn out in only 75 runs in 23 overs against 309 runs made by the national team of Srilanka.And this is how we faced a lesson learning defeat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">the result of the series proves that the National team has no consistency in its performance.</seg>
     <seg id="5">besides the home ground and all claims, the national team was defeated, what are the reasons of this in your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="6">which departments of the game should be addressed more by the authorities?</seg>
     <seg id="7">are you satisfied with the selection of the team?</seg>
     <seg id="8">which department you will hold responsible for the defeat, fielding, batting or bowling?</seg>
     <seg id="9">please provide your feedback.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Babar Hussain, Judah, it is very disappointing that even today these kind of heathenish  traditions continue. these feudal lords target innocent people with their feudal rule, who would call them Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="2">a Sardar should walk himself over these embers. why the present government do not act against them?</seg>
     <seg id="3">when the judicial justice will come in handy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370243-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Sir Lankan cricket team has reached Pakistan for playing one day international series.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Visit of a foreign team to Pakistan, in spite of Pak India tension is a good sign.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On reaching Karachi Airport the Sir Lankan team was given a warm welcome.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Two matches will be held between Pakistan and Sir Lanka in Karachi while the third one will be played in Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Both teams are asserting highly regarding their batting, bowling and fielding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If Siri Lanka venerates its spinners, Pakistans reliance is on its fast bowlers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Sir Lankas captain Mahela Jayawardene says that no one player but the whole Pakistan cricket team is dangerous.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Muralidharan and Mendis will be the trump cards, while Pakistans captain says that this competition will be tough.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Shoaib Malik has said we have played Murali Dharan before and will take care of Mendis as well. We have made a secret game plan and will reveal it on the ground.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Will the Pakistan and Sir Lanka series live up to claims of being interesting and thrilling?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Which side will dominate in the Pakistan and Siri Lanka series?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Who will win the series?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Who will be man of the series?</seg>
     <seg id="14">Inform us of your suggestions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Gulfam from London has published his own statement, you also give importance to such statements. We wish you also write some truth .and do not change statement like Mukherjee, because it is an order to say truth to the despotic ruler is legitimate. And it is equal to jihad. Mukherjee keeps changing his statements to stay in news.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Yusuf, Dubai.</seg>
     <seg id="2">How is all this is double for these people, when the Kashmiri people have been fighting for independence for the last 60 years?</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, no one asked, and they are now stuck in their war of extremism and terrorism, so they start talking about making up.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First they openly killed the Muslims, now they are in the efforts of setting things right.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Anyway, Pakistan will have to understand their double edged policies.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Asad Khan, London.</seg>
     <seg id="2">India is creating such a situation that the world's attention can be diverted from Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="3">but Pakistan has always shown the real face of India to the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now the British Government is also understanding that the Indians are taking cover from their occupation over Kashmir by blaming Pakistan of terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">and they hesitate to talk to Pakistan over this issue.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">British foreign minister David Milliband has said that by resolving the issue of Kashmir will bring an end to extremism, the government of Pakistan will effectively handle the threats rising on the borders.</seg>
     <seg id="2">it should be clear that the newly elected American president Obama has also expressed similar views over the Kashmir dispute.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The British foreign minister while talking to media in Mumbai and has written in an article that the idea of the war against terror is wrong and killing people just for the threats to one self was the policy of president Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="4">David Milliband has said that Pakistan should not be lenient with the extremist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">due to the stress over the need for resolution of the Kashmir dispute from the major powers, isn't India trying to divert the attention from this issue by creating unrest in the region?</seg>
     <seg id="6">isn't the terrorism in Mumbai a part of this strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is India using terrorism as a base to escape from comprehensive dialog?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Let us know of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Usman Aftab,</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think the big powers do not want to harm Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rather it wants to keep it in check, and hence is thinking of taking certain steps. They know that Pakistan is a nuclear state.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They want to bring about some kind of revolution here.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Foreign countries are only thinking that if they corner Pakistan, they would face some political and geographic problems. They want to help Pakistan, but also want to be successful in their goal.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A citizen, USA.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It has always been a Hindu tradition, that in the side is a knife and on the mouth is Ram.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I think that they get stomach aches over small issues and begin to warn Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are ready in all ways, the Indian Chief of Army should keep his mouth shut or else, we know how to give mouth breaking anwers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Faheem Siddiqi</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ras al Khaima, This conversation is going on due to American mischief. America's mind was already spoiled, but know India is also becoming like that. Let them attack, and they will see the reality, as to who is in how deep waters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel is attacking Hamas, but no one has the courage to stop it. Watching Israel, India also wants to do all that.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Prime Minister, Syed Raza Yusuf Geelani said that the newly elected American vice president, Joe Biden played an important role in removing the ex-president Musharraf's uniform and replacing it with a lame democracy, which is why the Pakistani government has honored him with a special star.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The credit for removing the uniform and replacing the democracy should not go to any political party. The Parliament is not a rubber stamp.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All decisions will be made in the parliament.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Prime Minister said that Qadeer's door was closed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In your opinion, do the public protests against Mina Marriot not mean anything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Has the lawyers movement not played any role?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you have to say about this statement of the Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Make us aware about your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American President, George W. Bush, in his outgoing press conference advised newly elected President Barack Obama saying that he had made many mistakes in his presidency, and that Barack Obama should do whatever he feels is appropriate.</seg>
     <seg id="2">'I did, as a president, whatever I felt was appropriate, according to the situation, and the American law and constitution, giving preference to American interest over my own acceptance'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">He said that the enemies of America are still planning to attack America, and that the biggest challenge for Barack Obama would be to stop those attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He said that not being able to find weapons of mass destructions in Iraq was the biggest disappointment for him, and considering the Iraq mission to be complete was his biggest mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Speaking at his last press conference at the White House, the American President said that this is my last press conference, and I thank the journalists and other friends who are present in the press conference.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you think Obama will not repeat the mistakes that Bush made?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Did Bush delay accepting his mistake?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Will Obama be able to follow Bush's advice?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Inform us of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The American Vice President Dick Cheney says I want to see Usama Bin Laden alive or dead.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He says that Usama Bin Laden is hiding in some hard to reach area and is of no use to his organization, if Usama Bin Laden is arrested alive or dead then his organization must be destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">America is ambitious on the arrest of Usama and the search of Usama is on.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Will Dick Cheney's wish of arresting Usama be accomplished?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Inform us of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the completion of Qaide Aazam Trophy match between PIA and Habeeb bank the all rounder cricketer Shahid Affridi had quarrel with one fan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">When Shahid Affridi came out of the drawing room after playing the match on the UBL ground then a big number of fans gathered him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On one situation a fan held the hand and asked to take a photo with him on which Shahid Affridi removing his hand said that he can take the photo tomorrow but on fan's insistence Affridi became angry and slapped him, before they start a quarrel the gathering people just dismissed the matter there itself.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After that Shahid Affridi said that without any reason he was made an issue therefore at that time he was in a hurry to attend the Prayer.</seg>
     <seg id="5">nevertheless I shall apologize to that spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="6">what would you say on this behavior of Shahid Afridi.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Let us know of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian prime minister Manmohan Singh has once again accused Pakistan of provoking for a war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And Pakistan is using terrorism as a state policy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">while addressing a Chief Ministers conference in new Delhi, Manmohan Singh said that the terrorist elements are backed by neighboring countries specially Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and the terrorists of the Mumbai attacks used the pelagic route and were safe from the Indian coast guards.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Indian prime minister said that the November attacks were carried out by Lashkare Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="6">he added that the terrorists are using modern techniques and the latest communication systems. We'll have to be more rigorous over the line of control where in the intrusion takes place. He said that terrorism will not be spared in any case and this is our policy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">how do you see this allegation from the Indian prime minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Do the internally opposed and separatist movements of India show the disturbed situation n India?</seg>
     <seg id="9">On whose orders is India taking this warning stance?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Give us your views.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Zubair Khan, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is a sad calamity that Israeli is massacring the Palestinians and the same situation is prevalent in Kashmir, but there is no effect on the Security Council.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the organisations present in Palestine and Kashmir should keep their war going until they gain independence, and they should form unity among themselves and keep facing any type of harm, and one day or the other their martyrdom will give fruit, God Willing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The air attacks by Israel on Gaza are continuing, just the same. Until now, hundreds of Palestinian men, women and children have been martyred.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Important Hamas leader Nazariyan was killed along with hwife and children.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Here the Security Council meeting concluded without any decision.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The meeting saw American opposition to the derogatory resolutions passed against Israel by Libya and other Arab countries.</seg>
     <seg id="5">From the last few days there has been bombing by Israeli planes on the Palestinian civilian population.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The whole world cried out about the Mumbai issue, but the Israeli attacks do not seem a massacre to anyone including America and Britain.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Why are the important Islamic countries quiet?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What do you want to say about this double standard of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Saeed, New York</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think that actually, most of our people are illiterate. They do not know where their money is going. The government fixes taxes and likes to fulfill its duties, the electricity and gas crisis will not be like this.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because everyone knows the role of those selected by the people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The electricity and gas crisis across Pakistan has taken a serious position.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other side, there was an increase of an average of 18% in gas rates, while the unavailability of petrol in some cities has become a cause of great difficulty for the public.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Among the manufacturing and business circles, there are strong protests and severe reactions going on, to the long power cut and gas crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The producers have given the ultimatum to close the factories.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Here in Karachi, the public is perturbed over the 8-10 hour load shedding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The production life cycle has become practically paralyzed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The government institutions are blaming each other to express their stand.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Are the talks of increasing the prices of electricity and gas not a joke against the nation?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Why is attention not being paid to solve the problems.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Are the wheels of national development not seeming jammed to the government?</seg>
     <seg id="11">What immediate steps can you suggest to gain control over this crisis?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Let us know of your opinions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Imran Khokar from Madnah Munawwarah, I would like to say that rulers are a reflection of societys morality.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I am surprised that government carrying slogan of public service is itself hurting them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">unavailability of electricity, gas and petrol has become a persecution.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Government has no control over the institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Law and order situation is deteriorating every day, may Allah bestow his mercy on this country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">new year has started.</seg>
     <seg id="2">last year was the year of outbreaks and political ups and downs. it will also be remembered in reference to the terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="3">stepping down of President Musharf and the end of the eight years rule of president Bush, throwing of shoes on Bush and formation of democratic government in Pakistan, calamities, earthquake in Baluchistan, global financial slump and monopoly.</seg>
     <seg id="4">new year is arriving, how do you foresee the new year?</seg>
     <seg id="5">in your opinion, what will be the result of the political or geographical situation. what will be the Obama's strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="6">is there a hope of a development towards eliminating terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="7">will the judicial crisis in Pakistan come to an end?</seg>
     <seg id="8">what direction will the Indo-Pak relation take?</seg>
     <seg id="9">is there a chance of surgical strikes or a full fledge war?</seg>
     <seg id="10">what are you expectation from the new year?</seg>
     <seg id="11">please provide your feedback.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370256-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First death anniversary of Benazir Bhutto Shaheed is being celebrated. she was martyred on 27th of December, 2007 after a  congregation at the Liaqat Bagh in Rawalpindi.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir is no more amongst us, she was a statesman, politician and world famous personality and had a unique status in national politics.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One year has gone by but the mystery of her martyrdom has not yet been resolved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">her efforts in bringing democracy in Pakistan and formation of government have not gone in vain.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Today Pakistan has a democratic government and her husband Asif Ali Zardari is holding the chair of the president.</seg>
     <seg id="6">how do you see Shaheed Benazir's role in Pakistan's politics?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Who can be behind her martyrdom?</seg>
     <seg id="8">she was recently awarded with the global award for human rights. what would you like to say about her political and democratic services.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">after ruling America for 8 years, president Bush has departed from the White House and shifted to the president camp office in Camp David so that the White House can be renovated according to the new president Barak Obama's likings.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During Bush's eight years rule, the historical attacks and destruction of the World Trade Center, attack on Pentagon and then in the name of war against terror, attacking Afghanistan and Iraq and involving forces from other countries into the war and use of American resources in it have become memorable examples of his time.</seg>
     <seg id="3">due to this war America itself faced the worst ever economical and financial crisis in history.</seg>
     <seg id="4">what do you think the world achieved and lost through this war?</seg>
     <seg id="5">were the policies of Bush successful?</seg>
     <seg id="6">what is your opinion on president Bush's rule?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the Indian government has stopped the Indian cricket team from visiting Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Indian cricket team was supposed to play three tests, five one day matches and one 20-20, during the tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rajiv Shekhla, the Vice President of the Indian Cricket Board, in an interview with Jeev News said that the board had asked the government for permission to go on the Pakistan tour, but due to the difficult situation in the two countries, the tour was not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Is the Indian government's decision to cancel the trip in view of the present political situation a proper step? Should sports not be separated from politics?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is the Indian government's decision not harmful for cricket?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Despite the fact that the security condition in India is bad, the England cricket team is continuing its tour, so why can't the Indian team make the tour of Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion on this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salman, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">Those people who are proud about going to India</seg>
     <seg id="3">and they make their films and videos over there, their eyes should open now, as to how much the people of India respect you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I remember an interview of Adnan Sami, in which he said that he is not Pakistani, rather, his citizenship is of England.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan Sami should return to Pakistan first chance he gets because respect did not suit you there either.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fareed Ahmed</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="3">Indian's attitude has changed after Bombay Attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jagjit Singh has showed his reaction in this way that he hates Pakistan and Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="5">One should know that Adnan Sami has sung with Asha Bhonsley. How is he a bad singer now? Adnan Sami Should stay in India, there is not need to come here.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muhammad Shamshaad Alam</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi, On the statement of Jagjit Singh, I would only say that he changes color like a chameleon.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who gives statements in relation to the circumstances. Pakistanis! open your eyes to how much value you are given in India. Understand their mentality.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the Bombay incident, there hateful statements have increased. The same people are now saying evil against the famous singer Adnan Sami.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">according to a foreign news agency, during his final visit to Iraq when American president Bush along with Iraqi president Noori Almaliki were in a press conference in his office, the situation went ludicrous when an Iraqi journalist while addressing President Bush said "You dog this is a farewell kiss"</seg>
     <seg id="2">after that the journalist removed his shoe and threw it towards Bush. president Bush expertly ducked before the shoe could hit and saved himself.</seg>
     <seg id="3">second shoe hit the American Flag.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Security personnels dragged the journalist away from there.</seg>
     <seg id="5">at this point, president Bush said that he didn't know why he had done so , Shoe was of number 10, I had no problem.</seg>
     <seg id="6">do you think this reaction of the journalist wasn't an expression of deprecation or President bush from the Iraqi people?</seg>
     <seg id="7">what would you say on this incident?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The tension between Pakistan and India's relations after the terrorism in Mumbai got further intense when the fighter planes from the Indian Air force violated the Pakistani airspace in Lahore and Kashmir sectors.</seg>
     <seg id="2">as a result of retaliation from Pak Air force, the Indian planes were forced to go back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">sources say that both Indian planes were loaded with ammunition.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the first of its kind incident in the current tensed situation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan Air Force says that Air Force is all set for country's air defense.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Information Minister Sherry Rahman says that Indian officials have accepted that aerial boundaries have been crossed. Although, this happened by mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan military sources have declared this incident felonious.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In your opinion, does India really have an intention of air strike on Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is this statement of India correct that this violation was a mistake or this was to find out the ability of Pakistan Air force.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Is this incident not going to aggravate the current estrangement among the two countries?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please inform us with your comments.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Respected martyr Benazir Bhutto was given the International Award for Human Rights after her death, which was received by her son and chairperson of the People's Party Bilawal Bhutto Zardari.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During a session of General Assembly in United Nations headquarters, former prime minister of Pakistan, martyr Benazir Bhutto was presented with this award for acknowledgment of her efforts for human rights in a ceremony.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The 60th anniversary of the passing of the human rights resolution by the United Nations was celebrated on the 10th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Among those people and institutes being recognized with honors on the occasion, for working for human rights, apart from Benazir Bhutto, were former American Attorney General, Louis Ramsey Clark and Human Rights Watch, the organisation that works around the world for human rights.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On this occasion, the Pakistani Ambassador to the United Nations, Abdullah Husain Harun and other senior embassy agents were present.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you say about the former martyr Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto receiving this award?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Samir</seg>
     <seg id="2">Chicago</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is true that she was martyred, but we also remember how many innocent people she killed in Karachi, upon which she was proud that Nasirullah Babar did well.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But later, she changed totally.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is also true that she ignored the senior members of her party, and made her son the representative of Peoples Party. What kind of democracy is that?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Jami Noor, Karachi, This news proves that disbelievers will only help disbelievers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But until the iron ax is not fitted with a wooden handle, it cannot cut a wing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our rulers are just like this, that they are adopting secretive ways. This is why calamities are befalling the country.</seg>
     <seg id="4">May Allah guide our rulers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Security Council panel of the United Nations have included the name of Hafiz Sa'eed as well as two other Pakistani citizens and that of Jama'athud Da'wah as well as four other organisations into the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Pakistanis whose names were included in the terrorist list by the Al-Qaidah and Taliban Sanctions Committee of the Security Council included Jama'athud Da'ah chief, Hafiz Mohammad Saeed, practically non-existent organisation Lashkar-e-Taiba Operation Chief, Zakiur Rahman Lakhwi and Financial Chief Haji Mohammad Ashraf.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Apart from this, a saudi national, Mahmood Ahmad Bazek was also included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Among the organisations were Jama'athud Da'wah, Pasban Kashmir, ArRasheed trust, and Al-Akhtar trust International.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The member countries will immediately freeze all the assets of these individuals and organisations, they will be restricted from traveling and will be under arrest.</seg>
     <seg id="6">They will have to face cases.</seg>
     <seg id="7">These regulations are not as a result of Indian influence, are they?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Why is India blaming these parties for the Bombay attacks without any proof?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Aren't there any terrorist groups in India?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Are International groups not aware of the tortures being done on the minorities in India?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please inform us with your suggestions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Occasion of Eid represents happiness and joy and monotheists sacrifice animals following the tradition of Ibrahim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During this turbulent time when inflation is at its peak, political situation is not promising, even after this rich and poor prepare for Eid within their means and wish their relatives a happy Eid in different ways.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We are also providing you with the chance through this blog to wish your loved ones a happy Eid through short messages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You can also wish by writing verses with reference to Eid</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Murtaza Jilani.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi, our leaders should understand this that people, they are doing the operation against, are the true valuers of Pakistan, who are tolerating all kinds of tortures but they love Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>

