<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="translator3">
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">French Proposal Endorsed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Committee met on Friday at Parliament House under the leadership of Committee Chairman Mushahid Hussain Syed, whereat it was proposed to the government that besides relief goods, a parliamentary delegation comprising of representatives of all the political parties should be sent to Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Talking to the media representatives after the meeting, Mushahid Hussain Syed said that the Committee welcomed the French proposal which states that Israel should observe immediate ceasefire and in addition, allow relief activities for the effected people of Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Declaring Israeli attack on Palestinians as crime against humanity, he said that all countries should condemn these attacks</seg>
    <seg id="5">Criticizing double-standards of the international community, Mushahid Hussain questioned as to why countries that speak against terrorism are now silent on the Israeli attacks on Palestinians.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Chairman of the Senate's Standing Committee for External Affairs also criticized the indifferent attitude of Muslim leaders towards the Palestine issue.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that the Committee expressed hope that America's newly elected president, Barack Obama, will address the Muslim community during his first one hundred days of government in order to bridge the gap between America and the Muslim community.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mushahid Hussain Syed said that not only should urgent steps be taken to bridge the gap between the Muslim community and the West but longstanding issues like Kashmir and Palestine should also be resolved.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The Minister of State for Foreign Affairs, Malik Emad Khan, informed the Committee that he is leaving for Saudi Arabia to attend the foreign ministers' meeting of the Organization of the Islamic Conference.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This urgent meeting has been called as a result of Israeli attacks on Palestine. He said is aware of the Palestine issue and the government is in touch with the leaders of other countries in this regards.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The Minister of State for Foreign Affairs said that the Palestine issue should be resolved in accordance with the United Nations' resolutions.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Two journalists related to Arab countries also attended the meeting and they informed about the current situation of Palestine, in the meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Meanwhile, students of the International University in Islamabad held a protest against Israeli attacks on Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Protesters were also holding banners and posters with slogans written on them against Israel.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Avoid Dieting to Protect Against Flu</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This research by American scientists has come out as a result of experiments conducted on mice.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Experiments proved that the ability to fight the flu virus, relatively decreased in mice kept on a low calorie diet.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Research has proved wrong the old saying, to 'starve a fever'.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to scientists one should eat heartily in a fever.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to the researchers of Michigan State University, mice on diet were found to have much less ability to fight infection and they had a higher possibility of death, whereas mice on a normal diet had a higher immunity against the flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to professor Elizabeth Gardner, people that are dieting will not only be affected by the flu more quickly but they will also take longer to get well.</seg>
    <seg id="8">She also said that those individuals who have already taken the flu vaccine should also avoid dieting during the few months of winter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'First Nuclear Test, Carried Out in 1990'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Thomas Reed, who has worked as Weapons Designer at America's Lever National Laboratory, wrote this book in coordination with former Director of Technical Intelligence at the Alamos National Laboratory.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This book has been written under the title, 'The Nuclear Express: A Political History of the Bomb and Its Proliferation' and both the writers have claimed in it that every country that has made the atom bomb has either stolen nuclear secrets from another country or has had the cooperation of another atomic power.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Thomas Reed said in an interview to the US News that in 1990 China tested Pakistan's first nuclear bomb during Benazir Bhutto regime.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Thomas Reed said that he believes, based on many reasons, that China had tested Pakistan's first atomic bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The reasons include the design of that bomb and information received during conversations with Chinese scientists.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He further said that this is why Pakistan was able to carry out atomic test within only two weeks and three days in response to India's atomic tests in 1998.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Thomas Reed recalled that Russia had suddenly conducted an atomic test in 1961 and in response to it, it took America seventeen days to conduct a test in spite of the fact that America had that bomb for a long time.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He further said that the atom bomb tested by Pakistan in May, 1998, had been made very carefully and Pakistani scientists had full confidence in it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">When asked, why China provided nuclear technology to Pakistan, Thomas Reed replied, it was because India was the common enemy of China and Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that there was also evidence that Dr. Abdul Qadeer Khan had in fact used Chinese design, and in addition, the documents that were later acquired from Libya confirm this.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Responding to another question as to whether joint atomic tests are common practice, he said that America had openly conducted nuclear test in the Nevada Desert for Britain in 1990.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said that we also speculate that Israel was also provided access to the results of this test.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Thomas Reed was also asked whether China's atomic proliferation program continues.</seg>
    <seg id="15">At this, Thomas Reed said that since 1991China had been providing raw materials, instructions and design for the nuclear installation in the Iranian city, Isfahan.</seg>
    <seg id="16">In addition to this, China also provided Iran with the enrichment plant in Karaj</seg>
    <seg id="17">He said that China had been providing atomic technology to Iran, Syria, Pakistan, Egypt, Libya and Yemen through North Korea.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">2008 - Best for Madonna</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This show had been organized, based on Madonna's album 'Hard Candy' which included one or two performances with Ukraine's Gypsy or Bedouin Band and Justin Timberlan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In it, an old racing car was also placed on stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Celine Dion's was the second most successful show of 2008 in terms of profit, in which $236.6 million was acquired.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Canadian show 'Taking Chances' toured 24 countries while Madonna only visited 17 countries, which was her first international tour during the last eight years.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Jimmy King, who had organized the 'Reunion' tour for the 'Spice Girl,' was the director of both the singers' shows.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Madonna has broken her own record set in 2006.</seg>
    <seg id="8">She had earned $193.7 million in 'Confession Concerts' in 2006.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Pollstar declared Bon Jovi the third most successful singer, who had earned $176 million.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bruce Springsteen took fourth position having earned $166 million and Police came in fifth with their share of $120.6 million.</seg>
    <seg id="11">According to this magazine, in 2008, very few people attended concerts and music shows in North America and only those attended these shows who were ready to buy costly tickets.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On average, ticket prices increased by eight percent in America and the most expensive tickets for Madonna's show sold for $350.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Gary Bongiovanni, Editor of Pollstar, said that in view of international economic recession, 2008 has proved to be a good year for singers.</seg>
    <seg id="14">He predicted that 2009 will prove to be a good year for U2 and Springsteen whose albums are to be released this year.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Co-education banned: Taliban</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Local Taliban of Hafiz Gul Bahadur group distributed pamphlets in Miranshah, the headquarter of North Waziristan, and other sub-districts, threatening those government and semi-government educational institutions where boys and girls are receiving co-education.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The pamphlet states that if co-educational institutions are not closed by 5th January, actions will be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The pamphlet said that women would be banned from obtaining identity cards for government assistance and educational purposes and they have also banned women from going to the offices of NADRA in all districts.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Local Taliban have announced the ban on women from obtaining identity cards at a time when around 200 women in North Waziristan have submitted application forms for identity cards to the offices of NADRA for Benazir Income Support program.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to local people, the pamphlet issued by Taliban was read out on loudspeakers of all the mosques.</seg>
    <seg id="7">However, it has not been mentioned in the letter whether or not separate educational institutions for girls will also be banned.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the pamphlet, if any woman is caught going to school for education or to the offices of NADRA for obtaining identity card, she and her family will be punished according to Shariah.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Moreover, according to the police of Bannu district, a landmine exploded on Miranshah Road, Bannu on Sunday, due to which one passerby was killed and another injured.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The injured person has been admitted to the Bannu Civil Hospital.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Target killing' More Bodies Found</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police, two beheaded bodies were found from Green Chowk and Sohrab Khan Chowk areas in the head quarter, Mingora.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The victims are said to be from Frontier Corps and police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to eyewitnesses, a letter was found near the bodies in which it was warned that if anyone removed the bodies before 11:00 am, he would be responsible for his own death.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the local people, bodies kept lying in the market till 11:00 am, however, later, security personnel picked up both bodies and moved them to the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="6">During the last few weeks, incidents of target killing have increased alarmingly in the headquarter, Mingora, and adjacent areas</seg>
    <seg id="7">in which ordinary civilians, including women and security personnel have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to local sources, more than 30 people have so far been killed in such incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="9">No organization has yet accepted responsibility for these killings.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Muslim Khan, spokesperson for the local Taliban in Swat, told BBC on Saturday that of the three bodies found on Friday, three were of his colleagues, including one of Deoli Taliban Commander, Rafiullah.</seg>
    <seg id="11">According to Muslim Khan, Rafiullah was in custody of the security forces for the last month and a half.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He said that when local Taliban kill someone, they issue him a notice prior to it, while on the other hand, these incidents have caused great panic among ordinary citizens.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The local people say that although a large number of security forces personnel are stationed in Mingora, attacks on civilians are still increasing.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bakhtawar's Song Pays Tribute to Benazir</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A rap song (a modern style of music) recorded in Bakhtawar's voice has now been posted on YouTube as well.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This five-minute song is illustrated with pictures and video clips of Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Eighteen-year old Bakhtawar is a student of Edinburgh University.</seg>
    <seg id="5">She is deeply fond of poetry and singing.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is being said that she started amateur singing apparently after her mother encouraged her.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Paying tribute to her mother, she says, 'You were intelligent and beautiful; you did everything in style.'</seg>
    <seg id="8">About the incident of December 27, she has said: You received bullets close to temple of the head, abandoned us at 54, leaving three children behind.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The entire nation is hopeless without you and you are present in their heartbeats.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bakhtawar, after 20-years old Bilawal, is second among the children of Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
    <seg id="11">She has been fond of music from an early time.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It is being said that before her mother returned to her homeland, she expressed her desire to meet the Grammy award winning music producer and rapper Puff Daddy through a journalist friend of her. But this meeting could not take place.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Some Sindhi newspapers had also published the translation of Bakhtawar's poetry but her voice is being heard for first time through YouTube.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Some activists and sympathizers of Benazir Bhutto have started making CDs of Bakhtawar's rap song.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Pakistan People's Party spokesperson Farhatullah Babar, on the other hand, has confirmed that the poetry and voice on YouTube is of Bakhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="16">He said over phone from Islamabad that this is the tribute of a saddened daughter to her brave mother, which has been broadcasted on Pakistan's official TV Network as well.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar said that, at the moment his party had not made any plans to distribute CDs of Bakhtawar's song.</seg>
    <seg id="18">He said that a few months back, his party's young Chairman, Bilawal Bhutto's fake account was created on Facebook which has been deleted later.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ajmal Kasab is Indeed Pakistani: Information Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Verifying Ajmal Kasab's citizenship, Federal Minister for Information and Broadcasting, Sherry Rehman, in an SMS message sent to BBC Urdu Service, had only this much to say, that further investigation is ongoing.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Earlier, the Prime Minister's Interior Adviser, Rehman Malik, had denied that he was a Pakistani citizen.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that he did not find any record of Ajmal from NADRA, the institution that keeps records of citizens.</seg>
    <seg id="5">About the latest announcement, it is not yet known on what grounds has the government changed its position and verified the citizenship of Ajmal Kasab.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Nevertheless, according to the spokesperson of Foreign Ministry, citizenship of Ajmal Kasab has been confirmed by the Interior Ministry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Earlier, BBC Urdu Service and some other newspapers and TV channels had reported that Ajmal Kasab was related to Faridkot village in Okara District of the Punjab province.</seg>
    <seg id="8">However, the government had been denying it.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is still not clear whether Ajmal is connect to the same Faridkot or some other area.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Rockets Fired from Lebanon Also, Bombardment in Retaliation</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Israeli forces and police authorities told media that four rockets were fired on Israeli territory from Lebanon of which one hit Nahariya, the northern Israeli town, mildly injuring two people.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In response to the rockets fired from Lebanon, Israeli artillery shelled Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It is not clear whether it was Hezbollah that conducted this attack or if Palestinian groups active in Lebanon were behind it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Lebanese government has said that it is also investigating to find out who was behind the rocket attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">BBC correspondent has termed it as an extremely dangerous turn in the ongoing crisis in the region.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the BBC's Middle East editor Jeremy Bowen, these rocket attacks have increased the danger of further escalation of the war.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Fear was being expressed for the last some days that the Gaza conflict could spill over to the north, at Israel's border with Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Israeli Air Force, on the other hand, launched sixty air attacks on the Gaza Strip, on Wednesday and Thursday midnight.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the Israeli army, these attacks targeted the offices of Hamas police, tunnels, ammunitions depots, places from where rockets were launched and armed activists of Hamas.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Apart from air attacks, the artillery of Israeli army and navy also shelled Gaza all night long.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to the Palestinian sources, air attacks on Gaza city destroyed one mosque.</seg>
    <seg id="13">According to unconfirmed reports, Israeli tanks backed by helicopter air support, advanced towards the Khan Younis region.</seg>
    <seg id="14">In this conflict, that has continued for the last twelve days, about 700 Palestinians have died, including a large number of women and children.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other hand, eleven soldiers of the Israeli army have also been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Israeli security forces have confirmed that a top defense official, Amos Gilad, is leaving for Cairo to discuss terms of ceasefire.</seg>
    <seg id="17">A Hamas delegation is also set to leave for Cairo for parallel talks.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Moreover, leader of the Palestinian Authority, Mahmoud Abbas, is also arriving in Cairo on Friday.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">My Heart is Broken, Give Me Back My Kidney</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Richard Batista said that he had donated his kidney to his wife Dawnell to save her life eight years ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the AFP news agency, Dr. Batista said that his wife, in return for his donated kidney, cheated on him and started an affair with someone else and has now filed for divorce.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Dr. Batista said in an interview to a local newspaper Daily News that her alleged affair has made a hole in his heart that is still there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the attorney of Dr. Batista, although he is asking for his kidney to be returned, he actually wants monetary compensation for the kidney.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to his wife, she will present her stand in the next few days before a judge.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">140 Year Old, 9 Kilogram Lobster Set Free</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">George the Giant Lobster had been caught from a sea two weeks ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The city's seafood company had bought it for $100.</seg>
    <seg id="4">And had immediately started using its pictures for its own publicity.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But an animal rights group Peta demanded the lobster's release and as a result, it will be returned to the ocean.</seg>
    <seg id="6">George had been caught from Canadian waters, after which he spent about 10 days in the tank of City Crab and Seafood.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The age of a lobster can be estimated from its weight.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Restaurant manager, Keith Valenti, said that he never intended to harm the lobster, and the decision to keep it in the tank was made to entertain the customers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Ingrid Newkirk, of the animal rights group, Peta, said that the restaurant's decision was commendable and it serves as an example for those who either want these unique animals to be confined to tanks or to boil them alive and eat them.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Search for Girl, through Mobile Assisstance</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After authorities were alerted about Natalie Maltais, police officers and firefighters of the Town of Athol, Massachusetts, came into action.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Authorities traced the exact location of the girl through GPS in her mobile.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, it was with the help of Google Street View that it was found that the girl was in a hotel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A week ago Natalie's grandmother Rose Maltais had taken Natalie away from the custody of her legal parents.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Athol Police Chief Timothy Anderson told BBC 'she said that now she will never return Natalie and then left the state.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Police contacted Ms. Malatais but when she did not return the child as promised, police decided to search her with the help of Natalie's mobile phone.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Since 2005 America has the law stating that, all cell phone service providers should be able to provide the location of 67 percent of callers within 100 meters and 95 percent of callers within 300 meters.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on Visit to India</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This is Hamid Karzai's second visit to India in the last five months.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is expected that in his meeting with Prime Minister Manmohan, the situation after the terrorist attacks in Mumbai would be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this visit, he wants to express the sentiments of Afghanistan and its people regarding the Mumbai attacks, and his solidarity with India.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Apart from extremism, talks will be held on bilateral trade during this visit of Karzai</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is expected the two countries will discuss bilateral cooperation to fight against extremism.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President Hamid Karzai said during his previous visit to India that terrorism would not be allowed to interfere between the relations of India and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said both India and Afghanistan were facing challenges of terrorism and merciless and murderous activities.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Peace and stability in both the countries is of benefit to the region and everyone in the world.</seg>
    <seg id="10">We realize that it is only through concerted effort between the two countries and the entire world that the curse of terrorism can be fought.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It should be noted that Karzai held Pakistani intelligence agency, ISI, responsible for the attack on Indian Embassy in Kabul, in July last year.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Four Indians including a top IFS official were killed in this attack.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In the wake of attack on the Embassy, during Karzai's visit to India, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh had said that the attack 'was an assault on India-Afghanistan friendship; we agree that we will not allow terrorism to become a hurdle in our relations.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Mumbai Attacks, Special Judge for Hearing</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mumbai Police Commissioner, Hasan Ghafoor, has said that the hearing of the case registered against the lone suspect arrested alive in the Mumbai terror attacks will be carried under the supervision of M. L. Tahiliani.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Prior to this, Ujjwal Nikam has been appointed public prosecutor in this case.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Ajmal Qasab is presently under police custody and it is expected that the police will file charges against him before January 24.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ajmal Kasab has no lawyer for his defense.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In a letter written to Pakistan, Kasab had requested for legal help.</seg>
    <seg id="7">India has presented Pakistan with evidence about the involvement of Pakistani extremists in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Pakistan has admitted that Ajmal Kasab is a Pakistani citizen.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the case filed by police, Ajmal and his accomplice Abu Ismail had killed ATS chief Hemant Karkare, Additional police Commissioner Ashok Kamte and encounter specialist Vijay Salaskar and fled with their squad car; they were later caught near DB Marg Gargam Chawpati.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Ismail Khan had been killed in police action and Ajmal was arrested alive by the police.</seg>
    <seg id="11">No lawyer has yet been appointed to plead Ajmal's case.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The government nominated lawyer, Dinesh Mota, who was member of the legal aid cell, had refused to take the case on ethical grounds.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Two lawyers withdrew their names after protests and opposition by people belonging to a political party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Constitutional Amendment': Committee to be Formed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Talking to media representatives after his speech at a seminar on climate change in Islamabad on Tuesday, he said that a meeting of the parliamentary party will be held in this regard where this committee will be formed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that so far, Muttahida Qaumi Movement has presented a constitutional amendment bill before the National Assembly to eliminate the 17th amendment, while other political parties will also present constitutional amendment bills in the parliament in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that Pakistan People's Party has also sent a draft to all the political parties to eliminate the 17th amendment, and this committee will review that draft as well.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Replying to a question, he said that the Parliament will decide on the balance of power between the President and the Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Prime Minister said that the parliament has the authority to make all decisions.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Replying to another question, he said that apart from the role of political parties regarding former President, Retired General Pervez Musharraf's decission to quit the post of the army chief, the former Prime Minister and chairperson of Pakistan People's Party, Benazir Bhutto, also played an important role as she pressed the international community to put pressure on former President Pervez Musharraf to let go of his uniform.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that the American Vice President elect Joe Biden supports Pakistan and democracy, and Pakistani President has conferred on him the honor of Hilal-e-Pakistan for his services.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Replying to a question on Indian government's threat to sever all kinds of relations with Pakistan in the wake of the Mumbai incident, Yousuf Raza Gillani said that Indian leaders are giving such statements as they are facing immense pressure from the public.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Protests Against Dismissal of Journalists</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Tuesday, journalists and news personnel, under the umbrella of Islamabad journalists' organization RIUJ, protested and shouted slogans in front of Islamabad Press Club against the owners of media organizations and government on the dismissal of a large number of employees working in television channels and newspapers.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Addressing the protesters, C.R. Shamsi, senior member of the largest journalist organization, Pakistan Federal Union of Journalists, said that the politicians who were, till yesterday, protesting with us on the roads, are sitting as rulers in the parliament but they are not doing anything for the rights of journalists because of the fear of a particular group of newspaper owners</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the newspaper owners who talk about human rights have turned their institutions into prisons and slave labor camps where despite the earnings of billions of rupees annually, workers are being paid very low wages and hundreds of them are being killed economically because of their dismissal.</seg>
    <seg id="5">An example of this is in front of us as an employee of Lahore based private TV channel 5 committed suicide because he did not get his salary for four months. Even today, many employees are living in hardship because of forced expulsions and non payment of salaries for months.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that right steps should be taken against owners of TV channels and newspapers and a permanent protest camp should be put in front of the parliament for the rights of journalists.</seg>
    <seg id="7">C. R. Shamsi criticized Punjab Governor, Salman Taseer, saying that employees are being dismissed from his Urdu newspaper 'Aajkal' without any notice.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Whereas the Daily Jinnah, Daily Khabrain, Channel 5, Business Plus TV and AaJ TV too have dismissed dozens of employees.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Addressing the protesters, Secretary General of PUFJ, Mazhar Abbas, said that journalist organizations all across the country are observing today as a black day against the dismissal of journalists and newspaper employees, while the journalists will go to the parliament session wearing black bands around their arms in order to claim their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Mazhar Abbas, employees and journalists are being exploited in 85% of the newspapers and TV channels where they are working without ant contracts.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that so far, more than 200 journalists and employees are being dismissed from newspapers and TV channels, while it is feared that the owners will dismiss hundreds of more employees during the current year under the pretext of economic crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas said that the movement of journalists will continue until the dismissed employees are reinstated, the Seventh Wage Board Award specifying the wages of newspaper employees is implemented and salaries unpaid for several months of TV channels and newspaper workers are disbursed.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Eleven-Member Cabinet Takes Oath</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The new cabinet includes six ministers from the former Prime Minister Sardar Atique Ahmed Khan's rival faction of Muslim Conference, two from Pakistan People's Party, two from People's Muslim League and one minister from Muttahida Qaumi Movement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The 11 member cabinet also includes one woman minister from the anti Atique faction of Muslim Conference.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The ruling alliance says that the cabinet will be expanded next week and a dozen more ministers are expected to be included in the cabinet. It should be noted that Sardar Atique Khan had been removed from the post of prime minister by his opponents through a no confidence motion early this month and Sardar Yaqub Khan had been elected as the new Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The departments of these ministers will be announced later.</seg>
    <seg id="6">At the time of oath taking, members of People's Party raised slogans in favor of Pakistan's former Prime Minister, Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">3.5 Million Consumers Affected by Virus</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">First discovered in October, 2008, this virus is known by such names as Conficker, Downadup and Kido.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Although, Microsoft had launched a patch to combat the virus, around 3.5 million computers and memory sticks have so far been affected.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Experts have said, the number of affected computers may go very high.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Consumers need to use Microsoft's 'MS08067' patch to deal with the virus.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Microsoft says the virus which has affected millions of computers, searches for file 'services.exe' and penetrates into its code.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After which, this virus turns into a DLL type file in the system folder of Windows.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This virus also creates the name of that file</seg>
    <seg id="9">Then it changes the details of Windows' registry.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After becoming active, this virus causes a problem with the 'HTTP Server' and changes the machine's restore point.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Then it downloads files from hacker's website.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Microsoft says this virus have affected the computers of various countries of the world.</seg>
    <seg id="13">These countries include China, Brazil, Russian, India, America and Britain.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Demand for Immediate Report on Indian Information'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Talking to media representatives after a meeting in the Interior Ministry on Saturday, he said the information provided by India</seg>
    <seg id="3">will help investigate into this matter.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that Pakistan is a sovereign country and we will not let</seg>
    <seg id="5">any country dictate us in the investigation carried on information received from India.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that besides the information received from India,other information is also being gathered.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The Interior Advisor said that law enforcement agencies have taken 124 activists of a banned organization into custody under suspected threat to peace and order</seg>
    <seg id="8">and if any evidence is found against some of them, action will be taken against them while the innocent individuals will be released.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Replying to a question, he said, none of the arrested persons will be handed over to India and action will be taken against them under Pakistani laws.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said, action was taken against them under the FIA law.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Replying to a question, he said that Indian law enforcement agencies took 42 days to gather information about those behind the Mumbai incident, therefore, he hopes that the international community, including India, will give Pakistan some time to investigate the information.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He reiterated the government's offer to form a joint investigation team to probe the incident.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It may be recalled that a three-member investigation team headed by Additional Director General of FIA has been formed, which is</seg>
    <seg id="14">studying the information India has provided to Pakistan regarding Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Pakistani High Commissioner to India Mr. Shahid Malik met President Asif Ali Zardari, in which the President made it clear that if any Pakistani individual or group was found involved in Mumbai attacks, action would be taken against them according to the country's laws and no one will be handed over to India, whereas the Indian leadership has been mounting pressure on Pakistan to hand over those behind the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Anything is Possible in America'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mr. Obama will take oath on 20th January as America's 44th president.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In Washington, while standing on the stairs of the monument build to commemorate the 16th American president, Abraham Lincoln, addressing a musical concert</seg>
    <seg id="4">Mr. Obama said, 'America is facing the most severe challenges of several generations and he is hopeful that America will overcome these problems.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Abraham Lincoln abolished the tradition of slavery in America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But at the same time Mr. Obama said that it will take time to solve the issues facing the country and the path will be tough.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But in spite of this, I am hopeful that the dream of our founders will live.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America is battling with a tough economic crisis, besides the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="9">extraordinary arrangements are being made for the swearing-in ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Organizers believe that two million people will attend the ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Monday is a national holiday in America, as on this day renowned human rights champion and Martin Luther King were assassinated.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Martin Luther King was black.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tribute to Martin Luther, Resolve to Work</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Martin Luther King was killed in 1968.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama paid tribute to Dr. King and urged Americans to work together to fulfill the nation's promises.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In Washington, on the other hand, preparations are being made for the unprecedented swearing-in ceremony of the new president on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Around two million people are expected to attend this historic presidential oath-taking ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On Monday, Barack Obama started the day by visiting a medical center in North Washington where he met with injured American soldiers,after which he visited a shelter for the homeless, where he painted a wall.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Talking to correspondents, Barack Obama said, 'We cannot sit idle in the face of the crisis we are confronting and the problems that have surrounded so many people.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that Martin Luther King devoted most of his life in the service of people.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Barack Obama said, 'Today as we honour his memory, it is not a day to just pause and reflect - it is a day to act.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that Tuesday's ceremony will be held on the same path where, in 1963, thousands of people had gathered to hear Martin Luther's, 'I have a dream'.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Martin Luther King had said in that speech that the day will come when there will be no discrimination on the basis of color.</seg>
    <seg id="12">BBC's Matthew Price says that it is an historical irony that Martin Luther King Day should fall 24 hours before the day when American history's first black president will take oath of his office.</seg>
    <seg id="13">For many in the southern states, Barack Obama's presidency will be the fulfillment of Dr. Luther King's dream.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Additional Political Agent Released</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Unknown masked men had kidnapped Additional Political Agent from South Waziristan ten days ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Sources said that the official had been kidnapped by the Mulla Nazir group of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to local administration, A tribal Jirga brought Additional Political Agent of South Waziristan, Amir Latif, to Wana Scouts Camp on Tuesday at around 4:00 in the evening.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, he did not say as to who had kidnapped the Additional Political Agent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, according to local people, the Political Agent had been abducted by the Mulla Nazir group of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Amir Latif was abducted when he was on his way from Wana to Tank.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Seven armed, masked men abducted the Additional Political Agent, Amir Latif, along with his driver in the tribal area of Karkanra of South Waziristan on January 11, 2009.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to government official, the abductors first unarmed the security guards present in the vehicle and then fled away with the Additional Political Agent in another car.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to local administration, following the abduction of the Additional Political Agent, security forces had blocked all check posts in South Waziristan and the semi tribal areas; everyone passing through was strictly searched and authorities had also imposed economic sanctions on Wana for the last one week.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Assistant Political Agent of North Waziristan Ismatullah was also abducted in December 8, 2008 when he was going from Mir Ali to Bannu to celebrate Eid holidays. And after that, unidentified masked men killed two people, including Tehsildar Amanullh, in North Waziristan.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">British Hacker Wins in Court</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A 42-year-old British citizen has admitted that he had hacked into American military website.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Garry suffers from Asperger's Syndrome. It should be understood that those with Asperger's Syndrome become obsessed with a particular activity.</seg>
    <seg id="4">His lawyers have said that he will be at risk of committing suicide if he is handed over to America.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Government laywers, however, said the risk to Mr Gary's health was low.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Lord Justice Maurice Kay and Mr. Justice Simon ruled that Gary is permitted to appeal for a review in the British Court.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Garry's lawyers had taken the stand in court that if he were removed from his home and family, he may commit suicide.</seg>
    <seg id="8">They further said that this aspect was not considered by the Home Secretary.</seg>
    <seg id="9">However, government lawyers said, the Home Secretary had acted within her powers.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Garry has never denied hacking into the American military website</seg>
    <seg id="11">Garry had hacked into American computer systems in 2001 and 2002, which caused a loss of $800,000 to the American Government.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Garry had hacked into 97 computers, including those of American Navy and NASA.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Garry said that he had no malicious intent in hacking, but was looking for information on aliens which he believed the American government had kept secret.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Gary's mother Janis Sharp said, she is happy with this ruling.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Gary's lawyer said, 'This is the right ruling.</seg>
    <seg id="16">This case has been going on since 2002 and finally a correct ruling has been made.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Kashmir: Two Hizb Commanders Killed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Spokesperson for the North command of the Indian Army stationed in Jammu, Lt. Colonel Acharya, told BBC: "At receiving verified information, 24 Rashtrya Rifles and Jammu Kashmir policemen cordoned off Batyas jungle in Gandoh Tehsil of Doda where armed extremists where hiding.</seg>
    <seg id="3">They opened fire on the military and two armed militants were killed in retaliation fire.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The spokesperson said that the two extremists who had been killed included Hizb-ul-Mujahideen's Tehsil Commander Zahuruddin Khande, who had been active in the district for 12 years and was an expert in gun powder explosions.</seg>
    <seg id="5">His companion was identified as Sajjad Hussein, who, according to the Army, had been associated with the extremists since last years.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Acharya, operation is still continuing in the said jungle area because, according to him, presence of more extremists is still possible. The army has said that two AK rifles were also recovered in the first stage of the operation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The head of the province's police, Mr. Kuldeep Kumar Khuda, released the 2008 statistics yesterday and declared the year as the most peaceful year yet.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that no violence took place during the assembly elections held in seven phases in November and December.</seg>
    <seg id="9">More than 1,300 candidates participated in these elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It should be noted that Hizb-ul-Mujahideen has been active in Jammu and Kashmir for the last 18 years.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Hizb had announced unilateral ceasefire for the first time in July 2000, after which talks were held between Hizb commanders and the Government of India.</seg>
    <seg id="12">However, the ceasefire ended in only fifteen days.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Many Hizb-ul-Mujahideen commanders were later killed in different operations.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Pakistan's prominent daily newspaper 'The News' had reported about the extremist groups in Pakistan-administered Kashmir on Thursday that Lashkar-e-Taiba and Hizb-ul-Mujahideen have decided to review the Kashmir policy.</seg>
    <seg id="15">It should be noted that the policy of both the organisations till now, was that the Kashmir issue could be resolved through armed struggle.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Dera Bugti: Explosion on Gas Pipeline</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police officials, the 18-inch diameter pipeline from Gas Field to Pirkoh was blown up.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This pipeline goes towards the Sui Plant.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Meanwhile, Sarbaz Baloch, proclaimed spokesperson for the banned organisation, Baloch Republican Army, accepted responsibility for the attack on behalf of his organization via telephone.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This is the fourth gas pipeline which has been blown up within four days.</seg>
    <seg id="6">An 18-inch diameter pipeline had been destroyed on Friday in Dera Allah Yar and the repaire work continued till Sunday morning.</seg>
    <seg id="7">General Manager of Sui Southern Gas Company, Mushtaq Siddiqi, has informed that the supply of gas from this pipeline will resume past the afternoon.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This pipeline connects with Quetta via Sibbi.</seg>
    <seg id="9">There is severe crisis of gas in Quetta, Ziarat and other nearby areas where, on one hand, snowfall continues and the temperature has fallen below zero while on the other hand, heaters and stoves are not working.</seg>
    <seg id="10">In addition, in Dera Bugti city, a motor cycle explosion occurred in Mal Mandi but according to the police, no loss of life took place.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Administrator for Jamaat-ud-Dawa</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Markaz-e-Taiba, the headquarter of Jamaat-ud-Dawa is situated in Muridkay 25, about kilometers from Lahore.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This Center includes a hospital, a school and a hostel for students.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Punjab Law Minister Rana Sanaullah said that the appointment of administrator in the Jamaat-ud-Dawa headquarter has been made so that the welfare activities of the organization are not affected.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Khalid Walid, son in law of Hafiz Saeed, head of Jamaat-ud-Dawa, a top government officer Khaqan Babar has been appointed as administrator to supervise the hospital, school and other welfare departments of the the center whereas, according to him, the number of police personnel at the headquarter has also been increased.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Following UN Security Council's ban on Jamaat-ud-Dawa, Pakistani federal government has taken action against Jamaat-ud-Dawa across the country and various leaders including chief of the Jamaat, Hafiz Saeed, have been detained. Appointment of administrator at Markaz-e-Taiba from the government of Punjab is part of the series of federal government's actions against Jamaat-ud-Dawa.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Khaqan Babar is from DMG, that is, theDistrict Management Group.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Hafiz Khalid Walid said that the Commissioner of Lahore division, Khusroo Parvez Khan, arrived at Markaz-e-Taiba, along with police and civil administration and inspected different parts of the headquarters. Khalid Walid condemned government's action to appoint administrator in the Center, and said that the number of patients in the hospital and children in school has already dropped because of government's actions.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to a press release of Jamaat-ud-Dawa, Chief of Jamaat-ud Dawa Hafiz Saeed has written a letter to the UN Secretary General Ban Ki Moon and the Committee regarding Taliban, urging them to lift ban on the organization imposed by the Security Council.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The letter reads that the unilateral decision to impose ban on Jamaat-ud-Dawa by the Security Council is unjust and that Jamaat-ud-Dawa has nothing to do with terrorism, rather, it is busy in welfare activities.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Edhi on Gaza's Relief Mission</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After passing through the several stages required for obtaining permission to enter Gaza, he could only manage to reach Egypt from New York.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Talking to the BBC Urdu Service from Cairo, he said that he still has not been able to reach Gaza because Egypt and Israel have placed many hurdles in the way.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said, it has been eight days since his arrival there, yet he still has not been given permission to enter Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="5">I am currently in Cairo and I hope that tomorrow permission will be granted to enter Gaza.'</seg>
    <seg id="6">He elaborated, 'First I was given a seven days' visa for Gaza and when I insisted, Pakistani officials helped me extend it to one month but with the condition that I will be going to Gaza only once, i.e. single entry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that his son and daughters are accompanying him and they want to participate in relief activities in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">I have brought some cash.</seg>
    <seg id="9">I have given a check for $100,000, and $ 10,000 in cash, to Egypt's Red Cross to send relief items to Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Four More Ministers in Cabinet, Total 63</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Four news federal ministers include two from Muttahida Qaumi Movement and two from Fazlur Rahman group of Jamiat-ul-Ulema-e-Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">New ministers were sworn in by President Asif Ali Zardari</seg>
    <seg id="4">Swearing-in ceremony was attended by Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani and the members of federal cabinet</seg>
    <seg id="5">With the inclusion of four new ministers in federal cabinet, the number of federal ministers, ministers of state and advisors has turned 63.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The MQM ministers are Farooq Sattar and Babar Ghauri while Azam Swati and Maulana Ataur Rahman are from Fazlur Rahman group of Jamiat-ul-Ulema-e-Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Departments of these ministers have not yet been announced.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Farooq Sattar is the MQM Convener while Babar Ghauri is its senator and his tenure is ending on March 10.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Azam Swati was elected senator as an independent and he is counted among the richest senators.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Maulana Ataur Rahman is a member of National Assembly and the younger brother of Maulana Fazlur Rahman.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It is worth noting that four advisors holding key posts are not members of the National Assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It is worth mentioning that 22 new ministers and 18 ministers of state were included in the cabinet on November 3, 2008, and it was then thought that the MQM will also be included but it did not join because of differences on the distribution of ministries.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Balochistan: Pipeline blown up</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police, this 18-inch diameter pipeline which connects the different wells of Pirkoh to the Sui Gas Plant, has been been blown up.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In addition, Well No. 3 in Sui was completely destroyed yesterday by explosion and a gas pipeline was damaged in an explosion near Dera Allah Yar.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Sarbaz Bloch, spokesperson of the banned organisation Bloch Republican Army, has taken responsibility of this attack on behalf of his organisation.</seg>
    <seg id="5">With start of the year 2009, violence has surged in Balochistan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Till now, dozens of gas pipelines have been blown up this month while attacks on trains and on people connected to Punjab have increased.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Although, Chief Minister of Balochistan, Nawab Aslam Raisani, has expressed concern over these incidents and has issued orders to the police to exchange information with intelligence agencies, but such attacks have not yet been prevented.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">$819 Billion Stimulus Package Approved.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">No member of the Republican Party voted in favor of this plan of President Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Republicans said that the stimulus package was too 'costly' and will not prove effective.</seg>
    <seg id="4">244 voted were cast in favor of this package while 188 votes were cast against it in the House of Representatives.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This stimulus package will be presented in the Senate next week where the ruling Democratic Party enjoys a very insignificant majority.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Concern is being expressed that due to intense opposition by the Republican Party it will not be easy to pass it in the Senate.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After the passage of the stimulus package in the House of Representatives, Barack Obama asked the members not to let political differences come in the way of this important plan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Obama said that the plan, which he hoped will turn into law by next month, will help create a better atmosphere in the country where American trade will grow.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Under this plan, ordinary people and the business community will be offered loan waivers of up to $275 billion and $540 billion will be given to repaire roads, bridges and ten thousand schools and unemployment allowances as well as new technology research.</seg>
    <seg id="10">BBC correspondent in Washington, Richard Lister, said that Barack Obama had vowed to introduce a new political culture, putting political differences behind, but the discussion on this economic package has once again created bitterness in the political bases.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Members of the Republican Party in the House of Representatives termed the bill proposed by the government as a waste of public money and said that this will not help create new employment opportunities.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On behalf of their Party, they stressed on their own bill which focuses more on tax exemptions.</seg>
    <seg id="13">They said that through their package, more employment opportunities can be created with much less investment.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They said tax exemption can create more and immediate employment opportunities as compared to construction plans.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bitter Exchange Between Israeli President and Turkish Prime Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Recep Tayyip Erdogan almost yelling at Israeli President said that a lot of blood has been shed in Gaza and he is disappointed to see that people can even clap over the pretext of this barbaric military action of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Erdogan said: "I think you are using such words and that too in a loud voice, to hide your guilt but you have killed people and I am thinking of the children who were killed near the coast.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Simon Perez said that Israel is not responsible for the Gaza tragedy rather Hamas is to be blamed which has established a dangerous dictatorship there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to BBC Correspondent in Davos, such a scene has never been witnessed at the World Economic Forum.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, later Erdogan said that he respects Israeli President and his age as well which is why he did not yell at him but whatever he was saying was miles away from truth.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Turkey is one of the few Muslim nations that have diplomatic relations with Israel but for the past few years there has been tension in these relations.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Attacks Were Not Planned in Pakistan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Speaking to the Indian channel NDTV, Wajid Shamsul Hassan said that the Pakistani investigation report of the Mumbai attacks will be released soon.</seg>
    <seg id="3">More than 170 people were killed in the Mumbai attacks last November.</seg>
    <seg id="4">India has blamed extremist organization Lashkar-e-Taiba for these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">India has also said that Pakistan's 'state elements' were also involved in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After the Mumbai attacks, relations between the two countries have been affected.</seg>
    <seg id="7">This is the first statement by the Pakistani High Commissioner, Wajid Shamsul Hassan, regarding the investigations that gives a clue about the contents of the investigation report.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wajid Shamsul Hassan said: 'As of now the investigators have concluded that Pakistani territory was not used.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is some other place, not even Britain.</seg>
    <seg id="10">These are the two places, Pakistan and Britain, about which I was concerned.</seg>
    <seg id="11">India and the international Community have put extensive pressure on Pakistan to act against those responsible for the Mumbai attacks. Pakistan says that it has arrested dozens of people in connection with its actions against groups allegedly behind Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Wajid Shamsul Hassan said: 'We are not trying to cover up.</seg>
    <seg id="13">We believe in acting on facts.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Our investigations will be accepted by the world.</seg>
    <seg id="15">We will try to convince India by the investigation results.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Defending the delay in Pakistani investigations, he said, it takes time to collect, understand and scrutinize this type of material.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Pakistani High Commissioner said that it took India 45 days to present its dossier.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A Black Leader Elected in Republican Party Also</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the sixth round of elections in the Republican Party, Michael Steele has emerged victorious who, out of 168 votes secured 91 votes.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the elections for the chairmanship of the Party, Steele's rival candidate Katon Dawson received 77 votes whereas the former Chairman Duncan withdrew in the second phase.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to correspondents, of the five candidates for the Chairmanship of the Republican Party, Michael Steele is considered to be the most moderate.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his post victory address Michael Steele said, 'I am here to invite both our friends and foes to come with us but those who want to create rifts should get ready to move away. Michael Steel is from Maryland where he has also served as Deputy Governor.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He rose to fame in 2006 when he stood in the election for a Senate.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But after the loss of the Senate elections he was made Chairman of the Party's Political Conservative Committee.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Now after his election as the Chairman of the Party, the nationwide campaigns of the Republican Party will be conducted under his supervision.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He fought the election on the promise that he would lend a new dimension to the party and try new techniques to bring back conservative supporters to the Party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">India Claims Presence of Lashkar-e-Taiba, Jaish-e-Mohammad in Jammu</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">There are reports of the presence of militants in Poonch District of Jammu.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to official sources, acting on a tip-off, the army and police surrounded the area and started searches.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Meanwhile, clashes began resulting in the death of four militants, two soldiers and one policeman.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to sources, till last reports were received, these clashes still continue and militants belonging to Lashkar-e-Taiba and Jaish-e-Mohammad are still present in the area. More forces have been sent there to combat them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Meanwhile, the coalition nominated Chief Minister Omar Abdullah met with the Governor and informed him about his election as the Leader of National Conference in the Assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="7">National Conference ally Congress, also informed the Governor about its support for Omar Abdullah.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Omar Abdullah will be given oath as the Chief Minister of the State tomorrow.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It may be recalled that in the recent State elections, National Conference won 28 seats in the 87-member assembly. It should be noted that separatist groups did not participate in the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Congress which won 17 seats, agreed to form a coalition government with National Conference.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Today on arrival in Srinagar, party workers gave Omar Abdullah a warm welcome.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On this occasion, Omar Abdullah said that he will play his part in bringing about a dialogue between the Indian government and the separatists, however, this will not be possible until elections are held in India and new government comes into power.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Role of European Union for Peace in Middle East</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">If seen officially, the European Union has a decisive role to play in the efforts to establish peace in the Middle East</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the official position of Brussels, efforts of Schwarzenberg delegation or Sarkozy are equivalent to lending a supportive hand in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Spokesman for the European Commission, Amadeu Altafaj, said, any such effort is commendable that will help to convey the joint message of the European Union to the warring factions.</seg>
    <seg id="5">As far as the official statement is concerned everything seems fine.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But in reality, the European Union presents a sad picture of internal conflicts.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Role of the Czech Republic as President of the Union is already weak.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On top of it, the internal conflicts have rendered it helpless.</seg>
    <seg id="9">On the other hand, the French President is behaving as if he is still discharging his duties as the President of the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Although France has already completed its six month term.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Sarkozy wants to play a leading role and he does have the ability to do that but he does not have permission to do so.</seg>
    <seg id="12">French Foreign Minister Bernard Kouchner finds himself in the most absurd situation</seg>
    <seg id="13">He is part of the delegation that is being led by the Foreign Minister of Czech Republic, Schwarzenberg.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On top of that, both Foreign Ministers are giving divergent statement regarding the Middle East war.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Kouchner believes that Israel has the right to defend itself whereas according to Schwarzenberg this war does not fall under the category of self defense. On the other hand Germany has also dispatched its special envoy to the Middle East. Until the European Union shows cohesiveness in its stand it can never be successful at the diplomatic front.</seg>
    <seg id="16">The proof for this is Israeli attitude that does not give any credence to the peace initiatives of Europe</seg>
    <seg id="17">This is a golden opportunity for the European Union to do something because America has failed in the Middle East due George W. Bush's policies.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Economic Crisis: German Billionaire Industrialist Commits Suicide</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Adolf Merckle of south Germany has left behind a huge business group.</seg>
    <seg id="3">But a little while ago ordinary German citizen did not know much about him.</seg>
    <seg id="4">And when he had to negotiate for several weeks with nearly 30 banks that gave loans to his business group, he came into limelight and he could also see the future of Merckle Group as bleak.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Merckle Group faced loss of several hundred million euros after buying shares of the German car manufacturer Volks Wagen, due to the economic crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After that, when financial institutions declined to lend to this Group the required loan of 700 million to 1 billion euros, Merckle came under immense pressure.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Some time ago, the same banks had agreed to give loan on emergency basis to the Merckle Group, but Adolf Merckle who started as a small industrialist and rose to this position and the annual income of whose industrial group was around 30 billion euros could not bear the loss of his investment powers.</seg>
    <seg id="8">When Adolf Merckle took over the family business after the death of his father, he organized it on modern principles and soon made enormous progress.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He named his company Ratiopharm, which today is a highly successful and a very large drug manufacturing company in Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Until some time ago, the business worth of this pharmaceutical company was between 5 and 6 billion euros and it still makes an annual income of 8.1billion euros. After the tremendous success of Ratiopharm, Merckle Group acquired many large companies; ranging from the building and construction material company, Heidelberg Cement, to the special vehicles manufacturing company, Kaessbohrer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The worldwide workforce of Merckle Group is almost 100,000 persons, and Ratiopharm pharmaceutical company has always enjoyed special significance.</seg>
    <seg id="12">During his life Adolf Merckle said on several occasions, "We have been making medicine for the last four generations.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Now the control of this company is in the hands of my children and I hope that for the next few hundred years it will remain under the administration of my family.</seg>
    <seg id="14">After Adolf Merckle's suicide, the banks have approved 400 million euros of bridge VEM loan for his group but on the condition that Ratiopharm has to be sold so that the VEM financial condition of this group can be improved over a long term.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Also, after the death of Adolf Merckle the Merckle Group will not be the same as it used to be.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Crime Rate among Foreigners in Germany</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to recent statistics, crime rate among foreigners, between 2004 and 2007,</seg>
    <seg id="3">has fallen from 22 percent to 21</seg>
    <seg id="4">per cent.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the Interior Minister of Bavaria province, Joachim Herrmann, this is just a superficial positive change.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said, "It should be kept in mind that the number of foreigners obtaining German citizenship is increasing.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Therefore, statistics should mention that although the one committing crime is a German citizen; his background is foreign.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Herrmann said that his province will keep this in consideration while gathering statistics from 2010 onward.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Apart from Bavaria, Hamburg is also thinking on these lines.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Senator of Interior Affairs, Christoph Ahlhaus, from CDU said, "When research is carried out on scientific lines, one cannot make conclusions of one's choice but they depend on the statistics gathered as a result of research.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Ahlhaus drew attention to an analytical report of the provincial office on the prevention of crimes which had been prepared in July, 2006 and which ascertained the rate of crimes among foreigners in Bergdorf area of Hamburg.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Results suggested that the crime rate among the foreigners here</seg>
    <seg id="13">was lower than that of crimes committed in all other areas of the province.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On the contrary, when the youth crime rate in Berlin during 2006 was analyzed, it became obvious that the rate of crimes in youths with foreign background</seg>
    <seg id="15">was 44 per cent.</seg>
    <seg id="16">However, Germany's other political parties such as SPD, the party of environmentalists and leftwing party Linkspartei are against the proposalthat data should be collected about foreign background of German citizens in the crime related statistics.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">We Want Immediate Withdrawal of Forces from Gaza: Olmert</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Ehud Olmert has stressed that permanent and durable ceasefire agreement is essential for complete withdrawal of forces.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamas and Israel announced ceasefire on Sunday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Announcing a one-week ceasefire, Islamic militant organization Hamas demanded that Israeli forces withdraw completely from Gaza Strip and blockade of Gaza strip be lifted.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hamas leader Ismail Haniya, on the other hand, has said that God has granted victory to Israel in the Gaza war.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said Israel had failed to achieve its targets in the Gaza war.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Prior to that, a meeting was held between the leaders of European and Arab countries at Sharm El-Sheikh which demanded of Israel, an immediate withdrawal of forces from Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It was decided in the meeting that an International Aid Conference for Gaza will be held soon.</seg>
    <seg id="9">German Chancellor Angela Merkel also attended the said meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="10">At least 1,300 Palestinians and thirteen Israelis including ten soldiers were killed in the three-week long war between Israel and Hamas fighters.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas, on the other hand, has stressed on formation of a national unity government in the Palestinian areas.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Al-Qaeda's Video Message to Germany</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this 30-minute long video, a masked person wearing a black turban and holding a gun is delivering a message to the German government.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This person introduces himself as Abu Talha and is speaking in German language.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The video message has Arabic subtitles as well.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Al-Qaeda logo is displayed the side of the screen and the date October 2008, shows in the video.</seg>
    <seg id="6">This message says to the German government that the deployment of such a large number of troops in Afghanistan indicates that this country believes it will not be attacked-this is nothing but foolishness.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Although this person, who called himself Abu Talha, did not threaten direct attacks on Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Currently, the number of German soldiers in Afghanistan, in NATO's coalition army, is 3,500.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In October last year, German parliament gave the legal authorization for deployment of an additional 1000 soldiers to Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This is the first message from Al-Qaeda, received by Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Mikhail LUEDERS, an renowned expert on terrorist affairs, said regarding this message: "The recent suicide attack outside the German Embassy in Kabul is proof that we must take it seriously in every way.</seg>
    <seg id="12">For the last few years, Al-Qaeda has been posting video messages on the internet, and such messages have also been followed by attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Militant organization, Taliban, assumed responsibility for the suicide attack outside the German Embassy in Kabul on Saturday.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Most German newspapers and analysts are seeing this attack linked to the Al-Qaeda message.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They are targeting Germany."</seg>
    <seg id="16">Fundamentalist Muslims see Germany's Afghan policy with a negative and critical view.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They allege German government for adopting a biased policy not only towards Afghanistan but for the Middle East as well.</seg>
    <seg id="18">This is the reason why they are considering Germany, more and more as their target.</seg>
    <seg id="19">Meanwhile, German government has said that German intelligence had information about this video even before it became public.</seg>
    <seg id="20">German federal department of crime prevention is busy investigating the video message.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama has Assumed Office of American Presidency</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this perspective, not only the American public the entire world has various expectations associated with Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Now, when Barack Obama is receiving felicitation messages from across the world, expectation associated with him are also coming to the fore.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this regard, the German Chancellor has expressed confidence in the new American President</seg>
    <seg id="5">I believe that on basis of the deep friendship and partnership between Federal Republic of Germany and the United States of America, we can solve the problems we are faced with.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin has said that Obama seems a serious and open hearted man, which is undoubtedly a good thing.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Although, former American President George Bush's policies had been in the face of criticism.</seg>
    <seg id="8">His administration, however, was commended for motivating China to play a more constructive role on the international level; whereas, China has said about the new president that he has to work for strong military relations between the two countries.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Chinese political expert, active in the German city of Bukhum, Guo Su Wei Wu has said,</seg>
    <seg id="10">"In this perspective, I believe that in the coming days, Obama and his economic team will exert great pressure, and will compel Beijing government to adopt a flexible and market-based exchange rate for Chinese currency.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Previous American administration has strengthened relations with India as well.</seg>
    <seg id="12">As to where Obama can take these relations, Delhi based expert in American studies, Professor Christopher Raj says, "Now we have come closer in strategic partnership but Obama cannot bring any major change overnight.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Pope Benedict has also stressed in his message to Obama to promote an atmosphere of peace and cooperation.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Provincial Elections in Iraq</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After 2005, these are first important elections in this war-torn country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">More than 14,400 candidates have stood up for 440 seats in the provincial elections.</seg>
    <seg id="4">More than 800,000 policemen and soldiers have been deployed to maintain law and order during the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Keeping in view the threat of bomb blasts and terror attacks on the historic day, all borders of Iraq were sealed on Friday, one day prior.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Moreover, airports have been closed and public transport has been restricted.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to information, due to restriction on transportation no traffic is seen on the roads in Baghdad and Iraqi children are being seen playing football on the streets.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Security situation during these Iraqi elections will on one hand help assess if the local security agencies will be able to control security of the country after the withdrawal of American troops in 2011, while political analysts are taking these elections as a test case to gauge as to what extent are the Iraqi people willing to bring change in their country through the democratic process..</seg>
    <seg id="9">Provincial elections are being held under the supervision of the United Nations and around 800 international commentators are monitoring the electoral process.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Youm-e-Ashur--Ashura was celebrated today with respect and honor across Iran in commemoration of the Chief of Martyrs, Hadhrat Imam Hussein's supreme sacrifice.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the report of Mehr News Agency, martyrdom anniversary of the Chief of Martyrs, Hadhrat Imam Hussein, was celebrated with full honor and dignity in all small and big cities including Tehran, the capital of Iran. On this occasion, the faithful participated in the mourning processions in large numbers and mourned the martyrdom of Prophet Muhammad's son Imam Hussein in the battlefield of Karbala. The entire Iran was aggrieved and in mourning today in the memory of the supreme sacrifice of the Chief of Martyrs, Hadhrat Imam Hussein in the field of Karbala. The faithful participated in the condolence meetings and mourning processions, in large numbers.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Retreat of Israeli troops from the Gaza Ajleen areas// Exceptional Steadfastness of Palestinian Mujahedeen</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Urdu Service of Mehr News Agency, Israel continued barbaric bombardment on civilian population in Gaza for the 16th day of the war between righteousness and evil. As of now, 880 people have been martyred and 3700 injured in the Israel's air, ground and sea attacks on Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The martyrs include 275 innocent children who went to the deep slumber of death, smiling at the infidelity of Arab leaders and callousness of the so-called champions of human rights.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Today, the Mujahideen of Gaza forced Israeli troops to retreat from the Ajeen area of Gaza and they are demonstrated extraordinary steadfastness and resolve on the basis of their faith and spirit for martyrdom and reducing the Zionist enemy's hold on life.</seg>
    <seg id="5">If the Egyptian President Hosni "Un"-Mubarak had not committed treachery, the brave and dauntless warriors of Hamas would have defeated Israel since long, but with Israel's grueling blockade, Egypt had also sealed Gaza borders - the most tragic incident of the Arab history.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On the other hand, the governments of Saudi Arabia and Jordan are also betraying the helpless Muslims of Gaza and helping Israel by providing political and economic support to it.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barack Obama: America Will Adopt a New Iran Strategy</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Mehr News Agency report, the elected American President Barack Obama told ABC News Channel that he would adopt a new and modern strategy on the Iran issue.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama said; "Iran will be a very big challenge for the American government."</seg>
    <seg id="4">Barack Obama said that was concerned over Iran's support to Palestinian Islamic organizations Hamas and Hezbollah and its uranium enrichment program.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, he will not continue the incumbent American President, Bush's policy and will adopt a different policy on relations with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama said that he will stress on mutual respect and his desire for dialogue while making his actual motives very clear.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Barack Obama has said in the past as well that preconditions should not be imposed on talks with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He expressed hope during the interview that his administration will act speedily on this new strategy on Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Regarding the Middle East crisis, Obama said that he is constituting a special team</seg>
    <seg id="10">that will start working after January 20 to establish peace in Middle East.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush: Inept and despised American President Bush has confessed his mistakes and crimes in the last news conference.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency has quoted Associated Press as saying that American President George Bush in his last news conference has confessed to many of his mistakes and crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Addressing a press conference at the White House, President Bush said that he has good wishes for the newly elected president Obama but the biggest challenge for him will be to stop the possible attack on America.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the completion of mission in Iraq and social security reforms were his mistakes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush said whatever he did, he did it for the America's security.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Replying to several questions regarding the ongoing Israeli oppression in Gaza, Bush said that Israel has the right to defend itself. According to him, Hamas had no right to defend itself and that Hamas should not strike Israel and like America, the world should strangulate the oppressed and not the oppressor.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Inept, incapable and despised American President said that arms should not be supplied to Hamas whereas America is supplying world's most lethal and deadly arms to Israel. Israel is using American weapons to perpetrate open massacre of the Palestinians. Bush has also admired the pro-Israel Arabs and termed them as Israel's friends.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Bush expressed embarrassment at some of the crimes committed in the Guantanamo and Abu Gharib jails.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to analysts, Bush should be tried for war crimes and the organizations that accomplish this task will be doing a big favor for humanity.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Ahmadinejad: Iran's President has expressed grief over the silence of Arab countries' leaders.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the report of Mehr News Agency, Iran's President Dr. Mahmoud Ahmadinejad has intensely criticized and expressed regret at Arab leaders' silence over Israeli oppression and brutality in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Expressing his shock over the silence of Arab countries' leaders on Israel's barbaric attacks on Gaza, President Ahmadinejad said that Israel is engaged in the holocaust of Palestinian people and is targeting Palestinian children, women and civilians with its barbaric acts while the Arab leaders have not even issued a statement.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmadinejad has asked all the Arab countries to be united against Israel and rescue the oppressed Muslims from the cruelty and ghastly acts of Israel in Gaza</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ahmadinejad Asks Saudi King to Make His Position Clear over Israeli Genocide in Gaza</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Mehr News Agency, President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad has said in his message to the Saudi monarch Abdullah that silence of Saudi Arabian Muslim King on the genocide and massacre of innocent children and women in Gaza is encouragement for the enemies of Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmadinejad has asked the Saudi king to clarify his correct stance on Gaza and support the oppressed people to fail the plans of the enemy who want to create divisions in the Muslims front.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmadinejad has said in his message that, you are aware that Israel is bent upon committing genocide in Gaza for last 19 days; it is massacring innocent children and is carrying out barbaric bombardment on houses, mosques, schools and hospitals; the Zionist government is openly murdering helpless Muslims. In circumstances like these, the silence of leaders like you is a source of encouragement for Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Ahmadinejad said to Malik Abdullah that the non-Islamic countries like Venezuela and Bolivia have taken concrete steps against Israel, therefore, you are expected to take stronger actions than those countries.</seg>
    <seg id="6">President Ahmadinejad said that the Palestinians would be victorious in Gaza</seg>
    <seg id="7">And the oppressed will overpower the oppressor, and it is God's promise.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090116.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush: Terrorism is still a threat to America</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency has quoted a German News Agency as saying that American President George Bush, in his farewell speech addressed to his successor Barack Obama and the nation, said that America is safer as compared to seven years ago, but the threat of terrorism is still looming over its head.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Bush said that the terrorist enemies are sitting patiently, watching, waiting to attack America and they have are determined to attack America. and America should also not be careless of its own security.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Ignoring the miseries and sufferings of millions of Palestinians, the American President defended his aggressive and wrong policies. The American President said that the United States was still a major champion of freedom of nations, but analysts, however, do not accept the truth of these claims by the despised American President because the America is neither a proponent of freedom nor supporter of human rights, but it is the world's biggest mischievous country which is not only supporting an oppressive government like Israel but is also a direct partner in its crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Israel is massacring children, women and civilians, and the American President is applauding it. This is the American brand of freedom and humanity that the world is is witnessing in Gaza and other parts of the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Osama Hamdan: Resistance to continue in Palestine</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Mehr News Agency, Hamas representative in Lebanon Osama Hamdan told French News Agency that the unilateral ceasefire by Israel is violation of international efforts of comprehensive ceasefire. He said the unilateral ceasefire will be meaningless if Israeli remains in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that the unilateral ceasefire was a futile attempt by Israel to avoid defeat. If Israel wants a long-lasting peace, it has to lift the siege as well as accept the terms of Hamas.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In Lebanon Hamas leader made it clear that if Israel goes for unilateral ceasefire in the presence of its troops in Gaza Strip, resistance will continue against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Addressing a Gaza Solidarity Conference in Beirut, Osama Hamdan asked the European countries to sever relations with Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Hamas leader said that, the rise in number of the martyred and injured will further strengthen our resolve.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He asked the Palestinian people to stand like a concrete wall of resistance, in the war against the enemy.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan: Taliban Kill 6 people in Northern Waziristan Tribal Area of Pakistan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency has quoted Reuters as saying that Taliban have killed four Pakistanis and two Afghan nationals, on the accusation of spying, in Pakistan's tribal area of Northern Waziristan</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to information, on Tuesday morning the locals found four bodies in Tehsil Chowk area of Mir Ali.</seg>
    <seg id="4">while two bodies were found in the headquarter Miranshah, that were thrown into a market.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Letters written in Urdu were found near the bodies which claimed that that the murdered had been spying.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Two weeks ago as well, two Afghan nationals, accused of spying, were killed in Miranshah, the capital of Northern Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Fifteen people have been killed on charges of spying for the United States during last twelve days.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that more than 100 people, accused of spying, have been killed in Southern and Northern Waziristan during last six years. Taliban are accused of being involved in such murder cases.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barack Obama: Likely to Sign Orders for Closure of Guantanamo Bay</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency has quoted sources as saying that the American president will sign an order for closing the notorious Guantanamo Bay Jail.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The new American President Barack Obama, on the surface, has started implementing his election campaign pledges.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this regard, President Obama has directed preparation for the plan of withdrawal of American troops from Iraq, whereas today, the American president will sign orders to close the notorious Guantanamo Bay Jail.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that possibly today President Barack Obama will sign the orders under which Guantnamo Bay Jail will be closed down within a year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Apart from that, instructions are likely to be issued from the White House to review the interrogation techniques used on terror suspects and to ban abusive language against the prisoners.</seg>
    <seg id="7">On the first day in office, Barack Obama has began fulfilling his election pledges, and firstly, he has taken steps to ensure transparency in government's actions.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to analysts, the American president has started attempts to save America's falling image on the global level but it is difficult for him to be successful in this task. As long as America continues to support the murderous regime in Israel, one cannot expect anything good of it. If the America wants to save its image, it should keep itself away from supporting Israel and should not become part of its crimes.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tony Blair: Stresses inclusion of Hamas in talks</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency has quoted British newspaper The Times as saying that Britain's former prime minister has stressed on the need for including Hamas in Middle East peace process.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the newspaper, Tony Blair has said that it is important to find a way to include Hamas in Middle East peace process. Blair has also severely criticized the Bush administration to include only Mahmoud Abbas and ignoring Hamas. It should be noted that the western countries are now talking of including Hamas in the talks in view of its public and administrative influences whereas earlier they considered Hamas as a terrorist organization - a terrorist organization which is defending its land, struggling to liberate its homes from oppressor's control and whose home and land, for sixty years, have been under the illegal occupation of a usurper government like Israel.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Killing of Baloch Traders in Karachi, Complete Strike in Quetta</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Quetta and some other areas were on complete strike on Thursday in protest against the killings in Karachi of four traders from Balochistan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">All the business centers remained closed during this, while traffic was less than the usual.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Strike in protest was called by Anjuman-e-Tajeran-e-Balochistan, Pakhtun-khwa Milli Awami Party and Jamiat Ulma-e-Islam. They accused that the Karachi Police allegedly shot the traders dead while they arrived by car to their car show room on Tariq Road.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President of Anjuman-e-Tajeran Abdur Rahim Kakar has demanded that police officials involved in the incident should be arrested and strict action taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, no immediate stand of the Karachi Police regarding this incident has come forward.</seg>
    <seg id="7">All four traders that were killed belonged to the border town Chaman.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Government had made large scale security arrangements for the strike and police officials had been stationed at important locations throughout the city.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Senior Hamas Commander Killed in Israeli Attack</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A senior commander of Hamas was killed in an Israeli air attack.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This is the second important Hamas personality killed Gaza Strip, in the Israeli attacks that have continued for a week.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Hamas authorities have said that Abu Zakaria Jamal was killed on Saturday at Al-Shujaiah colony, east of Gaza City.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In another Israeli air attack on Thursday, Hamas scholar Nazar Raiyan was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Exiled leader of Hamas in Syria, Khaled Mashal, has vowed for revenge and warned Israel against ground offensive in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Thousands of Israeli troops are deployed on the border of Gaza and waiting for instructions to attack.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America has appealed for ceasefire but has said that it is up to Israel to decide whether or not to launch ground offensive.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In a weekly radio speech, American President George Bush has alleged Hamas of inciting violence and aggression and termed rocket attacks on Israel as terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that America is working on ceasefire but no unilateral solution will be unacceptable.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Thee Bodies Found in Northern Waziristan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani security officials have said that three dead bodies were found in the tribal areas of Northern Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is suspected that they were executed by the Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="4">These bodied were found near Miranshah, the headquarters of Northern Waziristan. Letters were also found near these bodies, alleging that those men were spying for America.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officials said that one of the bodies is probably of the person who was abducted last week.</seg>
    <seg id="6">They said that the other two bodies, full of bullet holes, are of Afghan nationals.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Israeli Attacks in Gaza Continue for 10th Consecutive Day</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A Palestinian child was injured in Israeli missile attack. Israeli army is fighting the Hamas fighters across the Gaza Strip while the Israeli Air Force continued air attacks on suspected hideouts of the militants.</seg>
    <seg id="3">=Israeli Foreign Minister, Ehud Barak, said on Monday that Israeli military offensive will continue until residents of southern Israel are safe from Hamas rocket attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, despite Israeli attacks Hamas has continued to fire rockets in which four people including three civilians have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hamas leader Mahmoud Zahhar on Monday stressed upon his colleagues to crush the Israeli army and target Israeli civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But one of Hamas officials has said that his organization will send a team to Egypt on Monday to discuss the situation arising out of the fresh violence.</seg>
    <seg id="7">An injured Palestinian woman in Gaza. Medical sources in Gaza said that during the past ten days nearly 350 people have lost their lives and on Monday 11 civilians including at least five children, were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Israel has reported that one soldiers has been killed and 30 have been injured in the ground attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Israel has stopped foreign journalists from entering Gaza to report on its military offensive.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">American Vice President Elect Joseph Biden Arrives in Pakistan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Foreign Minister welcomed American Vice President elect</seg>
    <seg id="3">The American Vice President Elect, Joseph Biden, arrived in Islamabad on a visit to Pakistan, on Friday along with a delegation.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Foreign Minister Shah Mahmood Qureshi and top officials of the American Embassy welcomed him.</seg>
    <seg id="5">American Senator Lindsey Graham is also accompanying Biden on this tour.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Press Officer of the American Embassy Lofenter told Voice of America that during his visit the newly elected President would deliberate with the Pakistani leadership on various regional issues, however, he declined to divulge further details.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the Foreign Ministry sources Joseph Biden, will also meet Chief of Army Staff General Ashfaq Parvez Kayani besides other government officials.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is expected that during these meetings besides bilateral and international matters war against terrorism will also be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Joseph Biden was decorated with Hilal-e-Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After arriving in Islamabad, Joseph Biden met with President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="11">During the meeting President decorated him with Hilal-e-Pakistan for his role in promoting close ties between Pakistan and the America.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It is to be noted that Biden, in his capacity as the chairman of the American Senate's Foreign Relations Committee, along with Senator Richard Lugar introduced a bill that recommended a three-fold increase in America's non military aid to Pakistan amounting to $5.7 billion.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Prime Minister Gillani: Joe Biden Played Key Role in Ex President Pervez Musharraf's Decission to Doff Uniform</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Yousaf Raza Gillani and Joe Biden, File Photo</seg>
    <seg id="3">Prime Minister Yousaf Raza Gillani said that American Vice President Elect has played an important role in the former President Pervez Musharraf's decision to doff uniform and relinquish the charge of Chief of Army Staff and Joe Biden has also played an important part in the restoration of democracy in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Yousaf Raza Gillani gave this statement while speaking to media persons at Karachi Shipyard.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He said that Joe Biden is a "Pro-Pakistan" or a Pakistan supporting leader. In his capacity as Chairman of Foreign Affairs Committee of the Senate he presented a bill advocating $15 billion aid to Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Condemning once again, the missile attacks by American drones inside Pakistani territory, Prime Minister of Pakistan reiterated that the government has not entered into a secret deal with America regarding the attacks and according to him since it is a matter of Pakistan's sovereignty, therefore, we can in no way permit America to carry out air strikes within the national territory.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He also expressed the hope that after the inauguration of the new President the American policy towards Pakistan would change.</seg>
    <seg id="8">File Photo</seg>
    <seg id="9">Yousaf Raza Gillani maintained that government has very successfully managed to seperate ordinary civilians from the terrorists but the missile attacks by drones jeopardize government efforts and the terrorists once again team up with local tribes.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that the international community endorses this stand of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He further said that if reliable evidence is provided, Pakistani forces themselves take action in their own areas.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Regarding Mumbai attacks, Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani reiterated his stand that if India provides evidence then we will act on that basis and if anyone was found guilty then action will be taken against him as per the law of the land.</seg>
    <seg id="13">To a question on the Rehman Malik's visit to London and his meeting with the MQM leader Altaf Hussein, Prime Minister said that he has gone there with his permission.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Quetta: Four Policemen Including DSP Killed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">File Photo</seg>
    <seg id="3">On an important highway of Quetta, Siryab Road, four policemen including a DSP 'Deputy Superintendent of Police' were killed in firing by unknown assailants.</seg>
    <seg id="4">On Wednesday morning two DSPs, one Sub-Inspector and two constables were going towards the Police Training Centre in a jeep. Near Degree College at Siryab Road, assailants on a motorcycle began unprovoked firing at the police jeep killing the Sub-Inspector Mehdi and constables Sibghatullah and Nasrullah on the spot while DSP Hasan Ali later died of injuries in the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Hospital sources, the condition of the other severely injured DSP Ghulam Muhammad is also critical. He has received bullets in his head and neck.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After this incident police cordoned off the area. As of now no one has claimed responsibility for the attacks.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Another Indian Software Engineer Killed in America</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Another software engineer from Andhra Pradesh has been killed by unidentified assailants in America.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The 26-year AkshayVishal of Secunderabad was shot two days ago in Arkansas by unidentified persons. He died during treatment at the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was an employee of Satyam Computers and was serving in the Falcon Jet Airways.</seg>
    <seg id="5">During the past one year, seven students from Andhra Pradesh have been killed by anti-social elements in America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Rise in killings of those who come to America for higher education or in search of better employment opportunities has raised concern among families whose children are settled in America.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It should be noted that in Andhra Pradesh America is the preferred destination for higher education and better future.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the data of American Consulate in Chennai, more than 100,000 visa applications for American visa are received from south India and Andhra Pradesh accounts for the highest number i.e. 40 per cent of them.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Meanwhile, the State government has started efforts to bring back the body of the deceased to Haiderabad.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bush: America Must Remain Alert against Enemy Attacks</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">President George Bush in his final radio address has cautioned America to remain alert against enemy attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Bush said that the even now the biggest threat to Americans is the possibility of yet another attack by the terrorists. He warned that the enemies were waiting patiently, determined to strike again.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The outgoing President said that America must not be negligent of its security.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush also extended best wishes to the next President Barack Obama who will take oath of office on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The newly elected President Obama in his Saturday radio address highlighted the historical importance of the swearing-in ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that this is a ceremony wherein the American greatness and the peaceful transfer of power from one leader to the other are deeply related.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mr. Obama recalled that people in several parts of the world cannot even imagine that their leaders will relinquish power without any bloodshed or conflict.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Sharif Brothers, Federal Home Minister Meet at Raiwand; Political and Security Issues Discussed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A meeting between the Federal Home Minister Rahman Malik and Nawaz Sharif, leader of the largest opposition party in the country and ruling party in Punjab Pakistan Muslim League N, was held on Sunday at Raiwand. The meeting was also attended by Punjab Chief Minister Shahbaz Sharif.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to local media, Rehman Malik had possibly brought a message from Pakistan People's Party leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, Rahman Malik did not give details of the meeting to the media. He only said that they discussed political reconciliation and briefed the PML-N leadership about the post-Mumbai attack situation.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words: "Information has been provided about whatever action has been taken till now.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Do not forget that the main action was taken in Punjab and was taken by the Punjab Government and Punjab Government's help is also required in the team that I have formed now.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Rahman Malik said that media is not briefed everyday but messages are exchanged with PML-N leadership almost daily. On the other hand the spokesman for Pakistan Muslim League N, Pervez Rashid, also declined to give details of political issues discussed and said that Rahman Malik has said all he wanted to say.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be noted that the meeting of Home Advisor with the PML-N leadership was held at a time when more than 20 anti-government PML-Q administrators held a press conference with Punjab Governor Salman Taseer and had rejected the criticism of the initiatives of Provincial Government by the PML-N, as well as objected to the involvement of Punjab Governor in this whole issue.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Persident Zardari: Obama's Speech is a Welcoming Sign for Pakistan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Welcoming the inaugural address of new American president, Barack Obama, Pakistani President Asif Ali Zardari said that his pledge to promote relations with the Muslims world on basis of mutual interests and respect is a welcome step for Pakistan and its people.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In a statement released on Wednesday he said that the reiteration of his lofty commitment and ideas is hope for a better future for the people of the whole world.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the statement, President Zardari said, America undoubtedly has an important responsibility to work along with the international community to search for new avenues of peace, progress and prosperity in the 21st century.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It should be noted that in his inaugural address after taking oath on Tuesday, Obama said that America wants new progress in relations with the Muslim world based on mutual interests and mutual respect.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He had assured people of the poor nations that America will work with them so that there will be social development and reduction in poverty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Obama Appoints Special Representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Richard Holbrook: Richard Holbrook, former envoy to the UN, has been appointed as the special representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan</seg>
    <seg id="3">Holbrook played a key role in peace accords in Bosnia-Herzegovina</seg>
    <seg id="4">Holbrook said that he was ready to advise President Obama on Pakistan and Afghanistan matters.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, he added that this is not an easy task</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the history of the two nations is very different</seg>
    <seg id="7">For the Middle East, George Mitchell has been elected who will try to bring new life to the Arab-Israel dialogue.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mitchell is an ex-Senator and he has taken part in establishing peace in Northern Ireland.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Speaking in the State Department, Mitchell said that the situation in Middle East is extremely unpredictable, complex and dangerous.</seg>
    <seg id="10">However, despite this America will not hesitate to make efforts for establishing peace there.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghanistan: Voter Registration in Perils</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Afghanistan Election Commission has said that due to security concerns it is delaying voter registration in some areas in south of the country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">For the upcoming Presidential elections in southern Afghanistan, voter registration began this week.</seg>
    <seg id="4">But the Commission has said that unless the security situation improves, voters cannot register themselves in some areas of Helmand Province.</seg>
    <seg id="5">These southern areas have witnessed an increase in violence since last year where Taliban insurgents have increased attacks on Afghan army and the international forces.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Meanwhile, Afghan army and international forces have said that between Wednesday and Thursday nights, they have killed at least 28 militants in clashes carried across Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">NATO said that its forces have killed at least 22 militants in air and ground strikes in the northern Khost Province near Pakistan border</seg>
    <seg id="8">Earlier the Afghan Defence Ministry said that in the same Province the Afghan army killed eight rebels and wounded two.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is not clear whether the Afghan officials have referred to the same incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090123.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Missile Attacks in Waziristan, at least 18 Killed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani intelligence officials have said that in North Waziristan in the two suspected American missile attacks at least 18 people have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to officials, American drones launched three missile attacks on a house in Mir Ali town of North Waziristan killing ten members of the family.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to local officials, among those killed, five were foreign militants.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This area is considered to be a stronghold of Taliban and Al-Qaeda militants.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Few hours after this incident, another missile attack was carried out in southern Waziristan resulting in the death of at least eight people.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Despite objections of Pakistani government, around 30 missile attacks have been carried out since the middle of last year.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The current attacks are the first since Barack Obama assumed charge.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The Bush administration had avoided taking responsibility for these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="10">In the tribal area of Northern Waziristan of Pakistan, suspected American drones on Friday launched three missile attacks that have killed five people till now</seg>
    <seg id="11">the victims have not been identified.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to preliminary reports these attacks were carried out at a house in Mir Ali area.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It should be noted that this is the first missile attack after Barack Obama became American President.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">NWFP Province: Government Rejects Demand for Ban on Girls' Education in Swat.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">NWFP authorities have rejected the threat for ban on girls' education by Taliban militant saying that this declaration is both against the Law and Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On Sunday, the NWFP Education Minister Sardar Husain Babar said that government will never allow such attempts to succeed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the extremists want that children of our area should be deprived of education.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words: 'These people secretly try to blow up schools and threaten boys and girls.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Referring to the atmosphere of insecurity, he said that the Provincial government is well aware of this and wants to make it clear that no power can stop the promotion of education in the Pakhtoon land.</seg>
    <seg id="7">A day earlier, Taliban militants led by Maulana Fazlullah Taliban demanded a ban on girls education in Swat from 15 January and threatened that educational institutions found violating this decree would be destroyed.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Despite continued military action in Swat for the past one and a half year, the militants have destroyed around 150 educational institutions either by explosive materials or by setting them on fire.</seg>
    <seg id="9">As a result of the destruction of these educational institutions, thousands of boys and girls have been deprived of education facilities.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Security Beefed up in India on Republic Day</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In India 60th Republic Day will be celebrated on Monday. On this occasion intense security arrangements have been made and thousands of military personnel have been stationed across the country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On the occasion of Republic Day in the capital New Delhi, arms, aircrafts and other military equipments is displayed during the military parade.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Authorities have said that as part of the security arrangements, anti-aircraft tanks and "Sharp-Shooters" have also been deployed and police is maintaining a strict watch on the parade route. American President Barack Obama has congratulated India on this occasion.</seg>
    <seg id="5">And has sent a message wishing speedy recovery for Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh who underwent heart surgery on Saturday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It should be noted that the Indian police claimed to have gunned down two suspected Pakistani militants in a gunbattle in the outskirts of New Delhi, yesterday.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to local authorities police has recovered AK 47 Rifles, grenades and some papers which show that both of them were Pakistani.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Police are also investigating whether these two have any links with the banned organization Lashkar-e-Taiba which was involved in Mumbai attacks last November</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tea: Effective Cure for Breast Cancer</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a new research drinking three cups of tea a day</seg>
    <seg id="3">reduce the risk of breast cancer by one-third in women below 50 years of age.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The research conducted at the Moffitt Cancer Research Centre in America's state of Florida has revealed that the risk in developing breast cancer tumor in those women below 50 years of age</seg>
    <seg id="5">reduces by up to 37 per cent who drank at least three cups of tea daily.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The research has also revealed that among women of higher age, the daily dose of three or more cups of tea does not have any significant impact in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Experts believe that the reason for this is the presence of a substance in tea that is more effective against a particular type tumor that generally target women below 50 years of age.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In Moffitt Cancer Centre situated in Tampa city of Florida, America, this research was conducted on 5,000 women who had undergone treatment for breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Their ages ranged between 20 to 74.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Experts compared their medical records and lifestyle with such women who were free from breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Experts have also found that the tea had a significant effect on a particular type of cancer, Lobular, and it was reduced up to 66 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Almost every tenth patient of breast cancer suffers from this type.</seg>
    <seg id="13">This type of cancer is the most dangerous because it is located vary deep and is detected only after it has spread extensively.</seg>
    <seg id="14">According to the experts regular intake of at least three cups of tea daily significantly reduces the risk of breast cancer among younger women.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They say that the body develops proper immunity against cancer if tea is included in our daily drinks and is made part of our daily routine.</seg>
    <seg id="16">In Britain every year around 40,000 women are diagnosed with breast cancer.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghan War is the Biggest Military Challenge for America: Gates</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">American Defense Secretary Robert Gates has said that the war Afghanistan is the biggest military challenge facing America.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gates was briefing the Senate and House of Representatives on Obama administrations' strategy regarding the Afghanistan and Iraq war.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Gates told the Armed Services Committee of the Senate that war is not the only solution of the Afghan crisis but he also said that not enough troops were in place to protect a number of places and Taliban take action taking advantage of this.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Why Reduce Exercise with Age?</seg>
     <seg id="2">New Research</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="3">Exercise is good for health at any age.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It rejuvenates your heart, reduces cholesterol levels, helps lower weight, helps prevent diabetes and slows down the onset of Alzheimer.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Unfortunately, in many people the ability to exercise decreases with advancing age.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Experts say that exercise keeps our mind and body alert, however, age can affect it.</seg>
    <seg id="7">American medical experts say that lack exercise can lead to several health problems.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Dr. Patricia Polacco of the Mayo Clinic, Minnesota, says that age is a major factor in a person's reduce ability to exercise and reduction in physical acitivity.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Dr. Patricia teaches medicine at the Mayo Clinic.</seg>
    <seg id="10">She headed a study on the ability to exercise and heart diseases in old age.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Doctors used high frequency sound waves to observe the heart's activity.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In which the heart's action of pumping blood, its contraction and the heart's resting phase was observed.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Experts focused their attention on the left side of the heart which is the central point for pumping blood.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They found that with the advancing age there is an increased disturbance in the heart's process of relaxation.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Dr. Patricia says that with increase in age the heart's relaxation process slows down and it also affects ones ability to exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Dr. Gavan Ken was part of this study</seg>
    <seg id="17">He says that he was surprised to note that this thing necessarily affects it and it also clarifies as to what extent poor exercise regimen is related to the heart's relaxation process.</seg>
    <seg id="18">At times blood pressure can also be responsible for disturbances in heart's processes and heart diseases.</seg>
    <seg id="19">If doctors and patients work together they can benefit from exercise despite advancing age.</seg>
    <seg id="20">A detailed report in this regard has been published in the Journal of American Medical Association.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">No Chances of Immediate War with Pakistan: Indian Army Chief</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Chief of Indian army General Deepak Kapoor has rejected any possibility of an immediate war with Pakistan, however, he said that army was prepared to render sacrifices to defend the country and ensure the safety of its interest.</seg>
    <seg id="3">General Kapoor alleged that even after assurances and international pressure on Pakistan in the wake of Mumbai attacks the terrorist infrastructure in Pakistan is not only intact but is active as well,</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said this while speaking to media correspondents in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Chief of Indian Army was on a one day visit to Kashmir Valley to take stock of the overall security situation in the New Delhi Administered Kashmir as well as to observe the preparation of armed forces along the border.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He was asked to comment on media reports that Pakistan has rejected the evidence presented to it by India about the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="7">General Kapoor said that the political leadership decides the matters of war or peace.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Referring to the alleged presence of terrorist infrastructure on Pakistani soil, General Kapoor said that Indian army would fight such elements which are out to disturb the peace and weaken India.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He said between 700 and 800 militants are present in the Indian Kashmir of which almost fifty peer cent are foreign militants.</seg>
    <seg id="10">General Kapoor said that with improvement in weather infiltration from Pakistan and Pakistan-administered Kashmir may increase, however, India has stepped up vigil along the border.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He rejected the call to reduce the military presence in the Indian-administered Kashmir saying that national security cannot be compromised.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May prayers of the world come true and Barack proves a blessing to the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Although there is not much hope, but let us see how far the relations between Pakistan and America turn our way as a result of this change</seg>
     <seg id="3">Let us see how Mr. Barack, who himself is the realization of Martin Luther King's dreams, puts them into reality.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Oath-taking as President of America to-day by Obama, whose name also includes Hussein, is not only an historical event in all respects but also is a stern test in history</seg>
     <seg id="2">for him-self, but also for all of them who supported him wholeheartedly.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is also a test for the white majority who may find it difficult to wholeheartedly accept a black person as their ruler.</seg>
     <seg id="4">People in South Asia, especially the Muslims, who have pinned their hopes on him should remember that he has been elected as the President of America and Obama should bear in mind that an American President is practically a President of the world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A little while from now, a man, whose racial brethren were brought from their respective homelands to America with the yoke of slavery around their necks and who had - nurtured the foundations of the most powerful nation of the modern era with their blood and sweat, will become the forty-fourth President of this very America representing the same racially marginalized community.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A lot many people have a lot of expectations from this man.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is necessary for those who love him not to pin unrealistic hopes on him.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If Obama can somehow reduce the hatred emanating from sources such as race and religion, it will be a victory for those who love him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What impact will this change have on South Asia and can some meaningful change be expected in the American policy - due to this development.</seg>
     <seg id="2">How will this change affect the relations between Pakistan and America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">(BBC)</seg>
     <seg id="4">Dear Sir, whether it be Obama or someone else, - - the multi-billionaire, effective, strong and influential Jewish lobby determines the policy and nature of relations with the whole world.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And as far as Pakistan is concerned, the aggressive behavior of Indian-Israeli-American triangle in connection with the recent Mumbai blasts is before the whole world to see.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Frontier province of Pakistan, the series of targeting the educational institutes by the local Taliban is continuing.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The largest number of the schools, most of whom were for girls, have been destroyed in district Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Not being content with that, Taliban have also announced a ban on the education of girls in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thousands of boys and girls are being deprived of education.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you think Taliban want to achieve by stopping the education of the girls?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Why has the government so far failed in checking these illegal acts?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What - do you reckon the government should do?</seg>
     <seg id="2">For a long time even after the creation of Pakistan, the Wali of Swat was responsible for the administration of Swat with his regular army and law.</seg>
     <seg id="3">He handed over the administration of Swat to the government of Pakistan by a treaty</seg>
     <seg id="4">but it's a pity that our governments accorded a step-motherly treatment to Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Neither there has been an increase in number of schools at all in Swat since abolition of rule by the Wali of Swat</seg>
     <seg id="6">nor any interest has been taken in the construction and development of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The number of girls who have been getting education in the present era are many times lesser than these were in the previous era.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The question should be ; what will the ISI and the Pakistani agencies get?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Because the people of Swat have now understood this game that the army is there to serve the Taliban and not to kill them. Otherwise how five schools could be blown up in one night despite the curfew and how people could be slaughtered and hung in the central square of the city during the curfew hours?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">How can the government succeed in checking these illegal activities when it is not being allowed to establish its writ in Swat?</seg>
     <seg id="2">So the question is that the government has everything including armed forces, modern weapons, modern technology and the intelligence system, etc., then how come it cannot control handful of Taliban?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The answer can only be that they have the blessing of some 'secret saint' so neither they run out of ammunition nor they get caught</seg>
     <seg id="4">and the conclusion is that the Taliban are making the job of 'international imperialism' easy through their dark acts.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fifteen years ago, there had been a war in Afghanistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The ISI was controlling the Taliban and the opponents were the Northern Alliance who were being supported by Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Then the situation changed and the sins of Taliban began to surface</seg>
     <seg id="4">and the ISI too was offered dollars by the Americans so the former friends became enemies.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now the situation is that the war is still raging but in Pakistan; the helpers are the same: Iran, India and Russia</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">- Israeli attacks on Gaza have entered into the third week and the death toll has reached almost one thousand.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The war has not ceased so far despite international diplomatic efforts</seg>
     <seg id="3">and according to one estimate, ninety thousand Palestinians have left their homes for safe areas since the start of attacks on December 27.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Accusing the Israelis of being careless about the security of the Palestinian children, the aid agencies have alleged that a whole generation of the Palestinian children will have to experience acute psychological and emotional traumas.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="3">What should happen?</seg>
     <seg id="4">How can lasting peace be possible in Gaza?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Click here for details.</seg>
     <seg id="6">(Please note that owing to excess number of comments, only those comments will be published that are typed in Urdu script.</seg>
     <seg id="7">For this, press 'alt+shift' on the on-screen keyboard to select Urdu)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As long as a man does not develop a sense of right and wrong, he continues to err.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For instance, when a thief sets out to commit a theft but realizes in time that 'theft is not good; it is a curse; he will be punished and he also fears God', then he won't commit theft.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Similarly, as long as Israel does not realize that it has been committing something wrong by spilling the blood of the innocent people and rendering itself to punishment, it will continue to play havoc with the lives of the innocent people in Gaza.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Hello!</seg>
     <seg id="5">The question is: Do war, an armed movement and terrorism offer solution to the problems?</seg>
     <seg id="6">If not, then what is that magical formula which would lead to solution of the problems?</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is correct that war and violent means do not settle problems, rather they aggravate them.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Palestine, Afghanistan and Iraq should follow the same model for success of their movements which was adopted by Nelson Mandela in South Africa.</seg>
     <seg id="9">That is, - instead of armed struggle, they should opt for moral and political struggle and '' self-control.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It appears from their participation in elections that Kashmiris have endorsed this point of view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Taliban be given an opportunity</seg>
     <seg id="2">basit, Peshawar</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wake up! If the Taliban start doing the real jihad, who would then slaughter the innocent people?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Who would burn the girls schools?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And who will do kidnapping for ransom and in case the ransom is not paid to them, who would hang the people by the poles by declaring them American spies?</seg>
     <seg id="6">These Taliban have caused more harm to Islam than any other nation or religion.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pashtun Rohr</seg>
     <seg id="8">Kohat, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If the united Muslim world may just only give a threat to attack Israel jointly, you will see how much Israel's godfather, America, will be hurt</seg>
     <seg id="2">and not only there would be talks for immediate real ceasefire but a ceasefire will take place as well.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But what can we do, Sir. How can our Muslim rulers muster up so much courage?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Someone should ask Ahmadinejad to take initiative because a lot is being said about his bravery on BBC forum.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Responsibilities relating to maintenance of peace and human rights do not devolve upon Arabs or the Muslims of the world alone, rather it is duty of the international community to raise their voice against cruelty.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This horrific incident is the deadliest of the sins committed by Bush so far.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Just like corruption and plundering is let loose in government departments in Pakistan and India, by 30th of June, i.e. the end of a fiscal year, the American administration, before its dissolution, has given Israel the green signal to do whatever may please it.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">On the one hand America says that efforts will be made for ceasefire,</seg>
     <seg id="2">on the other hand, the United Nations is passing one resolution after another but nothing has been done practically. This leads one to reach the only conclusion that the United Nations is also working to crush the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the Muslim countries should immediately cancel their membership of the United Nations and form an international organization of their own.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We have many examples before us where America and the United Nations have only made pledges and passed resolutions but the loss has been suffered by Muslims alone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is all bunkum as the BBC is not going to publish anything.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Where have they - buried all the principles of journalism now? Whenever the innocent blood, especially belonging to the Muslims, is spilled, the BBC gets obsessed with nonpartisanship.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise, it is a self-proclaimed guardian of truth</seg>
     <seg id="4">Let alone revealing something at their own, they have plunged so deep in meanness that they do not even publish commentaries</seg>
     <seg id="5">by the Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The only difference between you and the Jews is that they claim their Jewish identity and kill Muslims and people like you live among Muslims, call themselves Muslims and kill Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">[syja786]</seg>
     <seg id="3">It has been a long time that a particular sect is being targeted on BBC forums sometimes on account of suicide blasts and other times on the pretext of terrorism in India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The favorite catch phrase of these anti-Islam comments is extremism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But who is the extremist? You can easily surmise from the comments above in which someone has virtually been declared a non-Muslim for writing against Iran.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When will our Muslim brethren understand that the evil-doers cannot be combated with sword.</seg>
     <seg id="2">One cannot help shedding tears of blood over the deaths of unarmed civilians in Israeli bombing?</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the basic fault lies with the sedition and bloodshed that is our misnomer for jihad and by doing so we try to tarnish the beautiful face of Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When the majority of the Palestinians has recognized Israel, why does Hamas have to fire rockets into Israel or conduct suicide attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">The behavior by both sides is inhuman.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The role of America and the United Nations again appeared to us as being supportive to Israeli atrocities.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah let the Muslims be united. Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">and consider bestowing the Nobel Prize for the war on terror to the real terrorists on this painful act of terrorism because they are the ones doing the actual work.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise, is it possible to do acts of terrorism at such a large scale without the backing of some powerful lord? And everyone knows who holds the strings.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This can then be said to be hoodlumism. i.e. do whatever you can.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The powerful man beats and then does not let the victim weep.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Arab rulers are providing medicines for the injured and shrouds for the dead and money as well but it is still being asked:</seg>
     <seg id="2">Israeli attacks, what should happen?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The problem actually is that the rulers of all the Muslim countries, including the Saudi king are in a slumber. Neither they have any army nor any defense plan. And they assume that by offering aid, they have done their duty.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They should at once take practical steps against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Like an embargo on petrol for the European countries and America. But alas!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salaam to all brothers and sisters!</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think in this hour of adversity, suggesting Hamas to stop its struggle in the name of peace will be sheer injustice to thousands of widows and millions of orphans and will be equivalent to their failure.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If Israel and its allies are at the height of their pharaoh like vanity, a Moses too will be born in their home shortly because such is the law of nature. The steps taken by America and Israel are working as a catalyst for producing suicide bombers in the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And these elephants who are intoxicated by power are unable to understand it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Abu Abdullah Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Hamas and Israel should strike peace now so that the bloodshed may stop.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Muhammad Sarfraz, Paris, France.</seg>
     <seg id="3">absolutely correct.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Lets us suppose that Hamas is hundred percent right in its cause - and wants to win Divine 'approval' by launching 'jihad' against the 'barbarity', even then it must know that if such virtuous acts start destroying happily living families, it no longer remains a virtue.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The love of humanity is a part of their faith for those who claim to love God, His Prophet, and their religion!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">So, it is God's commandment to wipe out all those on whom 'divine books' were revealed from the face of the earth except Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeeb-ur-Rehman Psycho, *Lahore [P@KI$T@N]*</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, the commandment is not to wipe them off but to preach Islam to them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But jihad is ordered against those who hatch plots against the religion.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They should be fought against until they stop hatching the plots. But it does not mean that one should wear a jacket and detonate it in a crowd.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">My brothers, the ultimate end of the murderer of the innocent children is destruction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But I beg to say to my friends that these Jews who did not have a shelter in the near past have become so strong that they do not listen to anyone in the world now because they are united.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They are neither Shia nor Sunni. All are Jews. And they have taken every step to progress in all walks of life.</seg>
     <seg id="4">On the contrary, look at the conditions of the 55 Islamic states?</seg>
     <seg id="5">They are lacking in every field. And now the situation is that they have become so helpless that the enemies are killing them and they are waiting for death.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is needed that all the Muslim countries unite and prepare a strategy against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Feroz magsi, Jhang, Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">And there is no better strategy than to recognize Israel and by doing so, learn the modern sciences and the ways to progress and let the world live in peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Muslims have enough land and resources.</seg>
     <seg id="5">All that is required is the proper usage.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The saddest part is that Hamas and Al-Fatah could not unite.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Great leaders like Yasser Arafat and Sheikh Yassin were killed with such precise planning so that the only brave nation of this territory carrying out 'jihad' for the sake of Al-Aqsa mosque may be weakened. And as long as Yassin and Arafat were not removed from the way, it was impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The world is seeing that how Palestine disintegrated after the demise of the these two leaders</seg>
     <seg id="4">and with every passing moment, the Jewish lobby kept on strengthening its hold.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">=In 1974, a Pakistani Prime Minister was a man with such international credentials that he brought together all the Muslim rulers of the world with hundred percent attendance under one roof.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Is it very difficult for this nation to promise on his 81st birthday to not only create unity among its own ranks</seg>
     <seg id="3">but also carry forward his incomplete mission (to set up an Islamic Commonwealth) by mediating to settle the differences amongst other Muslims as well. -</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The series of bombing on Gaza by Israeli war planes and the missile attacks has been continuing since December 27.</seg>
     <seg id="2">More than 300 Palestinians have been killed in these attacks so far.</seg>
     <seg id="3">After the aerial attacks, the Israeli tanks and armored vehicles have also reached the Gaza border with full preparations for a ground assault.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Security Council of the United Nations has asked Israel and the Palestinian Authority to stop the violence immediately.</seg>
     <seg id="5">However, the Israeli authorities say that they would continue action inside Gaza until they are certain that the rocket attacks on Israel will stop.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Do you agree with Israel's point of view that this action is an attempt to defend Israeli integrity?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Is the international community playing its part in this situation?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Is this aggression directly related to the coming elections in Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Can any improvement in the Middle East situation be expected after newly elected American President Barack Obama takes office.</seg>
     <seg id="5">(Please note that due to excess number of comments, only those will be published that are typed in Urdu script.</seg>
     <seg id="6">For this, press 'alt+shift' on the on-screen keyboard to select Urdu)</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is a genie who has been haunting Palestine for half a century.</seg>
     <seg id="8">This genie has many mouths.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Often it uses one of its mouths to condemn itself and to divert the pressure and attention of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="10">And the other mouths of this genie are eating humans in Iraq, Afghanistan, Iran and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="11">And this genie is most fearful of Islam because it knows that whenever it would be exorcised, it would be done by Muslims and their completely practical religion, Islam. Because history tells that Islam has taught lessons to all the powerful Abu Jahl's of the time.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Palestine is the most sacred place for Muslims for all the times to come and its security is our compulsory duty</seg>
     <seg id="2">and we must remember that it is our first noble sanctuary.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And Israel, India and America have to disappear one day because these countries were made to disintegrate. And God's wrath will soon visit these heathens. Sajid Sadiq, Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="4">"The night of separation cannot pass by weeping only</seg>
     <seg id="5">No affliction leaves with prayers only" (Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC searches for and publishes such comments.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After all, they have to maintain the impression of nonpartisanship.</seg>
     <seg id="3">By the way, the news by the BBC are generally correct but the actual problem lies with the presentation of the news.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What has to be highlighted and what has to be marginalized.</seg>
     <seg id="5">etc.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="7">Our Pakistani electronic and print media, in particular some Urdu newspapers and columnists are second to none in exaggerating due to 'Muawiya like spite' while covering or writing about the increasing extremism and terrorism over here.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">=Where is the United Nations that apparently talks of human rights and peace but when Muslims are subjected to the intense cruelty and suppression, the only words that we hear from their mouths relate to their demand to Hamas to stop the attacks. For how long, will this dual policy go?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why are the Muslims being subjected to so much cruelty? If countries like America stop backing these Jews, God has plainly told that this nation will live the meanest form of life and this nation can never live normally. So, O People of America, stop backing them and then you will see what fate holds for them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The so-called arbitrators of justice and those who murder and plunder in the name of peace should mind this fact that the peace in this world can be established only through justice, and not through injustice and genocide.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If a nation could be wiped out by genocide only and the desired results could be achieved, the very existence and glory of the Jews today would not have been possible after Hitler's actions.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As a poet has said</seg>
     <seg id="4">Barbarity ends when it stretches beyond limits</seg>
     <seg id="5">And blood congeals when it trickles down</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Who would tell now what is terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Does all this not fall under the category of terrorism? Why does everyone feels only one's own pain?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are the others not human beings or the blood of the Muslims is worth so little? Was the blood of all the innocents not red?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why is no one sending messages of condolence now?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I watched the Mumbai attacks as if my own house was on fire because I can't see the grief of human beings. - And who cannot see this grief? Would that the Muslims could - think about that on the same lines.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Dead bodies lying on the road, the helpless injured and blood-stained innocent faces, how do we condemn when we are lost for words.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I am brought to tears by the helplessness of the Muslims because when on the one hand, the people get killed in India, the whole world pushes Pakistan without any proof to take action or they shall take action themselves</seg>
     <seg id="3">and on the other hand, Israel is conducting blatant genocide of the Muslims and the world is silent; this is unbearable</seg>
     <seg id="4">God's Mill grinds slow but sure -, and when this darkness of disappointment will end then..</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Any threat to Israel's existence in the presence of America is a joke.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As far as the elections are concerned, the rulers may undoubtedly engage in this kind of activities to win public support, particularly in case of a state like Israel. And as far as Barack Obama's factor is concerned, history stands testimonial to the fact that neither any American ruler has ever gone against the policy nor he will. Imperialism, whether black or white, is after all imperialism.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is clear from the ongoing discussion on the forum that everyone is sad over the death of Benazir but her shortcomings as a politician have not been overlooked.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is debatable if Benazir sacrificed her life for democracy or for government.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If democracy was dear to her, why did she leave the public at the mercy of Musharaf's dictatorship for ten years till she got American clearance and struck the deal?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir did not come to Pakistan when people under the dictatorship needed her. Unfortunately she came to Pakistan when she had been promised acquittal from all cases and access to power.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no one to defend the historical figure who is being criticized unnecessarily.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="3">Some things are overlooked because nothing can be done about them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Another reader</seg>
     <seg id="5">Mr/Madam, perhaps you had better study history written in four friendly countries and seven other countries and not merely rely on history in Pakistan then you will probably agree with Mr. Psycho.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tariq Ayaz</seg>
     <seg id="7">'Those who don't have innate disposition, don't learn from training</seg>
     <seg id="8">The reflection of the tree won't become green no matter how long the tree stands at the edge of the stream'</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Britain never allowed them to be one and invented Hindu-Muslim dispute which was nurtured by Sir Syed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Psycho</seg>
     <seg id="3">How merciless is our nation. They write panegyrics for themselves and also for the glory of their party blindly. But now every historical figure and intellectual is being blamed and criticized and there in no one to raise voice against it.</seg>
     <seg id="4">we have made enough progress.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="6">Some things are overlooked because they cannot be helped. Like, an ass won't become a scholar simply by carrying a book load.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Although there has been a break in the ongoing dialogue process between Pakistan and India in the wake of the Mumbai attack, Pak-India should nevertheless continue this dialogue.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If we talk of war, there will be loss of human lives on both sides.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India has said that the man captured in the Mumbai attack is a Pakistani citizen who has sent a letter to Pakistan in Urdu, but on the other hand, when India arrested this extremist, they said that he was some senior engineer but now they say that he is educated only up to level 4. This is noticeable.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First of all, Christmas greetings to Mr. Bhana and all other Christian friends on the forum.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The mates on forum: my regards to Mr. Psycho, A. Raza, sister Sana, sister Shahida Akram and the rest.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We want the flowers of peace and not the flames of war!</seg>
     <seg id="4">War is a problem in itself</seg>
     <seg id="5">How can war provide solution to the problems</seg>
     <seg id="6">It will bestow fire and blood today</seg>
     <seg id="7">It will yield hunger and poverty tomorrow</seg>
     <seg id="8">Therefore, O conscious people</seg>
     <seg id="9">As long as the war is avoided, it is good</seg>
     <seg id="10">In your and our courtyard</seg>
     <seg id="11">It would be better if the light of peace keeps on burning</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">India-America relations have strengthened very deep now and India certainly knows that America will openly betray Pakistan in the hour of need.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The old history of America also proves this.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Whereas in case of an Indian attack not only will the American interests be met but also India will bear all the expenses.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan should make a clear announcement that it would not strike first but if any aggression is carried out, there will be no talk of reconciliation, peace and ceasefire until either India is completely destroyed or occupied, even if it may cause destruction to ourselves as well.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is the Islamic history.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even before this resolution, the message that the Pakistani people and the military had to convey has been conveyed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">India's attempts to gain military and diplomatic benefits in compensation for the Mumbai attacks has been portraying it more as a cunning party than the affected one. That is why the world community has lessened its pressure on Pakistan after harsh initial reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Without taking note of India's unnecessary hullabaloo, the expression of satisfaction over Pakistan's efforts by the United Nations and the appreciation by the Interpol's head of Pakistani efforts is the 'side-effect' of India's over enthusiastic diplomacy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There are no divided opinions on the fact that this is a very cruel act.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But the question is that when thousands of Taliban attacked the village of Pir Samiullah, where was the Pakistan army and what was it doing?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Should the army not be held accountable for what it has done there in one year?</seg>
     <seg id="4">How many Taliban are killed by thousands of mortar and heavy artillery shells they fire every day?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I appeal to the ISI that they, for God's sake, stop patronizing the Taliban and let us live in our Heavenly Swat in peace.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And stop this fake operation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The day is not far now when a resolution about military intervention in Pakistan will be passed in the United Nations in the same manner as it was passed against Jama'at-ud-Dawah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Riaz Ahmad Farooqi</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our extremists and their supporters are continuously providing all the proofs and justifications for action against them and, may I have soil in my mouth for saying such a cursed thing, the day such a resolution is tabled, there is every likelihood that no one will support us in the United Nations,</seg>
     <seg id="4">and suppose there is some delay in the passage of such a resolution, some powerful country, following the precedent set by America, will launch an attack by itself.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We have no knowledge of the personality and the achievements of Pir Samiuallah and of his activities.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Perhaps he was not a revolutionary.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Just as the dead bodies of comrade Che Guevara, Nawab Akbar Khan Bugti, Dr. Najeeb Ullah and thousands of other revolutionaries have been defiled by the enemies.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are immortal even after their death.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But an international game is being played here. The people are being ruled by terrifying them through barbarity and brutality.</seg>
     <seg id="6">So that a justification may be created that if we are not here, these beasts and brutes will take over the government.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This act of the so-called Islamists in the name of Islam is extremely condemnable act.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The supporters of these extremists can see the American atrocities but rather than expressing grief over such cruel acts, they evade the responsibility in the name of tribal customs.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No kind-hearted person has any justification for such a cruel act disguised in the tribal customs or perpetrated in the name of Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, the personnel of our army are collaborating with them.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is proven by the fact that when these people move, the movement would at least take so much time that that they could be arrested. But let alone reaching the spot, these people even if they are in vicinity, flee the place.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are these guys so powerful that they can take fifty to seventy men hostage and our army keeps watching the spectacle idly?</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are humans as is the army.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is evident that there is something fishy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Since the era of true dictatorship of Zia-ul-Haq, the Mullahism has been creating such an atmosphere of fear and terror in the name of religion by its descriptions of the various kinds of exemplary punishments and torture rather than highlighting the mercy and love of God. Besides, the incident of hanging of the corpse, their literature and books like 'What will Happen after the Death' strike terror in the hearts.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And these people are using this fear and terror as a weapon merely to get the wealth and status of this world.</seg>
     <seg id="3">'O Preachers</seg>
     <seg id="4">You have so terrorized the world by the fires of hell</seg>
     <seg id="5">That you have become fear incarnate'</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It surprises me when it is said that this cannot be a Muslim's deed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We are either ignorant of our history or overlook it for the sake of convenience.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who burnt the door of the house of the Prophet's daughter when she refused to the oath of allegiance and who dragged her husband by tying a rope in his neck?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Had they come from somewhere outside?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Were the attack on Madina by Yazeed's army and the tragedy of Karbala perpetrated by Hindus and Jews?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Without accepting the facts, we can neither quash the motives nor can we provide redress.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">O BBC people, stop this dual policy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A better, super hit title on this subject: 'was shoe-flinging at Bush justified or not?</seg>
     <seg id="3">should have been'</seg>
     <seg id="4">Tahir Chaudhary, Japan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Friend, feel some shame. A man's body was exhumed and suspended to the pole only because he had raised his voice against cruelty. And you are worried about titles for box office?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The success of the Operation Sherdil and of Operation Lionheart on the other side of the border depends on how favorable is the public opinion regarding them.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This act has been perpetrated by the Pakistani and American agencies and Pir sahib has fallen prey to this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">From now on, all the comments on this forum will be anti-Taliban because the agents of the secret services have successfully penetrated Taliban and are conducting such actions as can change the common man's opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I would just like to ask what was the army doing when this dead body kept hanging from the pole for the whole day? Are they sitting there just to target the common people? Their statements are like, 'shelling on the hideouts of the Taliban, 2 children and their mother killed by a shell hitting the home'.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Did they not know about this square?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Or, were they watching the spectacle?</seg>
     <seg id="4">We humbly request and plead that for God's sake, stop this game.</seg>
     <seg id="5">After all, there is one Ruler above you too.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Whether or not the question asked by BBC was appropriate, the credulity of the writers hurts. For instance, no one asked why had this thirty thousand strong army gone to Swat?</seg>
     <seg id="2">That the corpses of those who support the army and fight Taliban remain hanging from poles all day long.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even if we overlook what the ill-omened Pakistan army did to the Swati people, the media including BBC has done no good by hiding the facts from the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan army is play-acting.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Every child of Swat is saying that this is a gory play.</seg>
     <seg id="6">For God's sake, stop this drama.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These Taliban have tarnished the reputation of the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If all the true Muslims of the world don't call them as Muslims, how can then these terrorist find safe havens in their lands?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Those who lack all sense of honor and can't work hard take up the gun and join these groups.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Islam has not flourished because of gun or sword.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Shame, shame.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Neither any religion nor any family traditions provides its justification.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All the media including BBC comment through various sources on Taliban and the tribes.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But no one knows what the actual position is. We know it because we are the tribal people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In short, this is a game that involves CIA, RAW, Mossad, and our own ISI. There is neither any Talib nor any tribesman. These mutineers are the creation of these agencies and are now casting a slur upon Islam, Taliban, madrassahs, Pakhtun nation, tribes and the tribal customs.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The heads of all the Muslims are bowed in shame over this act.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I salute the MQM leader Altaf Hussein and the leadership of ANP and PPP who talk about this cancer, namely Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This cancer is the product of Zia-ul-Haq. He himself departed but also destroyed Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But I am hopeful that the present leadership will be able to expunge this cancer.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the Mumbai attacks, India said that some Pakistani extremists had a hand in these attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan refuted these claims and said that it will extend all possible help to India in the investigation process.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India said that it had given Pakistan a list containing the names of 20 suspected extremists who were wanted by India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now Pakistan has said that Maulana Masood Azhar, the leader of Jaish Muhammad, who is included in this list is not under house arrest and the Pakistan government has no information about him.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Earlier, the Pakistani President Asif Ali Zardari dismissed the impression that the western secret agencies and the Indian government had provided evidence regarding the Mumbai attacks to Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">President Zardari said about Ajmal Qasab that it had not so far been proved that he was a Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Meanwhile, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has warned Pakistan that its relations with India won't improve as long as its land is used for the terrorism purposes.</seg>
     <seg id="8">And in the most recent update, the Indian cricket team has cancelled its tour to Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should these political events affect the sports too?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What future for Pak-India relations do you foresee?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Neither America nor India will disintegrate Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan will be disintegrated by the Pakistanis.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What do you expect after so much provincialism, sectarianism and mullahism?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The time has proved that Jinnah did not do any good to the Muslims of India either.</seg>
     <seg id="5">yasmin Chicago.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Dear lady, if work had continued on Jinnah's vision, neither would the cancer of provincialism, sectarianism and mullahism have spread in Pakistan nor would the Muslims of India have been meted out such treatment.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is our mistake that we have not been able to produce a leader of his stature.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If we cannot honor our heroes then</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There are lots of skills in this area.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Only God knows when will the wisdom prevail here and this land will progress due to the bounty of unity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In both the countries, mullahs, pundits, Taliban, Shiv Sena, RSS etc. have been assembled to destroy peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And the satanic forces do not want that this land may progress in peace so these countries are being exploited.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can you imagine what would be the status of this area consisting of Pakistan, India and China if there is unity?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Pakistan is suffering God's wrath that is why thieves, robbers and cattle-lifters have been imposed as leaders on the nation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May our country Pakistan never come to any harm. Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But my Lord, open your eyes and look at the conditions and the ground realities around you and you will be able to see where the American forces have reached.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Moreover, the internal situation does not look right. The situation in Frontier, Baluchistan and Karachi in Sindh is in front of you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In these conditions, the country needs a leader who can make us a united nation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">O God, have mercy on us.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I think there is no solution other than one last war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Enough is enough.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There should be a breakthrough now.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The problem will not be settled by the hypocritical masquerades of talks.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Neither would it settle by minor terrorist activities in other countries.</seg>
     <seg id="6">After all, Europe did not have peace until it fought the last world war.</seg>
     <seg id="7">If this world war had not taken place, these countries would have been squabbling like Pakistan and India till now.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the aftermath of the Mumbai attacks India</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan relations have experienced bitterness and the improvement in the relations between the two countries over recent years has suffered severe setback.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India has persistently been holding active militant and non-militant groups in Pakistan responsible.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">And the normalization of the relations has been tied up with action taken against these groups.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whereas the Indian security agencies have held Lashkar-e-Taiba directly responsible for the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The name of Jama'at-ud-Da'wah has also surfaced time and again in this connection.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is not the first time that the relations between the two countries have suffered on account of some act of terrorism in India.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In December 2001, these two neighboring countries reached on the brink of war after an attack on the Indian parliament.</seg>
     <seg id="3">After this, in 2002, Lashkar-e-Taiba was banned and included in the list of the terrorist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now, it is being demanded that Jama'at-ud-Da'wah which the security analysts say is actually the new face of Lashkar-e-Taiba should be banned.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Should this group, in your opinion, be banned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Should Pakistan act decisively against the active extremist groups in its territory?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">By imposition of ban on Jama'at-ud-Da'wah,</seg>
     <seg id="2">can the present Pak-India crisis be averted and how important is it to ban the armed groups for lasting peace between the two countries?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Almost all of our political parties agree that terrorism and sectarianism should be expunged from the country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">But our military leadership does not seem sincere in this effort. On the one hand, America and Europe are ensured that we are with them in this war on terrorism and on the other hand, we secretly help the Taliban as well.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We have to think now, and determine our orientation and choose only one path. Thanks.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There is no doubt that the majority of the members of Jama'at-ud-Da'wah consist of those members of Lashkar-e-Taiba who joined this new party after Lashkar-e-Taiba was declared a banned outfit;</seg>
     <seg id="4">however, its activists have since then preferred to do aid work. And now the United Nations has declared it a banned group on strong insistence by India and the government of Pakistan is also continuing its crackdown against them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">I think these jihadist groups had better quit extremism and carry on with religious and aid work.</seg>
     <seg id="6">This news has crushed the heart.</seg>
     <seg id="7">What kind of world is this where those who just pronounce the name of one of the fundamental principles of God's religion Islam find life difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Non-Muslims can kill the Muslims but if a Muslim tries to exact revenge, all the non-Muslims of the world along with all our hypocritical rulers join forces to treat the true and the sincere servants of the religion in the same fashion as they are doing today with our great leader Hafiz Muhammad Saeed.</seg>
     <seg id="9">The terrorist organizations based in Pakistan who have employed professional criminals in the name of religion and - senior mullahs are the very people who call Pakistan as the land of the defiled and God knows what.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Now they are leaving no stone unturned in destroying Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="11">In fact, leave aside Muslims, they can't even be called human beings.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Without cleansing Pakistan of these mischief-mongers, national security will remain in danger.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Is it still debatable whether these malignant elements should be banned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="14">There is no room for the violent mullahs in this world as their only job is to get the others killed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The United Nation's Security Council has banned Jama'at-ud-Da'wah. After all, what proof the Security Council had for being so hasty?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Does the Security Council not always show such agility against Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is called a lazy claimant and over-active witness!</seg>
     <seg id="4">In a way, India has itself become a failed state!</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whose intelligence, army and other security institutions have failed. Who were kicked around by a few terrorists for 72 hours and by blaming Pakistan for this failure, India is cheating the whole world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If one heathen is killed, there is hullabaloo in the whole world. Why is there this double standard?</seg>
     <seg id="2">The only non-political, religious, welfare organization of the country.......</seg>
     <seg id="3">Furqan Farooq, Faisalabad.</seg>
     <seg id="4">As long as our Prophet (SAW), the mystics and the sufis accorded love and respect to all human beings, Islam flourished and developed in peace and tranquility.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Muslims too made progress in all walks of life.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But when this beautiful religion was taken over by Mullahism, distinction between believer and non-believer started and new chapters of violence and malignancy began which the world did not know before.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salam. Do it Sir, of course do it but do it on your own.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Don't do it under American pressure.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If India has some problem, should she not present some proof?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why does India not offer the proof?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And why does she blame us for everything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">There are extremist groups and organizations in India too. Why don't they ban them?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are we the only terrorist people in the world?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What name would you give to India's actions in Kashmir?</seg>
     <seg id="9">What name would you give to Israel's actions?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The truth is that we are the first Islamic nuclear state in the world. Why do we enjoy this status, is the bone of contention.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is in the last stages now.</seg>
     <seg id="2">kamranhassan, ABU DHABI</seg>
     <seg id="3">Your point of view appeals and the conditions too seem like this</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now the American magazines are openly publishing the new map of Pakistan and these sanctions also seem to be another step in that direction.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Americans are now strengthening their hold on Pakistan not slowly but very quickly.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In these circumstances, if we did not display solidarity and unity as a nation, then remember if Bangladesh can secede, a lot of other things can also happen.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Any amount of condemnation of the terrorist attacks whether they be in a hotel in Mumbai or in Marriott hotel in Islamabad or in Palestine is insufficient.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Similarly, irrespective of their origins from Pakistan, India, America or Israel, they should be exterminated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now the question is that why the whole world including the Pakistani authorities have been keeping silence on the terrorist attacks that take place in Pakistan every day and in which hundreds of people get killed?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Was the attack on Marriott hotel not conducted by the terrorists?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Then why.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Hats off to Advisor on Interior Affairs Mr. Rehman Malik. By God's grace, His Highness has become so brave and bold!</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to BBC, as (a committee of) the Security Council of the United Nations has banned Jama'at-ud-Da'wah, Mr. Malik said that they had not banned it and would do so only after serious consideration.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Not only this, according to BBC His Highness Mr. Malik has also dismissed this impression vehemently that the arrests of the terrorists are being carried out 'on someone's orders'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">O brothers, all praises be to God!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The security forces have raided an alleged camp of the banned Lashkar-e-Taiba in Pakistani administered Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After the Mumbai attacks, pressure is increasing on Pakistan to speed up the action against extremist organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India alleges that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved in Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">American Secretary of State, Condoleezza Rice, has asked the Pakistani leadership to conduct immediate and transparent action against those responsible for the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="5">She said that there was no doubt that the extremists who carried out the Mumbai attacks had used Pakistani territory.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Meanwhile, authorities in Peshawar have said that another trucking station used for supplying goods to the Allied forces in Afghanistan has been set on fire by unknown armed men. Fifty trucks have been destroyed in this incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is the second attack on NATO and the American forces' supply in Peshawar during the last 48 hours.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Meanwhile, Pakistan has conducted a raid on an alleged camp of Lashkar-e-Taiba. Prior to this, many efforts have been made to unarm the armed groups from Karachi to the tribal areas in which those who return the arms have been promised bounty and amnesty in return.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The conditions reveal that the attempts to take Pakistan back to pre-nineteen hundred &amp; eighty position by dismantling the armed groups that were formed during general Zia-ul-Haq's era as a result of former Soviet Union's intervention into Afghanistan and the consequent Saudi and American funded resistance, have not succeeded.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The question is: Does Pakistan want to do so?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Does Pakistan have the ability to do so?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What is your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Click here for details</seg>
     <seg id="3">(Please note that owing to excess number of comments, only those comments that are typed in Urdu script will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="4">=For this purpose, select Urdu by pressing 'alt+shift' on the on-screen keyboard.)</seg>
     <seg id="5">Having the ability or not, or saying that don't want to.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Whose war, we the Pakistanis are fighting?</seg>
     <seg id="7">And we have our interests too that we'll try our best to safeguard.</seg>
     <seg id="8">No one has the right to interfere in some other country's national affairs.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Apparently the colonial period is over.</seg>
     <seg id="10">If the people expect to find justice or the allies press for independent judiciary, respect the democratic institutions and do not support a dictator or military ruler, peace will be established in the third world including Pakistan which is probably not acceptable to the allies.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Pakistan, in any case, remains subservient to American and European ambitions.</seg>
     <seg id="12">This is done in spite of opposition by a large majority of the people of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="13">And this further ignites opposing sentiments.</seg>
     <seg id="14">If America and its allies have faith in democracy, they should shun the colonial practices and leave the area by showing respect to the sovereignty of the state.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Pakistan has enough ability to arm or disarm.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I have only one question to all the torchbearers of humanity:</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is impossible that you kill their children and they welcome you with garlands</seg>
     <seg id="3">Saeed, Multan</seg>
     <seg id="4">And my question to you is that do any system of knowledge ranging from Islamic to eastern and western, any logic, argument or philosophy sanction the murders of innocent prayer-goers, laborers, and poor working class servants in response to the American attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And if the answer is in negative, you are in dire need of amending your point of view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">People were armed. At the time there was the threat that after conquering Afghanistan, Russia would target Pakistan. Therefore, these people were armed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now when there is the danger that America would attack Pakistan via Afghanistan, the current American President has expressed this openly during his presidential campaign, so why should we disarm these people?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Only to ensure that after conquering the Pakistan army, America or India would not have to face any public resistance?</seg>
     <seg id="4">True, if anyone of them is found involved in a terrorist activity, only Pakistan should take action against him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">But the sad aspect of it is that government's action against Lashkar-e-Taiba has verified Indian claims that Pakistan is involved in it.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeeb-ur-Rehman Psycho, *Lahore [P@KI$T@N] *</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even if it is accepted that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved, blaming Pakistan government is not right.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And this question too: did these terrorists not have the support of some official or unofficial Indian agent?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are the terrorists produced and trained only in Pakistan and are not trained in India and the other countries of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post63" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As far as Lashkar-e-Taiba is concerned, it has no link with the recent terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is worth remembering that Hafiz Saeed was the first 'jihadist leader' who declared the Taliban activities as 'seditious'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I firmly believe that the Taliban insurgence is a vital part of American strategy so every person or group who opposes Taliban in any way will have to be removed from the scene.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Despite co-operation from all the nation, the action against Lashkar under Indian pressure is an indication of the nervousness and sycophantic disposition of Zardari &amp; Co.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To end this movement that started with American and Saudi funding, now request them to mop up this corruption that has contaminated our society.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Also let us register protest with America and Saudi Arabia that on what moral grounds had they spread the virus of dangerous arms and so-called jihadist which are actually hate literature and culture prompting killings in our country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the threat of Indian attack and the declaration by the Pakistan army that they would move the troops from Afghan border and post them against India, and the declaration by the Taliban that they would take care of the Afghan border, America stumbled and used full force to ensure that India did not attack Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This has revealed the truth about American power in the area.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Although India has neither threatened to attack nor does she have courage.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And the rest was done by the Taliban attacks on American supplies.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Thus it is proven that without the support of Pakistan army and the government of Pakistan, America is nothing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Karachi, Pakistan's financial hub is Dubai of all the backward areas.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Millions never return empty-handed from here. But ever since the supremacy of law has been challenged in the western frontier areas, all the people have diverted their attention to Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now they are bent upon to take this city hostage.</seg>
     <seg id="4">For the first time, the Pathans are being called Pakhtoons. People of the same city are being made to fight as strangers although there is need to show solidarity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One solution to the problem is that all Urdu speaking people learn to speak Pushto, or vice versa. And if all the people learn to speak English, it would be even better.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You would definitely consider it a ridiculous piece of advice but does the cause of the clash not seem ridiculous to you?</seg>
     <seg id="3">That language may be the cause of violence?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir, time and again I offered this piece of advice to my friends who belonged to all religious and linguistic groups, during my childhood but every time people used to laugh at it.</seg>
     <seg id="6">These linguistic and religious hatreds were at that time not as powerful and strong as they are today and were mellowing within the hearts.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I cannot understand what this is and why this is happening.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are these the signs of the doomsday?</seg>
     <seg id="3">For what crime are the innocent people being killed?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The reasons are before every one. Those who want to disintegrate this country are active and those who do it have neither any religion nor any country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whether it be Karachi or Mumbai, the destruction has been caused by inmates.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Whichever government comes, it only changes the names of places to become famous. For instance, now a days airports, roads and buildings are all called Benazir.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Does Benazir mean that what has been happening to the people of Karachi and Pakistan?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The failure of RAW's attempt to ignite linguistic violence in Karachi at the height of the Mumbai attacks proves that the political elements that used to be on RAW's payroll have now resigned from the service.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The murders of Pushto speaking laborers and the Indian threats have awakend the dormant nationalism in Pakistanis from Karachi to Khyber.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The identical patriotic reaction by all political, religious, ethnic and national parties not only made India to learn rules of diplomacy but also provided food for thought to American planners.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The responsibility for the worsening of the situation in Karachi lies on Muttahida and ANP and the administration is taking sides.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The administration can control situation in 1 hour but this is being aggravated on purpose,</seg>
     <seg id="3">due to the pressure of political parties on police and rangers, it refrains from taking action.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The talks of solidarity are restricted to statements only. The political parties should shun their interests and work for the benefit of the common man.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As long as the political pressure remains on the administration, such incidents will keep taking place. May God keep Pakistan under His watch.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I think these guys are the biggest terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And there must be some foreign powers involved in it though we do not know who they are.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the sad part is that if such a situation had been prevailing in some city of the Frontier, the government would have crushed it. But now that this situation does not relate to the Frontier, the government seems powerless.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government should conduct an operation here and save a large and important city of the country from terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Otherwise Pakistan will face a huge financial crisis.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC Urdu is not publishing truth out of fear and the condition of the Pakistani media is even worse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The whole truth is present on BBC English.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One solution to the problem is that either all the Urdu speaking people learn to speak Pushto or vice versa. Or an even better solution is that all the people learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You would certainly consider it a ridiculous piece of advice but do you not find the cause of the clash ridiculous?</seg>
     <seg id="5">That the language may be the cause of violence?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At last another epic in cruelty was written in Karachi which every citizen of Karachi had been fearing for a long time.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Everybody did whatever he could. The reports published in media hardly tell fifty percent of what happened here in the four days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We spent three sleepless nights and are still fearful.</seg>
     <seg id="4">All those who got the hotels vacated, killed the cobblers and peanut sellers,</seg>
     <seg id="5">looted on the Super Highway and amputated the ears of the innocent peoples are ignorant of God's wrath which will come upon them eventually.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What in your opinion are the causes of this sudden unrest?</seg>
     <seg id="2">(BBC)</seg>
     <seg id="3">Keeping in mind the dreadful killing spree in Mumbai, we do not have to search too deep for the cause of Karachi's turmoil. The straightforward and easy explanation is that this turmoil has unconsciously occurred because of strife in 'blood'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Evidently, if someone incites 'Dad', it would not be surprising if his 'son' gets out of control.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The blood of Liaqat Ali Khan and many other martyrs also came from that land. I am writing this couplet to amend Mr. Psycho's misconception</seg>
     <seg id="2">We shall repeat the custom of our forefathers</seg>
     <seg id="3">We sacrificed to make our homeland, we shall sacrifice to save it</seg>
     <seg id="4">Faizan Touseef Siddiqui</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is regrettable that the country is at stake and we are busy in infighting.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It is for your information Mr. Siddiqui that if Wikipedia</seg>
     <seg id="7">is searched for Liaqat Ali Khan, we shall learn that he came of a respected Punjabi family from Karnal in the Punjab province.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Because of his services to the refugees, the refugees today consider him one of their own.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Every action has a reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">One can bear as long as it is confined to one's person but.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Ejaz Awan</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sir, before you too gather a crowd of the advisors in no time, let me tell you that the blatant symbols of true hoodlumism are found in the form of wall chalking and the posters on the walls of Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We have been suffering both kinds of hoodlumism.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The ruffians did not even forgive Pakistan and its founder. They did not have to suffer any reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Rather they are still defiling Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Only the Muslin League (N) remained and now they too have handed a manuscript of the 18th amendment to the Peoples Party.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Before this, MQM and the Muslim League (Q) had submitted manuscripts of the 18th amendment in the National Assembly and the Senate.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It seems so far that the manuscripts for the 18th amendment are only a political gimmick and no one sincerely wants to have it passed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">That is why no one has either vociferously talked about it on the Assembly or the Senate floor or pushed the house to endorse it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It seems as if these parties have hoodwinked people by submitting the manuscripts of the 18th amendment. This means that they have got the justification now that they had submitted the amendment and it was the ruling party's Speaker who did not initiate proceedings on it.</seg>
     <seg id="6">MQM is the ally of the government while the Muslim League (N) is the hidden ally and the Muslim League (Q) is the party that passed the 17th amendment, how can these parties be sincere in repealing the 17th amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is sheer cheating.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In any case, Peoples Party is in no hurry to repeal the 17th amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="9">How can one think of cutting one's own hands?</seg>
     <seg id="10">As long as Zardari is the president, the 17th amendment won't be repealed.</seg>
     <seg id="11">This precisely was the opinion of the majority of the people in one of our recent surveys and this is also the truth.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Had they wanted to repeal the 17th amendment, Zardari would not have become the president.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Now, he is even stronger than President Pervez because he is the President and the chairman of the Peoples Party simultaneously.</seg>
     <seg id="14">As long as he remains the President, the 17th amendment will stand.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Before repealing the 17th amendment, the political parties will have to banish President Zardari from the presidential palace.</seg>
     <seg id="16">Neither MQM wants so nor do the other parties.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Most of the elders of my family belonged to labor class</seg>
     <seg id="2">and when in my childhood I used to watch my paternal and maternal uncles doing menial labor, I used to pray to God to spare me from such physical hardship.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To avoid this, I wrote a letter to the editor of Daily Imroz and asked him what I should do after matriculation so that I did not have to do hard labor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The editor replied that I should become doctor or engineer and start studying the respective subjects.</seg>
     <seg id="5">From the beginning, I was inclined towards engineering and in the matriculation I had studied Technical Drawing instead of Biology.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But at the time of admission in F.Sc., my elder brother forced me to do F.Sc. in pre-medical and become a doctor.</seg>
     <seg id="7">I studied Biology hardly for one month and when I could not understand a word of it, I exchanged it for Mathematics.</seg>
     <seg id="8">I mean the fear of menial labor made an engineer of me and now I am at a very good position among many of my peers and am always thankful to God for this blessing.</seg>
     <seg id="9">I was reminded of this when I was trying to lift the carpets from my old home with the help of my two young sons.</seg>
     <seg id="10">We were not even half an hour into the work when the younger son said, "Dad, I think I was not born to do this work".</seg>
     <seg id="11">I said if this were true then he should study diligently like me and get rid of the menial labor.</seg>
     <seg id="12">The son said that he was studying and would complete his studies but he could not do that kind of work.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Somehow, the three of us completed that work in three hours and returned home.</seg>
     <seg id="14">The purpose of narrating this is if one specifies a goal, for whatever reason may there be, nothing could stop him from achieving his goal.</seg>
     <seg id="15">And well, if you do not know what you want to do, then only God is your savior.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is said that we should not speak ill of the deceased but what can we do. Even on the first death anniversary of Benazir, we can only remember her shortcomings.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the one hand, she crushed the independence movement of the Sikhs by providing the list of Sikh freedom fighters to India for the sake of her interests, and on the other hand she provided India with the chance to focus on Kashmir after crushing the movement in the Punjab.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Benazir and Nawaz Sharif's scramble for power which plunged the country many years back is recorded in history.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir continued the streak of negative statements on Kashmir and the nuclear program during her exile.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In violation of the London accord with Nawaz Sharif, Benazir struck a deal with General Musharraf.</seg>
     <seg id="6">During her reign, she allowed her husband to openly amass wealth and for this reason, he was called Mr. Ten Percent</seg>
     <seg id="7">During Benazir's reign, her brother was killed and his killers have not yet been punished.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Although she was a woman, Benazir avoided the fight for woman's rights.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Just as Benazir played her politics over her father's corpse, similarly her widower husband is now playing his politics over her corpse.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Benazir won the government twice but, punishment aside, she could not even get a case registered against the political murderers of her father.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It has been 37 years since the East Pakistan seceded. And look at the extent of the insensitivity of our people and the rulers that none of them either mourn or repent over their mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The proper course of action should have been to commemorate December 16 as a day of admonition and we should have made such moves that such an accident would not happen again.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We should have sent goodwill messages to the people of Bangladesh and tried to bring them closer to us again.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The rulers should have opened the Hamood-ur-Rehman Commission's Report and considered the reasons that led to the secession of East Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They should have thought about some way to bring back the Biharis stranded in Bangladesh and sent them gifts for encouragement.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But we have become insensitive. If someone dies next door, we do not get the information now.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We no more care for our brothers and sisters because we have become selfish.</seg>
     <seg id="8">No matter how great a tragedy may befall us, we get back to business the next day.</seg>
     <seg id="9">As the East and West Germany have unified, would that East and West Pakistan could unify once again.</seg>
     <seg id="10">We can again unify if both sacrifice for each other and come out of the shell of selfishness.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But I do not see this wish coming true in the near future.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When it was reported in the news today that the Governor of the American state Illinois had been arrested on corruption charges</seg>
     <seg id="2">and as the state congress was preparing for his impeachment at the earliest to remove him from the governorship, a white American friend of mine who keeps a keen eye on the situation in Pakistan bragged to me that this was called democracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even the strongest man is not above law in America</seg>
     <seg id="4">and then there is your country Pakistan whose President has taken office only after getting the corruption charges against him dropped.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Our sense of humor was stirred and we replied that the arrest of one Governor in America was not a big deal since in our country one prime minister was arrested and hanged overnight and the other one was exiled in no time.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tell us if such a thing had ever happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan saw off the President from the presidential palace with guard of honor who had dismissed the constitution of the country? Tell us if it had ever happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="8">In Pakistan, the Chief Justice was dismissed in such a way that despite having public support he has not yet been reinstated. Has it happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="9">A fake degree holder was appointed health minister in Pakistan. Did it ever happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The poor American laughed himself out and conceded his defeat.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In this photograph, despite being surrounded on all sides by the Americans, President Zardari is smiling.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It appears from his smile</seg>
     <seg id="3">as if he thinks that America is with his government but he is forgetting that these same people were with Pervez Musharraf a year ago.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This photograph has been posed for as if it were a family photo.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Never has such a photo been published in a newspaper before this. That is one president with three American officials.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It seems as if America's workload has increased in Pakistan and she has to do it with more than one workers. Or it may be so that they don't trust the new slave as much as they did the previous one.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is also possible that this arrangement had been made keeping in view the notoriety of President Zardari's reneging.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Had there been some wise ruler, he would have not given a smile in this photograph and the shame over the yoke of slavery would have been visible on his face.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If the principle of democracy is applied to this photograph, President Zardari would find himself in the minority.</seg>
     <seg id="10">According to the democracy, only majority rules the country and the photograph tells who is in majority.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The conditions are steadily getting worse in the troubled areas of Swat in the Frontier province despite the military operation that has been going on for more than a year.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the one hand, the government's writ in this area has been reduced to passage of a resolution of condemnation in the National Assembly and on the other hand the influence of the illegal FM radio channel of the Taliban has been steadily increasing in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The third aspect is that the ordinary citizen finds it convenient to obey the person who is ruling the area.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The claims are made about the deaths of many extremists in Swat by the gunship helicopters and in the artillery fire in the operation being conducted by the security forces. But despite these deaths, not only have the Taliban consolidated even further but according to one estimate, their control has spread to almost eighty percent of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Consequently, on the one hand the government is not prepared to concede its failure and on the other hand, the Taliban are more stable.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And who has been crushed between the two: the ordinary citizens.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is said in Swat now that someone asked what kind of people Taliban were and the reply came that they were very good since they were the guardians of the faith and were fighting the 'enemies of God and religion'.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Then they were asked about the army and the reply was that the army was good because it 'guarded the country and fought against the enemies of the state'.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Then it was asked who were the enemies of the religion and the country and the answer came; we, the ordinary citizens.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The heavenly Swat is also called the Switzerland of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">According to the government strategy so far, the talks are being conducted along with the use of force.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But the use of force has been of no use except further enhancing the Taliban's power and creating sympathy for them among the public.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It is needed that the government addresses the causes of the problem rather than using the force.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If the causes are addressed, Fazlullah and the Taliban will automatically vanish.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The proposed Shariat bill from the ANP government will, to a great extent, provide the solution to the problems of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But along with the implementation of Shariat, the government will have to focus on the economic problems too</seg>
     <seg id="4">The initial steps taken by General Musharraf suggested that this nation might get rid of the unworthy politicians but the lust for power transformed all his intentions</seg>
     <seg id="5">whatever the hopes were, after joining the 'war of terror', he actually began to consider himself immortal</seg>
     <seg id="6">and expectations of taking certain steps ended.</seg>
     <seg id="7">As the Bush era neared its end, he began to worry about the end of his regime and signed a deal with the thieves in panic.</seg>
     <seg id="8">General Musharraf could nevertheless have controlled the military but the present government does not even know what is happening.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Whether it be Bajaur or Swat, the army does not control the terrorism. And it bombs the 'enemy' i.e. 'the people'. It harms the life and finances of the 'enemy', as well as make them psychotic. That means we are the enemies</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I wonder how Pakistan army will fight against the Indian army when it cannot control a small group of the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They cannot track down the illegal FM channel which I think is very easy to do.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even then this FM is poisoning the airwaves with full force.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the girls schools, the boys schools are now being destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The curfew is imposed so that the Taliban may easily move around.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tonight, during the curfew they came in 8 trucks and dug up trenches in the suburbs of Mingora.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The question is how they reached there in spite of the curfew.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The army can kill Akbar Bugti in his home but salutes the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="9">For God's sake, someone may explain to this army to liberate the powerless people of Swat from the clutches of Taliban and prove that the Pakistan army can overpower any enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">His Highness says that most of the blood in the world has been shed in the name of religion. Tell me that if there had been no religion, would no bloodshed had taken place?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are Punjabi, Pathan, white and black, Mehsud and the other tribes products of religion?</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, absolutely not. Sir, religion preaches that there is no distinction either between a white and a black or a Punjabi and Muhajir. Had there been no religion, half the world would have been killed in the wars of color and the rest would have perished due to the enmities based on caste.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In fact it is the religion that provides moral training to the man and binds him that he has not come here on his own, rather he has been sent by the Creator of the universe and he has to spend his life according to His commandments.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a Muslim, I am absolutely certain that Islam is a complete code of life and a true religion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After taking up residence in London, I used to call each of my relatives every morning to ask about their well being even though they did not return the favor even once. Then I realized that they even did not like our calling them and we stopped making the calls.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During my two years' stay here in France, I have also felt the same.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I wonder why do people - expect us to make phone calls.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The resolution about Iraq passed in a few hours, sending 'peace' force to Darfur no problem at all.</seg>
     <seg id="2">=Prompt condemnation of the Mumbai attacks and ban on the suspected organizations takes only a few hours.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And where the dance of death is on, we are procrastinating.</seg>
     <seg id="4">O contractors of world peace, life is dying here.</seg>
     <seg id="5">-are they waiting for its real extermination?</seg>
     <seg id="6">So that then no sufferer can even think of using a weapon of mass destruction like a slingshot to win his rights?</seg>
     <seg id="7">When a father is running, carrying the dead body of his beloved child, do you still not feel a pain in any part of your heart?</seg>
     <seg id="8">If not, then you do not have the right to be called a human being.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Rather, you are a stigma on the face of humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Well, at least this much is proved that this land has also been the home of the Israelites for thousands of years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The proper course would be that these two nations live together amiably. But, since their strings are in the hands of the West and the Arabs, there can be no peace here without their consent.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now even Iran wants to fight its proxy war from here.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If somehow the Israeli action might stop for the time being, it would start again in the wake of some incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The interests of the BBC's country are associated with American and Israeli agendas and this is the reason that it has arrived with a series of blogs consisting of 'pro-jewish' material in the guise of 'enlightenment' and is engaged in one-sided and blind 'propaganda'.</seg>
     <seg id="2">BBC is merely fulfilling the 'formality' and its sole purpose is to win sympathies!</seg>
     <seg id="3">Mr. Moderator is requested to kindly publish my comments so that one may have feelings that there still is some element of pro-realistic attitude left in BBC.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thanks.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">No one knows who wrote this story and how did it come into being but one thing stands tested that in every age, the Dracula have been feeding on the blood of the innocent people,</seg>
     <seg id="2">there have been wars and bloodshed in every age.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the surprising thing is that how can this man of the twenty first century who considers himself to be thoroughly civilized remain quiet over this open and blatant massacre,</seg>
     <seg id="4">how come he does not feel that whatever is taking place, is presenting the worst facade of humanity.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The regrettable and sad aspect is that what picture will the dark face of this civilized man present before the man of the following centuries.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Well wisher, Sajjad-ul-Husnain, Hyderabad Deccan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The winter rains are on these days in Dera Ghazi Khan and in the rest of the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Here is a poem in keeping with the weather conditions. Enjoy this poem with the rain.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These rains come with you</seg>
     <seg id="4">When they pour down, they are the heralds of spring</seg>
     <seg id="5">When they stop, they are the inner peace</seg>
     <seg id="6">Sometimes they come for no apparent reason</seg>
     <seg id="7">Sometimes they are here day and night</seg>
     <seg id="8">Noisy they are, and quiet sometimes</seg>
     <seg id="9">These rains come with you</seg>
     <seg id="10">In some memory on a night</seg>
     <seg id="11">And in these subdued embers</seg>
     <seg id="12">Put out sometimes</seg>
     <seg id="13">And sometimes burnt myself</seg>
     <seg id="14">Sometimes there is sadness in every drop</seg>
     <seg id="15">These rains come with you</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These rulers are about to run away with a briefcase; whether the country survives or not, they don't care.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whether the public sells tooth powder or polishes the bells in the temples with the rind of the lemon.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our media, too, is corrupt like our rulers.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Its sole purpose is to wangle out money from the government.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As far as the public is concerned, it is ignorant and talking about public is a greater display of ignorance</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Something strange happened yesterday afternoon.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The police was running around but neither questioned illegal parking nor.</seg>
     <seg id="3">and furthermore nypd traffic was in no mood to check the illegally parked vehicles.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It so happened that a US Air plane really became a 'plane' and landed in the Hudson river.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Only this much is known till now that the "terrorists" belonged to the bird species goose.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It was perhaps the historical chill of New York yesterday.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Temperature does not fall so much.</seg>
     <seg id="8">My jaw has begun to ache due to half an hour's walk in the open.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Just Imagine the condition of the people who would have jumped from the plane into the river.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The good thing is that all the people are safe.</seg>
     <seg id="11">And the sad part of it is that the plane of the company sank in this financial crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="12">While watching all this, I went to New Jersey by West Side highway and although I had noticed that the west-bound was closed, what did I do?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Yes, I got stuck in this very jam on the way back.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Thankfully, during my one hour trip, the route had partly been cleared and I found the exit of 56 street.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Otherwise I did not take the first two exits due to lines of traffic.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Makki, my Pakistan: thank you and Eid greetings to you as well.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ammar: of course believers</seg>
     <seg id="3">Shagufta: thank you, Eid greetings to you as well.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sara: I have sacrificed two hens. The sacrifice does take place and Jahanzeb has told you about its method</seg>
     <seg id="5">There is no other method.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And we have to go to that farm, cut all the meat including skinning.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Basim: dot.net might take some time in getting back in order.</seg>
     <seg id="8">What happened on the forum?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Linko</seg>
     <seg id="10">To combat the snow of the blog, browse it with Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Duffer: thank you, Eid greetings to you as well.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sir, use Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="13">The snow will disappear.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We unwittingly kept considering the Swati Talibani group uncivilized because they resented the education of the women.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They had been expressing this displeasure everyday by blowing up schools and colleges for women at one place or the other.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But like most other thoughts, this thought also proved untrue. According to this news item on CNN, a Taliban's group has demolished a school for boys with the help of explosives on this sacred Monday.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Swat, Taliban Demolish a Boys' School</seg>
     <seg id="5">Actually, the girls' schools were first destroyed following the famous English proverb "ladies first". It is beyond reason why people are still bent upon calling Taliban as uncivilized and wild people ignorant of civilization.</seg>
     <seg id="6">This clarifies another point that the allegation against the Taliban's group that they disapprove girls' education alone is incorrect.</seg>
     <seg id="7">They are, by the Grace of Allah,even against education itself.</seg>
     <seg id="8">God may grant these mujahedeen more power and the infidel government</seg>
     <seg id="9">that has been imposed on us, the Almighty may help them to uproot it.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Ameen.</seg>
     <seg id="11">By the Grace of Allah, 182 schools have been demolished so far.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As if the customs among Muslims of the confirmation of betrothal before birth, marriage of the women with Qu'ran to swindle property, and the insistence of numerous religious scholars on the assumption that a girl attains puberty and maturity at the age of 8 were not enough, the news of a girl's marriage with a frog arrived from India.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Look at the photograph of the bridegroom taken at the marriage ceremony.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It also refreshed the memory of a girl's marriage with a dog a little while ago.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Look at that bridegroom too.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Even in twenty first century, they are lacking in humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is the age of computer and the interference of computer in every walk of life is on the rise.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have plenty of reservations on this growing interference of the computer, for instance in financial matters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the one hand, credit card makes life easy for you and on the other hand, it tightens the grip of the law enforcing agencies on your private life</seg>
     <seg id="4">because you can now be revealed through financial transactions like the records of your credit card.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And in future when the use of actual currency will be considerably reduced, its usefulness will expand.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Similarly in the crime world, the credit card details are hacked rather than going through the hazards of robbing the bank.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Similarly, computerized means are now available to develop friendships.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Social networking websites such as Orkut, Facebook, and Myspace are top ranked websites in terms of popularity.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But don't you think that the more we rely on these social networks, the more we are distanced from the people practically.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Similarly, there are match making websites where you are shown the list of people by matching the list of your choices with their choices.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Can you spend your life with someone who is exactly like you?</seg>
     <seg id="12">I cannot. The life partner is, therefore, also called the better half.</seg>
     <seg id="13">So that he/she may compensate for my shortcomings.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I wasn't probably blessed with my due share of wisdom.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Right from my childhood, everything that any elder said was the truth for me.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Just as I believed that my father knew the answer to every question of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I used to be ridiculed for this behavior.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But only the possible things seemed to be true.</seg>
     <seg id="6">I felt uneasy about telling a lie.</seg>
     <seg id="7">And I have suffered even at present age because of this habit.</seg>
     <seg id="8">I, therefore, try to resort to lying as little as possible -.</seg>
     <seg id="9">I don't want to give someone a false hope, especially in the name of God.</seg>
     <seg id="10">And use God Willing only when I pray to God for a particular job.</seg>
     <seg id="11">In any case, only God knows the intentions better.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a dreadful problem and has been caused by the estrangement from religion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to our religion and the constitution of Pakistan, the infants should stay with the mother.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The father is responsible for their subsistence and can meet them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When the children mature, they may choose with whom they want to live.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You have correctly written that the real problem is the relatives who misguide</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In our society, if the spouse of a fifty or fifty-five years old person dies and the widow or the widower may marry someone else, why is it looked down upon with such disapproval?</seg>
     <seg id="2">A Pakistani uncle lives in our neighborhood. His wife died 10 or 12 years back. After performing the weddings of all this children, he married a widow and his children turned against him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, this is his right by Sharia. What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="4">What kind of mindset is represented by 'as long as we are alive, we cannot bear the thought of someone replacing our mother'?</seg>
     <seg id="5">The feudal mindset determines all our actions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even here the same mindset is working that new shareholders in the inheritance of their father will be born and this very fact is resented. Otherwise, this act of their father is worth praising and following.</seg>
     <seg id="2">These restrictions regarding match-making have given rise to social evils in our society</seg>
     <seg id="3">the concept of the marriage of the widow or the divorced woman is becoming extinct.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Owing to these useless beliefs and unreasonable customs, the family structure is suffering from disintegration.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I think the children of that man should think that he has committed no wrong by marrying a widow after the marriages of all his children?</seg>
     <seg id="2">This way, the widow found some support and the uncle too got someone to manage his household</seg>
     <seg id="3">because his children must have got busy in their lives and would not be giving him proper time.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is caused by ignorance</seg>
     <seg id="2">If tomorrow their wives refused to cater to the old man, what would they do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is the result of social pressure</seg>
     <seg id="4">when people make fun of their family on such an act, the children begin to feel ashamed at the second marriage of the father</seg>
     <seg id="5">though they should face the situation and tell that their father's act was absolutely in accordance with Islam</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a curse in our society and we have fallen prey to it completely over the past 40-50 years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Even a wife accepts that her husband may fornicate but will not allow him to marry again.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And if it were in her power, she won't let him marry even after her death.</seg>
     <seg id="4">She not only destroys her salvation and her husband's salvation but also becomes a cause of spreading corruption in society.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Singing the songs of Islam is useless because we actually like the things that are according to our customs and traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For instance Vanni, Kari, keeping the girls illiterate and killings by gun shots on love marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As far as your question is concerned, had the old man shifted to the widow's house after marriage rather than bringing her home, his heirs would have made token protests and then gone quiet and content (the heirs of the widow would then have had butterflies in their stomachs).</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We embraced Islam many centuries back in the Indian subcontinent but could not get rid of this ignorant mindset and preferred customs and traditions to Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="2">To consider the second marriage of a man as livid, divorce as a stigma, a divorced woman as an untouchable, love marriage as a shameful act, and the marriage of a younger man with an older woman as a sign of her wickedness are the results of this particular mindset.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Furthermore, in the footsteps of the western nations we declare abstention and Purdah as old fashioned.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It was easier to embrace Islam than to get rid of that mindset.</seg>
     <seg id="5">May God grant us power and courage for this.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Ameen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Writing in Urdu was never so difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="8">It has taken me centuries to write just this much.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Be content with this little effort.</seg>
     <seg id="10">May God take care of you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Amir Timur wrorte in his book 'I am Timur' that if the head of an army was found in the first line of attack, that army would never be defeated.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But here the conditions are entirely different</seg>
     <seg id="3">these guys say that the public is destined to die for us and if we die, we are martyrs</seg>
     <seg id="4">the death of a commoner is nothing more than a murder</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Assalam-o-Alaikum wa Rehma' wa Barakatu,</seg>
     <seg id="2">I was returning to the shop after Isha'a prayers tonight when a man who was sitting in a car lifted his hand and got my attention.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I thought that the man might have lost the way or wanted to ask something. I stopped. He had his family in his car.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He told his objective and said that he was not sure if he could understand Arabic well or not and I told him that it was not a problem and he should tell his story.</seg>
     <seg id="5">He started to say that he had come from Riyadh but here in Madina, someone had picked his pocket and requested me to help him. I asked him to excuse me because I had already experienced such an incident where I gave a person 20 Riyals and asked him to get the petrol tank filled and go to Riyadh, but he started the same thing a little further on the way.</seg>
     <seg id="6">I was enraged and I scolded him and threatened him with Police. At this, he ran away.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The situation now is such that we Muslims come in cars with families to beg and easily swindle two or three thousand in a day.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Although there is a renowned Hadith (Peace be Upon Him) that the upper hand is better than the lower hand. Lower hand means the hand of the taker and the upper hand means the hand of the giver.</seg>
     <seg id="9">May God bless us from His bounty and make us true Muslims. (Ameen=)</seg>
     <seg id="10">Was-Salam</seg>
     <seg id="11">Javed Iqbal</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Famous singer Adnan Sami's wife, while accusing him of torture, reached a Mumbai police station</seg>
     <seg id="2">The police station has directed her to invoke the court.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Adnan Sami's wife Saba Galadhari has filed a petition against her husband stating that Adnan Sami consistently tortures her</seg>
     <seg id="4">and has subjected her to inhuman treatment,</seg>
     <seg id="5">she cannot bear it anymore and a case, therefore, may be registered against Adnan Sami</seg>
     <seg id="6">Rather than registering the case, the police asked her to invoke the court since the matter cognizable by the police.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are, in your opinion, the allegations leveled against Adnan Sami by his wife justified?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Is it not an Indian attempt to defame Adnan Sami?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Please post your opinion on this issue.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">=Adam Sanghar, Maher.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As far as the allegations are concerned, anyone can level them against the other</seg>
     <seg id="3">There is nothing greater than honor</seg>
     <seg id="4">Whatever the nature of Adnan Sami and his present wife's relation may be, he left his life of honor and went to India to earn money. His notoriety has cost him dearly</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is the retribution of his own actions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Washington...</seg>
     <seg id="2">Senior American authorities say that President Obama will take tough stance on Afghan President Hamid Karzai</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the new American strategy on Afghanistan, the war has been given precedence over development.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The authorities say that Hamid Karzai is being seen as a big hurdle in the way of achievement of American goals in Afghanistan because the government is corrupt, the narcotics trade has flourished and the Taliban power is resurgent.</seg>
     <seg id="5">American authorities say that the people among the American administration who are putting pressure on Hamid Karzai to do more include Vice President Joe Biden and President Obama's envoy on Afghanistan and Pakistan Richard Hallbrook.</seg>
     <seg id="6">They told that this strategy has come to fore after the departure of President Bush who used to hold video conference with Hamid Karzai every fortnight and stress the need for American role in the reconstruction of Afghanistan and its civilian infrastructure.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The authorities say that the Obama administration would work with provincial leaders as substitutes for the central government.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The authorities say that they would further push Hamid Karzai to fight corruption.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Hamid Karzai is facing new elections this year and this is not yet clear if Obama and his colleagues will support him for presidency or not.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Does this statement by the American authorities foreshadow a - shift in American policy regarding Afghanistan?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Is the Hamid Karzai era nearing its end?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What is your opinion on this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Sri Lanka defeated Pakistan by 2-1 in 3 One Day matches series between Pakistan and Sri Lanka.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan beat Sri Lanka in the first One Day match. However, Sri Lanka won the next two matches.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The performance of the national cricket team in the third One Day match was shoddy. Replying to Sri Lankan team's 309, Pakistan crashed to a mere 75 runs in 23 overs and thus suffered humiliating defeat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The outcome of the series shows that the performance of the national cricket team lacks consistency.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In spite of the home ground and all the claims, the national team suffered defeat. What, in your opinion, are its causes?</seg>
     <seg id="6">To what aspects of the game should the authorities pay more attention?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are you satisfied with the selection of the team?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What aspect would you hold responsible for the defeat, fielding, batting or bowling?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Please post your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Babar Hussein, Jeddah. Its highly regrettable that such dark customs are still prevalent in this modern age. These feudal landowners and headmen target innocent people with their barbaric rule. Who would call them Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Let some tribal chief himself walk on these embers some time. Why does the government not proceed against them?</seg>
     <seg id="3">When will the courts provide justice=?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370243-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Sri Lankan cricket team has arrived in Pakistan to play One Day international series</seg>
     <seg id="2">In spite of Pak-India tension, the arrival of a foreign team in Pakistan is a welcome move.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Sri Lankan team was warmly welcomed on their arrival at Karachi airport.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Two One Day matches between Pakistan and Sri Lanka will be played in Karachi while the third will take place in Lahore,</seg>
     <seg id="5">Robust claims about bowling, batting and fielding are being made from both sides.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The Sri Lankans are proud of their spinners and the Pakistanis rely on their fast bowling.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Sri Lankan captain Mahela Jayawardena says that not any individual but the whole Pakistani team is dangerous.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Muralitharan and Mendis will be the trump cards whereas the Pakistani captain has said that it will be a tough contest.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Shoaib Malik says that they have already played Muralitharan and they will see Mandis as well; they have prepared secret game plan and they will reveal it in the ground.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Will Pak-Sri Lanka series really be as interesting and sensational as the claims sound?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Who will have the upper hand in the series between Pakistan and Sri Lanka?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Who will win the series?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Who will be the Man of the Series?</seg>
     <seg id="14">Please post your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Gulfam, London. You publish your favorite comments. You too prefer them. We wish that you occasionally write the truth as well. Don't change your statements like Mukherjee because it is an order to say the truth before the cruel rulers and it is equal in status to jihad. Mukherjee is a class apart, he tries to stay in the news by changing the statements.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">British foreign minister David Miliband has said that the solution of Kashmir dispute will check extremism; the government of Pakistan will be able to deal effectively with the dangers on the border.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It should also be noted that the newly elected American President Obama has also expressed similar views on the Kashmir dispute.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The British foreign minister has said in an interview with media in Mumbai and has written in an essay that the concept of war against terror is wrong. Killing people on the pretext of the dangers posed to oneself was President Bush's policy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">David Miliband has said that Pakistan should show no leniency towards the extremist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is India not trying to divert attention from this issue by creating tension in the region in the wake of the pressure put by the big powers on the need to resolve Kashmir dispute?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Is Mumbai terrorist attack not a part of this very strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Does India want to avoid the process of comprehensive dialogue on the basis of terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Please post your opinion.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Malik Yousuf, Dubai.</seg>
     <seg id="5">All this has been done by them. Kashmiris have been fighting the war of independence for the last 60 years</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">No one has asked them. Now as they are enmeshed in the war on extremism and terrorism, talks about peace have been started</seg>
     <seg id="2">First they massacred the Muslims and now they are trying to settle things</seg>
     <seg id="3">Anyhow, Pakistan has to comprehend their dual policy'</seg>
     <seg id="4">Asad Khan. London.</seg>
     <seg id="5">India is creating such a situation that the world's attention may divert from Kashmir</seg>
     <seg id="6">But Pakistan has always revealed the true face of India to the world</seg>
     <seg id="7">Now the British government too is comprehending this. That is why the Indians are trying to divert attention from their occupation of Kashmir by defaming Pakistan on the issue of terrorism -</seg>
     <seg id="8">and are reluctant to talk to Pakistan on this issue</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Usman Aftab</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think the big powers do not want to absolutely destroy Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rather they are thinking of some steps to keep it under the thumb. They know that Pakistan is an atomic power</seg>
     <seg id="4">They want to create an environment for revolution over here</seg>
     <seg id="5">The foreign countries are thinking that there can be some geo-political problems if Pakistan is cornered. They want to help Pakistan and in doing so accomplish their own interests.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One citizen, U.S.A.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Hindu have always traditionally been bad at hear but righteous in face.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I think they develop internal pangs periodically and begin to threaten Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are prepared in every respect. The Indian army chief may keep his mouth shut or we know how to give a jaw-breaking answer</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Faheem Siddiqui..</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ras-al-Khaima, This volley of statements is a result of America's mischief. America's mind is already abnormal but now India too has joined the league. Let India attack and be exposed as we shall get a true assessment of her power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel is attacking upon Hamas but no one dares to stop it. Taking a cue from Israel, India also wants to do so.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Prime Minister Syed Yousaf Raza Gilani has said that the newly elected American Vice President Joe Biden played an important role in the removal of the uniform of the former President Musharraf and the reinstatement of a crippled democracy, so the government has bestowed upon him the Sitara-e-Imtiaz.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The credit of the removal of the uniform and the reinstatement of democracy should not go to some political party. Parliament is not a rubber stamp.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the decisions will be taken in the parliament.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Prime Minister said that the chapter of Dr. Qadeer had been closed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Did public agitation, in your opinion, against the dictatorship had no weight?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Did the lawyers' movement played no part?</seg>
     <seg id="7">How would you like to comment on Prime Minister's statement?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Please post your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In his farewell press conference, President Bush said to the newly elected President Barack Obama by the way of advice that he made many mistakes during his reign and Barack Obama should do what he considers right.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I acted as the President according to the circumstances, the American constitution and law. I preferred American interests to my popularity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">He said that America's enemies were planning attacks on America even on that day. Checking these attacks would be the biggest challenge facing Barack Obama.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He said that the biggest disappointment for him was that the weapons of mass destruction were not found in Iraq and his biggest blunder was the declaration of the mission accomplished in Iraq.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Addressing his last press conference in the White House, American President said that this was his last press conference and he thanked all the journalists and others present for gracing the occasion.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you think that Obama will not repeat the mistakes that Bush made?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Has Bush not been late in conceding his mistakes?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Will Obama be able to follow Bush's advice?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Please post your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American Vice President Dick Cheney has said that he wants to see Osama-bin-Laden dead or alive.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He says that Osama is hiding in some tortuous area and has become ineffective for his organization. Even if Osama-bin-Laden is arrested alive or dead, his organization will have to be destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">America is determined to arrest Osama and search for him should continue.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Will Dick Cheney's desire to arrest Osama be fulfilled?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Please post your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All-round cricketer Shahid Afridi had a scuffle with a spectator after the end of first day's play in a Quaid-e-Azam Trophy match between PIA and Habib Bank.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As soon as Shahid Afridi came out of the drawing room after playing the match at the UBL ground, a large number of spectators gathered around him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On one occasion, a spectator requested to have a photograph with him while holding the hand. Shahid Afridi, while pushing him, asked him to get the photograph the next day. But on the insistence of the spectator, Shahid Afridi slapped him in anger. Before they could come to blows, the people helped settle the issue.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After this, Shahid Afridi said that it was being made into an issue needlessly. He was in haste for prayers at that time.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In any case, I shall apologize to the spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What will you comment on this behavior of Shahid Afridi.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Inform us of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has once again accused that Pakistan is trying to incite the atmosphere of war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And Pakistan uses terrorism as state policy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Addressing the conference of the Chief Ministers in New Delhi, Manmohan Singh said that the terrorist elements are backed by the neighboring countries, particularly by Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="4">and the terrorists involved in Mumbai attacks used naval route and remained safe from the Indian coastguards.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Indian Prime Minister said that the Mumbai attacks of November were carried out by Lashkar-e-Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He further said that the terrorists were using new techniques and the latest communication systems. They should increase the intensity at the Line of Control from where incursions take place. He said that terrorism would not be tolerated in any form and that was their policy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">How do you see this accusation of the Indian Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Are India's internal disorder and separatist movements not a reflection of its frustration?</seg>
     <seg id="9">On whose motivation, has India adopted threatening posture?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Inform us of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Israeli air strikes on Gaza are still continuing. Hundreds of Palestinian men, women and children have been martyred so far.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Hamas' key political leader Nazarian has been martyred along with his wife and children.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the other hand, the Security Council meeting ended without reaching a decision.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The resolution of condemnation against Israel tabled by Libya and other Arab countries in the meeting is facing opposition from America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Israeli aerial bombing of the Palestinian civilian population has been continuing for many days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The whole world began to shout at the Mumbai incidents but no one including America and Great Britain have taken notice of this massacre by Israeli attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why are the key countries of the Muslim world silent?</seg>
     <seg id="5">What would you like to say on this dual standard of the world?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Zubair Khan, Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It's a very painful tragedy that Israelis are massacring Palestinians and the same situation exists in Kashmir but the Security Council takes no notice at all.</seg>
     <seg id="8">All the organizations present in Palestine and Kashmir should continue their war till the independence and combat the aggression by standing united. One day their martyrdom will bear fruits by the will of God.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The electricity and gas crisis has assumed critical proportion in the width and breadth of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, the gas prices have been increased on average by 8% from the 1st of January whereas the non-availability of petrol in some cities of the country has been a big worry for the people.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Intense reaction by the industrial and business communities of Pakistan against the lengthy load shedding hours and gas crisis, public disorder and violent protests -have been continuing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The industrialists have served the ultimatum that they would close down the factories.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, the citizens are upset over eight to ten hour load shedding in Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The industrial activity is almost paralyzed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government institutions - have been defending themselves by accusing each other.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are the plans to raise electricity and gas prices not a joke with the public?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Why is the attention not being paid to the solution of the problems?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is the government not seeing the stalling of the national development?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What immediate steps will you propose to control this crisis?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Please post your opinion.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Saeed, New York.</seg>
     <seg id="11">I think the actual reason is that most of our nation is uneducated. They do not know where their money is going. The government is interested in fulfilling its responsibilities by levying taxes. The electricity and gas crisis will remain the same.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Because everyone is aware of the character of those who have been elected by masses.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Imran Khokhar, Madina Munawara. I want to say that the rulers are a reflection of the people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I am surprised that those who raised the slogan of people's government are now hurting the people.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The non-availability of electricity, gas and petrol has become a torment.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government has no control over the institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The law and order situation is getting worse day by day. May God have mercy on this country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The new year has begun.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The previous year was the year of turmoil and political upheavals. It will also be remembered for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="3">President Musharraf's separation from power and the end of President Bush's 8 year's reign, the shoe-flinging at Bush and the establishment of a democratic government in Pakistan, unwarranted catastrophes, earthquake in Baluchistan, financial crisis in the whole world and the recession.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It's the arrival of the new year now. How do you see the coming year?</seg>
     <seg id="5">What in your view will come out of the geo-political situation? What will be Obama's strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is there any hope of some progress towards the end of terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Will the judicial crisis end in Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="8">In what direction will Pak-India relations move?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is there a chance of surgical strikes or a full-scale war?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What are your expectations from the new year?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please post your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370256-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The first death anniversary of Benazir Bhutto Shaheed is being commemorated. She was martyred in Liaqat Bagh of Rawalpindi after an election procession on December 27, 2007.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir is not among us today. She was an intellectual, a politician and a world famous personality. She had a unique status in national politics.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even after one year, the riddle of her assassination could not be solved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Her hard work for the establishment of democracy and the government in Pakistan did not go in vain.</seg>
     <seg id="5">A democratic government is established in Pakistan today and her husband Asif Zardari is the President of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In what light do you view Benazir Bhutto Shaheed's role in Pakistani politics?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Who could have a hand in her assassination?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Recently she was given international award for human rights. What would you like to say about her political and democratic services?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After ruling over America for 8 years, President Bush departed from the White House and settled in the Presidential camp office at Camp David so that the White House could be decorated and prepared according to the wishes of the new President Barack Obama.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During the eight years of Bush's reign as President, the historic attack on World trade Centre and its destruction, attack on Pentagon, and then dragging the military forces of various countries in by launching military action against Afghanistan and Iraq and full use of American resources in this war on the pretext of world war against terrorism became the memorable examples of the Bush era.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because of this war, America itself had to face the worst economic and financial crisis in the history.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What, in your opinion, did the world gain and lose in this war?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Were the policies of President Bush successful?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What is your opinion on the Bush era?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Indian government has stopped Indian cricket team from touring Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Indian cricket team had to play three tests, five One Day matches and one Twenty20 match during its tour to Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Vice President of Indian cricket board Mr. Rajiv Shukla told Geo news that the board had sought permission from the government to tour Pakistan but owing to the recent tense situation between the two countries, the tour was not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Is Indian government's cancellation of the cricket team's tour on the pretext of recent political situation a correct step? Should the sports not be separated from the politics?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is Indian government's decision not harmful to cricket?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Why can Indian team not tour Pakistan while the English cricket team continued its tour of India despite worsening of the security situation?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion about it?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salman, Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Those who are proud of going to India</seg>
     <seg id="3">and star in their films or get their videos filmed there, should now understand how much the Indian people respect them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I remember an interview of Adnan Sami in which he had said that he was not a Pakistani and he had British nationality.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan Sami should come to Pakistan straight away because he could not savor respect in India too.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Farid Ahmad</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The behavior of the Indians has changed after the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jagjit Singh has expressed his reaction by saying that he hates Pakistan and the Pakistanis.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It should be noted that Adnan Sami has sung duets with Asha Bhosle. How come he has become an out of tune singer now? Adnan Sami should live in India. He does not need to come here.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muhammad Shamshad Alam.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi. I would say only this on Jagjit Singh's statement that he changes color like a chameleon.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who gives statements according to the situation. O Pakistanis! Open your eyes and see how much you are respected in India. Understand the mentality of the Hindu.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Their hateful statements are coming at a greater frequency after Mumbai's incident. Now they are uttering bullshit against the famous singer Adnan Sami.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">According to a foreign news agency, the situation became ridiculous during the press conference of the American President Bush, who is on his farewell visit to Iraq, and Prime Minister Nouri-al-Maliki at his Baghdad office when an Iraqi journalist addressed President Bush and said, 'O Dog, this is the farewell kiss'.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After this, the journalist took off one of his shoes and threw it at Bush. President Bush ducked skillfully before the shoe could hit him and saved himself.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The second shoe hit the American flag.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The security personnel dragged the journalist out of the place.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On this occasion, President Bush said that he did not know why he did so. The shoe was of size 10 and he had no problem.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Was, in your opinion, this act of the journalist not a reflection of Iraqi public's show of anger towards President Bush?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What would you say about this incident?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The tension that was created in Pak-India relations after the terrorism incident in Mumbai became severe when the air planes of Indian air force violated the Pakistani air space in Lahore and Kashmir sectors.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Indian planes were forced to retreat by the retaliation from Pakistan air force.</seg>
     <seg id="3">According to the sources, both the Indian planes were equipped with arms and ammunition.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the first incident of its kind during the present tense situation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan air force has said that the air force is fully prepared to defend the country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Information Minister Sherry Rehman has said that the Indian authorities have conceded that the air space was violated but this happened by mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The military sources in Pakistan have termed the incident as serious.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Do you think that India seriously intends to launch an air strike against Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is Indian point of view correct that this happened by mistake or was this aimed at assessing the ability of Pakistan air force?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Will this incident not increase the tension between the two countries?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Inform us of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Benazir Bhutto Shaheed was posthumously given international award for human rights which was received by her son and the chairman of Peoples Party Bilawal Bhutto Zardari.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This award was bestowed upon the former Prime Minister of Pakistan Benazir Bhutto Shaheed in honor of her services to the human rights in a ceremony at the Head Office of the United Nations during the General Assembly session.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The 60th birthday of the human rights resolution was celebrated on December 10 by the United Nations.</seg>
     <seg id="4">On this occasion, the persons and organizations who are being presented these awards in appreciation for their work on human rights include, other than Benazir Bhutto, the former Attorney General of America Louis Ramsey Clark and the international human rights' organization Human Rights Watch.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan's envoy to the United Nations Abdullah Hussein Haroon and other senior Pakistani diplomats were also present on this occasion.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What would you say on receipt of this award by former Prime Minister Benzair Bhutto Shaheed?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Sameer.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Chicago.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is true that she was martyred but we also remember that she killed many innocent people in Karachi. She used to be proud of the fact that Naseerullah Babar had done a great job.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But later, she completely changed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But this is also true that she ignored the senior members of the party and chose her son as the representative of the Peoples Party. What kind of democracy is this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The panel of United Nations' Security Council has included the names of three Pakistani citizens including Hafiz Muhammad Saeed and five organizations including Jama'at-ud-Da'wah in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Pakistanis whose names Al Qaeda and Taliban Sanctions Committee of the Security Council has approved for inclusion in the list of terrorists include the Emir of Jama'at-ud-Da'wah, Hafiz Muhammad Saeed, Operations Chief of the banned Lashkar-e-Taiba Zaki-ur-Rehman Lakhvi, and the head of the finance department Haji Muhammad Ashraf.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Besides, the name of a Saudi citizen Mahmoud Ahmad Bazek is also included in the terrorists list.</seg>
     <seg id="4">the organizations include Jama'at-ud-Da'wah, Paasban-e-Kashmir, Al Rasheed Trust and Al Akhtar Trust International.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The member countries will immediately freeze all the assets of these persons and organizations and they will be barred from traveling and will be arrested.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They will have to face cases.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are these sanctions not an outcome of the Indian propaganda?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why is India accusing these organizations of the Mumbai attacks in absence of any proof?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are there no terrorist organizations in India?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Are the international organizations not aware of the cruelties being meted out to the minorities in India?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Inform us of your opinion.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Jimmy Noor, Karachi. This news has proved a verse of Quran that a infidel will stand by another infidel.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But as long as the blade of an axe isn't connected to a handle, it can't cut a feather.</seg>
     <seg id="10">These are the manners of our rulers. They are adopting furtive manners and this is bringing all these catastrophes onto our country.</seg>
     <seg id="11">May God give sense to our rulers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The festival of Eid is a harbinger of happiness and joy and, following the tradition of Abraham, the monotheists sacrifice animals on Eid-ul-Azha.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In this difficult age, when inflation is at its highest and the political situation is vulnerable, the rich and the poor prepare for Eid to the best of their ability and send Eid greetings to their loved ones in many ways.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We are also giving you a chance through the blog so that you may send your loved ones Eid greetings in the form of brief messages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You can also send greetings in the form of verses suitable for Eid.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Murtaza Jilani.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi. Our rulers should understand that the people they are fighting against are the true patrons of Pakistan. They have been suffering from every act of cruelty but still love Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If a war starts, they will stand by Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When we shall feel their love. Politics of agitation won't yield anything. I think there is the chance of a decisive war between the two sides so that they may give vent to their anger.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>

