<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="mturk">
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Supporting the French proposal</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The meeting of the committee took place in the parliament house under the chairmanship of the committee chairman Mushahid Husain Syed, in which they proposed to the government to send a delegation, with representatives of all political parties apart from humanitarian aid to Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="3">After the meeting, speaking to representatives of the press, Mushahid Husain Syed said that the committee welcomed the proposal given by France, in which it was stated that Israel calls an immediate ceasefire and allow humanitarian work among the affected people of Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Calling the Israeli attacks on Palestine, a crime against humanity, he said that all countries should derogate these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mushahid Husain made the double standards of the countries of the world a target of his attack, and said that why are those who speak against terrorism, quiet about the Israeli attacks on Palestine?</seg>
    <seg id="6">The chairman of the standing committee of external affairs in the senate also targeted the leaders of Muslim nation who were taking a quiet stance on the matter of Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that the committee expressed hope that the newly elected American President, Barack Obama would speak to the Muslim nation, within his first 100 days of his government, to bridge the gulf forming between American and the Muslim nation.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mushahid Husain Syed said that the gap formed between Muslim nation and the West should be filled by taking not only sudden steps but also by solving long standing issues like that of Kashmir and Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The minister of foreign affairs, Malik Imad told the committee that he was going to Saudi Arabia to attend the meeting of the foreign ministers of the governments of Islamic countries.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This sudden meeting was called as a result of Israeli attacks on Palestine. He said that he was aware of the Palestinian matter and at present, the government was in contact with the premiers of other countries.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Minister of foreign affairs said that issue of Palestine should be solved according to the resolutions of the United Nations.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Two reporters from Arab countries also attended the seminar and they told about the current situation about Palestine in the seminar.</seg>
    <seg id="13">There in Islamabad, students of International University, Islamabad protested against the Israel attacks on Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Protesters carried banners and placards, on which slogans against Israel were written.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Avoiding dieting to prevent from flu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This research of American scientists came in front after experimenting on mice.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Experiments proved that mice on a lower calorie diet had comparatively less ability to fight the flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Research disproved the old axiom that " It is better to fast during fever"</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to scientists, eat a lot during fever.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Researchers of the Michigan State University say that mice getting diet food were found to have very less ability to fight the infection and their chances of death also increased. On the other hand, mice getting regular diet had more energy against the flu virus</seg>
    <seg id="7">Professor Elizabeth Gardner said that those who are dieting are not only sooner affected by the flu, but also take longer to recover.</seg>
    <seg id="8">She also said that those who have taken flu vaccines should also avoid dieting for a few months during the winter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">First nuclear test was done in 1990</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Thomas Reid, who worked in the Leur National Laboratory as a weapon designer had written this book with the help of Los Alamos National Laboratory's former Technical Intelligence Director, Danny Staleman.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this book, called 'Nuclear Express', the political history of the bomb and its spread, both the authors claim that whichever country made an atom bomb either stole the nuclear secrets from another country or they got help from a nuclear power.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Thomas Reid said in an interview with US News, that China tested Pakistan's first atom bomb in 1990, during the term of the Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Thomas Reid said that due to many factors, he is certain that China tested Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Among the factors are the design of the bomb, and information he gathered from Chinese scientists.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He further added that that was the reason that Pakistan was able to reply to India's Nuclear test with a nuclear test in just 2 weeks and 3 days.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Thomas Reid reminded that in 1961, Russia suddenly performed a nuclear test, in response to which America took 17 days to preform a test, despite having this bomb for a long time.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He further said that the test of the Atom Bomb which Pakistan conducted on May 28, 1998, was made with extreme care and Pakistani scientists had complete confidence in it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">When Thomas Reeds was questioned that China provided nuclear technology to Pakistan then he said in reply that because India was a common enemy for Pakistan and China.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that there is a proof to this too that Doctor Abdul Qadeer Khan used Chinese design and after this the documents which were acquired from Libia also confirms this statement.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On a one more question that doing combined nuclear tests is common then he said that in 1990 America conducted a nuclear test for Britain on open belt in Nevada desert.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said that we guess that too that Israel was given access to the results of this test.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Thomas Reed was also questioned that Is the Chinese Nuclear spread program is continuing?</seg>
    <seg id="15">On this Thomas Reed said that china has been supplying raw material, instructions and design to nuclear facility in Iran's city Isfahan since 1990.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Other than that china also provided Iran a nuclear enrichment plant.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He said that China has been providing nuclear technology to Iran, Syria, Pakistan, Egypt, Libia and Yemen thorough North Korea.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Year 2008 Best for Madonna</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This show was arranged on the basis of Madonna's 'album Hard Candy' and it also included few songs with Gypsy or Nomadic band of Ukraine and Justin Timberland.</seg>
    <seg id="3">An old racing car was also placed on the stage in the show.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The second successful show of the year 2008 by profit was Celine Dion who earned 236,600,000 dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Canadian show 'Taking Chances' toured 24 countries whereas Madonna went to 17 countries which is her first tour in previous 8 years.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The director for both singers was Jimmy King, who also organized the 'Reunion' tour of 'Spice Girls'.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Madonna has broken her own record of the year 2006.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In 2006 she earned 193,700,000 dollars through 'Confession Concerts'.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Pollster has awarded Bon Jovi as the third  most successful singer who earned 176,000,000 dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bruce Springsteen was on number 3 by earning 166,000,000 dollars and Police get the 5th position by earning 120,600,000 dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="11">According to this periodical in 2008 very few people participated in singing programs and concerts in North America and only those people attended the programs who were ready to buy expensive tickets.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In America a ticket is increased by an average of 8 percent by cost yearly, Most expensive ticket was sold of 300 dollars at Madonna's show.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The editor of Pollster Gary Bongioni said in prospect of  international financial crisis year 2008 proved to be good.</seg>
    <seg id="14">He predicted 2009 a good year for U2 and Springsteen whose albums are about to release.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ban on coeducation: Taliban</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Local Talibans of Gul Bahadur group have distributed a pamphlet in Miran Shah (Capital of Southern Waziristan) and in other Tehsils in which government and semi government coeducational institutes have been threatened.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Pamphlet included that if coeducation institutes are not closed till 5th of January, action will be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Pamphlet said that women are banned to have ID Cards for government aid and for educational purposes and women are prohibited to go to NADRA's Offices in all Tehsils.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The announcement on the ban of women ID Card has been made at the time when almost 200 women have submitted forms in NADRA Offices in Southern Waziristan for Benazir Income Support Program.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to local people the pamphlet issued by Taliban was announced on the loudspeakers of all the Masjids.</seg>
    <seg id="7">However it was not mentioned in the letter that separate educational institute for woman are banned or not.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to Pamphlet after this announcement any woman caught in the school for getting education or in NADRA's Office for having ID Card will be punished religiously along with her family.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Moreover Police of District Bannu says on Sunday a landmine exploded on Miram Shah Bannu Road in result of that a traveler died and one is injured.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Injured has been admitted in Civil Hospital.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">More bodies of target killing received.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police, in the central area of Mengoora, at Green circle, and Sehrab Khan circle, two bodies were found whose bodies were separated from their heads.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is being said that the dead belonged to the frontier core and the police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Eye witnesses say that a letter was also found near the bodies, in which it was warned that whoever lifted these bodies before 11:00 in the day, he will be responsible for his own death.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Local people are saying that the two bodies were left in the marketplace till 11:00after which security officers carried both bodies to the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In the central area of Mengorah as well as other nearby places, a dangerous increase in the number of target killing over the last few weeks has been seen</seg>
    <seg id="7">in which civilians, including women as well as security officers were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to local sources, until now, more than thirty people were killed in such incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="9">No organisation has accepted responsibility for these deaths yet.</seg>
    <seg id="10">On Saturday, the spokesperson for the local Taliban in Swat, Muslim Khan told BBC that among the bodies found on Friday, three belonged to his companions, among which the body of Dewli's Taliban commander Rafi'ullah was also included.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Muslim Khan said that Rafi'ullah was in the custody of the security forces for the last one and a half months.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He said that when the local Taliban kills anyone, first they send a notice to him, and on the other side a lot of confusion about such incidents occurring in Mengorah, is seen among the civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It is the statement of the local people, that heavy posting of security forces is found in Mengorah, but still, there is an increase on attacks on the civilians.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Benazir honored in a song by Bukhtawar</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A rap song (a type of new music), sung in the voice of Bukhtawar is now posted on YouTube.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this 5 minute song, photos and video clips of Benazir are shown.</seg>
    <seg id="4">18 year old Bukhtawar is a student of Edinburgh University.</seg>
    <seg id="5">She has a deep affection for poetry and singing.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is said that apparently she started singing pleasure rhymes upon the encouragement from his mother.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Praising her mother, she said that 'She was intelligent and beautiful, she used to do everything in a certain way'.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Regarding the December 27th incident, she said that she was hit near the cheek by a bullet. She left us at the age of 54, leaving behind three children.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The whole nation is desperate without her. She is present in all their hearts.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bukhtawar is second among Benazir Bhutto's children, to Bilawal Bhutto.</seg>
    <seg id="11">She was always interested in music.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It is being said that before returning to her mother's country, she had asked her journalist friend, in America, to introduce her to Grammy award winning producer and rapper, Puff Diddy, but this meeting could not take place.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The translation of some of Bukhtawar's poetry has been published in some Sindhi newspapers, but her voice is being heard for the first time in a YouTube video.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Some of Benazir Bhutto's party workers and admirers have started making CD's of Bukhtawar's rap song.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other hand, Pakistan Peoples Party spokesperson, Farhatullah Babar confirmed that the song and voice present on YouTube is that of Bukhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="16">He said on phone from Islamabad that this was the salutation of a brave mother by a sad daughter, which even started to play on Pakistan's government TV network.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar said that the party had no present plan to distribute CD's of her song.</seg>
    <seg id="18">He said that a few months ago, a fake page belonging to their party's young chairman, Bilawal Bhutto Zardari was created on Facebook which was later removed.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani: Minister for Media</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The joint minister of media and publishing, Sherry Rehman told BBC Urdu in an SMS message that he sent, confirming Ajmal Qasab's citizenship as a Pakistani, only that more investigations were going on.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Before this, the internal advisor to the Prime Minister, Rahman Malik had denied his Pakistani citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It was his saying that the record keeping offices do not have any record of him.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Regarding this new standpoint, it could not be cleared as to on what basis the Pakistani government changes their stand.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, according to the Foreign Ministry, the confirmation of Ajmal Qasab's citizenship was done by the Home Ministry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">earlier BBC Urdu service and some other newspapers and TV channels have told that Ajmal Qassab belongs to Farid Kot town of the Okara District in Province Punjab.</seg>
    <seg id="8">however the government had been denying it.</seg>
    <seg id="9">it has not yet been established that this Ajmal Qassab does belong to Farid Kot or some other place.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Rocket Fire from Lebanon too, and bombing in response.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Israeli Army and Police officials have informed the press that four rockets were launched from Lebanon on to Israeli land, one of which hit the Northern part of Israel in Naharia, which injured two people.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In response to the rockets launched from Lebanon, Israeli tanks bombed Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It's not certain that this attack was Hezbollah related or if aggravated Palestinian terrorists are behind this.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Lebanese government has said that they are also trying to investigate who is behind these rocket attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The reporters of BBC have declared this an entirely volatile and dangerous situation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the Head of the Middle East sector of BBC, Jeremy Button, these rocket attacks have increased the chances of spreading the war.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Over the past few days, it was been feared that the military operation in Gaza may extend further north, along the Lebanon- Israel border</seg>
    <seg id="9">and there on Wednesday night, the Israeli Air Force conducted sixty air raids on Gaza Strip.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Israeli Army, these attacks targeted Hamas's Police Force's offices, underground tunnels, weapons' caches, rocket launching sites and Hamas's armed personnel.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Apart from air raids, Israel Army's and Navy's artillery continued shelling Gaza during the night.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The Palestinian Authorities said that a mosque was destroyed during the air raids on the Gaza city.</seg>
    <seg id="13">According to unconfirmed reports tanks from Israeli Army, aided by the helicopters from the air, have advanced towards the area of Khan Younus.</seg>
    <seg id="14">During this conflict of now twelve days, around seven hundred of Palestinians, which include a large number of women and children, have died.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Whereas on the other side twelve soldiers from the Israeli Army have also been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Israeli Security Forces have confirmed that a high ranking defense official, Amos Gillad is going to Cairo to settle the terms for seize-fire.</seg>
    <seg id="17">A delegation from Hamas is also going to Cairo to conduct parallel talks with the Egyptian diplomats.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Apart from this, the leader of the Palestinian Authority, Mehmood Abbas, is also reaching Cairo on Friday.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">My heart is broken, return my kidney.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Richard Batista says that eight years ago, he had gifted his wife Dawnell his kidney, to save her life.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to AFP news agency, it is Dr. Batista's statement that his wife has repayed him for his gift by cheating him and having relations with another man, and now she wants divorce.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Dr. Batista said, during an interview to a local newspaper, Daily News, that her love affair has put a hole in my heart that still exists.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Dr. Richard Batista's lawyer, though Dr. Batista is demanding his kidney back, but he actually wants a monetary compensation for the kidney.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He will give his stand about his wife in front of a judge within the next few days.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">140 year old, 9 kilo weighing lobster free</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">'George the Giant Lobster' was captured from the sea two weeks ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Seafood company of the city had purchased it for a hundred Dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It also immediately started to use the pictures of the lobster  for the sake of publicity.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However an animal preservation group, PETA, demanded that they release the lobster, because of which it was released back into the sea.</seg>
    <seg id="6">George was captured from the sea in Canada, after which it stayed in the tank of City Crab and Seafood Company for ten days.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The age of the lobster can be estimated from its weight.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The manager of the restaurant, Keith Valenti said that he did not want to harm the lobster, and he only kept him in the tank for the sake of pleasing his customers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Animal protection organization PETAIngrid Newkirk said that they applaud the decision of the restaurant which serves as an example to those people who want to confine such intriguing animals to tiny tanks or boil them alive.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Girl traced with the help of Mobile.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When officials came to know about Natali Maltrice, firefighters and police force  of Athol city of Massachusetts started the action.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Officials located the exact location of the girl with the help of GPS in her mobile.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However with the help of Google Street View she was found in a hotel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A week earlier Natali's grandmother Rose Maltice took Natali with her from supervision of her legal parents.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The police chief of Athol Timothy Anderson told BBC, she said that now she will never return Natali and then she left the state.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Police Contacted Mrs. Maltice, but when he did not returned Natali despite of promise then police decided to find him with the help of Natali's cell.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Since 2005 it is in the law of America that Mobile companies have to provide location of callers 67 percent of callers at a distance of 100 meters and 95 percent of at 300 meters.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on India's tour</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">It is the 2nd tour of India by Hamid Karzai in last five months.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is hoped that he will discuss the state of affairs after the terrorists attack on Mumbai while in meeting with Prime Minister Manmohan Singh.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this tour he wishes to deliver emotions of Afghanistan and her people and express his unanimity with India.</seg>
    <seg id="5">During this tour of Karzai other then extremism bilateral trade will also be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Bilateral cooperation between the two for countering extremism is also hoped to be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="7">During his last tour of India President Hamid Karzai said that extremism will not be allowed to hinder the relations of the two countries.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He also said that Both India and Afghanistan are facing the challenge of extremism, ruthless and assassination activities.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Peace and solidarity in both the countries is beneficial for the area and the world as well.</seg>
    <seg id="10">We understand the fact that both countries and the whole world unanimously can eliminate the curse of terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="11"></seg>
    <seg id="12"></seg>
    <seg id="13"></seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2"></seg>
    <seg id="3"></seg>
    <seg id="4">Ajmal Qasab is now in police custody, and it is being hoped that the police will file a charge sheet against him before January 24th.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ajmal Qasab does not have any lawyer to defend him.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In a letter written to the Pakistani government, Qasab asked for legal aid.</seg>
    <seg id="7">India has give Pakistan proof of the involvement of Pakistani extremists in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Pakistan has accepted that Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani civilian.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the police case, Ajmal Qasab and his partner Abu Ismail killed 6 police officers including ATS chief Hemant Karkare, Additional Police Commissioner Ashok Kamte and Encounter specialist Police Inspector Vijay Salaskar, after which they fled with their squad car, which was later recovered near DB Marg, Gurgam Choupati.</seg>
    <seg id="10">During police action, Ismail Khan died and the police captured Ajmal alive.</seg>
    <seg id="11">No lawyer was appointed yet, to follow Ajmal's case.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The lawyer chosen by the government, from the legal aid cell, Dinesh Mota refused to accept the case on moral reasons.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Two lawyers pulled out their names after protests and opposition by the people of a political group.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Constitutional Amendment; Committee to be formed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After addressing a seminar on environment change, he told media representatives that for this sake, the parliamentary meeting will take place in which a committee will be formed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that until now, to complete the 17th amendment, the constitutional amendment bill was presented by the Joint National Movement to the National Assembly, whereas other political parties have also presented their constitutional bills in this regard to the parliament.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the Pakistan Peoples Party has also send all the political parties a rough version of the 17th amendment and the committee would analyze their version.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In answer to a question, he said that the parliament would decide the balance of power between the President and the Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Prime Minister said that the Parliament has the complete right to take any decision.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In answer to another question, he said that in getting the former President retired General Pervez Musharraf to leave his post, apart from the role of political parties, the former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Pakistan Peoples Party, Benazir Bhutto also played an important role, by forcing the global brotherhood to remove the uniform of President Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that the elected Vice President of America, Joe Biden was a supporter of Pakistan and democracy, and that the president honored him in return for his services with the Pakistani Crescent.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Replying to a question about the Indian governments warning of breaking all ties with Pakistan, after the Mumbai incident, the Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Geelani said that the leaders are under extreme pressure from the public, which is why they issue such statements.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Protest against the removal of journalists</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Tuesday the organization of journalists, RIUJ held protests in front of the Islamabad Press Club of journalists and newspaper workers against media owners and the government about the news channel and newspapers removing many of their employees.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking to the protesters, senior member of Pakistan's biggest journalist organization, Federal Union of Journalists,  C.R. Shamsi said that the politicians who used to protest with us till yesterday on the streets, today they have become rulers and are sitting in the parliament. Fearing a certain lobby of the media owners, they are not doing anything for the rights of the journalists.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the newspaper owners who speak of human rights have made their offices punishment houses and beggar camps, where despite earning millions of Rupees per year, the workers are given meager wages and by removing hundreds of them, they are killing them economically.</seg>
    <seg id="5">An example of this is in front of us of the worker of a private TV channel, Channel 5, in Lahore, who committed suicide over not getting his salary for four months. And even today, due to being unfairly removed or not getting salaries for months, many workers are leading very difficult lives.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that there should be firm steps taken against the TV and newspaper owners, and the journalists should put a protest camp in front of the parliament to get their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="7">C.R. Shamsi criticized the governor of Punjab, Salman Taseer, saying that employees were removed from his Urdu Newspaper 'Aaj Kal' staff, without prior notice.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wheras Junah daily, Khabrein daily, Channel 5, Burns Plus TV and Aaj TV have removed dozens of workers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Speaking to the protestors, the General Secretary of PUFJ said that today, throughout the country, journalist organizations are observing a black day against the removal of journalists and newspaper workers, whereas journalists will go to the parliamentary session wearing black bands on their arms to get back their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Mazhar Abbas, in 50% of the Pakistani newspapers and TV channels the workers and journalists were being exploited, where they work without any agreement.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that till now, more than 200 journalists and workers have been removed from newspapers and TV channels, while it is being feared that the owners will remove hundreds more in the present year, making an excuse of the present financial crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas said that the journalist movement will continue, until removed employees are not reinstated, the newspaper workers wages fixed by the seventh Wage board award is not enforced, and the salaries for many months payable to TV channels and newspaper workers is not paid.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">11 member cabinet takes oath.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The new cabinet has six ministers from the opposition party of former Prime Minister, Sardar Atheeq Ahmed, the Muslim Conference, two from Pakistan Peoples Party, two from Peoples Muslim League and one minister from the Joint National Movement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The 11 cabinet members include one lady minister, who belongs to the Ateeq opposition Muslim Conference party.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The joint ruler said that the cabinet will be expanded next week, and it is possible that 12 more ministers will be taken into the cabinet. It should be clear that in the beginning of this month, Sardar Ateeq Khan's opposers removed him from the post of Prime Minister by showing lack of trust, and they made Sardar Ya'qoob Khan the new Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The jurisdiction of these ministers will be announced later on.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On the occasion of oath taking, members of the Peoples Party shouted slogans in favor of former Pakistani Prime Minister, Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">3.5 million users affected by virus</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this virus first detected in October 2008 which is known by names such as Configure, Down and up, Kido</seg>
    <seg id="3">Microsoft has come out with a patch to deal with this virus, but still some 3.5 million computers and memory sticks were affected by this virus.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Experts say that number of infected computers could be many.</seg>
    <seg id="5">To settle with this, consumer has to use Microsoft's page 'MS08067'.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Microsoft says that virus which affects thousands of computers, searches for windows file 'services.exe' and adds itself into its code.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After that virus makes itself into a DLL file into system folder of windows.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This virus creates its file name too.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Then changes the details of the registry of windows.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This virus creates a problem after it gets active which comes out as 'HTTP Server' and changes the restore point of the machine.</seg>
    <seg id="11">After that it download files from the hackers website.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Microsoft has to say that this virus has affected computers in different countries.</seg>
    <seg id="13">These countries include China, Brazil, Russia, India, America and Britain.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'The Demand for a Quick Report on Indian Information'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In an interview with the representatives of the media, after a meeting of the Home Ministry, he said that the given by India</seg>
    <seg id="3">information will help in investigation in these regards.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that Pakistan was a sovereign nation and about the investigation on the information received from India, no country's</seg>
    <seg id="5">dictation wuld be accepted.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that apart from the information received from India, they was gathering other information as well.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The internal advisor said that the executive institutions have taken 124 members of practically non-existent groups into custody, solely on the basis of the fear of a reduction in peace.</seg>
    <seg id="8">And if any evidence is found against them, action will be taken against them, while innocent people will be freed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In an answer to a question, he said that no arrested person would be handed over to India, and that action would be taken against such individuals according  to Pakistani law.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that action would be taken against these individuals according to the law of the FIA.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In reply to a question, he said that the law enforcing agencies in India took 42 days to gather information about the guilty people in th Mumbai incident, so we hope that India, along with the global community will give Pakistan some time to verify this information.</seg>
    <seg id="12">They once again repeated the offer of the government to form a joint investigation team for the research of the Mumbai incident.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Let it be known, that a three member investigation team has been formed in the leadership of the Additional Director General of the FIA. The information about the Mumbai attacks given by India</seg>
    <seg id="14">to Pakistan, is being verified by this team.</seg>
    <seg id="15">The High Commissione of Pakistan in India, Shahid Malik, met President Asif Ali Zardari, in which meeting the president made it clear that if any Pakistani group or individual is found guilty in the Mumbai attacks, action will be taaken against them according to the country law, and no one would be handed over to India. This, when the Indian government is continuously pressuring Pakistan to hand over the guilty people to India.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Anything is possible in America'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mister Obama will take the oath on the 20th of January, to become America's 44th President.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Standing on the steps of the memorial built in the remembrance of the 16th American President, Abraham Lincoln, in Washington and giving a speech to the music concert,</seg>
    <seg id="4">mister Obama said that America is facing the most difficult challenges it has faced in many generations, and that he hopes that America can overcome those challenges.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Abraham Lincoln had got rid of the tradition of slavery from India.</seg>
    <seg id="6">At the same time, Mr. Obama said that it will take time to resolve the problems facing the country, and that the path will be trying.</seg>
    <seg id="7">'But despite this, I believe that the dreams of the founders of this country will remain alive'.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Apart from the Iraqi and Afghani wars, America is suffering from a devastating financial crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Extra normal steps are being taken for the oath taking ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Organizers believe that 2 million people will attend the function.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Monday is a national holiday in America, as on that date, the great standard bearer of human rights, Martin Luther King was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Martin Luther King was black.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tribute to Martin Luther King, Devoted to work</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Martin Luther King was assassinated in 1968.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama tributed Dr. King and asked Americans to work with united effort for fulfilling their promises.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In Washington preparations are taking place for the arrangements of unprecedented gathering of people for the new President oath ceremony on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Almost two million people are expected to gather to see this historical President Oath.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama has started Monday by visiting a medical center in Northern Washington where he met wounded American soldiers afterwards he went to a shelter for homeless and painted a wall.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Talking to correspondents Barack Obama said: The current crisis we are having and the problems many people are facing,in this situation we can't sit and relax.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that Martin Luther King has spent his life in serving people.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Barack Obama said that today when we are remembering him, this is not the day to stay and think. It is the day to act.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that Tuesday's ceremony will be held on the same place where thousands of people gathered for Martin Luther King's 'I have a dream' in 1963.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In this speech Martin Luther King said that the day will come when people will not be differentiated on the base of their color.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mathew Price of BBC says that it is the tragedy of history that the day of Martin Luther is 24 hours earlier then the day when first black President of America will sworn in.</seg>
    <seg id="13">For many in southern states of America  the Presidency of Barack Obama, will be the interpretation of Martin Luther King's dream.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">was the additional political agent.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The additional political agent was kidnapped ten days ago from south Waziristan by unidentified masked men.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Sources say that the agent was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer faction of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the local government, around 4 o'clock in the evening, Tuesday, the Additional Political Agent of South Waziristan, Aamir Latheef was brought to Wana Scouts camp, by a group of tribals.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, they did not reveal who had kidnapped the additional political agent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, the locals are saying that the political agent was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer faction of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Aamir Latheef was kidnapped when he was going from Wana to Tank.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On the 11th of January, 2009, seven masked men kidnapped the additional political agent, Aamir Latheef, along with his driver, from the tribal area, Karkandah of South Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the government agent, the kidnappers first disarmed the guards, and after that they seated the additional political agent in another car, and took him away from there.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the local government, after the kidnapping of the additional political agent, security forces guarded all the check posts in South Waziristan and semi-tribal areas, and the people coming and going were searched thoroughly, and from the previous one week, the rulers have placed economic restrictions on Wana.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the 8th of December, 2008, the Assistant Political Agent of North Waziristan was kidnapped when he was going to celebrate the Eid vacation from Meer Ali to Banoo, and a few days later, two people, including District Officer Amanullah were killed by unidentified masked men.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">British Hacker wins in court</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">42 years British citizen has admitted that he had hacked American Army website.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gary is suffering from Asperger syndrome. Keep in mind that the patient of Asperger syndrome has insanity of doing similar tasks.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to his lawyers, it is feared he may attempt suicide if handed over to America .</seg>
    <seg id="5">All government attorneys says that there are very fewer doubts about Gary's health.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Lord Justice Moors and Mr. Justice Simon has said that Gary is permitted to file an application for reconsideration in the British court.</seg>
    <seg id="7"></seg>
    <seg id="8">Further they said that Interior Secretary did not consider this issue.</seg>
    <seg id="9">But government's attorneys says that Interior Secretary had used his powers.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Gary has never denied of hacking American Army website.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Gary hacked American Computer Systems in 2001 and 2002 due to which American Government suffered a loss of 8,00,000 dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Gary hacked 97 systems including American Naval and NASA.</seg>
    <seg id="13">However Gary says that they did not hack with wrong intentions, rather they were looking for the information on aliens which they think were kept secret by American Government.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Gary's mother Jenes Sharp said that she is happy of the decision.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Gary's lawyer said it's a good decision.</seg>
    <seg id="16">This case is in the court since 2002 and at last a correct decision.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Two Hizb commander dead.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The spokesperson of the Northern Command of the Indian Army, posted in Jammu, Lieutenant Colonel Acharya told BBC that "24 National Rifles and Jammu police officers surrounded the parts of the Butty House woods in Gandoh province of Dodah district, in which the militants were supposed to be hiding, according to a confirmed report.</seg>
    <seg id="3">They fired at the army and in the fire back, two armed extremists were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Spokesman said that in the 2 killed extremists is district commander Zahoor-ud-din of prohibited Hizbul Mujahiddins who was active for 12 years in the district and who was expert in gunpowder explosives.</seg>
    <seg id="5">His partner has been identified as Sajjad Hussain who according to Army got connected with extremists from last year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Acharia, operation still continues in mentioned jungle areas because according to them there is more possibility that there are more extremists there. Army says that two rifles are recovered in the first phase of the operation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Yesterday Provincial Head of police Kuldeep Kumar Khudda while issuing statistics for the year 2008 established that this year was the most peaceful year so far.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that there was no violence in the election of assembly held in seven phases in November and December.</seg>
    <seg id="9">More than 1300 candidates participated in this election.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Be it known that Hizbul Mujahiddin is active for the past eighteen years in Jammu-Kashimir.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On 12 July 2000, Hizb for the first time announced one sided cease fire after that there was talk between Government Hind(India) and Hizb Commanders.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Although cease fire ended in just fifteen days.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Afterwards several elite commanders of Hizb-ul-Mujahddins were killed in different operations.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On Thursday, the renowned daily, 'The News' wrote about the extremist groups operating in Pakistan occupied Kashmir, that Lashkar-e-Taiba and Hizbul Mujahideen have decided to revise their Kashmir policy.</seg>
    <seg id="15">It should be clear that the policy of both groups until now, has been that the Kashmir issue could be resolved through armed resistance.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Dera Bugti: Explosion on gas pipe line</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police officials 18 inches diameter pipeline of Loti Gas Field to Pir Koh has been destroyed by explosion.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This pipeline is directed towards Sui Plant.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Moreover pretending himself as the interpreter of banned organization Baloch Republican Army has accepted the responsibility of the explosion on behalf of his organization on phone.</seg>
    <seg id="5">4th pipeline was exploded in four days.</seg>
    <seg id="6">An 18 inch diameter pipeline was destroyed in Dera Allah Yar on Friday whose mending was continued till Sunday morning.</seg>
    <seg id="7">General Manager of Sui Southern Gas Company Mushtaq Siddiqui told in Quetta that this supply line will be restarted after noon.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This pipeline arrives in Quetta via Sibbi.</seg>
    <seg id="9">There is intense scarcity of gas since 3 days in Quetta, Ziarat and suburb areas where on one one hand snowfall is continued and temperature has dropped below freezing point and on the other hand heater and stoves are not working.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Further in the city of Dera Bugti a motorbike exploded in animal market but according to police no casualties.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Administrator for Jamaa'athud Da'wah</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The central headquarters of Jamaa'athud Da'wah is in Taibah, about 25  kilometers from Karachi.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This center includes a hospital, a school and a hostel for students.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The law minister of Punjab, Rana Sanaullah Khan says that supervisors were appointed in the center of Jamaa'athud Da'wah, so that the work of social institutes there goes on unaffected.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Khalid Waleed, son in law of the Jamaa'athud Da'wah chief, Hafiz Saeed, a high ranking government officer, Khaqan Babar, was appointed for the supervision of the hospital, school and other social institutes, based in the center, as the administrator, while according to him, the posting of police at the center was also increased.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Security Council has passed a ban on Jamaa'athud Da'wah, after which the Pakistani government has started taking action against Jamaa'athud Da'wah across the country, and has put the chief of the Jamaa'ath, Hafiz Saeed along with other leaders under house arrest. The appointment of the administrator in the Taibah center by the Punjab government was also a part of the action being taken against Jamaa'athud Da'wah by the joint government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Khaqan Babar belongs to the DMG, i.e. District Management Group.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Hafiz Khalid Waleed said that the Commissioner of Lahore division, Khusroe Pervez Khan along with police and the civil government came on Sunday and inspected the Taibah center. Khalid Waleed spoke ill about the appointment of an administrator, by the government in Jamaa'athud Da'wah, and he said that the number of patients in the hospital and children in the school had already dropped due to government actions.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to a press release by Jama'athu Da'wah, here, the Jama'ath chief, Hafiz Saeed is said to have written a letter to the United Nations General Secretary, Ban Ki Moon, and the Committee on Taliban, appealing to remove the ban on Jama'athud Da'wah, passed by the Security Council.</seg>
    <seg id="10">In the letter, he mentioned that the passing of the ban by the Security Council on Jama'athud Da'wah, was a one-sided and unjust decision, and that Jama'athud Da'wah has no connection with terrorism, and rather is busy in social work.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Aidhi's Gaza humanitarian mission</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After passing many stages involved in getting the permissions required for entering Gaza, he has been successful in reaching Egypt from New York.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking to BBC Urdu service from Cairo, he said that he was not able to reach Gaza yet, as Egypt and Israel have placed many barriers.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said "It has been eight days since I got here, and I have still not got the permission to enter Gaza."</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I am now in Cairo, and hopefully I will be permitted to reach Gaza tomorrow".</seg>
    <seg id="6">Giving details, he said: "At first, I was given a seven day visa to enter Gaza, and later on, upon insisting, the Pakistani officials helped me out and increased it to a one month visa, but on the condition that I would go only once, i.e. it would be a single entry visa.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that he had brought his son and daughters with him, and that they wanted to do some social work.</seg>
    <seg id="8">"I have brought some money".</seg>
    <seg id="9">A one million dollar check has been given to Red cross of Egypt and ten thousand dollar cash is also given in order to send aid to Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">four more ministers in the cabinet, total of sixty three</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">four new federal ministers include two from Mutahida Qaumi Movement and Two from Jamiat Ulamae Islam Fazalur Rehman Group.</seg>
    <seg id="3">president Asif Ali Zardari took oath from the new ministers.</seg>
    <seg id="4">in the oath taking ceremony, the Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani and members of cabinet were also present.</seg>
    <seg id="5">after the inclusion of four new ministers to the federal cabinet, the number of Federal ministers, ministers for state and advisors has reached a total of sixty three.</seg>
    <seg id="6">two minister from MQM include Farooq Sattar and Babar Ghouri whereas ministers from Jamiat Ulamae Islam Fazalur Rehman Group include Azam Swati and Molana Ataur Rehman.</seg>
    <seg id="7">the departments of these ministers have not been announced yet.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Farooq sattar is the convener of MQM whereas Babar Ghouri is a senator from MQM whose term wil expire on tenth March.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Azam Swati was elected as a free senator and is considered to be one of the richest senators.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Moulana Ataur Rahman is a member of the National Assembly and is Moulana Fazlur Rahman's younger brother.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It should be remembered that four important officeholders are not members of the National Assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It should be clear that on 3rd December, 2008 28 new ministers and 18 ministers of state were taken into the cabinet. At that time it was believed that members of the MQM would also be included in the cabinet, but due to a difference in the distribution of ministries, MQM was not included.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Baluchistan, pipeline has been exploded</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police it is an 18 inches of diameter pipeline which runs to Sui Gas Plant from various wells of Pir Koh and it was exploded by some unknown armed persons early in the morning.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Moreover yesterday well number 3 was completely destroyed by explosives and a pipeline was damaged in explosion near Dera Allah Yar.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The responsibility has been accepted by Sarbaz Baluch on behalf of his organization an interpreter of  banned organization of Baluch Liberation Army.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Incidents of terrorism have increased in the beginning of 2009.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In this months dozens of pipelines have been exploded whereas attacks on trains and Punjabis have multiplied.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Chief Minister Baluchistan Nawab Aslam Raeesani has though shown anxiety on these incidents and ordered police to share information with secret agencies but yet these incidents couldn't be stopped.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">819 billion dollars package approved for economic reinstatement</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">No member of Republican Party has voted for this plan of President Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to Republican members this plan is too 'expensive' and will not be effective.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In the House this package 244 votes were casted in favor and 188 against.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The plan of economic reinstatement will be presented in Senate next week where ruling Democratic party has little majority.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is feared that due to the strong opposition from Republican party approval from Senate will not be easy.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After the approval of economic reinstatement plan from the House Barak Obama insisted the members not to hinder political opposition to this important plan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">President said this plan which he is hopeful of becoming a law till next month will help in establishing a favorable atmosphere in which American trade will get better.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to this plan common people and traders will have relief of 75 billion dollars debt and 500 billion will be allocated for renovation of roads, bridges, 10,000 schools, unemployment allowance and for research of new technology.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Washington's correspondent of BBC has said that Barak Obama had resolved to introduce a new political culture by ignoring the political differences but discussion on this economic package has produce bitterness in the politics.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In the House The members of Republican party declared government's proposed bill as wastage of government finances and said that it will not be helpful in creating new opportunities for employment.</seg>
    <seg id="12">They insisted on the bill proposed by their party in which rebate on taxes is focused more.</seg>
    <seg id="13">They said by their package very less investment will be able to generate more employment opportunities.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They said that in place of construction plans, rebate in taxes can produce instant and more employment opportunities.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bitterness between Israeli President and Turkish Prime Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Recep Tayyip Erdogan told the Israeli president, almost screaming, that the blood of many humans were spilled in Gaza, and it saddened him to see that people could watch this armed killing from Israel and clap in agreement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Erdogan said that "I believe that you are using such words to erase your guilty feeling, and outloud, that too. But you killed those people, and I am remembering those children who were killed near the shore."</seg>
    <seg id="4">Simon said that Gaza's calamity is not Israel, but Hamas, who have established a dangerous dictatorship over there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A BBC journalist from Davos said that he had never seen such a scene in an global economic forum before.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, Erdogan later stated that he respected the Israeli president and his age, which is why he did not scream at him, but whatever he was saying was very far from the truth</seg>
    <seg id="7">Turkey is one of the few Islamic countries which have diplomatic relations with Israel, but for the last few years there has been tension between them.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">""Attacks were not planned in Pakistan""</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Wajid Shams ul Hassan while talking to Indian channel 'NDTV' said that the Pakistani investigations report about Mumbai attacks will be released soon.</seg>
    <seg id="3">More than 170 people were killed in last November's Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to India extremist organization Lashkre Taiba is responsible for the attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">India also said that 'state elements' of Pakistan were involved in Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The mutual relations of the two countries are affected.</seg>
    <seg id="7">High Commissioner Wajid Shams ul Hassan delivered his first statement about Pakistani investigations which shows, what could be in the investigations report.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wajid Shams ul Hassan said: As for as the result of investigators, Pakistani soil was not used.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It can be any other place, not also England.</seg>
    <seg id="10">I was worried about these two places(Pakistan and England).</seg>
    <seg id="11">India and International community has pressurized Pakistan to take action against the responsible s of Mumbai attacks. Pakistan says that she has arrested dozens of workers of the groups who are supposed to be involved in Mumbai attacks</seg>
    <seg id="12">Wajid Shams ul Hassan said: We are not trying to hide it.</seg>
    <seg id="13">We believe in taking actions on facts.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Our investigations will be acceptable for the world.</seg>
    <seg id="15">We will try to satisfy India through the results(investigation's).</seg>
    <seg id="16">While defending the delay in the Pakistani investigations he said that the collection, understanding and verification of such a materiel takes time.</seg>
    <seg id="17">High Commissioner Wajid Shams ul Hassan said it took India 5 days to present her dossier.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Black person chosen as Republican leader as well.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the sixth round of elections of the Republican party, Michael Steele,who got 91 votes out of 168, won.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the selection for the post of Chairman, the candidate opposing Steele, Katon Dawson got 77 votes, whereas the ex-Chairman Duncan withdrew from the competition in the second stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Newspaper writers say that among the five candidates who stood for the chairmanship of the Republican Party, Michael Steele was considered the most moderate leader.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After winning, Michael Steele said in his speech, 'We are going to tell our friends and foes together, that you can join with us, but whoever wants to spoil this, they should be ready to be separated from us'. Michael Steele is from Maryland, where he was Deputy Governor.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He rose to fame in 2006, when he stood in the voting for a seat of the senate.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But after losing in the voting for the senate seat, he became the chairman of the Political Conservative Committee of the party.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Now, after being selected the chairman of the party, the country wide projects of the party will be under his supervision.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He fought in the election, promising that he would take the party in a new direction, and that he would use new techniques to join old-fashioned supporters with the party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Indian claim of the presence of Lashkar-e-Taiba and Jaysh-e-Mohammad in Jammu</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">There are reports of the presence of militants in the Ponch province of Jammu</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to government sources, upon receiving secret reports, the police and the army have surrounded the region and have started searching.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this period small fights ensued in which four militants, two soldiers and one police agent were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to sources these fights were going on until the last reports received, and Lashkar-e-Taiba and Jaish-e-Mohammad militants are present in these regions, to fight with whom more army battalions were sent there.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Meanwhile, the chief minister selected by the joint government, Umar Abdullah met the governor and informed him about his being selected the leader of his party, the National Conference in the assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The allied party of the National Conference, the Congress also informed the governor of their support for Umar Abdullah.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Umar Abdullah will be administered the oath as the chief minister of the state tomorrow.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Note that in the recently held state elections, the National Conference got 28 out of the 87 seats of the parliament, coming forth the biggest party. It should be clear that separatist groups boycotted the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Congress, which got 17 seats, was prepared to form a joint government with the National Conference.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Today, upon reaching Srinagar, Umar Abdullah was jubilantly greeted by the party members.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On this occasion, Umar Abdullah said that he would try to play a role in generating dialog between the Indian government and separatists. However, this would not be possible until the elections took place and the new government came to power in India.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The role of European Union for the peace in Middle East</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Officially European Union plays a decisive role in the mediatory efforts taken for stopping the war in Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the official stand of Brussels, Schwarzenberg delegation or efforts of Sarkozy are helping hands in this process.</seg>
    <seg id="4">European Union spokesman Amadeu Altafaj said every single step which may help in delivering the conjoint message of European Union to fighting parties is appreciable.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officially everything seems fine.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But in fact European Union is portraying a picture of internal tension, stress and strain.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The role of Czech Republic as the President of the Union is already weak</seg>
    <seg id="8">plus internal affairs has made her helpless.</seg>
    <seg id="9">On the other hand the course of action of French President Sarkozy depicts that France is still the President of European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Although 6 months Presidency tenure of France is over.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Sarkozy wants to play a leading role which he is capable of, but he isn't the authority.</seg>
    <seg id="12">French Foreign Minister Bernard Kouchner is facing the funniest side.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He is in the delegation which is led by Schwarzenberg the Foreign Minister of Czech Republic.</seg>
    <seg id="14">In addition to that, the two foreign ministers are giving different statements on the war in Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Schwarzenberg says that Israel has the right to defend herself, while according to Kouchner war is not the defense. Germany has also sent a special ambassador to Middle East. As long as European Union does not show unanimous stand, she can not be successful on diplomatic front.</seg>
    <seg id="16">The prove is the no lift conduct of Israel to mediatory efforts of European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="17">This is the best time for European Union to prove herself, as America has failed in Middle East due to the policies of George W. Bush.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Financial crisis: German millionaire industrialist's suicide</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Adolf Marclay, resident of Swabia in south Germany has left behind a huge industrialist group.</seg>
    <seg id="3">But he was not known to German public a while back.</seg>
    <seg id="4">when he had to negotiate with 30 banks for weeks regarding his debts towards industrial groups, he became the hot news and could see the dark future for Marckay group.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Marclay Group had to bear the loss of hundreds of million euros after it bought the shares of one of known industry Folks Wigan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">then the financial institutes rejected to provide the much needed 100 Million and 1 billion euros to this group and this exerted severe pressure on Marclay.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Recently the same banks accepted to provide loan to Marclay group on urgent basis but Adolf Marclay who started as a small industrialist to reach a place where his industrial group's annual income reached 30 billion euros, couldn't bear the the loss in his financial strength.</seg>
    <seg id="8">After the death of his father when Adolf Marclay took the responsibility of the business he used modern methods and made the business more successful.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He named his company Ratiopharm which is now Germany's most successful and biggest pharmaceutical company.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Till recent times this phamasutical company had a budget of around 5 to 6 billion euros and even now it is earning around 8 billion euros annually. After the great success of Rasue farm the Marclay Group bought many big industries like Hi-Del Barag Cement a manufacture of construction equipment. Kassbohrer and other good car maker</seg>
    <seg id="11">Marclay Group has a employee number of around 100 thousand around the world and among its industries, Rasue Farm has always been given special importance.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Adolf Marclay has said this many times in his life. ""We have been in pharma business since four generations"".</seg>
    <seg id="13">Now the industry is handled by the children and i hope that it continues to work for few hundred years by our family.</seg>
    <seg id="14">After the suicide of Adolf Marclay,the banks have given approval of temporary loan of 400 million euro for his group VEM but on this condition that VEM have to be sold to  Rasio Farm so that the financial position of this group is improved on long term basis.</seg>
    <seg id="15">After the death of Adolf Marclay the Marclay Group will not remain the same as it was before.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Crime rate of foreigners living in Germany</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to recent statistics the crime rate of foreigners between 2004 to 2007 .22</seg>
    <seg id="3">9 percent has reduced to .21</seg>
    <seg id="4">4 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Joachim Herrmann the Interior Minister of Bavaria it is only an apparent positive change.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said: It must be considered that foreigners having the German citizenship are increasing.</seg>
    <seg id="7">So it must be added in the statistics that though the criminal is a German citizen but his background is foreigner.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Herrmann said that from 2010 his state will keep this fact in mind while collecting the data of criminals.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Other than Bavaria, Hemberg is also working on same pattern.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Senator Christoph Ahlhaus of Interior ministry from CDU said:"" When the scientific research is conducted one can not draw results of his own rather they depend on the data which is calculated after research.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Ahlhaus presented an analysis report of provincial office of crime management prepared in 2006, according to which in the Bergdorf area of Hemberg the percentage of foreigners in the crimes committed there was calculated.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Results indicate that here foreigners</seg>
    <seg id="13">crime rate is less then the crimes committed in the whole province.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On the contrary during 2006 when youth crime rate in Berlin was observed revealed that the youth having the foreign background was .44</seg>
    <seg id="15">7 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Other political parties of Germany like SPD, clean atmospherics party Greens, and leftist party Linkspartei are against the of gathering information whether the background of a German citizen is foreign while collecting the data about crimes.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">We want quick evacuation of the army from Gaza, Olmert</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Aihud Olmert stressed that for complete evacuation of forces, a proper and stable ceasefire would be necessary.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamas and Israel announced a ceasefire on Sunday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Islamic militant group, Hamas has said, announcing a one week war break, that the Israeli army should evacuate the Gaza strip within one week and stop their guarding of the strip.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On the other side, Hamas leader Ismail Junaih has said that Israel has received victory in the Gaza war from God.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that Israel was unsuccessful in achieving their goals in the Gaza war.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Before that, in Sharm-el-Shaikh in Egypt, on Sunday, the leaders of Arab and European countries had a meeting in which there was a call for immediate evacuation of Israeli army from Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It was decided in the meeting, that soon, an international aid conference for Gaza would be held.</seg>
    <seg id="9">German Chancellor, Angela Merchel was also present in the mentioned meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="10">At least 1300 Palestinians including 10 soldiers as well as 13 Israelis were killed in the three week long war being fought between the Israeli and Hamas soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the other side, Palestinian President, Mahmood Abbas stressed upon an international rule in the Palestinian regions.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Al-Qaida's video message to Germany</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this thirty minute video, a man wearing a black turban, covering his face and holding a gun in his hand addresses the German government.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The same man is introducing himself as the Father of Talha and is talking in German language.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Arabic subtitles are also present in this video message.</seg>
    <seg id="5">There is a log of Al-Qaeda on the side of the screen and video has the date of October 2008.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In this message, it is said to the German Government that is the country expressing their belief that they will not be attacked on after assigning army in a great number in Afghanistan. If this is not innocence, what is it?</seg>
    <seg id="7">This man calling himself "Father of Talha" did not threaten about attack on Germany indirectly.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In Afghanistan, the number of German army soldiers included in the United army NATO is almost 3500 at this time.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In October last year, German Parliament has approved of sending 1000 more soldiers to Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This is the first message received by Germany from Al-Qaeda.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Mikhael Luders, who keeps a close watch on the activities related to terrorism, says in relation to this message :" The suicide bombing outside German consulate recently has proved that we should take it seriously in every condition.</seg>
    <seg id="12">For the last few years, AL-Qaeda has been distributing messages over the internet and there have been attacks after such messages.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The responsibility of suicide bomb attack outside the German Embassy in Kabul has been accepted by the armed organization called Taliban's.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Most of the German magazines were associating these attacks with Al Qaeda.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They are targeting Germany</seg>
    <seg id="16">The fundamentalist Muslims are seeing German Afghan policy as negative and discriminatory.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They are blaming Germany for keeping discriminatory policies not only in Afghanistan but in the Middle East also</seg>
    <seg id="18">And because of this they are considering Germany  their target evenmore.</seg>
    <seg id="19">In the mean time, the German Government says that the German intelligence agencies already knew about this video before it came into the lime light.</seg>
    <seg id="20">The German department for the elimination of crimes is busy in analyzing this video.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama has taken charge of the American presidency.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this perspective, keeping the American people aside, all the world has developed various expectations for Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Now that Barack Obama is receiving congratulatory messages from around the world on becoming president, the expectations from him are also becoming clear.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In these regards, German Chancellor, Angela Merchel also expressed reliance on the new American President.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I believe that the Joint Republic of Germany and the United States of America will be able to get together on the basis of strong relationships and partnership, to solve the problems facing us".</seg>
    <seg id="6">Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin said that Obama seems a serious and open hearted person, and this is definitely something good.</seg>
    <seg id="7">As such, the previous American president's policies were subject to criticism.</seg>
    <seg id="8">However, his government is definitely credited with arousing China into playing a more constructive role on the international level, whereas, with regards to the new president, China has said that he will have to work for strong military ties between the countries.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Expert on Chinese politics, who is active in Bokhum, Germany, Gosuwe Hu, says:</seg>
    <seg id="10">From this viewpoint, I am certain that Obama and his economic team will, within the coming weeks and months, pressurize the Beijing government into pegging the Chinese currency to a stable and market representing exchange rate.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The previous American government also increased ties with India.</seg>
    <seg id="12">About where Obama might take those ties, Professor Christopher Raj, expert on American sciences in New Delhi, says that we are now closer to a strategic partnership, but Obama cannot make any change overnight.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In a message sent to Obama by Pope Benedict, he also stressed upon the need to create an environment of peace and mutual help in the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">State elections in Israel</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This is the first important election in this war ridden country since 2005.</seg>
    <seg id="3">For the state elections, more than 14,400 contestants have entered the arena for 440 seats.</seg>
    <seg id="4">To maintain peace and safety during the elections, 800,000 police and soldiers were posted in Iraq.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Fearing that some bomb blast or terrorist attack might take place on this important day, all the borders of Iraq were sealed one day in advance, i.e. on Friday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Apart from this, the airport was closed and restrictions were placed on public trasnsport.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to reports, due to the restrictions on public transport, there was no traffic on the roads of Baghdad, and children were seen playing football on the roads.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the present Iraqi elections, the security arrangements will tell, on one hand whether or not the local security agencies will be able to take over the country after the return of the American forces from Iraq in 2011, and on the other hand, political analysts are using this as a test as to what extent the public is prepared to bring change to the country in democratic ways.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The state elections are being held with help from the United Nations and almost 800 international supervisors are overlooking the elections.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Today, the Day of Aashura was celebrated throughout Iran in remembrance, respect and honor of the great sacrifice of the chief of all martyrs, Imam Hussain.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to Mehr news agency, All small and large cities including the capital city of Tehran witnessed the celebration of this day in the respect of the chief of martyrs, Imam Husain, with great respect and honor. On this occasion, the believers gathered in great numbers in such honorary gatherings and remembered the deaths of the Holy Prophet (PBUH) and his family members. Today, the whole country of Iran is mourning the great sacrifice of the martyrdom of the Prophet's grandson, Imam Hussain in the battle field of Karbala. The believers are remembering this unmatched sacrifice and attending such large honorary gatherings in its honor.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Retreat of Israeli soldiers from Ajleen province of Gaza, unmatched forbearance of Palestinian soldiers.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Urdu service of Mehr news agency, even on the 16th day of the fight between truth and falsehood in Gaza, there was beastly bombing by the Israel on the city population  of Gaza, by the use of air, land and naval attacks, due to which 880 people have died so far.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Among the martyred are 275 innocent children, who have slept in the lap of death, smiling at the deception of the leaders of Arab countries and of so called human rights organisations.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Today, the always ready to die, Mujahids of Ajeen province have defeated the Israeli army, with the power of faith and martyrdom, and a show of amazing forbearance and steadfastness, tightening the collar of life, around the necks of the Zionist enemies.</seg>
    <seg id="5">If it were not for the deception of Egyptian president, Hasani (not) Mubarak, the brave and loyal Hamas Mujahids would have defeated Israel a long while ago, but apart from the Israeli siege, the Egyptians have also placed Palestinian Muslima under siege, which is the saddest story of Arab history.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Here, the Saudi Arabian and Jordanian governments are giving the Israeli government political and economic support, and are helping Israel by deceiving the helpless Muslims of Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barack Obama: America will use a new policy towards Iran.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report from Mehr news agency, the newly elected president of America, Barack Obama told ABC news channel, in an interview with them, that they would take a new approach towards the Iran dilemma.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama said that Iran would be a very big challenge for the American government</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that they are in a dilemma with regards to Palestinian Islamic organizations Hamas and Hizbullah's support of Iran and Iran's nuclear enrichment program.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But he will not retain the policy of present American president George Bush, with regards to Iran, but would adopt different policies for Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama said that he would make his actual goal completely clear, while stressing on the hope for mutual respect and dialog.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Barack Obama has mentioned in the past that no prerequisites will be set with regards to dialog with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the interview , he expressed the hope that his government would take quick policy decisions on Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Regarding the Middle East crisis, Obama said that he would form a special team</seg>
    <seg id="10">which will start working on establishing peace in the Middle East from the 20th of January.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush, unable and disliked president Bush accepted his mistakes and crimes in his last press statement.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency related from Associated Press that the American president George Bush, in the last press conference of his term, accepted numerous of his mistakes and crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking during the press conference at the White House, President Bush said that though newly elected president Obama has the feelings of well wishing, still, the biggest challenge facing Obama would be to prevent possible attacks on America.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the completion of the Iraq mission and social security reforms were his mistakes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush said that whatever he did, he did it for the sake of protecting America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Upon being asked various questions about the Israeli inflictions on Gaza, President Bush said that Israel has the right to defend itself. According to him, Hamas does not have the right to defend itself and Hamas should not do anything to Israel, and like America, the whole world should choke the oppressed rather than the oppressor.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The incapable and despicable president of the United States said that Hamas should not be given weapons either, while America is providing Israel the worlds most destructive weapons. Israel is using American weapons to massacre Palestinians and Bush also praised the Israel supporting Arabs, calling them the friends of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Bush expressed shame at some of the crimes going on in the Abu Ghraib and Guatenamo jails.</seg>
    <seg id="9">People are opining that cases should be filed against Bush for his war crimes, and that the organisations which manage to do this will have done a great service to humanity.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President of Iran Ahmadinejad has expressed sorrows on the silence of Arab Leaders</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the report of Mehr news agency has said that Iranian President Dr. Mehmood Ahmadinejad has strongly condemned and expressed sorrows on the silence of Arab Leaders on the aggression and cruelties of Israel in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="3">While expressing his amusement about Arab countries and silence of their leaders on the inhuman brutalities of Israel in Gaza President Ahmadinejad has said that Israel is Holocausting the Palestinian people, targeting the Palestinian children, women and civilian people and Arab Leaders didn't even bother to issue a statement.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmede Nejad has called upon all the Arab countries to unite against Israel and to save the oppressed Muslims of Gaza Israel's harm and tyranny.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ahmade Nejad; Saudi King should clarify his stance on the  genocide being done in Gaza by Israel.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the report by MAHAR/MEHR news agency, President Ahmede Nejad in his message to the Saudi King Malik Abdullah declared that the silence on the human genocide in Gaza and muteness on the murder of innocent children and women by  the Muslim King of Saudi Arabia is a reason that  is encouraging of the enemies of Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmede Nejad has said in his message; You should show your true stance on Gaza and declare support for the oppressed, so that the enemy's efforts of planting differences in the Islamic block should fail.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmede Nejad has said in his message; You know that for the last 19 days Israel is bent upon human genocide, murdering innocent children, subjecting homes, mosques, schools and hospitals to barbaric bombing. The Zonist Regime is brutally murdering the unarmed Muslims in Gaza. In situations like these, silence on the part of leaders like you is only encouraging Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Ahmede Nejad has told Malik Abdullah that even non- Muslim countries like Valenzuela and Bolivia have taken concrete steps against Israel and that he is expected to take better steps.</seg>
    <seg id="6">President Ahmede Nejad told the Palestinians that success will be at their feet in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">and Oppressed will win over the oppressors and thats Allah's promise.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090116.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush; Terrorism is still a threat to USA.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">MEHER/MAHAR news agency has copied with reference from the German news agency that the US President while addressing his successor Barak Obama and the nation in his farewell speech, said that though the US is safer than it was seven years ago but the threat of terrorism still looms over USA.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Bush said that the enemy terrorists are waiting patiently to attack America, and they have a strong determination to attack America so America should never be unaware about its security.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The American President ignored the hurts and suffering of the hundreds of thousands of Palestinians in Gaza, and defended his policies saying that America is still the biggest supporter country of independence. However commentators do not accept the reality of the unpopular president's remarks, as America is neither a supporter of freedom, nor a supporter of human rights, but rather it is the most mischievous country in the world, which not only supports a blood thirsty country like Israel, but is also directly involved in its crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Israel, openly kills children, women and civilians and the American president is congratulating them. This is the American humanity and freedom which the world is seeing in Gaza and other places.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Usama Hamdan: Presence of army in Palestine continues</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by Mehr News Agency, the Hamas leader in Lebanon, Usamah Hamdan told French News Agency, during an interview, that the one sided ceasefire from Israels side is against the comprehensive international efforts for a ceasefire. He said that as long as Israel is present in Gaza, a one sided ceasefire is meaningless.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that the one sided ceasefire was an unsuccessful effort of Israel to escape defeat. Hamdan said that if Israel wants long term peace, it will have to accept Hamas's conditions as well as end this siege.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The Hamas leader in Lebanon made it clear that if Israel tries a one sided ceasefire with its army remaining in the Gaza belt, there will be resistance against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Addressing a one way conference from Beirut, the Usamah Hamdan called for the European countries to break ties with Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Hamas leader said that the increasing numbers of the martyred and injured will only increase our determination.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He told the Palestinian public to stay firmly rooted and resist the enemy like a boulder.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan, six men have been killed by Taliban in tribal area of Pakistan North Waziristan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Translation of the second sentence goes here.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to information on Tuesday morning local people discovered 4 dead bodies killed by bullets in Tehsil Chowk of Tehsil Mir Ali.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Whereas two dead bodies were found in capital Miran Shah thrown in a market.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Urdu written letters were also found nearby dead bodies in which the victims were blamed espionage.</seg>
    <seg id="6">2 weeks earlier in Miran Shah capital of North Waziristan 2 Afghan men were killed on the charge of espionage.</seg>
    <seg id="7">15 men have been killed on the charge of spying for America during last 12 days.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Note that during last 6 years more than 100 men have been killed on the charge of espionage in Southern and Northern Waziristan, Taliban are blamed for such murders.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barack Obama is expected to sign the order of closing of notorious Guantanamo be Prison.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the resources of Mother news agency that today American President will sign the order of closing of notorious Guantanamo be Prison.</seg>
    <seg id="3">New American President Barack Hussein Obama has started to fulfill his promises of election campaign.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this regard President Obama has instructed to plan for withdrawal of American Army from Iraq, whereas today American President will sign the order of closing of notorious Guantanamo be Prison.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that President Barack Obama is about to sign an order by which Guantanamo be Prison will be closed within a year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Moreover Wight House is expected to release orders about the revision of investigation procedure for dubious terrorists and ban on using rubbish language with prisoners.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President Barack Obama has started to work from the first day of his presidency on his promises of election band first of all took measures to transparent the deeds and sayings of his government.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Observers say that American President has started the struggle to strengthen the reducing cadre of America on International level but his success rate is very low as till the time America supports the brutal government of Israel nothing good is expected from America. If America wishes to raise his cadre in the world then she must back off from Israel support and must not participate in her crimes.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tony Blair stresses upon the need to include Islamic organization, Hamas in the talks</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr news agency quoted from the Britain newspaper, The Times, that former Prime Minister Tony Blair stressed upon the need to include Hamas in the talks, to bring about peace in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the newspaper, Tony Blair said that it is important that a path be found for bringing Hamas into the Middle East peace process. Blair criticized the Bush administration for speaking only to Mahmood Abbas and ignoring Hamas. It should be clear that the western countries have realized the democratic and organizational powers of Hamas and are calling for bringing them into the talks, whereas previously they used to consider it a terrorist organization. A terrorist organization which is trying to defend its country and struggling to save its own house from the clutches of others. Whose house and country have been in the hand of the occupying Israeli government for 60 years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Assassination of Baloch traders in Karachi, complete strike in Quetta.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Complete strike was observed in Quetta and some other areas against murder of four Baluchi traders in Karachi.</seg>
    <seg id="3">During this all the trade centers remained close traffic was also less then normal.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The protest was called by Baluchistan trades organization, Pakhtunkhah Milli Awami Party AND JUI who blamed that Karachi Police has allegedly killed them  by firing when they reached their car showroom at Tariq Road.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Abdul Rahim Kakar President of Traders Organization has demanded that police officials involved in the incident should be arrested and punished.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However no instant statement of police has arrived.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The killed traders belonged to the city of Chaman.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Government arranged security vastly during strike and police was deployed at all the important places of the city.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Senior Hamas Commander died in Israeli attack</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In an air strike of Israel a senior commander of Hamas has died.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is the death of 2nd Hamas leader in Israel continual attack for a week in Gaza Strip.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The office bearer of Hamas has said that Abu Zakaria Al Jamal died on Saturday in the Al Shujahia street, located in the east of Gaza City.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In another air attack on Thursday,the scholar of Hamas Alam Nazar Rehan was also killed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Hamas expatriate leader living in Syria Khalid Mashal has shown his will to take revenge and warned Israel against ground attack.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Thousands of Israeli soldiers and tanks are located at Gaza Border and they are waiting for the orders to attack.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The Americans have appealed for the cease fire but they have said that the decision to attack Gaza or not will be taken by Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="9">President George Bush in his weekly address on radio has accused Hamas of increasing atrocities in order to aggravate the situation and termed it's Rocket Attacks on Israel as terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He has said that America is working for the cease fire but any one sided pact will not be acceptable.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Three dead bodies recovered in North Waziristan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The officials of Pakistani security forces has said that  dead bodies three men have been recovered from the tribal area of North Waziristan</seg>
    <seg id="3">There is a doubt that Taliban has killed them by giving them death sentences.</seg>
    <seg id="4">These bodies were found near the capital city of north Waziristan, Meeran Shah, and such papers were found on them on which accusations of their spying for America were written.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officials say that perhaps one of these bodies belonged to the local person who was kidnapped last week.</seg>
    <seg id="6">They said that the two remaining bullet ridden bodies belonged to Afghani citizens.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Israeli attacks continue for a tenth day, in Gaza.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Palestinian children injured in Israeli missile attacks. All along the Gaza belt, the Israeli army is fighting against Hamas soldiers, while the Israeli air force is attacking suspected residences of the militant groups, for the tenth continuous day, in the region.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Israeli defense minister Yahud Barak, said on Monday, that the attacks will continue as long as the people of south Israel are not safe from Hamas rocket firing.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, despite Israeli attacks, the rocket firing from Hamas's side has continued, due to which four people, including three civilians have died.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hamas leader Mahmood Zuhr pressured his companions on Monday, to destroy the Israeli army and target Israeli civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, Hamas leaders say that the organization is planning to send a delegation to Egypt, on Monday, to think over the new developments.</seg>
    <seg id="7">A wounded women in Gaza. Medical sources say that over the last ten days, about 530 people have died, including the 11 people who died on Monday, of which 5 were children.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Israel has reported the death of one soldier and the injury of 30 others in land attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Israel has stopped other-national journalists from entering Gaza, for investigating military action.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Elected Vice President of America Joseph Biden reaches Pakistan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Foreign Minister received the elected Vice President of America</seg>
    <seg id="3">America's Vice President Joseph Biden has reached Islamabad on his visit to Pakistan on Friday with his delegation.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Foreign Minister Shah Mehmood Qureshi and high ups of American Embassy received them.</seg>
    <seg id="5">American Senator Lindsy Graham is also accompanying Biden.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Press Officer of American Embassy Lew Fenter told Voice of America, during his tour newly elected President will discuss several regional affairs with Pakistani Leadership, however he refused to disclose further details.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to Foreign Office Joseph Biden will also meet Army Chief General Ashfaq Pervez Kiani along with high ups of government.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is hoped that in these meetings beside important bilateral and International issues war against terrorism will also be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Joseph Biden has been awarded the Hilal e Pakistan</seg>
    <seg id="10">After reaching Islamabad Joseph Biden met President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In meeting President awarded him the Hilal e Pakistan medal for playing his role in the establishment of closer ties between America and Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It should be noted that Joseph Biden as the Chairman of Committee for foreign relations of American Senate with collaboration of Senator Richard Lugar introduced a bill which proposed a 3 times increase making it 5.7 billion dollars civilian aid for next five years to Pakistan.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Joe Biden played an important role in removing Musharraf's uniform, Prime Minister Geelani.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Yusuf Riza Geelani and Joe Biden (File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Prime Miniter, Yusuf Riza Geelani said that the American newly elected Vice President played an important role in removing former President Pervez Musharraf from the position of Army Chief, and that Joe Biden helped Democracy in Pakistan considerably.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Yusuf Raza Geelani gave this statement, speaking to journalists in the Karachi shipyard.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He said that Joseph Biden was a Pro-Pakistan leader and as chairman of the committee for foreign relations of the American Senate, he passed a bill for aiding Pakistan with 15 Billion dollars</seg>
    <seg id="6">About the missile attacks by American spy planes within Pakistani boundaries, the Pakistani Prime Minister once more derogated them saying that there is no agreement with the American government about allowing such attacks as according to him, it was a matter of Pakistani sovereignty and hence by no means could they give permission for such attacks within their territory.</seg>
    <seg id="7">he also expressed a hope that after the succession of the new American government, change will come to the American policy as well.</seg>
    <seg id="8">(File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="9">Yusuf Raza Gilani has said that the government has successfully separated taliban from ordinary tribesmen but the drone attacks have proven to be very harmful to the efforts of the government and the terrorists once again join hands with the local tribes.</seg>
    <seg id="10">he said that the international community agrees to this stance of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Prime Minister added that if reliable evidence is provided, then the Pakistani Forces will operate itself in its own territory.</seg>
    <seg id="12">prime minister yusuf Raza Gilani repeated his stance over Mumbai attacks and said that if India provides evidence, then investigation will be carried out on its basis and if there is any proof of someone's involvement, he will be dealt according to the laws of the country.</seg>
    <seg id="13">while answering a question about Rehman Malik's tour to Britain and his meeting with the MQM leader Altaf Hussain, the Prime Minister said that Rehman Malik went to London on his approval.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Quetta, four policemen including DSP killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">File Photo</seg>
    <seg id="3">on an important highway of Quetta, Saryab road, firing by unknown people killed four policemen including DSP 'Deputy Superintendent of Police".</seg>
    <seg id="4">On Monday morning, a jeep carrying two DSP's one Sub Inspector and two constables was traveling towards the police training center when two people sitting on a motorcycle near the degree college on Siryaab road started firing at them without any provocation, resulting in the death of Sub Inspector Mehdi, Constable Sibghatullah and Nasrullah died on the spot, while DSP Hasan Ali died upon reaching the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hospital sources say that the other injured DSP Ghulam Muhammad's situation is also critical, and he has been shot in the neck and the head.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After the incident, the police have surrounded the area, but as of yet, no one has accepted responsibility for the incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The death of another Indian software engineer in America</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Another software engineer belonging to Andhra Pradesh has been shot and killed by unknown attackers.</seg>
    <seg id="3">26 year old Akshay Vishal of Secunderanadwas shot two days ago by unidentified assailants in the state of Arkansas. Vishal died in the hospital while undergoing treatment two days later.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was an employee of Satyam Computers and was providing services for Falcon Jet Airways in America.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In the last one year, seven students from Andhra Pradesh have been killed by American anti-social elements.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The rise in the deaths of those going to America for higher studies and employment from the state has increased the worries of the thousands of families whose children are in America.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It should be known that America is preferred in Andhra Pradesh for higher studies and brighter futures.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the numbers and statistics in the American consulate in Chennai, a hundred thousand applications are received for visa every year, of which the most, i.e. 40%, is from Andhra Pradesh.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Meanwhile, the state government tried to bring the murdered person's body to Hyderabad.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">America must remain vigilant against enemy attacks: Bush</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">President George Bush insisted America to be vigilant against enemy attacks in his last weekly speech from radio.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr.Bush said the biggest threat for America is the possibility of any other terrorist attack. He warned that enemies of the state are waiting patiently and they are targeted to attack again.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Discharging President said that America must never be negligent of her defense.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush conveyed best wishes for upcoming President Barack Obama, who will sworn in on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Newly elected President Barack Obama threw light from the platform of Democratic party on the historical importance of Oath ceremony in his speech on weekly radio.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that the ceremony is such a tradition in which the peaceful transfer of powers is deeply tied to American greatness.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mr. Obama reminded that many people even can't imagine that their leaders will quit the authority without struggle or bloodshed.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Meeting of the Sherif brothers and the joint home minister in Raiwand; exchange of thoughts on political and security matters.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The biggest and ruling party of the deferring parties, Pakistan Muslim Leagues (n)'s leader Nawaz Sherif and Pakistan's home minister Rehman Malik met on Sunday in Raiwand in which meeting, Punjabi Chief Minister Shehbaz Sherif was also present.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the local media, Rehman Malik probably got an important message from the Pakistan Peoples Party leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, speaking to journalists after the meeting, Rehman Malik did not disclose anything of the nature and only said that they talked about agreement politics and that he briefed the PML(n) leadership about the conditions after the Mumbai attack.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words 'I let them know about the action taken so far'.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It should not be forgotten that a lot of action was taken by the Punjab government and that the team that I formed will need the help of the Punjab government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Rehman Malik said that every day the media is not told, but PML (n) leadership is sent messages. Here the Pakistan Muslim League (n) spokesperson Pervez Rasheed also spoke, but avoided speaking about some political matters, and said that Rehman Malik has already said what needs to be told.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be known that Pakistan Muslim League (n)'s leadership met the Internal Advisor at a time when the state was in a state of hot political activity with 20 or more leaders belonging to the opposition party, PML (q), held a press conference with the Governor of Punjab, Salman Taseer, rejecting the steps of the government in the state and opposing the inclusion of the Governor of Punjab, who is from the Pakistan Peoples Party in this matter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama's speech is glad tidings for Pakistan, President Zardari.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani president, Asif Ali Zardari welcomed the opening speech of the new President of America Barack Obama, saying that his statement that he would advance the relationship with the Muslim world, based on mutual interests and mutual respect, is a good news for Pakistan and it's public.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In a statement given on Wednesday, he said that the high ideals and values which the American President has promised to uphold gives the people worldwide hope of a new life.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the statement, President Zardari said that the responsibility of joining the global brotherhood and searching for roads to peace, development and prosperity, in the 21st century falls, no doubt, on the shoulders of America.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Let it be clear that President Obama said on Tuesday, after taking the oath, in his opening speech, that America wants a new approach towards the Muslim world, based on mutual interests and mutual respect.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He ascertained the people of poor countries that America will work with them to let there be cultural development over there, and to reduce poverty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Obama has appointed a special representative for Afghanistan and Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Richard Holbrook, ex ambassador for UN Richard Holbrook has been appointed as special representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Holbrook had played an important role in the signing of peace agreement of Bosnia Herzegovina.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Holbrook said that he is ready for the consultancy of President Obama for Afghanistan and Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He added that it is not an easy job.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the history of both the countries is different.</seg>
    <seg id="7">George Mitchell has been selected for Middle East who will try to improve the peace talks between Arabs and Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mitchell is ex senator and he played a key role for the establishment of peace in Northern Ireland.</seg>
    <seg id="9">While speaking in State Department Mitchell said that the situation of Middle East is very dangerous, complex and unpredictable.</seg>
    <seg id="10">But even though America will not step back from the attempts of establishment of peace.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghanistan: Voter registration in danger.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Afghanistan Election Commission has said that due to a doubt in safety, it is delaying the voter registration in some of the southern regions.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The voter registration for the upcoming presidential elections had started this week in South Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">But the commission has declared that as long as the security conditions do not improve, the voters in some parts of Halmand state will not be able to register themselves.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Extremism has been on the rise in those regions of the south, where Taliban rebels have increased attacks on Afghani and international governments.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In the meanwhile, the Afghani army and the international armies are claiming that during the night between Wednesday and Thursday, during small fights, they killed at least 28 soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="7">NATO said that its armies had killed 22 soldiers in land and air strikes in the Western province of Khost, near the Pakistani border.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Previously, the Afghan Defense Ministry had said that the Afghan army had killed eight rebels and injured two in the same province.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is not clear whether the Afghani officeholders are talking about the same incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090123.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Two missile attacks in Waziristan, at least 18 killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistan Intelligence officials have said that in two doubtful American missile attacks in North Waziristan, at least 18 people were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the officials, unmanned planes dropped three missiles on a house in Mir province of north Waziristan, due to which ten people in that house died.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to local officials, five of the dead were non-national soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This region is considered the center of the Taliban and Al-Qaidah soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="6">A few hours after this incident, a missile attack was performed on south Waziristan as well, in which at least eight people died.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Despite the objections of the Pakistani government, since mid-last year until now, about 30 missile attacks were done in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The present attacks were the first attacks since President Barack Obama took office.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The Bush government was avoiding to take acceptance for or deny the attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="10">On Friday, suspected American spy planes dropped three missiles in the tribal region of North Waziristan. Until now, five people have died.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The dead could not be identified.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to initial reports the missile attacks were on a house, in the locality of Mir Ali.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It should be known that these are the first missile attacks on the tribal regions of Pakistan, since Barack Obama became president.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">In the state of Sarhad, the officials have rejected the demand of putting a restriction on girls education.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the state of Sarhad, the officials have rejected the warning to put a restriction on girls education, by the Taliban soldiers, saying that this announcement is against both law and Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On Sunday, the education minister of Sarhad state, Sardar Husain Babar added that the government will never allow such efforts to succeed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that it is the effort of the extremists that the children of our region remain deprived of education.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words: "These people try to secretly blow up schools and frighten the boys and girls"</seg>
    <seg id="6">Talking about the environment of fear and insecurity, he said that the local government knows well and wants it to be known that no force can stop the spread of education in the land of the Pukhtons.</seg>
    <seg id="7">One day ago, the Taliban soldiers, led by Moulana Fazlullah had demanded the banning of girls from studying in Swat's educational institutions from the 15th of January.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Despite the military activity going on in Swat, during the last one and a half years, about 150 educational institutions were destroyed by the militants by the use of explosives and arson.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Due to the destruction of these educational institutions, thousands of girls and boys were deprived of the facility of education.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Strict security arrangements in India on Republic Day.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The 60th Republic Day is being celebrated in India on Monday. On this occasion, strict security measures are being taken and thousands of soldiers were posted throughout the country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On the occcasion of Republic Day, during the army parade in New Delhi, weapons, planes and other military equipment is displayed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Officials are saying that the security arrangements include anti aircraft missiles and sharpshooters and that police will be deployed to watch the roads of the parade. American President Barack Obama congratulated India on the occasion.</seg>
    <seg id="5">And he also wished Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, who had undergone a heart operation on Saturday, a speedy recovery.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It should be remembered that yesterday the Indian police claimed to have killed two suspected Pakistani militants after a shootout in the outskirts of Mew Delhi.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Local officials say that the police recovered AK 47 rifles, granades and some documents from them which proved that they were from Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Police are also investigating whether these two belonged to Pakistani debarred organization, Lashkar-e-Taiba, which was found guilty in the Mumbai attacks carried out in Bombay, November of last year.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tea: an effective cure for breast cancer</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a new research, three cups of tea a day,</seg>
    <seg id="3">if taken, can decrease the risk of cancer in women below 50 years of age, by more than a third.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In a research carried out by the Moffitt Cancer Institute, in the American state of Florida, it was revealed that the risk of occurrence of breast cancer tumors, in such women below the age of 50 years</seg>
    <seg id="5">who drink at least three cups of tea a day, is reduced by up to 37%.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It was also revealed in the research that there was no significant benefit, in these regards, in the woman aged above 50, who drank three or more cups of tea a day.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Experts believe that the reason for this is that tea has such ingredients in it, which are more effective against specific tumors which generally occur in women below the age of 50.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In Moffitt Cancer Center, in the city of Tampa, Florida state, a research was conducted on over 5000 women, who had undergone treatment for breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Their ages were between 20 and 74 years.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Experts compared their medical records and lifestyles with women who were safe from breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The experts also found out that on a specific type of cancer called lobular cancer, the drinking of tea has shown clear effects, and has decreased its occurrence by 66 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="12">A tenth of every breast cancer patient suffers this type of cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="13">This type of cancer is more dangerous because it is deeper and is usually only known after it spreads quite a bit.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Experts say that regular tea consumption, at least three cups a day, can drastically reduce the occurrence of breast cancer in young women.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They say that making tea a regular beverage taken on a daily basis and included in ones daily activities causes the suitable defense required against cancer in the body.</seg>
    <seg id="16">In Britain, every year, approximately 40,000 women are diagnosed with breast cancer.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The biggest military challenge facing the American war in Afghanistan is gas.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">American Defence Minister Robert Gates has said that the biggest  Military challenge to America is  the war in Afghanistan</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gates is today giving a briefing to American Senate and representatives of the Congress on the Obama Administrations policy on Afghanistan and Iraq wars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Gates told the Armed Services Senate Committee that the war is not the only solution to Afghan problem but he further said that in order to make many areas secure, Army Personal are not available,taking the advantage of it the Taliban carry out actions.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Why reduction in exercise with increase in the age</seg>
     <seg id="2">New Research</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="3">Exercise is good for health in every age</seg>
    <seg id="4">This keeps the heart healthy,reduces the level of cholesterol,Helps in keeping the weight low, helps in reduction of sugar and reduces Alzheimer meaning decreases the speed of dementia.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Unfortunately, in many people with the increase in the age, the capability to carryout exercise also decreases.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The specialists say that with exercise our body and brain remain active but age can have effect on it.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The American Medical Association says that Many health problems can occur if exercise is not carried out.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Dr. Patricia Palecca of Mayo Clinic, Minnesota says that an increase in age is a major cause of inability to excercise and lack of bodily activity.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Dr. Patricia teaches medicine at Mayo Clinic.</seg>
    <seg id="10">She lead a study of how heart related diseases and the ability to exercise is related to old age.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The team of doctors used high frequency sound waves to measure the working of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In which the pumping of the blood by the heart, its contraction and relaxation was studied.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The experts focussed on the left part of the heart which is the main part for pumping blood.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They learnt that as people grew old, there was an increase in faults in the relaxation of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Dr. Patricia says that as age increases, the faults in the relaxation of the heart begin to appear, and this affects the ability to exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Dr. Garwin  Cain was also a part of this study.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He says that we were surprised to see that there is a definite effect of this. And this clearly proves how deep a relation the worsening of exercise has with the relaxation of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Sometimes blood pressure can cause faults in the working of the heart and can become a cause of heart diseases.</seg>
    <seg id="19">If the doctor and the patient work together on the faults of the heart, they can achieve the benefits of excercise, despite the increase in age.</seg>
    <seg id="20">A detailed report of this has been published in the magazine of the American Medical Association.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">No chances of instant war with Pakistan: Indian Army Chief</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Indian Army Chief General Deepak Kapoor says that no chances of instant war with Pakistan, however for the defense of country and to assure the security of her interests we are always vigilant.</seg>
    <seg id="3">General Kapoor blamed that despite of sureties and International pressure in result of Mumbai attacks, in his words, terrorism network is not only present in Pakistan but is also active.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said this in Srinagar while talking to correspondents.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Indian Army Chief was on a day's tour of Kashmir for the analysis of preparations of armed forces on borders and of complete defense situation in New Delhi administered Kashmir.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He was asked that according to media reports Pakistan has refused the proves of Mumbai attacks presented by India, what is his opinion in this regard?</seg>
    <seg id="7">General Kapoor said that decisions of war or peace affairs  are managed by political leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Talking about the alleged terrorism network in Pakistan he said that Indian Army will have to face the forces which are objected to destroy peace and weaken India.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He said that 700 to 800 militants are present in Indian Kashmir almost half of them are foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="10">General Deepak Kapoor said with the betterment of weather attempts of slander may increase from Pakistan and her side of Kashmir, however India has increased vigilance on borders.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He refused the chances of reducing the number of deployed army in Indian administered Kashmir by saying that no compromise on country security.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah bless the tongues of the world and may Barack become a blessing for the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Though it was not expected, still we shall see how this change  will work out in our favor with regards to Pak-American relations.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And what Barack Obama, who is the result of Martin Luther Kings dreams, gives to the world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Obama's (whose name has Hussein also), oath as a President of America on one hand is historical while on the other hand is a hard test too</seg>
     <seg id="2">not only for him but for all those people who has supported him heartily.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This will also be a test for white people majority as it is not easy for them to accept heartily the presidency of black on them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here in Southern Asia specially Muslims who have developed expectation from him must remember that he has been elected as President of America and Obama must remember that President of America is Practically the president of the whole world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A little while from then, a person whose real brothers were brought to America from their own countries, wearing the neckband of slavery,and whose blood and sweat watered the roots of the strongest country of the new era, today the a representative of that very same targeted lineage will be called the 44th President.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have many expectations from this man.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is necessary for those who admire him that they do not make unrealistic expectations about him.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If Obama is even successful in somewhat reducing the hate that is spread on lineage and religion based lines, it will be a victory for his admirers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What effect will this change have on South Asia, and what considerable change can be expected in the American policy in this regards?</seg>
     <seg id="2">How will these changes affect Pakistani-American relations?</seg>
     <seg id="3">?</seg>
     <seg id="4">My Sir, whether it be Obama or someone else, the type of policies with regards to the whole world is decided by the multi-billionaire, influential, strong Jewish lobby.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As for Pakistan, with regards to the recent Mumbai blasts, the injurious actions taken by India, Israel and America has been seen by the whole world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the creation of Pakistan, the administration of Swat remained with the Ruler of Swat, who had a regular Army and Law.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He handed over administration of Swat to Pakistan under a  pact</seg>
     <seg id="3">but it is matter of sorrow that our government treated Swat like a step mother.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There was no increase in the number of schools after the end of the government of the ruler of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">and no interest was taken in the building and development works</seg>
     <seg id="6">The girls who are getting education today are much lesser in number than  those who used to get educated in the previous era.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Frontier Province, there is a continuous targeting of educational institutions by Taliban's.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The maximum number of schools have been destroyed in district Swat in which majority are the girls schools.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is not just this, the Taliban has imposed a ban on girl education.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thousands of male and female students have been deprived from getting education.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you think Talibans wants to achieve by stopping women education.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Why the government has failed to stop these illegal actions?</seg>
     <seg id="7">In your opinion what government should do.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Question must be this that what ISI and Pakistani Agencies will get.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Because Swat people has understand the game that army is there to serve Taliban not to kill them otherwise how five schools can be destroyed in a single night during curfew, how people can be butchered and hanged in the square.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When government writ is unable to implement in Swat in these circumstances how the government will succeed in eliminating these illegal activities.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now the question is when government has every thing like armed force, latest weapons, latest technology and spy system then why these Taliban can;t be controlled?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The only answer is that they are supported by some unseen power that neither their weapons finish nor they get caught.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The essence is that these Taliban are paving the path for 'International Imperialism' by their bad deeds.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">15 years ago, the war was on in Afghanistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">ISI is controlling Taliban when at that time opponent was north coalition who was supported by Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Then suddenly situation changed, actions of Taliban began to appear.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And ISI was also offered Dollars from America so past friends became enemies.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now situation is this that war continues but helping in Pakistan are still those Iran, India and Russia.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Unless this feeling does not emerge in Human that what is right and wrong till then Human will keep doing mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As an example a thief when goes to steal if he at that time gets this thought that stealing is not a good thing and theft is a curse, there is also punishment in it and he fears from God then that Human will not steal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Same like this that unless Israel do not gets this apprehension that i am doing wrong and draining blood of innocents and i will get punishment for this, he will keep playing Holi with the blood innocents of Gaza till then.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Respects!</seg>
     <seg id="2">Question is that is war, armed movement, terrorism is solution to problems?</seg>
     <seg id="3">If not then what is the specific prescription which takes to the solution of the problems?</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is true that war and extremism do not solve problems, but rather it puts 'blessings' in them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Palestine, Afghanistan and Iraq should adopt the same model for their development, that Nelson Mandela had used in South Africa.</seg>
     <seg id="6">That is, to struggle character wise and politically, more than in an armed manner.</seg>
     <seg id="7">From the Kashmiris taking part in the elections, it looks as if they have accepted this view point.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the third week of Israeli attacks on Gaza and the number of deaths have gone close to a thousand.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Despite worldwide diplomatic efforts, to date, a ceasefire was not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">According to another report, since the start of attacks, on the 27th of December, 90,000 Palestinians have left their homes and moved towards safer locations.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here, aid groups have accused Israel of being careless about Palestinian children, and said that a whole generation of Palestinian children will be victim of grave psychological and emotional difficulties.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What should happen?</seg>
     <seg id="7">How is permanent peace possible in Gaza?</seg>
     <seg id="8">For details, click here.</seg>
     <seg id="9">(Please note that due to the increase in the discussions, comments typed in Urdu will be only published.</seg>
     <seg id="10">For this press alt+shift on the On-Screen board and select Urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Give Taliban a Chance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Basit, Peshawar</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wake up! If Taliban starts the real Jihad, who will slaughter innocent people?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Who will burn down girls schools?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And kidnapping for ransom and if they do not get the ransom money, who will hang people on poles by claiming they were American spies?</seg>
     <seg id="6">These Taliban has damaged Islam so much that no other nation or religion has done.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pushtun force</seg>
     <seg id="8">Kohat, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If the whole Islamic world just threat Israel for launch of attack you will see that in how much pain father of Israel America will be in</seg>
     <seg id="2">and not only talks about real ceasefire rather ceasefire will be accomplished.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But what to do our Muslim leaders lack the courage greatly.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Some one ask Ahmadinejad to take the initiative because your bravery is very popular in BBC Forum.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The responsibility of establishing peace and human rights falls not only upon the Arabs, or the Muslims of the world, but rather it is the duty of all the nations in the world that they speak up against oppression.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This troubling incident is one of the worst misdeeds of Bush yet.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Similar to how, in Pakistan and India, on the 30th of June, that is before the close of the financial year, the government institutions are looted, in the same way, before the winding up of the American government, Israel was given the green signal to do whatever it wants.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">On one hand, America says that it will try for a ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other side, the United Nation is passing one resolution over another but both have done nothing practically, this means that united nation is also working  to crush the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the Islamic Countries should cancel their membership of United Nations and they should lay the foundation of there own international organisation.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Many examples are in front of us, where only promises and resolutions of America and United Nations came forward but only the Muslims suffered.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What is the advantage of these actions when BBC does not have to print anything.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, where have the principles of general ism been buried,When the unrequired blood especially of the Muslims starts flowing, at that time the ghost of unbiased reporting starts riding over the BBC.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise portrays itself as flag bearer of righteousness.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Saying something from their side is a far away thing, they do not want even comments</seg>
     <seg id="5">from the Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The difference between you and Jews is that they call themselves Jews and Martyr the Muslims and people like you live among Muslims, by calling themselves Muslims, to Muslims</seg>
     <seg id="2">[syja786]</seg>
     <seg id="3">For a while, BBC forums have been making a certain point, sometimes while discussing suicide attacks and other times, terrorism in India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The most used word in these anti-Islamic comments is extremism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But, who is extremist, that you can easily figure out from the above comment.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When will our Muslims understand that Dajjal can not be fought with the sword?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Looking at the helpless people facing the Israel bombings, if the heart does not cry tears of blood what coes it do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the most basic mistake behind this destruction and killing is that we try to use the name of Jihad to disfigure the beautiful face of Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When majority of the Palestinians have accepted the existece of Israel, then what need does Hamas have to send rockets into Israel or conduct suicide attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The conduct of both sides is misanthropist.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The action of the United Nations and the United States seem to be supporting the Israeli wrongdoings.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah allow the Muslim nation to unite. Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As a matter of fact,think about giving Noble Prise to terrorists for carrying out this painful terrorist activity, as a campaign against terrorism, eventually the actual work is being done by them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise, is it possible to carryout terrorist activity on such a massive scale without the assistance of Chiefs and  every one knows who are pulling their strings.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In such a situation it can be termed as high handedness "Do what ever you can".</seg>
     <seg id="5">The strong mans fist,it beats over the head and do not let one cry.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Arab rulers are giving medicines for the injured,Funeral clothing's for the dead and money and they are asking</seg>
     <seg id="2">should the Israelis continue attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The actual problem is that the rulers of Islamic countries including Saudi Arabia are dreaming undutiful while asleep,Neither they have army nor they have defence plans,they just think that by providing aid they have done their duty.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They should immediately take practical steps against the Israel</seg>
     <seg id="5">like cutting of oil supply to European countries and America, but sorry for them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Regards to all brothers and sisters</seg>
     <seg id="2">I believe that in this time of difficulty, telling Hamas to stop their struggle for the sake of peace is an injustice to thousands of widows and hundreds of thousands orphans, and it is similar to considering them defeated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If Israel and its supporters are at the height of their Pharoahism, soon Moses will be born within their house, as this is the rule of nature, as the steps taken by America and Israel have acted like a fertilizer in growing suicide bombers among the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Which these power intoxicated elephants are not realizing.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Abu Abdullah, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Israel and Hamas should enter a truce so that the death and destruction can come to an end.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Mohammad Sarfaraz, Paris, France</seg>
     <seg id="3">Absolutely correctly stated</seg>
     <seg id="4">Supposing that Hamas is 100% on the truth, and they are struggling against oppression, to become successful in the eyes of Allah. Even then, they should know that if a good deed is resulting in the destruction of an established house, it is no more a good deed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Those who claim to love God, love the messenger and love their religion, loving mankind is a part of their faith.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As if it is the order of Allah to evacuate all the people of the Book from the face of the earth, other than the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeebur Rahman Syco, Lahore</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, not to kill them, but rather the order is to invite them to Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But those people who plan against the religion, there is the order to perform Jihad against them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">To fight them until they stop their plans, but this does definitely not mean that you wear a jacket and blow up in a crowd.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Brothers, the end result of killing innocent children is destruction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But I would like to tell my friends that yesterday the Israelis did not have any place for shelter, but today they have become so strong that they do not listen to anyone. This is because the Jews are one.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They do not have Shia, Sunni. They are all just Jews, and they have made everything for development.</seg>
     <seg id="4">On the other hand, what is the state of the 55 Islamic countries?</seg>
     <seg id="5">They are behind in every field, and now the situation is that they have become so helpless that the enemy is killing them and they are waiting to die.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The need is for all the Muslim countries to get togetherand prepare an action plan against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Feroz Magsi, Jhang, Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">And there is no better action plan than this, to accept Israel and to learn modern science and developmental ways from it, and allow the world to live in peace and calm.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Muslims have a lot of land and resources.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The need is for proper utilisation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First, the part that hurts the most is that there could not be unity between Hamas and Al-Fath.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Great leader like Yasir Arafat and Sheikh Yasin were systematically killed to weaken the brave nation of the only region which is still fighting for Masjid Aqsa, and this was not possible as long as Yasin and Arafat were in the way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The world is watching how Palestine is getting scattered, second by second, after the death of these two leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And how the Jewish lobby is increasing its reach, second by second.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In 1974 a Pakistani Prime Minister was of such an International trust that first time in history he united all the Muslim leaders under one roof with 100 percent attendance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today on his 81st birthday is it hard enough for the nation to promise for unity with each other</seg>
     <seg id="3">but by eliminating the differences between other Muslims will accomplish its (establishment of Islamic Common Wealth) incomplete mission.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a Jinn, which has entered Palestine for half a century.</seg>
     <seg id="2">That Jinn has many mouths.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Many a times, this Jinn calls itself bad names from one of its other mouths to divert the attention and reduce the pressure of the world from it.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is another mouth of this Jinn whichis eating people in Iraq, Afghanistan, Iran and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This Jinn fears Islam the most, as it knows that whenever it is removed, only Islam, Mulsims and the complete religion of Islam being followed practically, in its followers can remove it, as history proves that Islam has brought many Abu Jahls to the path.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The series of bombings of Gaza by Israeli war planes and missile strikes has been going on since the 27th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="2">More than three hundred Israeli citizens have died so far in these attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now, after the air strikes, Israeli tanks have reached the Gaza border, completely prepared to launch a land offensive.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Security Council of the United Nations, through an agreed upon resolution passed in an emergency meeting, have demanded that Israeli and Palestinian authorities stop extremist activities immediately.</seg>
     <seg id="5">However, Israeli officials claim that they will continue their action in Gaza until they are convinced that Israel will be safe from rocket attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In your opinion, is the statement by Israel, that this is an Israeli struggle for safety, acceptable?</seg>
     <seg id="7">In this situation, is the global brotherhood doing its job?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Can this inhumane action have a direct relation with the upcoming elections in Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Can there be any expectation of improvement in the Middle East situation, after newly elected president Barack Obama takes office?</seg>
     <seg id="10">(Please note that due to an increase in the number of comments, only comments typed in Urdu will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="11">For this, hit Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard and select Urdu.)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Palestine is a holy land for the Muslims, all over the world, and protecting it is a necessary duty for us.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We should also remember that it was our first Qiblah.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And Israel, America and India have to disappear one day, as they are made only to be destroyed, and Allah will definitely destroy the disbelievers. Sajid Sadiq, Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="4">"When has the night of loneliness been spent shedding tears,</seg>
     <seg id="5">When has a calamity been averted only by supplication" (Nawab Zadah Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Such reviews are anxiously telecasted by BBC.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After all the image and prestige of neutralism has to be kept.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Though BBC news are often true but the real thing is the delivery.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What to highlight and which news is given less importance.</seg>
     <seg id="5">etc. etc.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="7">Now In this regard our Pakistani print and electronic media, specially few Urdu newspapers and columnists etc. are not behind in the trade who in the coverage or writing of increasing terrorism exaggerate to hell.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">He said that the United Nations which speaks of human rights and peace, but though the Muslims ar being oppressed greatly, you hear them say that until Hamas does not stop it's attacks, this unfair policy will continue.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why is so much oppression being done on the Muslims? If people such as America stop supporting these Jews, then Allah has declared that they will live the life of a disgraced people, and such people can never lead a proper life. So if the Americans have courage, let them stop their support, and then see what kind of life they get.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The famous just people of the world and those that kill people in the name of peace should understand that peace will only be prevalent through administering justice, and not by being unjust and killing people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If any tribe could be finished by killing their people, and if the required results could be obtained, then after Hitler's steps, not only the presence but the rise that the Jews are enjoying today, could not have been possible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the words of a poet</seg>
     <seg id="4">Oppression is oppression, that the more it's done the more it is erased.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Blood is blood, that the more it falls, the more it gathers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now who can tell who did terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Is all this not included in terrorism? Why does everybody worry only about their own pain?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are others not human? Or is it that the blood of Muslims has become so cheap? Was the blood of this many innocent not red?</seg>
     <seg id="4">And why is there no one to send a mourning message from anywhere?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I watched the progress of the Mumbai incident, as if my own house was on fire. The sorrow of humans can not be watched, and who can not see this sorrow? If only Muslims would think a bit, together.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">How can words derogate the bodies strewn on the streets, helpless innocent faced people, injured and soaked in blood?</seg>
     <seg id="2">I feel like crying about the helplessness of Muslims, that on one side, people are dying in India, and the whole world is climbing onto Pakistan, without any proof and saying, take action or else we will.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And on the other side, Israel is ruthlessly killing Muslims and the whole world is silent. This is unbearable.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is delay, but no darkness, with God. That too, when this darkness comes to pass.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Danger to Israel, with America present, is a joke.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As for elections, there is no doubt, to gain public support, such actions will have to be taken for the sake of power, especially in a state like Israel. As for Barack Obama, history is witness that no American ruler has been able to go against the American policy and nor will they go. Whether the ruler is white or black, he is still a ruler.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It appears from the conversation of forum that everyone is grieved over Benazir death but as politician her mistakes are not forgotten.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is debatable that Benazir died for democracy or for power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If she sacrificed for democracy then why she left democracy in the dictatorship of Musharraf for 10 years till she got a deal and American clearance?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir did not return Pakistan when dictatorship affected people needed her she returned Pakistan when she has the assurances of free from cases and of power.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">No one is going to say anything about the way that this historical figure is being falsely accused.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Sana Khan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Some things are ignored because nothing can be done about them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">One more writer.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir/Madam, maybe if you read not only the history of Pakistan, but of it's neighboring four countries, or of seven other countries, then you might understand the meaning of Mr. Psycho.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tariq Abbas</seg>
     <seg id="7">One whose nature is wrong cannot be taught.</seg>
     <seg id="8">For reflection in water is not always clear.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Britain never let them become one, and invented the hindu-muslim friction which was taken ahead by sir Syed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Psycho</seg>
     <seg id="3">How merciless is our nation. We are blind when writing in favor of ourselves and our party but now when every historical intellectual is being blamed and critiqued, no one is saying a word.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We have succeeded a lot!</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="6">Some things are ignored thinking that nothing can be done about them. Just like a donkey does not become a scholar if you en wreathe him with books.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Although the ongoing talks between Pakistan and India were interrupted after the Bombay attacks but Pakistan and India should continue these meetings.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If they talk about war then both the sides will suffer human loss.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India says that Pakistani citizen is caught in Bombay attacks. And he has written and sent a letter in Urdu to Pakistan. But earlier, when India caught this extremist, said that he is a smart engineer but later they declared him to have studied only four grades. This is what has to be considered.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First of all, merry Christmas to Mr. Bhana and  all christian friends of the forum.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Friends of the forum: Greetings Mr. Psycho, A. Raza, Sister Sana, Sister Shahida Akram and all.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We want flowers of peace rather in the flame of war.</seg>
     <seg id="4">War is itself a problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What solution will the war give?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Today will give Fire and blood.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Tomorrow will give hunger and necessity.</seg>
     <seg id="8">For this wise people</seg>
     <seg id="9">it is better that war keeps postponing.</seg>
     <seg id="10">In your and our garden</seg>
     <seg id="11">it is better that candle keeps lit.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The relationship of India America have become deep and India knows that when the time comes America will openly deceive Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is that old history of America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because in the case of an Indian attack, America's goals will also be fulfilled and the expenses will be India's.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan should clearly announce that it will not start, but if injury is caused, there will be no talks of peace or truce, and the war will not stop until India is completely destroyed or captured, even if it involves our destroying ourselves.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is Islamic history.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Before this resolution Pakistani people and army has delivered their message.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Indian struggle for having unusual diplomatic and military benefits in compensation of Mumbai attacks are proving her cunning party then affected. Therefore the world has reduced its pressure on Pakistan contrasting to its initial hard reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="3">UN has expressed faith on Pakistani efforts ignoring the unnecessary lamentation of India and Interpol's appreciation of Pakistani efforts is the 'side effect' of unwanted Indian diplomacy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no two opinions about this being a very beastly action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But the question is, that when thousands of Taliban were attacking Pir Samiullah's town, where was the Pakistani Army, and what were they doing?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Should the army not be taken into account, as to what they did there for one year?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Every day, how many Taliban die due to the firing of the thousands of mortar and canon shells they fire?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I appeal to the ICI that they stop their guardianship of the Taliban, for Gods sake, and let us live peacefully in paradise like Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And they stop this fixed operation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The day is not far when in UN resolution of Army intrusion in Pakistan will be approved just like the one against Jamat Aldawa.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Riaz Ahmed Farooqi</seg>
     <seg id="3">First our extremists and their supporters are continuously providing proves and reasons for the action against them and God forbid, the day when such a resolution is submitted then it is very much possible that no body will favor us in UN,</seg>
     <seg id="4">and suppose if this resolution took time to approve then considering the example of America any country will launch the attack at her own.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We do not know about the personality and works of Pir Samiullah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Perhaps he was not a revolutionist.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As the bodies of Comrade Che Guevara, Nawab Akbar Khan Bagti, Dr. Najibullah and thousands of other revolutionists were dishonored at the hands of the enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are immortal even after they die.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But there is a international game being played here in which place public is ruled by frightening through barbarism and ferociousness.</seg>
     <seg id="6">So that license can be created that if we are not here than these ferocious and barbaric will clutch the government.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These acts of so called Islamic activists on the name of religion is without limit worthy of condemnation.</seg>
     <seg id="2">These supporters of extremists can see the injustice of America but instead of expressing grieve on those dishonest acts they clearly shun them by giving them name of tribal traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Sometimes by cloaking in tribal traditions, sometimes on the name of Islam, any pious man cannot give reason for such dishonest acts.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my view, our Army people are associated with theses people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As such that when these people move from a place then it takes such time that they can be caught, there should be time for that but its a stretch that they get there on time even if they are there, they are long gone.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are they so merciless that they kidnap fifty seventy men and our Army putting hand on hand looks at them like a spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are servant of Allah and  so is Army.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is clear that something is sinister.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malaiyat. In the dictator of the age, Ziya-ul-Haqq's dictatorship, instead of presenting the Noble and Merciful characters of God, an atmosphere of religio-phobia was created by the use of many types of narrations of punishments and incidents apart from the incident of the body hanging. Even the literature and books like 'what will happen when we die?' created fear and terror.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And these people are only using this fear as a tool or a weapon to gain worldly pleasures and honor.</seg>
     <seg id="3">preachers!</seg>
     <seg id="4">As you have preached against the fire of Hell</seg>
     <seg id="5">that you have yourself become the face of fear.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is surprising when it is said that this can not be a work of a Muslim</seg>
     <seg id="2">We are either unaware of our own history, or we ignore it for some reason.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Upon the death of the Prophet, upon refusing to pledge alliegance, who burnt the door of the daughter of the Messenger and pulled her husband out with a rope around his neck?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Had they come from somewhere outside?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Was the attack on Medina by the the Army of Yazid and and the incident of Karbala was the conspiracy of Jews and Pagans?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Without accepting the facts, neither motives can be removed nor these can be corrected?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC people, stop this dual policy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The better super hit title than this is:  the beating  of Bush with shoes is right or wrong?</seg>
     <seg id="3">this should have been the topic.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Tahir Chowdary, Japan</seg>
     <seg id="5">Be ashamed, the body of a person was taken out of the grave and hanged on a pole because he spoke against the cruelty and you are struck up over the topic of Box Office.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The success of operation Sherdil and across the border the success of operation Lion Heart depends on the direction of sympathies of common folk.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This step is of American and Pakistani intelligence agencies and Pir Sahib is the victim of this conspiracy</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the comments on this forum would be against the Taliban because intelligence agents have successfully infiltrated in the Taliban ranks and they are carrying out such actions that can change their perception of people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I only want to ask that when this body was hanging for a whole day, what was the army doing? Are they only there for targeting the public. They even report something like this 'Bombing on Taliban residences, a shell falling on a house kills two children and their mother'.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Did they not know about this mistake?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Or were they watching the show?</seg>
     <seg id="4">We fold our hands and request them to please, for God's sake, stop this game.</seg>
     <seg id="5">After all, there is a ruler above you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Whether the question asked by BBC is understandable or not, it is saddening to see the lack of perspective of the writer. For instance, no one asked what the army of 30,000, in Swat went there to do.</seg>
     <seg id="2">That the bodies of the Taliban who helps the army is left hanging on poles throughout the day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Whatever the green footed Pakistani government did with the Swat public, the media, including BBC did not do good by keeping the world ignorant about the reality.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Pakistani Army is putting up a drama.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Every child in Swat is saying that this is a bloody drama.</seg>
     <seg id="6">For God's sake stop this drama.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These Talibans have tarnished the Muslim image.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If in the whole world true Muslims don't call these terrorists as Muslims then how come these elements are able to live in the lands of true Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Those who become shameless, can't do hard labor they pick up guns and become the members of terrorist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Islam did not spread on the point of a sword or barrel of a gun.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Feel the shame.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no allowance of this in any religion or family traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Including BBC all the media present their views in different styles on Taliban or the tribal people.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But no one is aware of the ground realities or what the truth is. It is us the tribal people who know what rally is the matter.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In short, its a game in which CIA, RAW, MOSAD and our own ISI are invloved. No one is a talib or a tribal. Who made these institutions? Warmongers who are against Islam, Taliban, Madrassa's, Pushtoon people, tribes and tribal traditions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The heads of Muslims have hung from shame over this action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I salute the leader of MQM, Althaf Husain, and the leaderships of ANP and PPP, as they have spoken against this cancer, i.e. the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This cancer was given birth to by Zia-ul-Haqq. He has gone, but he has destroyed Pakistan as he went.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But I have hope that the present government will eradicate this cancer.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After Mumbai attacks India said that few extremist groups are involved in these attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan denied these blames and said that she will fully cooperate in the investigation.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India said that she has provided Pakistan a list of 20 extremists, who are wanted to India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Noe Pakistan said that leader of Jaish e Muhammad Maulana Masud Azhar present in this list is not detained and Government of Pakistan has no information about him.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Before this President Asif Ali Zardari has denied the impression that Western Secret Agencies and Indian Government have provided Pakistan the proves of Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">President Zardari said about Ajmal Qasab that it is not yet proven that he is Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="7">During this Prime Minister Manmohan Singh warned Pakistan that Indian relation with her can't get better till the time her soil is used for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="8">And in recent updates Indian Cricket team has canceled its tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should these political incidents affect sports?</seg>
     <seg id="10">How do you see the future of Pakistan and India relations?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Neither America nor India will break Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan will break itself.</seg>
     <seg id="3">With so much regionalism, factionism and infiltration, what else can you expect?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Time has proved that Jinnah did not do good to the Indian Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Yasmin, Chicago</seg>
     <seg id="6">Madam, if work was continued in Jinnah's manner, neither would the tumors of regionalism, factionism and infiltration have spread in Pakistan, nor would the Indian Muslims been treated in this way.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It's our fault that after him, no other leader could stand in his shoes.</seg>
     <seg id="8">But if we can't appreciate our heroes, then....</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This sector does have a lot of abilities.</seg>
     <seg id="2">God knows when they will come to their senses and use the blessing of unity to make some progress.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Both countries have priests, Shiv sena, RSS etc. that constantly oppose peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And these negative forces do not want the sector to make any progress, hence the countries are kept on their toes.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can you imagine the status of this place in the world for Pakistan, India and China, with just a little bit of unity?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Pakistan is cursed by God for having robbers and thieves as their appointed leaders.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">may Allah protect our country from any harm, Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">but Sir, open your eyes to see the surrounding situation and ground reality, you will figure out how far American forces have penetrated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Other than that National matter are not looking good as well, circumstances in Sarhad, Balochistan, Karachi in Sindh are in front of you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In this situation country needs a such leader who can unite us as a single Nation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">O Allah Have mercy on us</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion there is no way other than a last war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Enough much has happened</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now this affair has to win or lose.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This problem will not solve with hypocrisy deceit.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And neither with small big terrorism in each other countries.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Even Europe too came to rest after fighting the last great war.</seg>
     <seg id="7">And if this Great war had not happened then they all would be chattering like Pakistan and India.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Almost all our political parties agree that terrorism and factionalism should be finished.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But our military leadership does not seem to be sincere in these regards. On the one hand, America and Europe are ascertained that we are with them in their war against terrorism, and on the other hand we secretly help the Taiban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We should think and fix our direction and choose only one way. Thanks.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no doubt that majority of the workers of Jama'athud Da'wah are the previous members of Lashkar-e-Taiba who joint the group called Jama'athud Da'wah Pakistan, after Lashkar-e-Taiba was rendered inexistent.</seg>
     <seg id="2">However, after that, the members gave preference to social work, and now even Jama'athud Da'wah was rendered inexistent by the United Nations, due to the pressure applied by India and the crackdown being enforced by the Pakistani government.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I believe that if Jihadi groups leave religious fundamentalism and take up social efforts, that would be better.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The present terrorist groups that bring up criminals in the name of Jihad, and the elders of these Mullas, are the same people who used to call 'Pakistan' 'Palidistan', and who knows what else.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now they are not leaving any stone unturned in destroying Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Actually, these are not even fit to be called human beings, let alone 'Muslims'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Without cleaning Pakistan of these mischief mongers, the national security will remain at risk.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can we still think about whether or not to put a ban on these mischief mongers?</seg>
     <seg id="6">There is no place on earth for extremist Mullahs whose only work is to cause killings.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Heart is breaking into pieces on this news.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What world is this where it is hard to survive for the one who names an important part of Allah's religion Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Non Muslims can kill Muslim, but if Muslim even tries to take revenge then along with the whole non Muslim world our hypocrite leaders also treat the ones sincere with true and sincere religion like they are treating our great leader Hafiz Saeed now a days.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As a penalty of Mumbai attacks India.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan relations are affected, and the recent improvement of relations between two countries is enormously shocked.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India has been continually blaming active armed and unarmed groups in Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="4">and is linking the establishment of normal relations with the action against these groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whereas Indian Security agencies has directly blamed Lashkr e Taiba for Mumbai attacks</seg>
     <seg id="6">, in this regard Jamat Adawa has also been nominated.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is not the first time that because of any terrorist attack the relation of these two countries are worsen.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In December 2000 after the attacks on Indian Parliament both countries were at the brink of war.</seg>
     <seg id="9">After that, in 2002 Lashkr e Taiba was banned and was included in terrorists list.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Now Jamat Adawa, to whom security analysts is a fresh disguise of Lashkr e Taiba, is demanded to be banned.</seg>
     <seg id="11">What do you think, should this group be banned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Should Pakistan take decisive action against active extremist groups on her soil?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Can by banning Jamat Adawa present India,</seg>
     <seg id="14">Pakistan crisis will vanish and to what extent it is vital to ban armed groups for establishing forever peace between the two countries.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Security Council of the United Nations has passed the ban on Jama'athud Da'wah. However, what proof did the Security Council have based on which it showed such urgency.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Does the Security Council always show this type of urgency against the Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is what they call a slow complainant and a fast witness.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If you look at it, even India has become an unsuccessful state.</seg>
     <seg id="5">whose intelligence, army and security institutes failed, and were forced to dance at the fingertips of a few terrorists for 72 hours. And India wants to put the blame for its inability on Pakistan, to fool the whole world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When one disbeliever dies, there is hue and cry in the whole world. Why these double standards?</seg>
     <seg id="2">To a non political, religious and social organisation of our dear country---</seg>
     <seg id="3">Furqan Farooq, Faisalabad</seg>
     <seg id="4">As long as our Prophet (PBUH), the Awliya Kiram and the Sufis continued to teach people the lesson of love and respect, the religion of Islam would spread and prosper with peace.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Muslims have also advanced in every field.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But when there was a rise of Mullaism in the religion, there was a division of people into Muslims and Kafirs, and new avenues of mischief were opened, which were not known to the world previously.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salute, sir, salute happily, but get your work done on your own.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Do not do it under the pressure from America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If India is in difficulty, let them prove it, no?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why does it not give?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And why do they accuse us with everything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">There are fundamentalist groups and organisations, even in India. Why does no one put any restrictions on them?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are we the only terrorist in the whole world?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What is it that India is doing in Kashmir?</seg>
     <seg id="9">What is it that Israel is doing?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The truth is that we are the first Islamic Nuclear State. Why, is what the fight is about.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is now in the last stages.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Kamran Hassan, ABU DHABI</seg>
     <seg id="3">Your talk touches the heart and circumstances also seems to be such</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now American magazines are very boldly printing the new map of Pakistan and all these sanctions seems to be the part of this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">American are not slowly but now very swiftly tightening there grip over Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">We must remember that in these circumstances,if we as a nation does not display unity and solidarity then if Bangladesh can be created,anything else can also happen.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">More the terrorism is condemned lessor it is , whether it is in a Hotel at Mumbai or it is in Marriott Hotel Islamabad or it is in Palestine.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Like wise irrespective of the origin of the terrorist, these should be eliminated, no matter these are Pakistanis or Indian or American or Israelite.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now the question is that why the whole world including the Pakistani officials are silent on the terrorist attacks that are conducted daily in Pakistan, resulting in the death of hundreds of people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Was the attack carried out on Marriott Hotel was not a terrorist attack?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Then why?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Praise the worthy Advisor interior,Mister Rehman Malik,by the grace of God, how brave he has become!</seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">Not only this , according to the BBC Mister Malik has also tried to negate this impression with full strength that all these imprisonments are being carried out on whose orders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Praise the lord!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Having this capability or not, this I don't want to say.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whose war we Pakistanis are fighting</seg>
     <seg id="3">and why. We have our own priorities which we shall protect with our full strength.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Nobody has an authority to interfere in any other country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Apparently colonial period does not seem to exist.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If people expect justice, or demand that an external united court be established, respect democratic institutions, and not help any dictator or army man, there will be peace in the third world, including Pakistan, which I think is not acceptable by those calling for unity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As such, Pakistan is always following the goals set by Europe and America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This happens, despite the opposition of a majority of the Pakistani population.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And this causes more opposing feelings.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If they trust America and the United republics, then let them leave the style of new populations, and let them work on those lines, upholding the sovereignty of the state.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan has the ability to arm and disarm.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Security forces raid an alleged camp of banned Lashkr e Taiba in Pakistan administered Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pressure is being increased on Pakistan for taking rapid action against extremist organizations after Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India blames Lashkr e Taiba for Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
     <seg id="5">She says that no doubt the extremists responsible for Mumbai attacks used Pakistani soil.</seg>
     <seg id="6">During this Peshawar Government says that unknown armed persons has set another truck stand for supply of goods to Allied Forces deployed in Afghanistan on fire, due to which more then fifty vehicles are destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is the second attack on Neto and American supplies during 48 hours in Peshawar.</seg>
     <seg id="8">During this Pakistan raid an alleged camp of banned Lashkr e Taiba and before this struggles has been made to unarm the armed groups from Karachi to Tribal areas including rewards on returning of the weapons and assurance of taking no action.</seg>
     <seg id="9">It is revealed that during the reign of General Zia ul Huq because of the invasion of the ex USSR in Afghanistan and its resistance started by the American and Saudi funding resulted in the birth of armed groups of which Pakistan unable to terminated could not get back herself to the era before 1980s.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The question is does Pakistan want to do it?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Is Pakistan capable of doing this?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What do you think?</seg>
     <seg id="13">For details click here</seg>
     <seg id="14">(Kindly note that due to the increase in reviews, Urdu typed reviews will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="15">For this press alt+shift and select Urdu on onscreen keyboard)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I have only one question for the standard bearers of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If you kill their children, will they come to garland you? It is impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4">And I ask you, does any science, from Islamic sciences to the sciences of the East and the West, any logic or philosophy, anywhere, give the permission to kill innocent public, including worshipers, laborers, and poor workers, in revenge for the American attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">If your answer is in negative, then you really need to fix your viewpoint.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Peoples were armed at that time it was feared that after Afghanistan, Russia will attack Pakistan so people were armed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now when there is the danger of American attack via Afghanistan of which current American President clearly expressed in his presidential campaign then why should we disarm these people?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Only for this that after defeating Pakistani Army America or India may not face any public resistance?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Yes, if any of them is involved in sabotage activities then only Pakistan should take action against him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">But it is sad that the fact that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved proves India's claim that Pakistan is guilty in this.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeebur Rahman Syco, Lahore</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even if we accept that Lashkar-e-Taiba is guilty, it is still not correct to blame the Pakistani government.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And another question is that were these terrorists not supported by an Indian governmental or non-governmental agent?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are terrorists only born or prepared in Pakistan, and not in any other country of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post63" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As for as Lashkr e Taiba is concerned ongoing terrorism is not linked to it.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It must be recalled that Hafiz Saeed was the first 'Militant Leader' who declared activities of Taliban 'revolt'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I am quite sure that Taliban agitation is a vital part of American plans so every person or organization must be eliminated who challenges Taliban in any aspect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Despite the cooperation of the whole nation action against Lashkr due to the pressure of India indicates the nervousness and flatterness of Zardari and Co.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To terminate the expedition started by the American and Saudi funding, they should be requested to clean up the mess which is poisoning our society.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Also protest them that by what ethics American and Saudis are spreaded dangerous arms and so called Jihadi but in fact the virus of  loathsome literature and culture, due to which human butcher houses established in our country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After facing the risk of attack from India, the Pakistani Army's announcement that it would remove forces from the Afghan border and post them at the Indian border, and the announcement of the Taliban that it would handle the Afghan border, caused America to stumble, and pressurize India not to attack Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This showed the strength of America in the region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Though India did not warn that they would attack, and nor do they have that much courage.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Taliban attacked and finished most of the remaining American supplies.</seg>
     <seg id="5">That proves that without the Pakistani Army and tha Pakistani government, America is nothing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Karachi Business Financial Center of Pakistan is Dubai of underdeveloped areas.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Hundreds of thousand never return empty pocket from here, but since the grip of law has weekend in Western Frontier areas all eyes are on Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now they are about to kidnap this city.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First time Pathans are named Pakhtoon, residents of a city are involved in fighting like strangers, although need of the time is unity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One possible solution to the problem is this that either Urdu speaking learn Pashto or Pashto speaking learn Urdu, or whats better is they all learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You will surely think this as a ridiculous suggestion but do you think that reason of this conflict is not ridiculous?</seg>
     <seg id="3">That reason of violence is language?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir i gave this suggestion  in childhood in reality to my friends in which there were people according to classification from every religion and dialect but friends used to laugh on my talks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At that time the condition of Jinn of hatred of dialectal and religious was not that alive and strong but it was brewing internally.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Do not understand what and why is this happening?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are these the very same signs of Last day?</seg>
     <seg id="3">For what crime are innocent and guiltless being killed?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The reasons are in front of everyone who wants to divide Pakistan in pieces same are active here and who do this they neither have religion and nor country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Either Karachi or Mumbai it is an inside job.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Every upcoming government gets herself involved in changing the names of places, like now a days airport, roads, buildings all Benazir.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is this the meaning of Benazir which is happening in Karachi and to the peoples of Pakistan?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At the height of the Mumbai attacks, the fact that the efforts to cause mischief on linguistic and racial lines in Karachi failed is proof that those politicians working on racial parole have resigned from their jobs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The taking of the lives of innocent Pushtu speaking labourers and the Indian warnings have awakened the sleeping Pakistani feelings from Karachi to Khyber.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The identical country loving reaction of all the political, religious, linguistic and national parties has not only taught India the manners of diplomacy but it has also given the American policy makers a chance to think again.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">MQM and ANP are responsible for the worse situation in Karachi and administration is not neutral.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Administration can control the situation in an hour but it is incited deliberately</seg>
     <seg id="3">, police and rangers don't take action because of political parties pressure.</seg>
     <seg id="4">To unite is only expressed in speeches, political parties should have to quit their interests and work for common people.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Till the end administration is under political pressure such incidents will increase, Allah bless Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I believe these people are the biggest terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And there are definitely some foreign forces at work here, but I do not know whose?</seg>
     <seg id="3">And the sad thing is that if such a situation was prevalent in any border town, the government would take care of that place, but as this is far from the border, the government looks helpless.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government should set up an operation here, and save a big and important town from terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Otherwise Pakistan will face a huge financial crisis.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even BBC Urdu is not writing the truth due to fear, and as for the local media, it is even thinner.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The whole truth is available on BBC English.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One solution to the problem is that either the Urdu speaking people learn Pushtun or the Pushtun speaking people learn Urdu or even better, both learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Definitely, you might think this is a funny proposal, but do you not think the reason for the clashes is funny?</seg>
     <seg id="5">that the cause of extremism be language?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">They spilled blood in Karachi and the story that each citizen was fearing for a long time was finally written.</seg>
     <seg id="2">No one left any stone unturned, and the reports that surfaced in the media was 50% of what actually happened here in four days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I stayed up the last three nights and I am still afraid.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The people who killed the cobblers and peanut sellers who evacuated the hotel</seg>
     <seg id="5">The people who looted the super highway and cut the ears of innocent people are all unaware of Allah's punishment which can catch them anytime.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What do you think are the reasons for this sudden violence?</seg>
     <seg id="2">(BBC)</seg>
     <seg id="3">Keeping the heart rendering Mumbai attacks in view and diving to search for a cause for the violence in Karachi is not at all needed, rather the quite straightforward reason for this violence is the subconscious change in 'blood'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is obvious that if someone mistreats the father, it is no surprise if the son becomes out of control.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Liaqat Ali Khan and many devotees also belonged to there,for correcting the misunderstanding of Mr. Psycho I am quoting a verse</seg>
     <seg id="2">We also will follow our ancestors</seg>
     <seg id="3">sacrificed for her existence and will sacrifice to save her.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Faizan Taufiq Siddiqui</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is very sad, the whole country is at stake while we are fighting with each other.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mr. Siddiqui for your kind information if Wikipedia.</seg>
     <seg id="7">org is searched for Liaqat Ali Khan, you will know that he belonged to a noble Punjabi family of an area of Punjab Karnal.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Due to his services for Muhajirs, they consider him their leader.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Every action has a reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">One can bear ones self, but..</seg>
     <seg id="3">I'jaz A'wan</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sir, before you get a large number of people with proposals, I shall tell you that the open signs of this mischief is also found on the walls of Karachi, in the form of posters and wall chalking.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We have been bearing both types of mischief.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mischief mongers did not leave Pakistan or the founder of Pakistan. They did not have to face any reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Contrary to that, they are pecking at the chest of Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Only Muslim League (N) was left, she also handed over the draft of 18th amendment to Peoples Party.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Before this MQM and Muslim League (Q) has already submitted the draft of 18th amendment in assembly and senate.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Till now it appears that 18th amendment was a political move and none of the party is sincere in its approval.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is why nobody has raised voice in the favor of this amendment in senate or assembly and neither forced the House to approve the amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It seems that by submitted the draft of 18th amendment these parties has beaten around the bushes means they can claim that we had submitted the amendment but the ruling party's speaker did not proceed.</seg>
     <seg id="6">MQM is i coalation with government, Muslim League(N) is secret partnership with government and Muslim League(Q) is the party that passed 17Th ammendment, then how it is possible that these parties are sincere in abolishing the 17Th Amendment</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the way to get ones name entered in the list of martyrs by just getting painted.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The Peoples Party is otherwise not in hurry to end the seventeenth ammendment.</seg>
     <seg id="9">How any one can think of getting his own hands cut.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Seventeenth Ammendment cannot be abolished till Zardari is the President.</seg>
     <seg id="11">This was the opinion of majority in one of our survey and it is also correct.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Zardari would not have opted to be the President, if seventeenth ammendment was to be abolished.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Now he is more powerful than President Musharraf, since along with President he is also  the chairman of Peoples Party.</seg>
     <seg id="14">The seventeenth ammendment is there till he is the president.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Political Parties will have to remove President Zardari first, in order to abolish  the seventeenth ammendment.</seg>
     <seg id="16">Neither MQM wants it nor the other parties.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In our family, most of the people are of the laborer type.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And in our childhood, when we used to see our uncles toil, we used to wish in our hearts that Allah save us from labor that is hard on the body.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To save ourselves from this, we wrote a letter to the editor of the Amroz daily, asking him what we can do after metric to save ourselves from having to toil.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The editor wrote in reply to become a doctor or engineer and take such and such subjects.</seg>
     <seg id="5">My focus was always on engineering, and after metric, instead of Biology, I took Technical Drawing.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But while entering the FSC, my elder brother forced me to do FSC in medicine and become a doctor.</seg>
     <seg id="7">I studied Biology for a month with great difficulty, and when I still could not understand anything, I took maths as a subject instead.</seg>
     <seg id="8">So the scare of having to work made me an engineer, and today I am in a very good condition compared to many of my same aged relatives, for which I am always thanking Allah.</seg>
     <seg id="9">I remembered this when I was trying to lift the carpet of my old house along with my two young sons.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It was not half an hour since we started working, that the younger son said "Dad, it looks as if I was not made for this job"</seg>
     <seg id="11">We said, if that is true, then study a lot like us, and free yourself from bodily pain.</seg>
     <seg id="12">The son said that I am studying and will continue studying, but I cannot do this work.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Anyway, the three of us finished that work in three hours and returned.</seg>
     <seg id="14">My purpose of saying this is that if a person has set a goal, whatever be the reason behind it, no one can stop him from achieving his goal.</seg>
     <seg id="15">But if you do not even know what you have to do, then Allah alone is your protector.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is said that don't accuse the dead, but can't help it as we see only evils in her on the first anniversary of Benazir.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On one side Benazir crushed independence movement of Sikhs by handing over the list of Sikh freedom fighters to India for her own sake and on the other hand provided India an opportunity to fully concentrate in Kashmir after crushing the movement in Punjab.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The greed of Benazir and Nawaz Sharif for government is a part of history which pushed the country back for many years.</seg>
     <seg id="4">During her exile Benazir continued to give negative statements on Kashmir and Atomic Program.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Benazir made a deal with Pervez Musharraf while betraying the London agreement with Nawaz Sharif.</seg>
     <seg id="6">During her reign Benazir provided her husband the opportunity of making money and because of this he popularized as Mr. 10 percent.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Benazir brother was killed during her reign whose assassins are still safe.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Though a woman still Benazir avoided to fight for the rights of women.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Just like Benazir politicized her father's dead body similarly his widower husband politicizing her dead body.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Benazir reigned twice but not only she failed to punish her father's political murder but could not file a case against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is 37 years since East Pakistan was separated from us, and look at the height of insensitivity on the part of the public and the rulers, that no one ever mourned or expressed sorrow over their mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We should have been observing 16th December as a day of reflection, and made plans to prevent the re occurrence of such incidents.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We should have been sending greetings to the people of Bangladesh on this day and been trying to bring them closer to ourselves.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The ruler should have opened the Jamudur Rahman commission file and pondered over the causes of separation of West Pakistan, mentioned therein.</seg>
     <seg id="5">He would plan on bringing back the people of Bihar who were stuck in Bangladesh and he would send them gifts to keep their spirits up.</seg>
     <seg id="6">We have become so insensitive that if someone dies in our neighborhood, we are not even aware of it.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We do not care for our brothers and sisters because we have become selfish.</seg>
     <seg id="8">A huge calamity can pass by, but the next day we are lost in our day-to-day routine of life.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If only East and West Pakistan could become one again, like East and West Germany became one.</seg>
     <seg id="10">We can become one again, if we sacrifice a little for each other and leave our selfishness behind us.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But this wish does not look like it will be fulfilled in the near future.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Today when it was told in the news that Governor of American State Illinois has been arrested for charges of corruption</seg>
     <seg id="2">and to remove him from governorship provincial Congress is preparing for his rapid accountability, our American friend who has a keen interest in Pakistani affairs exaggeratedly said to me 'see this is democracy'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No one is beyond the law in America.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and here is your country Pakistan whose president was dropped of the corruption charges before sworn in.</seg>
     <seg id="5">My sense of humor rouse and I said what's strange if a governor has been arrested in America, in our Pakistan prime minister was arrested overnight and once was hanged and second time was exiled.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tell me, has it ever happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="7">In Pakistan the country law breaker has been departed from President House with guard of honor, tell me has it ever happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="8">In Pakistan Chief Justice has been dismissed as despite of public support he is not reinstated yet, has this ever happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="9">In Pakistan fake degree holder has become the Health Minister, did this happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="10">By hearing this American laughed like mads and also accepted his defeat.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In this picture, President Zardari is smiling, despite being surrounded on all four sides by Americans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It seems from his smile that</seg>
     <seg id="3">he thinks that America is with his government. He is forgetting that one year ago, they were with Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This picture was passed on, as if it was of some family.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Previously, such a photo was never printed in newspapers before, i.e. one president with three American agents.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It seems as if America's work in Pakistan has increased and now more than one agent was needed to complete it, or that they did not trust the new slave as they trusted the first one.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is also possible that this was done keeping in mind the notoriety of President Zardari breaking his promises.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If it was a smart ruler, at least he would not have shown his teeth in this photo, and he would have at least seemed ashamed of the neckband of slavery that he was sporting.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If the rules of democracy are implemented on this photo, President Zardari is in minority.</seg>
     <seg id="10">According to democracy, the majority are the rulers of the country, and the photo is speaking for itself who that is?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Paradise-like Swat is also called the Switzerland of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to the government tactic so far, along with force, discussions have been going on.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the use of force is not giving any benefit other than increasing the force of the Taliban and increasing the public favor for them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is required that the government finish the causes of this problem, rather than use force.</seg>
     <seg id="5">By finishing the causes, Fazlullah and the Taliban will be finished themselves.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The proposed Shariah bill of the ANP government will become a moderate solution to the problems in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="7">But alongside the establishment of the Shariah, the government will also have to take care of economic problems.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">From General Musharraf's initial few steps, it looked as if the nation would be freed of useless politicians, but the love for power changed all his plans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whatever expectations were, after joining the 'war of terror', he began to consider himself irremovable.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And whatever steps were expected were no more.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Just as Bush's rule began to close, he started to worry about the end of his own rule, and he struck a deal with thieves in the dark.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Even then, General Musharraf could have commanded the army, but the present government does not even know what is happening.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Whether in Bajod or Swat, the army cannot control terror, and instead they bomb the 'enemy', i.e. the public. Apart from loss of life and money, if they are making the 'enemy' psychologically ill, then we are the enemies, aren't we?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The conditions in the  terrorism struck area Swat in the Frontier Province are continuously deteriorating in spite of continuous Army action in the area</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the one side the governments writ in the area is restricted to the extent of just getting the condemnation resolution passed from the National Assembly and on the other side the effect of Taliban's unlawful radio is increasing everday in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the third side the common folk consider it safe to listen to those who are in control of the area.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The security forces claim killing many extremists during Gunship Helicopter attacks and Artillery Bombardment but in spite of these killings the Taliban's has not only gained strength but according to estimate they have established their control over eighty percent of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The result is that on the one side the government is not ready to accept its defeat and on the other hand the Taliban has established their hold.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In between who got grinded, the poor citizens.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is said that in Swat somebody asked, which type of people are the Taliban's are? The answer was  "very good people because they are the custodians of the religion and they are fighting a war against the enemies of the country".</seg>
     <seg id="8">Then asked how is Army, the answer was that the Army is very good since they protect the country and they fight with the enemies of the country.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Then it was asked, who are the enemies of religion and country, the answer was "the citizens"</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I am astonished, how the Pakistan Army will fight with the Indian Army, while it is unable to control a small group of Taliban's.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They could not track the illegally set up FM channel of the Taliban, which I believe was very easy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But still, the FM channel is spreading poison with all vigor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the girls schools, now boys schools are being destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Curfews are called so that the Taliban can move around easily.</seg>
     <seg id="6">During curfew tonight, eight trucks entered the outskirts of Mengorah and formed barriers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The question arises as to how they got there despite the curfew.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The army could kill Akbar Bugti in his house, but salutes the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="9">For God's sake, can someone explain to the army to save the poor public from the grip of the Taliban and prove that the Army can defeat any enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">He says, maximum bloodshed has been done on the base of religion, you tell me in the absence of any religion wont bloodshed occur?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Punjabi, Pathan. white and black, Mehsud and other tribes, are all these created by religion?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Not at all, sir, religion preaches us that there is no white, black, Punjabi or Muhajir, if there is no religion then half of the world would have been destroyed by the war of black and white and remaining half by the war of cast.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Actually religion nourishes human morally and restricts him that he is not here at his own rather is sent by The Creator of Universe and he has to live by God's rules.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a Muslim I believe that Islam is true religion and a complete code of life.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After settling down in London, every morning I would first call my relatives and ask them how they were. Most of them had never called me to find out how I was doing, and I then realized that they do not like me calling them either, so I stopped calling them.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Living here in France, for two years, I also felt the same way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I do not know why people only expect us to call.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A resolution about Iraq, passed in a few hours, to send a 'peace' force to Darfur is not at all a problem.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Immediately criticizing the Mumbai attacks and restricting suspected groups is a matter of a few hours.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And where there is a matter of death, we are still holding meetings about that.</seg>
     <seg id="4">O upholders of world peace, life is finishing over here.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is the wait really going on for it to finish?</seg>
     <seg id="6">So that some oppressed person would not even be able to think about using some mass destruction weapon like ill will to obtain their right?</seg>
     <seg id="7">When a father is running around holding the corpse of his son, even then a small wave of sorrow does not arise from any part of your heart.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If not, you have no right to be called a human.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Rather you are a black spot on the name of humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">OK, this was proved that this area was also the home of the Israelis for thousands of years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ideally, these two tribes should have lived happily together with love and affection, but since their strings are in the hands of the western and Arab countries, therefore peace is not possible without their will.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rather, now even Iran wants to fight a proxy war from here.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even if Israeli action has stopped for a while, it will start again after some incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The interests of BBC homeland are affiliated to America and Israel and this is why under the wrapper of 'broadmindedness' it has produced a series of blogs consisted of 'Jewish favor' and is conducting one sided and blind 'propaganda'.</seg>
     <seg id="2">BBC is only carrying the 'formality' and its objective is to have sympathies!</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is requested to Mr. Moderator that he must publish this review so that it may be proved BBC has element of realism to some extent.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thanks.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I don't know who wrote this story or how this story came to being, but one thing is for sure, in every age, draculas have been drinking the blood of innocent people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In every age, wars have been fought and blood has been spilled.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the surprising thing is that this 21st century man, who considers himself civilized, is quiet over this ruthless open massacre.</seg>
     <seg id="4">How could I not feel that whatever is happening is presenting a very ugly picture of mankind.</seg>
     <seg id="5"></seg>
     <seg id="6">Well wisher, Sajjad Alhasnain, Hyderabad, Deccan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At this time, including Derah Gahzi Khan, summer showers are taking place throughout the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Presented is a poem according to the season. Enjoy the rain along with this poem.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These rains are also from you</seg>
     <seg id="4">which when fell brings spring.</seg>
     <seg id="5">When it stops there is no movement</seg>
     <seg id="6">sometimes it came just like that, without a reason.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Sometimes it spread day and night.</seg>
     <seg id="8">sometimes loudly, sometimes silently.</seg>
     <seg id="9">These rains are also from you</seg>
     <seg id="10">in some remembrance some night</seg>
     <seg id="11">on some suppressed ashes</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sometimes it was such, that the wind put it out.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Sometimes it burnt itself.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Sometimes each drop seems sorrowful.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Even these rains are from you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All these rulers are going to run away carrying a suitcase. What is it to them, whether the country lasts or not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whether the public sells scrubs or takes lemon peels and scrubs the temple bells with them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">For one, our media is also corrupted, like our leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It's goal is only to extract money from the government, and nothing else.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As for the public, they are ignorant. To speak about them is the biggest ignorance.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Yesterday noon strange thing happened.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All together police running here and there but not ask on illegal parking</seg>
     <seg id="3">and moreover that NYPD traffic was also not in a mood to look at illegal parked cars.</seg>
     <seg id="4">it happened like this that a plane of US Air really became a plane and landed in Hudson river.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Till now it is just known this that "Terrorists" relation was with birds race Goose.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Yesterday was maybe New York's historic cold</seg>
     <seg id="7">Temperature do not drop to this degree</seg>
     <seg id="8">Me my own jaw is beginning to hurt after half hour of stroll outside.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Imagine that what would have happened to those people who jumped from plane in the river.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Happy news is that people all together stayed safe</seg>
     <seg id="11">and sad news is that ship of company sank in this financial crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="12">While watching all this I went to New Jersey by West Side Highway. I Noticed that South Bound is blocked, still what I did?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Yes, I was jammed in it on my way back.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Thanks God,during my an hour trip the road was bit cleared as I get an exit from 56 street.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Otherwise I did not avail the first two exit due to the long lanes of vehicles.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Makki, My Pakistan: Well, Congratulations, Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ammar: Of course, believing women</seg>
     <seg id="3">Shaguftah: Well, Congratulations, Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sarah: I have slaughtered two chickens and how they are slaughtered, Jahanzeb has already mentioned.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Apart from this, there is no other way.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At this farm, one has to get his own meat done,, including removing the skin.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Bossom:It may take some time for the Dot Net to get fixed</seg>
     <seg id="8">What happened on the forum?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Linko</seg>
     <seg id="10">To fight with the "listen to the blog", use Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Duffer: Khair Mubarak! Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sir use Firefox</seg>
     <seg id="13">Snow till disappear</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">For no reason, we thought that the Taliban group from Sawat was non religious, who were only against women education.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They were expressing this irritation by demolishing schools and colleges for women every day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But like majority of the ideas, this was not proven right also. According to this news of CNN, on the lucky day of Monday, a group of Taliban demolished a Boys school with gunpowder.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Swat, The Taliban has destroyed a boys school.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The girls schools were already destroyed, acting according to the famous English saying "Ladies First". I do not know why people are still bent on calling the Taliban uncultured and barbaric.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Another thing that becomes clear from this is that the accusation against the Taliban, that they are against girls education, is not true.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Rather, Masha Allah, they are against education altogether.</seg>
     <seg id="8">May Allah give these Mujahideen more power, and the evil government</seg>
     <seg id="9">which is let loose on us, may He help them in uprooting them.</seg>
     <seg id="10"></seg>
     <seg id="11"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">just a while before this, the wedding of a dog with a girl took place.</seg>
     <seg id="4">look at that groom.</seg>
     <seg id="5">humanity is still a rarity in the twenty first century.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Today is the age of computer and computer's interference is growing in every aspect of life.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Lots of people have many reservations about this growing interference of computer like in financial issues.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As you have facilities for using credit cards but by this law enforcement agencies has also firmer grip on your private life.</seg>
     <seg id="4">That just by tracking the record of your credit card you can be exposed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And in future when use of currency will be minimal its utility will increase.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Similarly in crimes world there is no need to rob the bank, information of credit card are hacked.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Similarly friendship has become computerized</seg>
     <seg id="8">, social networking websites like Orcet, Facebook and MySpace are ranked first in popularity.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But don't you feel that the more closer we are getting of these sites mentally, practically moving further away from people.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Similarly there is the website of match making, where by knowing your choice you are provided with a list of people according to your likings.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Can you spend life with your own cologne (of course not physical)?</seg>
     <seg id="12">I can't do it, that is why a life partner is known as better half.</seg>
     <seg id="13">That he/she may cover my deficiencies.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Perhaps I have got a small share of sense.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I used to believe everything someone elder says.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the same way, I thought that my father knew the answer to every question on earth.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I used to get laughed at a lot for this.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But only that saying seemed true which could be possible.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Become much irritation because what was the reason to tell lie?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Bore loss on that saying even at this age</seg>
     <seg id="8">So it is my effort to say lie the very least.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Do not misguide someone by lieing and that also by attaching Allah's name.</seg>
     <seg id="10">and Allah willing say only when there is pray to Allah that work completes.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Remaining Allah knows better the state of intention.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a disgusting problem which is created due to reason of distance from religion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to law of both our Pakistan and religion, minor child should stay with mother.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Their expense is due to their father and father can meet with children.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Then when the child becomes of age, he or she can stay with whomever they will.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You rightly mentioned that the actual problem is that of the relatives who mislead.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Possessiveness is present in all our actions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is this very factor in effect over here, that there will be new shareholders in the father's property born, and they will go against him. Otherwise his fathers action is commendable.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These restrictions have caused social evils, even in our marriages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The concept of the marriage of a divorced woman or a widow has become obscure.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is these wasteful ideologies and baseless traditions that have made the family structure a mess.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In our society, if the wife of a 50-55 year old man or the husband of such a wife passes away, why are they not looked at in a nice manner?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Near us, there is a Pakistani uncle, whose wife passed away 10-12 years ago. Now, after marrying off all his children, he has married a widow, so even his children have gone against him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I believe this is his legitimate right. What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="4">What type of mentality is the 'while we are there, no one can take our mother's place', kind of mentality?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I believe that this persons children should have thought what is wrong if he married a widow, after he married off all his children?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Thereby, this widow also got support and the uncle also got someone to look after the house.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As the children would definitely have gotten busy in their own worlds and would not be able to give time to him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The reason for this is ignorance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Tomorrow if their wives refuse to look after them, when they are old, what will they do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is a result of the force of society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When people begin to make fun of such a family for doing something like that, children start to feel ashamed of their father's second marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Though they should face the environment and say that their father's action is in perfect accordance with Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a curse in our society in which we are sunk since last 40 to 50 years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Even a wife is agreed on the unethical activities of her husband but does not allow her for second marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If she had the power She wont allow him of this even after her death.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Along with husband spoils her afterlife too and causes an increase in corruption in society.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Chanting Islam, Islam does not mean anything. In reality, we like only our culture and traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For instance keeping girls  from gaining education and fearing marrying the girl of ones choice.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As for your question about the old man going to the widows house instead of bringing the widow to his house, so that the children could make some fuss and then become quiet and relax, (though the stomach of the widows children would hurt).</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In IndopPak we embraced Islam centuries ago but can't get rid of this unlettered thinking and considered traditions and customs superior then Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Second marriage of man as ridiculous, divorce as stigma, divorced woman as untouchable, love marriage as disgrace and man's marriage with an elder woman as the result of her cunningness is all because of such thinking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Moreover to copy the western nations we declare veil and worship backward.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It was easy to embrace Islam to get rid of such thinking is very difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Allah grant us all spirit and courage for this.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Amen</seg>
     <seg id="7">Writing Urdu was never so difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Century passed writing such little writing</seg>
     <seg id="9">Know that little is much.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Allah Hafiz</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Ameer Taimoor in his book "I am Taimoor" writes that i found this secret in my life that if leader of any Army is in front line then that Army will never lose.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But here situation is else.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To say that Common people are there to die for us if we die then martyr</seg>
     <seg id="4">if someone from common people dies then murder</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">AsSalaamu Alaikum wa Rahmatullahi wa Barakatuhu (greeting)</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today, as I was returning to my shop, after Isha prayer, when a man sitting in a car at the circle raised his hand and diverted my attention towards him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I thought this man might have lost his way, or he might want to ask something, so I stopped, and his whole family was sitting in the car.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He asked whether I could understand Arabic well or not. I said no problem, tell me what you want.</seg>
     <seg id="5">He started to say that I have come from Riyadh, to Madinah, but someone has pick-pocketed me, so please help me out. I asked him to excuse me, as such an incident had taken place with me previously, that I had given the person 20 Riyals to buy petrol to reach Riyadh, but he went a little ahead and started to ask somebody else.</seg>
     <seg id="6">I got very angry and scolded him and warned him that I would call the soldiers, so he got very frightened.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Now the situation  has become, that we Muslims come on cars, with our families to beg throughout the day and gain at least two or three thousand illegally.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Whereas there is a clear Hadith of the Prophet (SAWS) that says that the upper hand is better than the lower hand; the lower hand being the begging hand and the upper hand being the giving one.</seg>
     <seg id="9">May Allah have mercy on us and make us true Muslims (Amen, Amen)</seg>
     <seg id="10">WasSalam</seg>
     <seg id="11">Javed Iqbal</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The wife of famous singer Adnan Sami approached a Police Station in Mumbai, accusing him of torture.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Police Station advised her to approach the court.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Saba Galadari the wife of Adnan Sami gave an application against her husband that Adnan Sami continuously tortures her</seg>
     <seg id="4">and he is also administering in human behavior against her.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now this thing has gone out of her tolerance, therefore, a case may be registered against Adnan Sami.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Police  station has advised her to approach the court instead of registering  the case, on the plea that the case is not within the valid jurisdiction of police station</seg>
     <seg id="7">Do you think that the accusation on Adnan Sami by his wife is correct?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Can this accusation is an attempt of India to defame Adnan Sami?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Inform us about your opinion on the Subject.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Adam, Sanghad, Mehr</seg>
     <seg id="2">As far as accusations go, any person can accuse the other.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To get enraged for honor is not sensible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Whatever be the case between Adnan Sami and his present wife, he had left his honorable life and went to India to earn money. Now that fame has fallen around his neck.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is the result of his own actions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Washington...</seg>
     <seg id="2">High ambassadors of America say that President Obama will take a strong stand against Afghan President Hamid Karzai.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In America's new policy for Afghanistan, instead of development, war has been given more importance.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The envoys say that Hamid Karzai is being considered a barrier in the achievement of American goals in Afghanistan, as there is corruption in the government and the business of middlemen has increased and the Taliban are once more gathering strength.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The American envoys say that among the people in the American government who are stressing upon Hamid Karzai to do something more are Vice President Joseph Biden and President Obama's representative to Afghanistan and Pakistan, Richard Hallbrooke.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that this policy appeared after President Bush, who used to video conference with Hamid Karzai every two weeks, left. He used to stress upon the American role in rebuilding Afghanistan and its civilian institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Officials say that the Obama government would work with the State leaders rather than the central government.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The officials say that it will pressurize Karzai to step up the war against corruption.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Hamid Karzai is facing fresh elections this year, and it is not yet clear whether Obama and his group will support Karzai for presidency or not.</seg>
     <seg id="10">This statement of the American officials is not a precursor for a change in the American policy towards Afghanistan, is it?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Is Hamid Karzai's rule coming to an end?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What is your opinion about this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In a series of three one day matches between Sri Lanka and Pakistan, Sri Lanka defeated Pakistan 2-1.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan had defeated Sri Lanka in the first match, but Sri Lanka was victorious in the remaining two matches.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the third one day match, the national cricket team's performance was very poor. In reply to Sri Lanka's 309 runs, it only managed to hit 75 runs in 23 overs before going all out. As such, it had to face a humiliating loss.</seg>
     <seg id="4">From the results of the series, it becomes evident that the performance of the national cricket team is not consistent.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Despite home ground and all claims, the national team suffered defeat. What do you think are the reasons?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Which aspects of the game should experts focus on?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are you satisfied with the selection of the team?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Which part do you place the responsibility of the loss on, fielding, batting or bowling?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Let us know of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Babar Husain, Jeddah. It is very sad that even in todays modern age, such ignorant traditions are prevalent. If the landlord or the property owner targets innocent people with his harsh dictatorship, who will call them Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Let any big shot walk on these burning coals. Why does the government allow them to do that?</seg>
     <seg id="3">When will court justice come into play?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370243-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Sri Lankan cricket team has reached Pakistan, to play the one day international series.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Visit of a foreign team to Pakistan, in spite of Pak India tension is a good sign.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On reaching Karachi Airport the Sir Lankan team was given a warm welcome.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Two matches will be held between Pakistan and Sir Lanka in Karachi while the third one will be played in Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Both teams are asserting highly regarding their batting, bowling and fielding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If Siri Lanka venerates its spinners, Pakistans reliance is on its fast bowlers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Sir Lankas captain Mahela Jayawardene says that no one player but the whole Pakistan cricket team is dangerous.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Muralidharan and Mendis will be the trump cards, while Pakistans captain says that this competition will be tough.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Shoaib Malik has said we have played Murali Dharan before and will take care of Mendis as well. We have made a secret game plan and will reveal it on the ground.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Will the Pakistan and Sir Lanka series live up to claims of being interesting and thrilling?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Which side will dominate in the Pakistan and Siri Lanka series?</seg>
     <seg id="12">who will win the series?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Who will be the man of the series?</seg>
     <seg id="14">Let us know of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Gulfam, London, Publish statements that are of liking, you give preference to those too, it is our wish that even you write some truth, do not entangle the statement like Mukher Jee because it is commanded to say truth in front of tyrant and it is equal to Crusade(Jihad). What to say of Mukher Jee, change the statement between news and try to weep.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Mailk Yousaf, Dubai</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is all these people's doing Kashmiris are fighting war of independence for the past sixty years.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, no one  asked, now they are caught in war of extremism and terrorism so they have started talking about peace and settlement.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First they generally massacred Muslims now they are perplexedly settling the matters.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In any way Pakistan has to understand their duplicitous policies.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Asad Khan London</seg>
     <seg id="2">India is making situations so that the Kashmir situation is overlooked.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But Pakistan has always shown India's true face to the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even the British government is now understanding this, that is why India is now ruining Pakistan's reputation by terrorism accusations to distract from the Kashmir situation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And hesitates to talk with Pakistan about this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">British foreign minister David Milliband has said that by resolving the issue of Kashmir will bring an end to extremism, the government of Pakistan will effectively handle the threats rising on the borders.</seg>
     <seg id="2">it should be clear that the newly elected American president Obama has also expressed similar views over the Kashmir dispute.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The British foreign minister while talking to media in Mumbai and has written in an article that the idea of the war against terror is wrong and killing people just for the threats to one self was the policy of president Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="4">David Milliband has said that Pakistan should not be lenient with the extremist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">due to the stress over the need for resolution of the Kashmir dispute from the major powers, isn't India trying to divert the attention from this issue by creating unrest in the region?</seg>
     <seg id="6">isn't the terrorism in Mumbai a part of this strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is India using terrorism as a base to escape from comprehensive dialog?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Let us know of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Usman Aftab.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think Super powers don't want to destroy Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">rather they are thinking of certain policies to control her they are familiar that Pakistan is an atomic power</seg>
     <seg id="4">want to bring some sort of revolution</seg>
     <seg id="5">Foreign countries believe that by cornering Pakistan few hurdles may generate want to support Pakistan and also wish to achieve their goal</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A citizen, USA.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It has always been a Hindu tradition, that in the side is a knife and on the mouth is Ram.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I think that they get stomach aches over small issues and begin to warn Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are ready in all ways, the Indian Chief of Army should keep his mouth shut or else, we know how to give mouth breaking anwers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Faheem Siddiqi</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ras al Khaima, This conversation is going on due to American mischief. America's mind was already spoiled, but know India is also becoming like that. Let them attack, and they will see the reality, as to who is in how deep waters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel is attacking Hamas, but no one has the courage to stop it. Watching Israel, India also wants to do all that.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Prime Minister, Syed Raza Yusuf Geelani said that the newly elected American vice president, Joe Biden played an important role in removing the ex-president Musharraf's uniform and replacing it with a lame democracy, which is why the Pakistani government has honored him with a special star.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The credit for removing the uniform and replacing the democracy should not go to any political party. The Parliament is not a rubber stamp.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All decisions will be made in the parliament.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Prime Minister said that Qadeer's door was closed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In your opinion, do the public protests against Mina Marriot not mean anything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Has the lawyers movement not played any role?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you have to say about this statement of the Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Make us aware about your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American President, George W. Bush, in his outgoing press conference advised newly elected President Barack Obama saying that he had made many mistakes in his presidency, and that Barack Obama should do whatever he feels is appropriate.</seg>
     <seg id="2">'I did, as a president, whatever I felt was appropriate, according to the situation, and the American law and constitution, giving preference to American interest over my own acceptance'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">He said that the enemies of America are still planning to attack America, and that the biggest challenge for Barack Obama would be to stop those attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He said that not being able to find weapons of mass destructions in Iraq was the biggest disappointment for him, and considering the Iraq mission to be complete was his biggest mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Speaking at his last press conference at the White House, the American President said that this is my last press conference, and I thank the journalists and other friends who are present in the press conference.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you think Obama will not repeat the mistakes that Bush made?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Did Bush delay accepting his mistake?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Will Obama be able to follow Bush's advice?</seg>
     <seg id="9">let us know your Suggestion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">vice president of America Dick Cheney said that he want to see Usama Bin Laden Either Alive or Die.</seg>
     <seg id="2">he said that Usama Bin Ladin Hide-in his self in some mountain area , and he becomes inactive for his organization, if Usama Bin Ladin arrested either Alive or dead so his have to finished his  organization</seg>
     <seg id="3">America hopeful to arrest Usama Bin Ladin and search for Usama should continues.</seg>
     <seg id="4">did Dick Chiney wish come true to arrest Usma Bin Ladin.</seg>
     <seg id="5">let us know about your suggestion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Shahid Afridi like all rounder cricketer in Qaiud-e-Aazam trophy  PIA and at the end of first day match of  Habib Bank he fight with one spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="2">at Ubl ground when Shahif Afridi go out from drawing room after finished match so many spectator gathered around him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">on one time one spectator request him by holding his hand to take a snap with him on that Shahid Afridi neglect him and siad that take snap tomorrow, although due to spectator insist Shahid Afridi gets angry and give him slept before they start fighting people resolve this matter.</seg>
     <seg id="4">after that Shahid Afridi said that mde him issue with out any reason, at that time he was hurry for prayer.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Any way, I beg pardon for this drama.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you say about Shahid Afridi's actions?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Let us know about your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Manmohan Singh once again accused Pakistan of creating a war-like atmosphere.</seg>
     <seg id="2">and that Pakistan is using terrorism as a policy of state.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Speaking to a meeting of the cabinet of ministers, Manmohan Singh said that terrorist factions are being supported by neighbouring countries, especially Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And that the terrorists who attacked Mumbai used the sea way and remained safe from the coastal guard.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian Prime Minister said that the Mumbai attacks of November were carried out by Lashkar-e-Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that the terrorists were using new techniques and modern communication systems. We will have to step up the forces at the line of control as well, from where there is infiltration. He said that terrorism will not be accepted in any form, and this is our policy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">How do you see this accusation of the Indian Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Is the internal chaos and separation movements of India not the show of India's anxiety?</seg>
     <seg id="9">On whose signals is India has chosen to be in threatening attitude?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Let us know of your opinion</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Zubeer Khan, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is very hurtful incident that Israel is publicly massacring the Palestinians, same situation is here in Kashmir but Security Council do not even bother by it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As many organizations who are in Palestine and Kashmir should continue their fight till freedom and by creating unity between themselves keep fighting every kind of aggression, one of these days their Martyr will bring result. By the will of Allah</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Israeli air attacks still continues in Gaza, since now several Palestinian Men, Women and children have been martyred.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Important political leader of Hamas Nazarian have been martyred with wife and kids.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There meeting of Security Council ended without any decision.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The condemning resolution presented by Libia and other Arab countries against Israel is facing American opposition in the meeting.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Israeli airplanes bombardment is continued since many days on Palestinian civil population.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The whole world reacted on Mumbai attacks but no country including America and England can see bloodshed caused by Israeli attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Why the major countries of Muslim world are silent?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What will you wish to say on this double standard of the world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Saeed, New York</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think that actually, most of our people are illiterate. They do not know where their money is going. The government fixes taxes and likes to fulfill its duties, the electricity and gas crisis will not be like this.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because everyone knows the role of those selected by the people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The crisis of electricity and gas has worsen in whole of the Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="2">, on the other hand gas prices have been raised by average 8, while in few cities unavailability of petrol created immense worry for people.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Intense reactions, riots and torturous demonstration are continued in the industrial and business circles of Pakistan against the crisis of electricity and gas.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Industrialists have threatened a shutdown ultimatum.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In Karachi people are worried due to 8 to 10 hours load shedding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Industrial sector is almost paralyzed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Government Institutions are expressing their opinion by blaming each other.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Increasing the prices of electricity and gas is not a joke with people?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Why the solutions of the problems are not considered?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Is government not seeing the full stop on national development?</seg>
     <seg id="11">What steps you will instantly recommend for managing this crisis?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Let us know your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Imran Khokhar, Madina Munawwarah, I want to say that, as the people, the rulers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I am surprised that they are giving difficulty to the public who called for a democratic government.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The unavailability of electricity, gas and petrol has become a torture.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is no control over government institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The law and order situation is getting worse, day to day. May Allah have mercy on this country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The New Year started.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The previous year was a year of protests and political ups and downs. It will also be remembered for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The removal of President Musharraf from power, and President Bush's eight year regime coming to an end, Bush getting shoes thrown at and the establishment of a democratic government in Pakistan, sudden calamities, the earthquake of Balochistan, the global financial crisis and depression.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now a new year has arrived, how do you see the new year?</seg>
     <seg id="5">According to you, what color will the political and geographic scenario take, and what wise steps will Obama implement?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is there any hope of moving towards eradication of terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is the judicial crisis of Pakistan will finish?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What shape Pakistan and India relationship will adopt?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is there a chance of surgical strike or full scale war?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What expectations do you have from the new year?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Inform us about your opinion</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370256-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The first anniversary of Benazir Bhutto is being celebrated,she was martyred in an election rally at Liaquat Garden Rawalpindi on 27 December 2007.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today Benazir is not within us,she was a seasoned politician and a personality of international repute,she had a unique status in the countries politics.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The mystery of her killing has not been solved till today.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Her efforts to establish government and democracy in the country has not been wasted.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Today, a democratic government has been established in Pakistan and her husband Asif Ali Zardari is holding the office of the President of the State.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you think is the role of martyr Benazir Bhutto in Pakistani politics?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Who can be behind murdering her?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Recently,, she was given the global human rights award. What would you like to say about her democratic and political services?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After ruling over America for eight years, President Bush left the White House, for presidential camp office, Camp David, so that the White House can be decorated and prepared for new President Barack Obama, according to his wishes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In Bush's eight year presidency, the historic World Trade Center attack, the attack on the Pentagon, the action against Afghanistan and Iraq in the name of a global war against terrorism, in which armies of many countries were pulled into the war, and American resources were completely exhausted, were some of the memorable events of the Bush era.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As a result of this war, America had to face the worst economic and financial crisis in history.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What do you think the world got and what do you think they lost, as a result of this war?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Were the policies of President Bush successful?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What are your views of the Bush era?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian government has stopped the Indian cricket team from touring Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Indian cricket team was supposed to play three tests, five one day matches and one 20-20, during the tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rajiv Shekhla, the Vice President of the Indian Cricket Board, in an interview with Jeev News said that the board had asked the government for permission to go on the Pakistan tour, but due to the difficult situation in the two countries, the tour was not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Is the Indian government's decision to cancel the trip in view of the present political situation a proper step? Should sports not be separated from politics?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is the Indian government's decision not harmful for cricket?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Despite the fact that the security condition in India is bad, the England cricket team is continuing its tour, so why can't the Indian team make the tour of Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion on this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salman, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">Those people who are proud about going to India</seg>
     <seg id="3">and they make their films and videos over there, their eyes should open now, as to how much the people of India respect you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I remember an interview of Adnan Sami, in which he said that he is not Pakistani, rather, his citizenship is of England.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan Sami needs that he should come to Pakistan at first opportunity because respect did not suited him even there.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fareed Ahmad</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="3">Indians attitude have changed after Mumbai attack.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jagjit showed his reaction in this form that he hates Pakistan and Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="5">it should be known that Adnan Sami sung seven songs of Asha Bhosla, now how can he be out of tune, Adnan Sami should stay in India, no need to come here.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muhammad Shamshad Alam</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi, i will only say this on the statement of Jagjit Singh that he changes color like a chameleon.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who gives statements suitable to situation Pakistanis open your eyes that how much you are given worth in India, understand the thinking of Hindu.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the Mumbai incident, their hateful statements have increased now they are spitting poison against popular singer Adnan Sami.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">According to foreign news agency the situation has become funny when President Bush along with Prime Minister Noor Almalki in press conference at his office in Baghdad when an Iraqi journalist said to President Bush, ""Dog, this is farewell kiss"".</seg>
     <seg id="2">After this journalist removed his shoe and threw it at Bush, President bush expertly moved his head out of the way and saved himself.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Second shoe hit the American flag.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Security officials dragged him out of there.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On this occasion President Bush said I don't know why he did this, shoe was of size 10, I was not bothered.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you think that this action by the journalist depicts the anger of Iraqi people against President Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="7">What will you say about this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the terrorists attacks on Mumbai the tension between India and Pakistan relations worsen when fighter planes of Indian Air Force violated the air space limit of Pakistan in Lahore and Kashmir sectors.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Due to the counter action of Pakistan Air Force Indian planes were forced to return.</seg>
     <seg id="3">According to resources both Indian planes were fully armed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In the current tensed situation it is the first incident of its own kind.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan Air Force says that Air Force is fully vigilant to defend the country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Minister of Information Sherry Rehman says India has admitted that it was a violation of air space limit, however it was a mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan Army resources declared this incident as crucial.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Do you think India really intends to launch an air attack on Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is India's claim is correct that this violation was a mistake or it was objected to measure the capability of Pakistan Air Force.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Not this incident will increase tension between the two countries?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Tell us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Respected martyr Benazir Bhutto was given the International Award for Human Rights after her death, which was received by her son and chairperson of the People's Party Bilawal Bhutto Zardari.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During a session of General Assembly in United Nations headquarters, former prime minister of Pakistan, martyr Benazir Bhutto was presented with this award for acknowledgment of her efforts for human rights in a ceremony.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The 60th anniversary of the passing of the human rights resolution by the United Nations was celebrated on the 10th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Among those people and institutes being recognized with honors on the occasion, for working for human rights, apart from Benazir Bhutto, were former American Attorney General, Louis Ramsey Clark and Human Rights Watch, the organisation that works around the world for human rights.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On this occasion, the Pakistani Ambassador to the United Nations, Abdullah Husain Harun and other senior embassy agents were present.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you say about the former martyr Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto receiving this award?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Samir</seg>
     <seg id="2">Chicago</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is true that she was martyred, but we also remember how many innocent people she killed in Karachi, upon which she was proud that Nasirullah Babar did well.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But later, she changed totally.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is also true that she ignored the senior members of her party, and made her son the representative of Peoples Party. What kind of democracy is that?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Jami Noor, Karachi, This news proves that disbelievers will only help disbelievers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But until the iron ax is not fitted with a wooden handle, it cannot cut a wing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our rulers are just like this, that they are adopting secretive ways. This is why calamities are befalling the country.</seg>
     <seg id="4">May Allah guide our rulers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Security Council panel of the United Nations have included the name of Hafiz Sa'eed as well as two other Pakistani citizens and that of Jama'athud Da'wah as well as four other organisations into the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Pakistanis whose names were included in the terrorist list by the Al-Qaidah and Taliban Sanctions Committee of the Security Council included Jama'athud Da'ah chief, Hafiz Mohammad Saeed, practically non-existent organisation Lashkar-e-Taiba Operation Chief, Zakiur Rahman Lakhwi and Financial Chief Haji Mohammad Ashraf.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Apart from this, a saudi national, Mahmood Ahmad Bazek was also included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Among the organisations were Jama'athud Da'wah, Pasban Kashmir, ArRasheed trust, and Al-Akhtar trust International.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The member countries will immediately freeze all the assets of these individuals and organisations, they will be restricted from traveling and will be under arrest.</seg>
     <seg id="6">They will have to face cases.</seg>
     <seg id="7">These regulations are not as a result of Indian influence, are they?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Why is India blaming these parties for the Bombay attacks without any proof?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Aren't there any terrorist groups in India?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Are International groups not aware of the tortures being done on the minorities in India?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please inform us with your suggestions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Eid is the festival of joy and happiness and Muslims sacrifice animals on Eid ul Azha by following the Sunnah of Hazrat Ibrahim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Despite of this hard time when inflation is at peak political situation is worst, rich and poor make preparations for Eid according to their capabilities and wishes Eid to their dear ones by different ways.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We also are providing you an opportunity through blog to wish Eid to your dear ones in form of short messages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You can wish Eid through appropriate poetry.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Murtaza Jilani.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi, our leaders should understand this that people, they are doing the operation against, are the true valuers of Pakistan, who are tolerating all kinds of tortures but they love Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>

