<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="site19_FSC_constrained">
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Supported the proposal of France.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The committee meeting of the committee in the parliament on Friday the house was under the chairmanship of Syed Mushahid Hussain, which don't have been given this proposal that as the relief goods sent of all political parties and a parliamentary delegation of the Palestine.</seg>
<seg id="3">After the meeting, while talking to representatives of the media Mushahid Hussain Syed said that the committee has given to the proposal was welcomed in which said that Israel should immediately affected people in the Gaza Strip to allow.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said Israel's attack on by the crime against humanity, and said that all countries should condemn these attacks</seg>
<seg id="5">The double standards of the world countries, said that the target of people who are talking against terrorism, but the Israel attacks on the Palestinians, &quot; why are silent.</seg>
<seg id="6">Foreign Affairs in the chairman of the Senate Standing Committee on the leaders of the community while they also made the target of criticism.</seg>
<seg id="7">He said that the committee has expressed his hope that the United States, the newly elected president of Barak during the first 100 days of his government will also address the Muslim Ummah so that the United States and the gulf between the Muslim Ummah should be abolished.</seg>
<seg id="8">Mushahid Hussain Syed said that the Muslim Ummah and the west of the space to not only emergency measures be taken but as long as Kashmir and Palestine issues have been resolved.</seg>
<seg id="9">Minister of State for External Affairs of the country, Khan said, the committee said that the foreign ministers of the Organization of Islamic countries to participate in the meeting of are going to Saudi Arabia.</seg>
<seg id="10">The emergency meeting on Israel's attacks on of the result has been called in. He said that Palestine is aware and in this regard, the government is in touch with the leaders of other countries.</seg>
<seg id="11">Foreign Affairs Minister of State, said that the Palestine should be resolved according to UN resolutions</seg>
<seg id="12">Arab countries belonging to the two journalists, who also attended the meeting and the meeting, he said in the current situation in Palestine.</seg>
<seg id="13">In the Islamabad International University students demonstration against the Israeli attacks on Palestine.</seg>
<seg id="14">The demonstrators were carrying banners and which were also on slogans against Israel.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">To avoid refrain from flu</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">American scientists of the research were on the experiments have come after.</seg>
<seg id="3">This proved that continue to have food on the flu virus capable of dealing with the relatively low.</seg>
<seg id="4">The research has proved wrong old myth that ' it is better to prove to be starvation in fever.</seg>
<seg id="5">According to the scientists, they eat fever in the country.</seg>
<seg id="6">The investigation State University said that the recent has to fight and the ability of his death was also increased while the normal food in the who take more strong resistance against the flu virus.</seg>
<seg id="7">According the flu, not only to the people affected will very soon, but they will take more time to be.</seg>
<seg id="8">He also said that those people who have taken the flu vaccination he was also a few months during the winter should refrain from.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">In 2002, is the best for 2008.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">This shows the hard to form the basis of the &quot; and had been put out or nomadic band and Justin with one or two songs were also included.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is also an old car was kept on the stage.</seg>
<seg id="4">A profit of two show, which was the second most successful in obtaining million sixty million dollars.</seg>
<seg id="5">Canadian show the 17 countries who were in his first visit last eight years in the world.</seg>
<seg id="6">Both show the singer, director of the King, the girl ' of the ' Union, the visit also arrangements.</seg>
<seg id="7">Set up in 2001, six have broken only by their record.</seg>
<seg id="8">Six in 2000 he earned $19 million dollars, 37 million.</seg>
<seg id="9">The bone to take the third most successful singer declared 17 million, which has earned 60 million dollars.</seg>
<seg id="10">Bruce earn 16 46 million dollars to the fourth and fifth position and in the region, and 12 million to six million dollars.</seg>
<seg id="11">According to the magazine, in 8, very few people in North America and in the concert of songs to participate in the programs and only those people who were involved in groceries were ready to buy tickets.</seg>
<seg id="12">A ticket in the United States of eight percent increase in average, and show the most expensive ticket in the three hundred was sold.</seg>
<seg id="13">Gary editor of the magazine said that in light of the international economic marketing glue for eight year 2000 proved to be a good.</seg>
<seg id="14">He said for reconstruction of the U - 2 and this year, of which are issued a year of proving predicted.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Ban on education mixed: Taliban</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The president of the North Waziristan tribal region in Miran Shah and other districts of local Taliban Gul, a group detainees in which the government has distributed them and semi - governmental educational institutions have threatened, the boys and girls in education is being given to the coalition.</seg>
<seg id="3">Pamphlet hindrance in January that if the five to the educational institutions were closed, have not started action will be taken against them.</seg>
<seg id="4">Pamphleteer in that government aid and other educational institutions for women affairs identity cards will be a ban on women in all counties and the offices of NADRA had also refused to go on.</seg>
<seg id="5">Local the Taliban announced a ban on identity cards of women at a time when the North Waziristan has offices for the support of the about two hundred women in the form of the identity cards.</seg>
<seg id="6">According to the local people, to all of North Waziristan on was read aloud on</seg>
<seg id="7">However, in the letter that there was no mention of the girls have different educational institutions will ban on or not.</seg>
<seg id="8">According to the detainees after the announcement of education or identity card to get to in the form of arresting the office, the woman and her family members to share will be punished.</seg>
<seg id="9">Apart from this the Bannu district police said that the Bannu on Sunday a land mine on the road mrannshah explosion took place is, in which a passerby were killed and one injured.</seg>
<seg id="10">The wounded was admitted to civil hospital in Bannu.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">&quot; target killing more bodies recovered</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the police, the president on Sunday morning the areas in the green at and Sohrab Khan at the bodies of two people who were found beheaded.</seg>
<seg id="3">Those who were killed belonged to the frontier corps and police said.</seg>
<seg id="4">Eyewitnesses said that a letter from the dead bodies were found that has also raised the dead bodies, 11 am before his death will be responsible for themselves.</seg>
<seg id="5">Local people said that till 11 dead bodies are lying in the market, however, security officials said after the two bodies and also shifted.</seg>
<seg id="6">President in and around areas during the last few weeks in the target King incidents in the increase in dangerous</seg>
<seg id="7">Which civilians including women and security personnel have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="8">So far, according to local sources, this kind of incidents in more than 30 people have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="9">So far no organization has claimed responsibility for the killings.</seg>
<seg id="10">On Saturday, the local Taliban spokesman in Swat Muslim Khan told the BBC that was received on Friday in the three dead bodies of the dead bodies of their colleagues, were also in Taliban commander including the body.</seg>
<seg id="11">Muslim Khan said that last one and a half was in the custody of the security forces.</seg>
<seg id="12">He said that local Taliban were killed, are the first to notice, while on the other hand, these incidents in general are in severe concern.</seg>
<seg id="13">Local people say that in a large contingent of security forces, but this is in spite of the attacks on civilians is increasing.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Benazir Bhutto to the singing of in</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Voice was recorded in a rape the new style (1) of the tube, has been on the post.</seg>
<seg id="3">Five minutes on the pictures of Benazir Bhutto and video.</seg>
<seg id="4">18 year old Edinburgh University student.</seg>
<seg id="5">Her poetry and deep affection with singing.</seg>
<seg id="6">It is being said that he has apparently the encouragement of their mother after his fond was started.</seg>
<seg id="7">He said while presenting the mother is intelligent and said, the work you have done in a way. &quot;</seg>
<seg id="8">He said the December 27 in the incident, said the bullet shot, years, we were in the age of three children we, leave.</seg>
<seg id="9">The entire nation to hope you and your are present in the heart of all.</seg>
<seg id="10">Benazir Bhutto 20 - year - old children in the second position after Bhutto.</seg>
<seg id="11">He started with a music interest.</seg>
<seg id="12">He said it is being said that the return home of his mother in a journalist friend and refuted the award of music producer daddy had expressed his desire to meet, but it could not be met.</seg>
<seg id="13">Some of the Sindhi newspapers poetry, was also published the first time but their voice heard through the installation of the tube.</seg>
<seg id="14">Benazir Bhutto, and workers of some of the needy raped the CDs started.</seg>
<seg id="15">On the other hand, a spokesman of Pakistan Peoples Party, Farhatullah Babar has confirmed that the tube at the voice and poetry.</seg>
<seg id="16">He said on the phone from Islamabad said that it is a healthy mother, daughter of his courage, which is the government of the Pakistan TV network, also has been issued.</seg>
<seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar said that the distribution of the CDs, the program said that his party is not at present.</seg>
<seg id="18">He said that a few months ago on the website of young years his book the party chairman, Bhutto of Zardari's fake account was made after the end of which has been made.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Pakistan is the butcher, Pakistani Information Minister</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Federal Minister for Information and Broadcasting, Shiri Rahman, told the BBC Urdu service in a message sent S. M. S. Ajmal confirmed the citizenship of the butcher, just so said that more investigations are underway.</seg>
<seg id="3">Prior to this the advisor to the prime minister of the home country, Rahman refused citizenship.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the citizens of the record of institutes to Ajmal had no record of them.</seg>
<seg id="5">The latest announcement the government has not been able to know that how the Pakistan now has changed its stand on the basis of the butcher, Ajmal citizenship confirmed.</seg>
<seg id="6">However the spokesman Ajmal butcher, according to the Foreign Ministry of the Interior Ministry has confirmed.</seg>
<seg id="7">Prior to this, the BBC Urdu service and a few other newspapers and TV channels town Okara district of Punjab province, said.</seg>
<seg id="8">However, the government had refused to do.</seg>
<seg id="9">It is not clear that this is the same Ajmal Fareed from Kot or from the area.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Rockets fired from Lebanon also,</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Israeli army and police of the Lebanese media representatives from the area said that the four rockets on Israeli soil were fired the northern Israel, in which one down in the town of which two minor injuries.</seg>
<seg id="3">The region of rockets were fired in response to the Israeli bombardment on Lebanon.</seg>
<seg id="4">It is not clear that this attack Hezbollah has done, or behind an active Palestinian groups in Lebanon.</seg>
<seg id="5">The Lebanese government has said that it is also trying to know that those who is behind the rocket attacks.</seg>
<seg id="6">The BBC correspondent for the recent crisis in the region it has a very dangerous turning.</seg>
<seg id="7">The editor of the BBC for the Middle East according to rocket from the threat of the spread of war has increased.</seg>
<seg id="8">In the last few days it was being and feared that the operation were held in Gaza anywhere in the north of the border with Lebanon should not be spread.</seg>
<seg id="9">The Wednesday and Thursday night between the Israel Air Force has 60 air attack on the Gaza Strip.</seg>
<seg id="10">Israeli forces in these attacks, according to the office of the police of Hamas, tunnels, weapons, the water fired rockets and weapons to the places of Hamas activists were targeted.</seg>
<seg id="11">Besides the air attacks, the Israeli army and the Navy from the Gaza Strip continued the whole night on the bombing.</seg>
<seg id="12">Palestinian sources said that the air attacks in a mosque in Gaza City has been destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="13">According to unconfirmed reports, the Israeli army tanks, helicopters, was the area of the progress toward the Khan Yunis.</seg>
<seg id="14">Last 12 days in this fight seven hundred near to the Palestinians, including a large number of women and children have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="15">On the other hand, the Israeli army 11 soldiers were also killed.</seg>
<seg id="16">Israel's security forces have confirmed that one of the most high - ranking defense official to the terms of the ceasefire to the Cairo.</seg>
<seg id="17">Hamas, a delegation of the ambassadors of Egypt, also is going to Cairo for talks.</seg>
<seg id="18">Besides this, the leader of the Palestinian Authority, Mahmoud Abbas will arrive in Cairo on Friday.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">My heart is broken, my back.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">He said that Dr. Richard eight years ago to save the lives of his wife of their as they had donated.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to the News Agency, AFP, the doctor said that his wife had donated their relations with and that he deceived and re - and now the divorce for the move.</seg>
<seg id="4">Dr., a local newspaper Daily News said in an interview with the alleged he said that in my heart, the so far.</seg>
<seg id="5">Dr. Richard's lawyer, according to Dr. the return of their are demanding, but in reality they equivalent to the value of the subsidies.</seg>
<seg id="6">According to his wife, stand in the next few days, he will appear before the judge.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">140 years, free</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">&quot; George gave joint was arrested from a sea two weeks ago.</seg>
<seg id="3">The city's sea food company had purchased 100 dollars in it.</seg>
<seg id="4">And immediately pictures of him for the use of the start.</seg>
<seg id="5">But to work for the protection of animals, the group A has demanded to leave, as a result of which, in return, it will be left in the sea.</seg>
<seg id="6">George was arrested in Canada from the sea, after which the city and seafood company spent 10 days in the tank.</seg>
<seg id="7">The age of the weight of this can be done.</seg>
<seg id="8">Manager of restaurants said that his intention to damage to the tank and it was not in the purpose of the goods to provide the interest of consumers.</seg>
<seg id="9">The Organization of the protection of animals who belonged to say that when the decision is commendable, and is an example for the people or in the tank or want to keep them alive and food.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">With the help of mobile search for the child</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">When the officials found out about, the city police officer and the extinguish the forces came into.</seg>
<seg id="3">Officials of the girl with the help of your GP S. the right to know the place.</seg>
<seg id="4">However, with the help of the street interviews came to know that he is the girl in a hotel.</seg>
<seg id="5">A week ago the grandmother on the day of their legal supervision of the parents were.</seg>
<seg id="6">The police chief told BBC, he said that he never return to now and then he will not leave the state.</seg>
<seg id="7">The police have contacted Mrs., but when he returned to the police to do not of the have decided to search it through mobile phone.</seg>
<seg id="8">Two thousand five in the United States or the law that the mobile phone service companies to provide the 100 meters, far from the 67 percent and the 3, 100 meters, far from places 95 percent of the offer.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Hamid Karzai, on a tour of India</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Hamid Karzai five months in the second Indian tour.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is the hope that the Prime Minister Manmohan during his meeting with the extremist attacks in Mumbai, the situation will hold the talks.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said this during a tour of the Mumbai attacks on Afghanistan and its people's sentiments and expressed their solidarity with India wants.</seg>
<seg id="5">During the visit of Karzai extremism in addition to the bilateral trade will be discussed.</seg>
<seg id="6">The extremism for mutual cooperation between the two countries hope the talks.</seg>
<seg id="7">President Karzai during his last visit to India has said that terrorism and the relations between India and Afghanistan would not let the challenges.</seg>
<seg id="8">He also said that both India and Afghanistan and cruel terrorism and assassination operations, is facing a challenge.</seg>
<seg id="9">Both countries in the region and the entire world is beneficial for peace and stability.</seg>
<seg id="10">&quot; We think that both countries and the entire world and should unite and fight the menace of terrorism.</seg>
<seg id="11">It should be remembered that in July last year, the Indian Embassy in Kabul by Karzai for the attack on Pakistan's Intelligence Department has ISI was responsible.</seg>
<seg id="12">The attack in a F. I. C. S. including four Indian officials were killed.</seg>
<seg id="13">After the attack on the embassy during the visit of Karzai, India Prime Minister Manmohan Singh said that India and the friendship between the attacked Afghanistan was attacked, we agreed that we terrorism will not let the relations between the politics to.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Mumbai attack, for the special judge.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Mumbai Police Commissioner Abdul Ghafoor said that during the attack on the Mumbai extremists were arrested alive only one accused Ajmal Amir issue against the butcher. The hearing will be under the supervision of.</seg>
<seg id="3">Before this in this regard, the government has appointed a lawyer.</seg>
<seg id="4">Ajmal butcher, are currently in police custody and hoped that the police before the charge sheet against them will be.</seg>
<seg id="5">Ajmal butcher have no lawyer to defend himself.</seg>
<seg id="6">The Pakistan government has written a letter to the butcher appealed for legal help.</seg>
<seg id="7">Mumbai, India, Pakistan to the attacks of the extremists in Pakistan, included of evidence.</seg>
<seg id="8">Pakistan has accepted that Ajmal butcher Pakistani citizens.</seg>
<seg id="9">According to the police of the case and his companion Abu - Ismail A. T. S. chief, additional police Commissioner Ashok, the police Inspector Vijay including six police officers were killed after his car to snatched the ran away, and who was later D. B. have to worry.</seg>
<seg id="10">The police action in the death of Ismail Khan, the police had been located and arrested Ajmal to be alive.</seg>
<seg id="11">The yet, lawyer for the case has not been nominated.</seg>
<seg id="12">The government lawyer for legal add cell was nominated he refused to take on the basis of a moral case.</seg>
<seg id="13">The two lawyers, a political party of the people of his name after the protests and opposition.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Constitutional amendment, the committee will be formed.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">On Tuesday in Islamabad the environmental changes in an address to the representatives of the media after talking to the Jung, he said that in this regard will be called a meeting of the committee, which will be the formation of the</seg>
<seg id="3">He said that so far the Muttahida Qaumi Movement from the end of the 17th amendment to the constitution amendment bill was presented in the National Assembly while the other political parties are also in this connection constitutional amendment bill will be presented in the parliament.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that for the 17th constitutional amendment, the Pakistan People's Party has also sent to all political parties and a draft to this committee will review the draft constitution.</seg>
<seg id="5">In response to a question, he said that the balance of power between the president and the prime minister decided parliament.</seg>
<seg id="6">The prime minister said that all the parliament to make decisions in the parliament.</seg>
<seg id="7">In response to another question, he said that the retired former President General Pervez Musharraf from the post of the army chief of the political parties, former prime minister and the role of the chairperson of the Pakistan People's Party Benazir Bhutto, who is also an important role on the international community in the former President Pervez Musharraf for the stressed.</seg>
<seg id="8">He said that the US who elected vice president of Pakistan and democracy and services to the supporters of President of Pakistan, has Hilal in honor of.</seg>
<seg id="9">Mumbai after the incident, the Indian government to every kind of severing ties with Pakistan of Raza, in response to a question he said that at this time the Indian people to heavy pressure which is due to such statements.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Protest against the dismissal of journalists</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The journalists in Islamabad on Tuesday at the U. N. J. R. under the auspices of the Islamabad press club in front of the TV journalists and media workers have channels and newspapers, a large number of employees of media owners and the government's protest and shouted slogans.</seg>
<seg id="3">Addressing the protestors, the biggest organization of journalists, to the Federal Union of Journalists of Pakistan, a senior member of R. Shamsi said that till yesterday on the with which the protest today they are sitting in the house, but the owners of a certain group is holding the ruling due for the rights of the journalists nothing.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that he has talked to the human rights of the owners said their bodies are kept and the camps where the earning billions of rupees in spite of the very few members of the dismissed the charges and of their economic is being murdered.</seg>
<seg id="5">The example of Lahore, a private TV channel, one of the five workers, four months before us, which is not salary many workers and forced and months due to the lack of salaries and are spending a life of the people.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the TV and newspapers, we should direct action against the owners of parliament for the rights of journalists and in front of a permanent protest is the need camps.</seg>
<seg id="7">C. R. Salman, the governor of Punjab in criticized said that the target of the Urdu daily ', ' the newspaper employees without any notice to the countries of being on.</seg>
<seg id="8">Meanwhile, Daily News Channel, daily, five, and plus TV and TV has dozens of employees were also dismissed.</seg>
<seg id="9">F. P. J. Mazhar Abbas, secretary general of the said that protestors, while addressing a press briefing against the workers of organizations in the country, and the Black day journalists are celebrating their own rights and for the production of the parliament session will be tied bandage on effective in the black.</seg>
<seg id="10">Mazhar Abbas, according to the 80 percent of newspapers and TV channels in the exploitation of workers and journalists, where he was going to work without any agreement.</seg>
<seg id="11">He said that so far, more than 200 journalists and activists to newspapers and TV channels are being carried out and it is feared that the current year, the economic crisis as the owners and workers to be dismissed and hundreds more.</seg>
<seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas said the movement of the journalists will continue until the dismissed employees are not restored, the newspaper the wage board to decide the implementation of the employees of the newspapers and TV channels, and several months, the supplies were not a payment of salaries.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The 11 - member cabinet took oath</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In the new cabinet of former Prime Minister Sardar Ahmad Khan, of the anti - Muslim opposition conference of six, the Pakistan People's Party, Muslim League, Muttahida Qaumi Movement and two of the a minister.</seg>
<seg id="3">In the 11 - member cabinet minister, a woman and they are also belong to the rival Muslim Conference Atiq.</seg>
<seg id="4">The ruling coalition has said that the cabinet next week will be extended and there is possibility that more than a dozen included in the cabinet, it should be noted that in the beginning of this month, Sardar Khan, opponents of the ministry through the lack of confidence removed from the post of and was elected as the new prime minister.</seg>
<seg id="5">These departments of the ministers will be announced later.</seg>
<seg id="6">Taking oath of office on the occasion of the workers of the Pakistan People's Party shouted slogans in favor of former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">35 million consumers is affected by the virus.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">October 8, 000 for the first time in identified the virus, and up and it is known as the names.</seg>
<seg id="3">To deal with the virus this but this was in spite of this, about 35, 000 computers and have been affected by this.</seg>
<seg id="4">Experts say that the number of computers affected much more.</seg>
<seg id="5">To deal with this consumers are using Microsoft's ' M. S. of zero to zero, plot is the need to use.</seg>
<seg id="6">Microsoft has said that the virus to windows of the computers of ' A ' E. S. services the search and this is included in the code.</seg>
<seg id="7">The virus after of this system in the framework of such a plan.</seg>
<seg id="8">This virus is the name of its creation.</seg>
<seg id="9">Then the details of the its changed.</seg>
<seg id="10">This virus active after an issue, which is T. T. H. P. Sarwar, the machine is on and its to change the point.</seg>
<seg id="11">After it download files from the website of the wounds.</seg>
<seg id="12">Microsoft has said that the virus has affected the computers in various countries in the world.</seg>
<seg id="13">In these countries, Brazil, Russia, China, India, the United States and Britain.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">On the Indian information.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Interior Ministry, in a meeting of the representatives of the media, he said that India has given by the</seg>
<seg id="3">In this way, will help in the investigation.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that Pakistan and India is an independent country received them in any information on the investigation of any country.</seg>
<seg id="5">Will not accept.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that information received from India and other goods are also information.</seg>
<seg id="7">Advisor to the Interior said that the law enforcing agencies, the members of a banned organization fear to the peace process has been taken under custody</seg>
<seg id="8">And if some people found any evidence against the action will be taken against innocent people and should be released</seg>
<seg id="9">In response to a question, he said that any person who were arrested and will not be handed over to India, according to the Pakistani people and laws should be taken.</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that his action against the FIA has been under the law.</seg>
<seg id="11">In response to a question, he said that the Indian law enforcing agencies involved in Mumbai incident, people in 42 days - the information so they hope that the international community, including India will give some time for the investigation.</seg>
<seg id="12">He offered the government in the joint investigating incident that the team should be formed.</seg>
<seg id="13">It should be noted that additional director general of FIA, under the leadership of a three - member team was formed from India, which is that the Mumbai bomb attacks</seg>
<seg id="14">Pakistan in connection with the investigation on the information.</seg>
<seg id="15">Pakistan's High Commissioner in India, the met the president of Asif Ali Zardari, in which the president has made it clear that if any individual or group found involved in the Mumbai attack the action will be taken according to the laws to India will not be handed over involved in this incident, the Indian leadership to the people of India to put pressure on Pakistan.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">&quot; Nothing is possible in the United States.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Mr. on January 20 United States will take oath as president.</seg>
<seg id="3">The 16th in Washington, President of the United States in the memory of construction on the stairs of the building in a concert of music, speaking</seg>
<seg id="4">Mr., in the United States, said that the most serious of many generations face and he is hopeful that the United States is to successfully deal with these problems.</seg>
<seg id="5">Lincoln slavery in the tradition of the United States.</seg>
<seg id="6">But with Mr. said that the country to solve problems in time and way would be difficult.</seg>
<seg id="7">In spite of this, but I am hopeful that this dream of of the country will remain alive.</seg>
<seg id="8">The United States the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, is a severe financial crises.</seg>
<seg id="9">The oath taking ceremony for the extraordinary measures are being taken.</seg>
<seg id="10">Organizers of the two million people will attend the ceremony.</seg>
<seg id="11">On Monday, the United States National holiday because of human rights in the same day a great and Martin Luther King was killed.</seg>
<seg id="12">Martin Luther King black.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Martin Luther tribute to the determination to work.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Dr. Martin Luther King tournaments in 1968, were killed.</seg>
<seg id="3">Dr. paid tribute to the King and with the Americans, he said that the entire nation has promised to work.</seg>
<seg id="4">In Washington on Tuesday, the new president of the people on the occasion of the presidency of the a gathering of preparations are being made.</seg>
<seg id="5">It is expected that the president this historic presidential oath to see the 20 million people will be collected in Washington.</seg>
<seg id="6">On Monday, the day the Washington from a medical center where he was meeting with the injured US soldiers after they set up their homes for a shelter and were on a wall in color.</seg>
<seg id="7">Talking to reporters, said: &quot; The present crisis, which we are facing difficulties in which many people have been surrounded and then we cannot sit dismissed.</seg>
<seg id="8">He said that the King has spent more than in the service of the people.</seg>
<seg id="9">Said that the today, when we respect the memory of his working days, it is not so that we should stay and hearts. This is a process that we do.</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the ceremony will be held on the same path on which several thousand people of Martin Luther King ' the is a dream for me to listen to, ' in Nineteen sixty one was collected.</seg>
<seg id="11">Martin Luther King in his speech said that the day will come when people of color to the will be no discrimination.</seg>
<seg id="12">Mathew price of BBC says that the history of irony Martin say that day, the day has come to 24 hours before the U. S. history, when the first black president will take oath of his office.</seg>
<seg id="13">The United States for many people in the south states, presided over by Dr., the King's dream of.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Additional political agent.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Additional political agent to South Waziristan, in the first 10 days of unknown masked men shot.</seg>
<seg id="3">Official sources say that the local Taliban Mullah Nazir Group, was kidnapped.</seg>
<seg id="4">According to the local administration on Tuesday evening at four additional political agent of South Waziristan near Wana, Lateef to a tribal Jirga the camp.</seg>
<seg id="5">But he did not say that additional political agent who was kidnapped.</seg>
<seg id="6">However, that the political agent of the local people to Mullah Nazir group of local Taliban was kidnapped.</seg>
<seg id="7">Aamir Lateef this was kidnapped when they were going from Wana.</seg>
<seg id="8">Two thousand 9 to 11 January the South Waziristan tribal region seven armed masked men, additional political agent in Aamir Lateef driver kidnapped.</seg>
<seg id="9">According to the official kidnapping of cars in the first vehicle and the political agent to sit in a car and from there.</seg>
<seg id="10">According to the local administration, the kidnapping of additional political agent of South Waziristan, security forces in the tribal areas and paramedics of all check posts and to the people and was being searched for the last one week, the authorities have also imposed a ban on economic Wana.</seg>
<seg id="11">On December 8 2, 000 up to the political agent of North Waziristan Asmat Ullah was also kidnapped at that time when she was going to celebrate the Eid holidays Bannu and after a few days in the North Waziristan Amanullah, two people, including an unidentified masked men was killed by militants on Monday.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">British in the court.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">42 - year - old British citizen has admitted that he had the US military website.</seg>
<seg id="3">Gary asperger it should be noted that the patient was a way of working is similar to the mania.</seg>
<seg id="4">The lawyer said that if they were handed over to the United States fear that they will try to commit suicide.</seg>
<seg id="5">However, the government lawyer said that the health of Gary apprehensions are very limited.</seg>
<seg id="6">Lord Justice and stages of Mr. Justice Simon has said that the decision to said Gary given permission to the British High Court, in that they can apply for the review.</seg>
<seg id="7">The lawyers of the court order that was adopted in Gary, if his home and away from family, if they can commit suicide.</seg>
<seg id="8">He further said that it did not consider the home secretary.</seg>
<seg id="9">But government lawyers said that the home secretary has used his powers.</seg>
<seg id="10">Gary ever of the US military Web site to also denied.</seg>
<seg id="11">Gary and two American computer system in 2001 to which was due to the US government has caused a loss of 8 million dollars.</seg>
<seg id="12">Gary and including a computer system to 97.</seg>
<seg id="13">However, has no intentions to but that he did not have information about natural creation of looking for, which in his opinion, the US government was kept secret.</seg>
<seg id="14">Gary mother sharp said that they are happy with this decision.</seg>
<seg id="15">Gary's lawyer said this is the right decision.</seg>
<seg id="16">This case is moved to continue and eventually has a right decision.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Two of the commander killed in Kashmir:</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Stationed in Jammu, the Indian army's Northern Command spokesman Lieutenant Colonel told BBC: 24 rifles and Jammu and Kashmir and the police force has confirmed receiving the tehsil in gandwah Doda district on district of the jungle prevails in has surrounded the place where the armed extremists hiding somewhere.</seg>
<seg id="3">He fired at the army operation in the two armed forces and extremists, have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="4">The spokesman said that two militants were killed in 12 years the district of Mujahideen district commander Hizb - ul - Din, who is also an expert in the blast.</seg>
<seg id="5">Along with this, the identity of Sajjad, according to the army, which is the last year was linked with the extremists.</seg>
<seg id="6">According to the operation is still continuing in the region because according to him, the more possibility of the presence of extremists rifles in the first phase of operation, were also recovered.</seg>
<seg id="7">Yesterday, the head of the police of Kumar, the province has issued eight of the year, while statistics, so far this year the most peaceful year.</seg>
<seg id="8">Worth mentioning is that in November and December in seven stages, there was no violence in the assembly elections.</seg>
<seg id="9">In these elections. 13</seg>
<seg id="10">It should be remembered that in the last eighteen years Hizbul Mujahideen is active in Jammu and Kashmir.</seg>
<seg id="11">The program was the first time in July was announced a one - sided, after which the government of India and the talks between the commanders.</seg>
<seg id="12">However, only 15 days within the ceasefire ended.</seg>
<seg id="13">Later, in many different to senior commanders of the Hizbul Mujahideen were killed.</seg>
<seg id="14">Pakistan's famous Daily on Thursday, the News, The Pakistan controlled Kashmir was written about the extremist groups that Lashkar - e - Hizbul and has decided to review its policy of Kashmir.</seg>
<seg id="15">It should be noted that the policy of it was said that the Kashmir issue should be resolved through the armed resistance.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Dera Bugti on gas pipeline explosion</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to police officials, the Loti gas field, the Pir Koh in 18 from Qatar to the pipeline explosion was.</seg>
<seg id="3">This pipeline is the direction of the Sui plant.</seg>
<seg id="4">Meanwhile, the leader of the banned organization, a Republican Army spokesman expressed the Baloch, a person named by telephone organization claimed responsibility for the attack.</seg>
<seg id="5">The fourth in gas pipeline blast on.</seg>
<seg id="6">On Friday in Dera Allah Yar, 18 destroyed the pipeline of the diameter of which Qatar was the repair work on Sunday morning was continued.</seg>
<seg id="7">Sui Southern Gas Company, general manager in Quetta Mushtaq Ahmed has said that the supply of gas from the pipeline after noon will be started.</seg>
<seg id="8">This pipeline is the way of Sibi Quetta.</seg>
<seg id="9">Quetta leaves and other areas in the past three days, there is a severe shortage of gas from where one of the snow is continuing, and has the temperature fell down below 0 OC, and on the other hand, heaters, and stoves have been cool.</seg>
<seg id="10">Besides this market in the city of Dera Bugti motor cycle in the explosion, but according to the police, the loss was not.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Administrator for the party.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Jamaat - e - Tayyaba center of about 25 kilometers away from Lahore in the school.</seg>
<seg id="3">The center in schools and hospitals, the students of the hostel was also included.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Punjab Law Minister Rana Sanaullah Khan said that the Jamaat - I - in the center of deployment for observation, the process has been brought in, so that welfare organizations to work there will not be affected.</seg>
<seg id="5">Emir, Jamaat Khalid Walid according to the center of the located in hospitals, schools and other welfare organizations for the supervision of the chief administrator senior government official has been appointed a while in the center, according to him, the police force has also increased.</seg>
<seg id="6">The UN Security Council has imposed the ban on group which is after the federal government of Pakistan against the Hafiz Saeed and other leaders of the Punjab government. The detainee has been appointed by the center from the federal government should also against the continuation of action.</seg>
<seg id="7">Khaqan Babar, D. G. M. belonged to the district management group.</seg>
<seg id="8">Hafiz Walid Khalid said that the Commissioner of Lahore Division Khusro Pervez Khan on Sunday, police and civil administration with the center and in different parts of the Center. The Khalid Walid by government - appointed administrator in the center of to be condemned and said that the government due to the activities in the center located in the hospital patients and a reduction in the number of children in school.</seg>
<seg id="9">According to a press release, the UN General Secretary of the race for the name of Taliban and the Committee for the moon has written a letter to the Security Council, in which them to the ban imposed on party has appealed to the end.</seg>
<seg id="10">It was said in the letter that the Security Council decision to ban on the party sided is an injustice and no connection with terrorism but it is engaged in welfare work.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Edhi relief mission in Gaza</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In the Gaza Strip entered the need to get permission to after passing through many stages of from New York so far to be successful in Egypt.</seg>
<seg id="3">Speaking with the BBC Urdu service from Cairo, he said that he still could not reach Gaza because Egypt and Israel has many are the obstacles standing.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that I have come here for eight days and is still not allowed him to leave Gaza.</seg>
<seg id="5">In Cairo, in this time and I hope that tomorrow the Gaza will be allowed to get.</seg>
<seg id="6">Giving details, he said: &quot; I am the first to Gaza after only seven days before and after the visa was given to me in insisting on the Pakistani officials and help me and it's only one month, but on the condition that will go only once in Gaza, single.</seg>
<seg id="7">He said that his son and daughters and they want to work in Gaza.</seg>
<seg id="8">&quot; I have brought some of the money.</seg>
<seg id="9">Egypt's Red Cross a check of 100, 000 dollars and 10, 000 dollars in cash so that they are also given in sending relief goods to Gaza.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">In the four more cabinet ministers</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Four new federal ministers and two members of the Jamiat e Ulma e Islam Fazlur Rehman group are included.</seg>
<seg id="3">The new president of Asif Ali Zardari ministers administered the oath.</seg>
<seg id="4">Swearing - in ceremony, the Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani, the federal cabinet members were also present.</seg>
<seg id="5">The four new ministers in the federal cabinet minister, minister of state and the secretaries of the total number.</seg>
<seg id="6">The MQM Dr. Farooq Sattar, and the two ministers, Babar Ghauri and Jamiat Ulema Islam, and Maulana Fazlur Rehman group ur Rehman, and the prime minister.</seg>
<seg id="7">Ministers heard their departments were not announced.</seg>
<seg id="8">The MQM Coordination Committee Dr. Farooq Sattar, while the MQM Senator Babar Ghauri and his period ended on March 10.</seg>
<seg id="9">Senator was elected and the as a senator in the richest one.</seg>
<seg id="10">Moulana Ataur Rahman, a member of the National Assembly and Maulana Fazlur Rehman, the younger brother.</seg>
<seg id="11">It may be recalled that important is working at the four members of the National Assembly are not.</seg>
<seg id="12">It should be noted that on 22 November 2, 2000, eight in the new ministers in the cabinet and the 18 cabinet ministers were included, this time was believed that the cabinet was being made in differences will also be included the distribution of ministries due to the MQM has not been included.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Baluchistan, a gas pipeline in the</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the police, the 18 of the diameter of which is in the pipeline Pir Koh different fields in the Sui gas plant, and the unidentified people blew up in the morning.</seg>
<seg id="3">Besides this, well number three in Sui yesterday to blast was completely destroyed by the explosion and a gas pipeline near Dera Allah Yar, has been damaged by the explosion.</seg>
<seg id="4">The responsibility of the explosions, a banned organization army spokesman on behalf of his organization.</seg>
<seg id="5">In the year 2, 000 have been started in the increase in incidents of violence.</seg>
<seg id="6">So far this month, dozens of gas pipe line was destroyed by the blasts while the rail cars belonging to the Punjab province and an increase in attacks on people.</seg>
<seg id="7">Balochistan Chief Minister Nawab although Aslam has expressed concern over these incidents and police with the orders of the intelligence agencies, but so far is the prevention of these incidents could not be possible.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">819 billion dollars of economic rehabilitation package</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">President of the plan in favor of any belonging to the party from any member who did not vote.</seg>
<seg id="3">Members of the economic plan, said that it is a very expensive ', and will not be effective.</seg>
<seg id="4">The House of Representatives in this package while the opposition in a hundred votes were cast.</seg>
<seg id="5">The economic rehabilitation plan for the next week is to be presented in the Senate, where the ruling Democrat Party is to obtain a simple majority.</seg>
<seg id="6">It is feared that the severe opposition from party due to the approval from the Senate will not be easy.</seg>
<seg id="7">The House of Representatives economic after the approval of the plan of the members, said that he be political differences in the path of this important project.</seg>
<seg id="8">The president said that this plan, in which he expressed the hope that in the next month will form a law adopted in the country will prove be helpful in making a legislative environment prevailing in the US trade promotion.</seg>
<seg id="9">Under this plan, common men and the community of traders for the two hundred billion dollars in loans of 175 out and five hundred and forty billion and roads, bridges, schools, unemployment and of ten thousand new would be given for the research.</seg>
<seg id="10">The BBC correspondent in Washington, Richard has said that the political differences now has been casting a new political culture was to praise the debate on the economic package, but it has once again created bitterness in the political basis.</seg>
<seg id="11">Members in the House of Representatives of the party of the government bill proposed by the government declared a waste of money and said that the new in creating employment will not get any help.</seg>
<seg id="12">He said from the party, he stressed on the bill which proposed that more attention is given in the rebate.</seg>
<seg id="13">He said the package, the much less of investment in the engaging can create more.</seg>
<seg id="14">He said that the construction project in a filing with the practice of taxes immediately create more employment can</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Israeli president, prime minister in bitterness</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Rajab Tayyeb said while crying the Israeli president said that in the Gaza Strip near blood has been shed of human beings in and he was sorry to see that people by the Israeli military operations are conducted on the justification of also rang.</seg>
<seg id="3">Mr. said: &quot; I feel that you might feel such words are used and that the people and their children, to remember those who have been killed near the beach.</seg>
<seg id="4">Said the tragedy of that Israel is not Hamas, which has been set up there a dangerous dictator</seg>
<seg id="5">A BBC correspondent to said that the World Economic Forum in the first ever seen such mishaps.</seg>
<seg id="6">However, he said that the president of respect, and he also, because of which they not yell at them but what he was saying miles away from the truth.</seg>
<seg id="7">Turkey, the sugar cane is likely in Muslim countries which have diplomatic relations with Israel, but is found in the last few years.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">&quot; attack in Pakistan</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">An Indian TV channel, N. D., while talking to Wajid Shams Hasan said that the Pakistani investigation report of the Mumbai attacks will be issued soon.</seg>
<seg id="3">The attacks in Mumbai last November in more than one hundred and seventy people were killed.</seg>
<seg id="4">India has said that the responsibility of the attack extremist organization Lashkar - e - Taiba.</seg>
<seg id="5">India has also said that the Mumbai bombings in Pakistan ' state elements &quot; were involved.</seg>
<seg id="6">After the Mumbai attack the relations between the two countries have been affected.</seg>
<seg id="7">Shams ul Hassan, the Pakistani High Commissioner Hasan made about the investigation which is the first statement as it is said that the investigation in the report.</seg>
<seg id="8">Wajid as far as a result of their investigations have reached on the soil of Pakistan, has not been used.</seg>
<seg id="9">It is also not be, Britain and place.</seg>
<seg id="10">These two places and Britain (Pakistan) , which I was worried about.</seg>
<seg id="11">Mumbai, India and the international community of the attack to take action against Pakistan has made a lot of pressure in Pakistan has said that the attacks in Mumbai for allegedly involved in dozens of groups against the action was taken into custody.</seg>
<seg id="12">Wajid, Shams - ul - Hasan said: &quot; We are not trying to disguise.</seg>
<seg id="13">We believe in to take action on the facts.</seg>
<seg id="14">Our investigation approved the world.</seg>
<seg id="15">The results of investigation (India) , we will try to be satisfied.</seg>
<seg id="16">He said that the delay in the investigation of Defense said that this kind of explosives, and to make to understand the and this is a.</seg>
<seg id="17">The high commissioner of Wajid Shams ul Hasan said that India has started to present himself in 45 days.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Also elected leader of the black</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Republican Party in the elections in the sixth round, away from a votes in to win votes.</seg>
<seg id="3">Chairman of the party in the elections a candidate for the post of 77 votes, while former Chairman Duncan in the second stage competition from.</seg>
<seg id="4">Correspondents say that the chairman of the Republican Party candidate for the championship, which were five Michael in the most moderate leader, have been accepted.</seg>
<seg id="5">After the victory in his address, said Michael rivals with one of his friends and saying that you are with us, but this the people who would like to show in the US to be ready for where he has also served as the deputy governor.</seg>
<seg id="6">Two thousand in six at the time when he was standing in the elections for a seat.</seg>
<seg id="7">But in the Senate elections after losing a political party the Helms, the chairman of the committee were made.</seg>
<seg id="8">Now the party after being elected the chairman of the Republican Party of the country - wide campaign of these efforts will be made of them in the head.</seg>
<seg id="9">He said that the election on the promise that he received a new agenda through the party to give the Conservatives and supporters from the party for will use new technical means.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">In Jammu Lashkar - e - Tayyaba and Jaish - e - Mohammad claimed the presence of Indian</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In Poonch in Jammu the corpse of one of the militants present information.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to government officials on the information, the army and police cordon off the area and started.</seg>
<seg id="4">During the clash began in which four militants, two soldiers and a policeman was killed.</seg>
<seg id="5">According to meet in the final reports of the clashes were continuing in the region and to the Lashkar - e - Tayyaba and Jaish Muhammad associated with the militants are present in the army to further of there has been sent.</seg>
<seg id="6">During this coalition government nominated by the Chief Minister Omar Abdullah and his meeting with his party's national conference on behalf of the leader of the Assembly of the organization in the area reported.</seg>
<seg id="7">The national conference of party ally, the Congress has also informed him of the support.</seg>
<seg id="8">Omar Abdullah, chief minister of the state, the status will be made to take oath.</seg>
<seg id="9">It may be recalled the state elections that 87 members of the National Conference of the 28 seats in the house after having become the biggest party. . It should be noted that a separation the parties in the elections.</seg>
<seg id="10">The congress, which were obtained 17 seats, the national conference to agree on a coalition government with them.</seg>
<seg id="11">Today Srinagar on the arrival of the party with Omar Abdullah, received a warm era.</seg>
<seg id="12">On this occasion, Omar Abdullah has said that talks between the government and separatists to role, however, the elections will be held in India, and this will not be possible for the new government coming to power.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Peace in the Middle East and the role of the European Union.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">If the government from the war in the Middle East, to stop the reconciliation efforts in the decisive role of the European Union.</seg>
<seg id="3">Berg delegation, according to the order, or this job efforts are in the hand.</seg>
<seg id="4">The European Commission spokesman Amadeu altafaj He said that every effort is commendable try the European Union through a joint message of the parties to get help in May.</seg>
<seg id="5">In the government statement, there is all right.</seg>
<seg id="6">But the European Union family slowly inside a picture is regrettable.</seg>
<seg id="7">The president of the Czech Republic on the role of the already weak.</seg>
<seg id="8">The internal squabbles him the helpless.</seg>
<seg id="9">On the other French he is still president of the European Union presidency be giving duty.</seg>
<seg id="10">Although France presidential term of six months has.</seg>
<seg id="11">Want to play and they can also, but they are not allowed.</seg>
<seg id="12">The most ridiculous situation with Bernard Kouchner, the French foreign minister.</seg>
<seg id="13">They are included in the delegation, led by the foreign minister of the Czech Republic are Schwarzenberg.</seg>
<seg id="14">It said that this was a war in the Middle East, the two foreign ministers are different statements.</seg>
<seg id="15">Schwarzenberg says Israel to defend themselves have the right that Kouchner near the defense in the category of war is not on the other hand, Germany has also been a special emissary to the Middle East is. . Unless the European Union, based on equal order to show national harmony, not on the diplomatic front, it may not be successful</seg>
<seg id="16">. This is the proof of Israel is the practice of no importance to Europe's reconciliation efforts.</seg>
<seg id="17">The European Union is to do something this time a golden opportunity because the United States due to the policies of the George W. Bush has failed in the Middle East.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The financial crisis, a German industrialist of billionaires suicide</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In the area of the South Germany has a very big business group, left.</seg>
<seg id="3">But some time ago, a German common citizens do not know much about them.</seg>
<seg id="4">When he and industrial group 30 near the banks to have talks with several weeks, even though they also became the subject of group, they also look to the future of the dark.</seg>
<seg id="5">The group deserves German Institute for the purchase of the shares of the financial crisis due to the loss of several hundred million euros had also to bear.</seg>
<seg id="6">The financial institutions, said the group is to essentially 700 million and 1 billion euros worth of new loans declined to give, came under pressure.</seg>
<seg id="7">Some time ago, the bank group on an emergency basis to provide loans, but they were ready to have a small industrialists that this position that the industrial group of the annual income of approximately 30 billion euros irresponsible power investment could not bear to deprivation.</seg>
<seg id="8">After the death of his father died when he took his family business on the lines while it is also very development soon.</seg>
<seg id="9">He named ratiopharm Company of Germany, which today is very successful and large drug manufacturing company.</seg>
<seg id="10">For some time before the drug of organization, between five and six billion euros worth of business and it still has an annual income of 1.8 billion euros. Form after the tremendous success of the group has many big institutions to purchase in which the construction equipment to prepare for the cement from the types of vehicles to the company is also named kssbohrer is ready.</seg>
<seg id="11">The number of employees all over the world, the group is approximately 100 in the drug manufacturing company a form of medicine makers to get special importance.</seg>
<seg id="12">His life in many times said: &quot; We have four generations.</seg>
<seg id="13">The arrangement of this organization is my children and I hope that this organization is still only a few hundred years in my family will continue.</seg>
<seg id="14">Commit suicide of the banks of the group after vem for interim loans worth 400 million euros of the approval is given, but the condition is that vem sell form to be the group's financial position so that on the basis of a long term can be better.</seg>
<seg id="15">Thus, after the death of the group, they will not remain which he never.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Foreigners in Germany people in the crime rate</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The latest statistics from 2004 to 2007, between the the crime rate of 22.</seg>
<seg id="3">9 percent to be slashed to 21.</seg>
<seg id="4">Has come to 4 percent.</seg>
<seg id="5">The province of Interior Minister Joachim Herrmann, only familiar with it a positive changes.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said: &quot; it necessary to be kept in mind that German citizenship to get the number of foreigners.</seg>
<seg id="7">Therefore, it should be said that the statistics was to commit the crime of the German citizen, but this background of foreign.</seg>
<seg id="8">Herrmann said that his province with the criminals in the collection of data, the time it will continue keeping.</seg>
<seg id="9">Besides in province is also thought to be on the lines.</seg>
<seg id="10">The CDU from the Interior Affairs ahlhaus in a scientific way, said: &quot; When the research is the man, already in its own results can not but it depends on statistics which come after research.</seg>
<seg id="11">The provincial office of the anti - crime ahlhaus a, drew attention to the report, which was prepared under the part of the city in bergdorf discovered it was part of foreigners in the crime that is how many percent.</seg>
<seg id="12">It was known that the results of the foreigners here.</seg>
<seg id="13">All the crime rate in the province in the face of the crimes.</seg>
<seg id="14">On the contrary, when the young in the crime rate in the survey, it has come forth foreign background to the youth, the ratio of 44.</seg>
<seg id="15">7 percent.</seg>
<seg id="16">However, other political parties of Germany, for example, a SPD - wing nationalists, the Party and the Jamaat - e - Linkspartei that this proposal is against the time the crime and figures related to information should be collected that what is the background of the German citizens foreign.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">We want to withdraw forces from Gaza: soon</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The masses stressed the complete withdrawal of forces for a permanent and lasting ceasefire agreement is necessary.</seg>
<seg id="3">On Sunday, Israel and Hamas has announced the war.</seg>
<seg id="4">Islamic militant group Hamas has announced a ceasefire on Saturday, said that the Israeli forces within a week the Gaza Strip, and cordoned off the end of the Gaza Strip.</seg>
<seg id="5">On the other hand, the leader of Hamas has said that the war in Gaza to Israel on behalf of the God's victory</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that he was in Gaza and Israel failed to achieve their goals.</seg>
<seg id="7">Prior to this, the Egyptian city of Sharm el - Sheikh on Sunday in the European leaders of Arab countries and a meeting was held in which the withdrawal of Israeli forces from Gaza was demanded immediate.</seg>
<seg id="8">In the meeting it was decided that the international relief for the Gaza conference will be held.</seg>
<seg id="9">In the meeting, the German chancellor also participated.</seg>
<seg id="10">Israel and Hamas three weeks for the ongoing war at least 13 Palestinians and 10 Israeli soldiers were killed, including 13</seg>
<seg id="11">Other Palestinian President Abbas has stressed the need to form a national government.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The name of al - Qaeda's video message</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The duration of 30 minutes in the video, a black person wearing the color of mouth and taking guns in hand a message to the German government is.</seg>
<seg id="3">The man in the been introduced and in conducting a German language and is.</seg>
<seg id="4">There are all the Arabic of video message.</seg>
<seg id="5">On the screen of al - Qa ' ida, and the history of has been registered in 2008.</seg>
<seg id="6">In the message, the German government has been that such a large number of troops deployed in Afghanistan in the country and expressed the belief that it is doing will not be the attack, it is not, and</seg>
<seg id="7">The person who are telling themselves not on the threat of indirect attacks.</seg>
<seg id="8">At NATO in Afghanistan, the number of German soldiers in about three and a half thousand.</seg>
<seg id="9">The German parliament in October last year, more than 1, 000 troops to Afghanistan to give approval of the law.</seg>
<seg id="10">Germany to the to meet the, this is the first message.</seg>
<seg id="11">Terrorism affairs, to keep an eye on the renowned Mikhail lders, the message of the &quot; in Kabul recently, in front of the German embassy in the suicide attack is a proof that we take it seriously in any circumstances.</seg>
<seg id="12">The last few years is issued messages on the Internet video messages and there were also after the attack.</seg>
<seg id="13">On Saturday, the German embassy in Kabul suicide attack outside the Taliban have taken the responsibility of the military organization.</seg>
<seg id="14">Most German newspapers the attack and observers are looking to the link to message.</seg>
<seg id="15">&quot; They are the target of Germany.</seg>
<seg id="16">The basis, Germany's Party of the Muslims, Afghan policy should be added to the negative.</seg>
<seg id="17">The German government not only in Afghanistan, the Middle East but also adopt a policy of accusing.</seg>
<seg id="18">Germany, and because they have to understand more than its target.</seg>
<seg id="19">Meanwhile, the German government has said that the video on the scene before the German intelligence agencies know about this.</seg>
<seg id="20">German federal anti - crime of Organization of the video is busy in the message.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Assumed the post of US presidency.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In this context, the American people, on the one hand, the entire world from different expectations were made.</seg>
<seg id="3">Now the United States, the president received congratulations from all over the messages are subject to their expectations are coming forth.</seg>
<seg id="4">In this regard, the German chancellor on the new president expressed confidence.</seg>
<seg id="5">&quot; I believe that the Federal Republic of Germany and deep friendship between the United States and on the basis of partnership we can solve the problems.</seg>
<seg id="6">Russian Prime Minister is the owner of a serious and open hearts, and it is a good thing.</seg>
<seg id="7">Thus, the former U. S. President George W. Bush's policies on the face of criticism.</seg>
<seg id="8">However, the administration to China at the international level to play a more constructive role of the Movement for the new president is appreciated, while the China has said that he strong military relations between the two countries will have to work.</seg>
<seg id="9">In the German city of active politics, the Chinese expert says:</seg>
<seg id="10">&quot; In this context, I am sure that in the coming weeks and months and his economic team will cast and the Beijing government to pressure for the Chinese currency market and a and the exchange rate will be forced to adopt.</seg>
<seg id="11">Former US administration has made to further relations with India.</seg>
<seg id="12">Where these relations are conducive to take, in this connection in New Delhi, the professor of the American Studies rule says: &quot; Now we have more close strategic partnership, at every moment, but can not bringing any change.</seg>
<seg id="13">Pope also had a message in the name of peace in the world and to promote cooperation in the atmosphere has stressed upon.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Provincial Elections in Iraq.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The year 2005 after the war - torn country in the first important elections.</seg>
<seg id="3">Provincial seats in the elections for the 14, have landed in more than 400.</seg>
<seg id="4">During the elections to maintain law and order situation in the 8, 000 police and soldiers have been stationed in Iraq.</seg>
<seg id="5">In view of this danger that no explosion or any such important day and not be attacks all the borders of Iraq, only one day before the cell on Friday.</seg>
<seg id="6">In addition, the airport have been closed and public transport ban has been imposed on.</seg>
<seg id="7">According to the information, because of transport ban on traffic the roads and the Iraqi children are seen playing football on the roads are active.</seg>
<seg id="8">During the recent Iraqi elections and the security situation on the one hand, it will be the year of 2011, the US military forces in Iraq after returning from local agencies of the country's reigns or there would be no political analyst, on the other hand, it also experience, which are taking estimate democratic way that the Iraqi people to bring about changes in the country are ready to what extent.</seg>
<seg id="9">The United Nations to help provincial elections are being held in and around eight hundred international observers are to observe the election process.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Iran today, all the Yaum aashura the Yaum aashura Hazrat Imam Hussain (of the great respect and honor was celebrated with memory of sacrifice</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to a report of the Mehr news agency, the Iranian capital of Tehran, all small and big cities, including Syed Hazrat Imam Hussein () was marked with great respect and reverence said on this occasion the believers of Islam and Majalis Aza rallies in a large number of Prophet Mohammad (PBUH) and them (the of the condolence of whole Iran today's son of Prophet Mohammad (PBUH) , Hazrat Imam Hussain (in the field of the azadar and mourning in memory of is of sacrifice of Hazrat Imam Hussain (in the field of the Karbala, for example, of the latest example of the sacrifice, and large - scale and remember on a large scale and also to participate in the meeting.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Israeli troops from the Gaza Strip area of example of the Palestinian Mujahideen loyalty</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the Mehr news agency in the Gaza Strip the day of the 16th of battle also Israel's civilian population from bombardment continued air, ground and naval attacks on the Gaza till now and 880 persons killed in 3700 and Palestinians were injured.</seg>
<seg id="3">275 innocent at which are included in the Arab leaders called the treachery and international human rights organizations, lost their lives in the embrace of the death.</seg>
<seg id="4">Gaza today the burial of Mujahidins area, the Israeli soldiers forced the faith and support to the use of force and and of splendid of tolerance and the Zionist enemy, we are trying to narrow life.</seg>
<seg id="5">Egyptian President Hosny, if not, the Swiss of Hamas, Mujahid the noble and brave to stay away from the Israeli siege, but have been four, but with the Palestinians, Egypt has also made the Muslim siege of the Arab history, which is the most terrible incident.</seg>
<seg id="6">The Saudi Arabia and also to political, economic, and help to the the unarmed of the Muslims in the Gaza Strip and are giving the Israelis</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The United States with Iran will adopt a new strategy</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the Mehr news agency report, the United States has been elected president of the ABC news channel said that while talking with Iran on the issue of new and modern will adopt strategy.</seg>
<seg id="3">Said that &quot; Iran big challenges for the American government will be &quot;.</seg>
<seg id="4">Said that Islamic organization Hamas and Hezbollah Iranian support and concern over Iran's nuclear program of.</seg>
<seg id="5">In Iran, but he said the present President Bush's policy relations with Iran and we will not be different in the policy.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the real aim to completely clear, mutual respect and stressed the desire of the talks will give in.</seg>
<seg id="7">In the past, have also said that the talks with Iran in the first not impose any conditions.</seg>
<seg id="8">During the interview, he expressed the hope that his administration to the people of Iran on this new strategy will be the '.</seg>
<seg id="9">The Middle East crisis, he said that in this connection, a special team are formed</seg>
<seg id="10">Efforts for the establishment of peace in the middle of the started work after January 20.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">George Bush US President Bush, in his address to the press acknowledged the mistake.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr news agency quoting told the Associated Press that the US President George W. Bush in his last press conference in its mistakes and admitted the crimes.</seg>
<seg id="3">The White House President Bush, while addressing the press conference he said that the newly elected President the sentiments of goodwill, however, for this on the United States that it will be possible to attack the stop.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the completion of the mission in Iraq and social security reforms his mistakes.</seg>
<seg id="5">President Bush has said that whatever he did so for the protection of the United States.</seg>
<seg id="6">The Israeli aggression in Gaza in response to the many questions were asked about President Bush has said that Israel has right to defend themselves according to him, Hamas has not got the right to defend himself and should not be the United States to the world the brutal instead of the oppressed and Gila.</seg>
<seg id="7">Incompetent and people of the United States, the president said that the United States and to provide weapons to Israel to join the United States to the world's most deadly and destructive weapons is providing the massacre of Palestinians in Israel, because Bush has to benefit from the United States is also praised the pro - Israel and Arabs and eliminate a friend of Israel.</seg>
<seg id="8">Bush has held in Abu Ghraib and jails on some crime expressed his shame.</seg>
<seg id="9">Observers say Bush is on the case for war crimes should be established and the organizations who will carry out this job would be a very good deeds on the humanity.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Iranian President Ahmadinejad president of the Arab countries leaders expressed their concern on the quiet.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the Mehr news agency report said that the president of Iran, Dr. origin, the Israeli aggression on the Gaza Strip and the leaders of silence on the injustice and oppression criticism over the grief expressed took place.</seg>
<seg id="3">The origin of the Arab countries, and the head of summits on Israel's barbaric action on Gaza on surprise, said that the Palestinian people is of Palestinian children and women Arab civilians, is targeting of their violence and a statement issued by the could not.</seg>
<seg id="4">President Ahmadi Nejad said that all Arab countries is united against Israel and Gaza for the oppressed Muslims to Israel and to the evil and injustice and oppression of the innocent.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Ahmadinejad, the King of Saudi Arabia in the Gaza Strip by Israel, the human race into their viewpoint about it.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the Mehr news agency report, the president Mahmood Ahmadi Nejad said the ruler of Saudi Arabia, the name of the country, Abdullah said in his message is that the King of Saudi Arabia Muslims of the genocide in the Gaza Strip on the human race in the Gaza Strip and massacre of innocent women and children the silence of Islam and encourage the reason for the visitors there.</seg>
<seg id="3">President Ahmadinejad said in his message is that you the right in the Gaza Strip and the order to support the oppressed people and will be consolidated and that the enemies of the grave differences they failed efforts</seg>
<seg id="4">President Ahmadi Nejad said in his message that you know that 19 days in the Gaza Strip from Israel and massacre of innocent children mosques, schools and hospitals is the brutal bombing in the Gaza Strip, the Israeli government toward massacre is in these circumstances, your silence as the leaders of Israel, the initiatives of</seg>
<seg id="5">President Ahmadi Abdullah said that the country and like non - Islamic countries against Israel, then you have to take solid steps to meet the expectations of the these countries.</seg>
<seg id="6">President Ahmadi Nejad said that the success of the Palestinians in the Gaza Strip will prosper.</seg>
<seg id="7">And they will get victory on the and it is promise Allah.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Osama will continue to teach in Palestine</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the Mehr news agency report, the Hamas representative in Lebanon Usama Bin Ladin, the French news agency said that while talking with the International said that Israel has one - sided ceasefire by comprehensive cease fire against the efforts of the when he said that Gaza is still present in will continue until the ceasefire to the time this will be meaningless</seg>
<seg id="3">He said that a ceasefire to avoid defeat by the Israel's failed attempt to said that if Israel wants peace that it is to end with the Hamas to accept the conditions</seg>
<seg id="4">Hamas leaders in Lebanon has made it clear that the Israeli army in the rest of the Gaza Strip if Israel has sided the cease fire, the resistance will continue.</seg>
<seg id="5">Beirut while addressing severing ties with Israel, asking the European countries.</seg>
<seg id="6">The Hamas leader said that increasing the number of injured has been our courage and determination and will be raised.</seg>
<seg id="7">He said that the Palestinian people, he said that the war against the enemy in a resistance.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Pakistan tribal region of North Waziristan, in Pakistan has killed six people.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency has reported that tribal region of North Waziristan, two Afghan civilians and four Pakistanis accused of spying Talibans have killed here.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to the local people on Tuesday morning Chowk area of Tehsil in which four dead bodies are totally shot and killed.</seg>
<seg id="4">The president while two bodies were found from the place are thrown in the market was a market.</seg>
<seg id="5">The dead bodies were found in Urdu also written letters in which has been claimed that spying.</seg>
<seg id="6">Two weeks ago in North Waziristan, the president of the two Afghan nationals accused of was murdered.</seg>
<seg id="7">In the last 12 days 15 people accused of spying for the United States have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="8">It should be noted that in the north and south Waziristan during the six years, more than 100 people on charges of espionage have been killed in the Taliban is that they are involved in the murder cases.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The jail to the order of the expected signed the petition</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency has reported that the sources of the US president today ordered to shut the jail will be signed the petition</seg>
<seg id="3">New U. S. president Hussain his election campaign at the level of well organized, has started.</seg>
<seg id="4">In this connection the president of the American army from Iraq, for the plan while today, to the US president the jail to the order will be signed the petition.</seg>
<seg id="5">It is being expected that the president today signed this order, who are under which the sentence will be closed within a year.</seg>
<seg id="6">Apart from this the suspected terrorists from the White House to review the ways of investigation and prisoners from also ordered a ban on it is likely that there will be.</seg>
<seg id="7">President the first day of his election promises to fulfill and started to work on the first and the process of his government to make steps are taken.</seg>
<seg id="8">Observers say that the the international level, and President of the United States to have started efforts to protect them success in this meet, but it is very difficult, because the United States and Israel until the government on the support of waist till then it is a United States wants to save its reputation in the world, then it is Israel's should be deprived from diarrhoea and this should not be involved in crimes.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Tony Blair Islamic organization Hamas stressed the need to be included in the talks</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Mehr News Agency, the British Times newspaper that British Prime Minister Tony Blair said the peace process in the Middle East to include Hamas, has stressed the need.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to the newspaper, Tony Blair said that it is important that a way should be found out through which Hamas, in the Middle East peace process has to be brought in only Mahmoud Abbas, Bush to talk to and to ignore the Hamas also criticized the Western countries have made it clear that Hamas and Nizami power, and now it should be included in the dialogue to be before this, he said, while Hamas as a terrorist organization, the e - mail to a terrorist organization, which is trying to defend their country is from his home to occupation of the others is free from the struggle of the House, which is based on the country usurping like Israel and the government has seized more than 60 years, with the man.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The businessmen in Karachi, the murder of a complete strike in Quetta.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The four businessmen in Karachi on Thursday to protest against the killing of complete strike in Quetta and some other areas.</seg>
<seg id="3">During this period, all the business centers remained closed while the traffic also was less than usual.</seg>
<seg id="4">The protest strike for appeal in Balochistan, the Association of cattle, had Milli Awami Party and Jamiat e Ulema e Islam, who alleged that traders, Karachi police allegedly killed in firing at the time when his car in their vehicles on the road of Tariq was reached.</seg>
<seg id="5">The president of Merchants Association has demanded that the incident involved in police arrested action will be taken against them.</seg>
<seg id="6">However, this incident in the Karachi police immediately there.</seg>
<seg id="7">The four businessmen belong to the border town of Chaman.</seg>
<seg id="8">Strike on the occasion of the government on a large scale the security arrangements were made, and all important places in the city and the police were deployed, the TMA.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Commander of Hamas was killed in Israeli attack</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">An aerial attack in Israel, a senior commander of Hamas was killed.</seg>
<seg id="3">In the Gaza Strip to Israel's continued attacks a week of Hamas in the killing of other important person.</seg>
<seg id="4">Hamas officials said that Abu Zakaria Saturday, located in the east of Gaza City were killed in localities.</seg>
<seg id="5">The Israeli air attacks Thursday and in the world, dull of Hamas were killed.</seg>
<seg id="6">Syria is living in exile expressed determination to take revenge from and ground attack on Gaza, warned against Israel.</seg>
<seg id="7">Israel on the Gaza border of thousands of soldiers and tanks are deployed and they are waiting for the orders.</seg>
<seg id="8">The United States has appealed to the cease - fire but said that the military on Gaza or the decision not to depend on Israel.</seg>
<seg id="9">US President George W. Bush in his weekly radio speech on Hamas violence on the anger of the allegation, and the rockets on Israel's attacks as terrorism.</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the cease fire in the United States are working for a bilateral agreement, but there will not be acceptable.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Three bodies recovered in North Waziristan</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Pakistani security officials said that three men in the North Waziristan tribal region bodies were found.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is believed that the Taliban had given the death of them have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="4">The bodies of near Miran Shah, the main town of North and they were found with such men have been found in which the United States has been accused of spying.</seg>
<seg id="5">Officials said that it is probably a body which is the local the man was kidnapped last week.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said if the remaining two - riddled bodies of Afghan nationals.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Joseph elected US Vice President Arrives in Pakistan</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">External Affairs Minister has welcomed the US vice president</seg>
<seg id="3">The United States sees elected vice president on a tour of Pakistan, along with his delegation arrived in Islamabad on Friday.</seg>
<seg id="4">External Affairs Shah Mahmood Qureshi, chief of and the US embassy officials have welcomed him.</seg>
<seg id="5">US Senator Lindsy Graham was also in this tour.</seg>
<seg id="6">The U. S. embassy press officer low the Voice of America, said that the newly elected President during his visit, the Pakistani leadership will hold talks on regional issues, he said, however, declined to disclose more details.</seg>
<seg id="7">According to the sources of the Foreign Office, Joseph high government officials of the army chief General Pervez Musharraf to Ashfaq, will meet.</seg>
<seg id="8">It is expected that these meetings in bilateral and international issues related to the war against terrorism will also exchange views on the issues.</seg>
<seg id="9">Joseph retzinger was Hilal to Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="10">After his arrival in Islamabad, said the president, Joseph Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
<seg id="11">In the meeting, the president of Pakistan and the United States to set up the close ties between the role of in the Pakistan - Hilal recipient of the honor.</seg>
<seg id="12">It should be noted that last year, the U. S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee chairman Senator as of with a bill, which was introduced in the next five years the United States during the non - military aid and three times increase to 7.5 billion dollars has been recommended.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Former President Pervez Musharraf's uniform, has played an important role, in Prime Minister</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Yousaf Raza Gilani and file photo</seg>
<seg id="3">Yousaf Raza Gilani, the prime minister said that the United States, who has been elected vice president of former President Pervez Musharraf's uniform, to leave the post of the army, and has played an important role in and made of democracy in the subject for help</seg>
<seg id="4">Yousuf Raza. The statement of Karachi ship yard while talking to the journalists.</seg>
<seg id="5">He said that the &quot; or &quot; pro - supporters of Pakistan, and they are as chairman of the Foreign Affairs Committee of the US Senate of a bill to the aid of 15 billion dollars.</seg>
<seg id="6">American spy planes to the US once again condemned the prime minister of Pakistan with government, is not any kind of agreement, and Pakistan's it is a matter of independence such attacks in the country so that they can not allow any</seg>
<seg id="7">He also expressed hope that the United States in the new government after the United States changes in will come.</seg>
<seg id="8">(file)</seg>
<seg id="9">Yousaf Raza said that the government has made a great success to the terrorists from the tribal, but this is the government efforts made a missile attack planes to harm for tribes and terrorists are to get.</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the international community agreed to the stand of Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="11">The prime minister further said that if no reliable evidence given to Pakistan forces will themselves in action.</seg>
<seg id="12">The attacks in Mumbai, the Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani its stand has said that if India will provide evidence on this basis will be investigated and found evidence of the involvement of, according to the country against the law will be conducted.</seg>
<seg id="13">The country's tour of Britain and Rahman visited the MQM leader Altaf Hussain, the meeting, in response to a question, the prime minister said his country Rahman allowed to London.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Quetta, the DSP, including four policemen killed</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Files.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Quetta a highway road in firing by unknown persons, the one on the DSP, a deputy police, including four police personnel.</seg>
<seg id="4">On Wednesday morning in a jeep and two DSP, a sub - inspector and two police constables were training center said that the degree College situated on the road near the motor cycle by unknown assailants on the jeep, the police started firing on which sub inspector and Mehdi were killed on the spot when a constable pagara when a DSP Hassan Ali, had died after reaching the hospital.</seg>
<seg id="5">Hospital sources say that the other seriously injured the DSP Ghulam is also in critical condition, and he bullet in the head and neck.</seg>
<seg id="6">After this incident, the police surrounded the area has the responsibility of the incident will not accept any.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The death of another Indian software engineer</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In Andhra Pradesh from the United States, and a software shot and killed by unknown attackers.</seg>
<seg id="3">The 26 - year - old living in state unknown attacked in two days ago to attacker in hospital for medical aid, during the prayer.</seg>
<seg id="4">He was an employee of the United States and services in the jet was visible.</seg>
<seg id="5">Andhra Pradesh in the past year the hands of the United States, social elements have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="6">Higher education and employment in the United States for the production of the increasing number of students of the thousands of families in the province have created concern in which children are living in the United States.</seg>
<seg id="7">It should be noted that the higher education and better future Andhra Pradesh in the United States is given priority.</seg>
<seg id="8">According to the data from the US consulate in Chennai, south India, US visa for every year to one lakh in which all are received, more than 40 percent of which are from Andhra Pradesh.</seg>
<seg id="9">In the meantime, the provincial government has made efforts to bring the body of Hyderabad have started.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The attacks against the US forces are easily: Bush</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">President George W. Bush, in his last weekly speech on the United States that the enemy are vigilant against attacks.</seg>
<seg id="3">Mr. Bush said that for the Americans and the biggest threat the there is a possibility that the attack, and he warned that the enemies of the country are waiting with patience and they have been under to war again.</seg>
<seg id="4">The president said the United States never definitely going should not be negligent of their safety.</seg>
<seg id="5">President Bush for the next president Ehud Barak also expressed best wishes, who will take his post on Tuesday.</seg>
<seg id="6">The newly elected President Barak the Democratic Party in his speech on the radio on Saturday in the oath - taking ceremony of the light on the historic importance.</seg>
<seg id="7">He said that this is a tradition of the ceremony, which is a leader of the other leaders to peace on the transfer of power to the greatness of very deep link with us.</seg>
<seg id="8">Mr. has reminded that many people from all over the world, it can not even think that their leaders of the carnage of conflict or the powers would be deprived from without.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Sharif brothers, and the wind the interior minister in security, political and exchanged views on the matters.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The biggest opposition and in Punjab, the ruling party Pakistan Muslim League (N) and Federal Interior Minister Aftab between the country on Sunday, meeting in the Punjab Chief Minister Shahbaz Sharif were also present.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to local media, the country, the possible on the leadership of the Pakistan People's Party was an important message to.</seg>
<seg id="4">However, speaking to journalists after the meeting in Rahman to this country has not given details and only said that the political affairs said that he is a consensus among the politics of Mumbai, and the situation after the attack on the P. M. L. n the leadership of the briefing.</seg>
<seg id="5">In his words so far as the operation is to provide information about it.</seg>
<seg id="6">Remember that the big operation there in Punjab and the Punjab government and is still in the team, which has been formed to the Punjab government is in need of help.</seg>
<seg id="7">Malik said that every day, the media, but it has not been revealed to the P. M. L. n the leadership of the daily exchange of. Meanwhile, on the other hand, spokesman of the Pakistan Muslim League (N) , Rashid said Musharraf is also in the political affairs, to tell Mr. Malik, who said that the country has been telling.</seg>
<seg id="8">It should be noted that the leadership of Pakistan Muslim League (N) and advisor to the interior of the meeting that there is such a time when the government that politics in Punjab province and the Warm Summer P. M. L. in more than 20 with the governor of Punjab in a press conference with Salman P. M. L. N, administrators of the steps taken by the provincial government, rejecting the criticism of the government, the Pakistan People's Party, belonging to the governor of Punjab in the participation in this matter on the inclusion of objection.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Pakistan's speech is a welcome President Zardari for</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Pakistani President of the new president of the United States, Asif Ali Zardari Barak welcome the opening address said that the Muslim world with mutual interests and respect to enhancing the relationship between Pakistan and its people for the promising.</seg>
<seg id="3">On Wednesday issued a statement in which he said that the US president values and ideas with the reiterated and people around the world and the the hope of a better future.</seg>
<seg id="4">Zardari, according to the statement, the president said that the United States with the international community in the 21st century together with the peace, prosperity and development of the new finding Hali important to have a responsibility.</seg>
<seg id="5">It should be remembered that president on Tuesday after taking his oath in the opening address, said that the United States wants the Muslim world with the new initiative which is based on mutual interests and mutual respect.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said the poor countries, assured them that the United States should work together with there so that social development and poverty.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The president appointed special representative for Afghanistan and Pakistan.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Richard Hall former Hall for the United Nations to Pakistan and Afghanistan has been appointed as special.</seg>
<seg id="3">Hall in the Bosnian peace agreement and to play an important role.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that President on matters of Afghanistan and Pakistan are ready for consultation.</seg>
<seg id="5">He added that it is not an easy task.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that history is different from both countries.</seg>
<seg id="7">George was elected for the Middle East to have been the Arab peace talks that Israel will try.</seg>
<seg id="8">Former Senator and Northern Ireland in peace, he said played a role in the event.</seg>
<seg id="9">While talking in the State Department said today that the Middle East situation, a very complicated and dangerous.</seg>
<seg id="10">But despite this, the United States and the efforts of peace will not back down.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Afghanistan: voter registration has been in danger.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Afghanistan's Election Commission has said that he was concerned about the security in some areas of the south due to the delay in voter registration.</seg>
<seg id="3">In southern Afghanistan near the voter registration for the presidential election this week began.</seg>
<seg id="4">But the commission has said that until the security situation will not improve, in some areas of Halmand province the voter register will not be able to get.</seg>
<seg id="5">These areas in the south violence last year to Afghan army and the international forces have increased their attacks.</seg>
<seg id="6">Meanwhile, Afghan army and the international forces, has said that he has on Wednesday and Thursday nights and increases in Afghanistan during the clashes at least 28 militants were killed.</seg>
<seg id="7">NATO said that the eastern Khost province near the border have killed 22 militants in air and ground attacks.</seg>
<seg id="8">Earlier, Afghan Defense Ministry said that the Afghan forces in the province has eight rebels were killed and two injured.</seg>
<seg id="9">It was not clear whether Afghan officials referred to the incident.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Frontier government has rejected the ban on the demand of education.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Border officials during the Taliban militants in the Swat banned on the threat of the girls education rejected by saying that this was announced, it is against Islam and both the law.</seg>
<seg id="3">On Sunday, the education minister of the border province Sardar Hussain Babar further said that the government efforts to do that will not succeed.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the extremists in children deprived of education in the region.</seg>
<seg id="5">In his words: &quot; These people stealing is hiding the schools and children trying to.</seg>
<seg id="6">The atmosphere of fear and harassment, the provincial government, he said that it is well aware of the fact that it wants to clear the land can not stop the power to promotion of education.</seg>
<seg id="7">One day ago, under the leadership of Maulana Fazal, Taliban militants from January 15 educational institutions have demanded the banning the education of girls and threatened to break that the institutions will be destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="8">Suwat, in spite of the ongoing military action during the last one and a half years, approximately 150 of the educational institutions to the militants exploded the explosives destroyed in the arrow.</seg>
<seg id="9">In the educational institutions to destroy thousands of girls and boys have been deprived of their education.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">On the occasion of Republic Day in India on the strict security arrangements</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In India Republic Day is being celebrated the 60th anniversary of this occasion all the security arrangements, and throughout the thousands of soldiers were deployed.</seg>
<seg id="3">On the occasion of the Republic Day parade in New Delhi during the military weapons, planes and other military equipments of the exhibition.</seg>
<seg id="4">Officials said that the security arrangements under the anti - aircraft battery and sharp &quot; and parade have also been deployed on the routes of the police and the US president Barak have extended congratulations to India on the occasion.</seg>
<seg id="5">Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh on Saturday in the heart of the operation was a recovery as soon as the desire of message.</seg>
<seg id="6">I think that the Indian police arrested two suspected Pakistani militants in the outskirts of New Delhi after fighting claimed to have killed.</seg>
<seg id="7">According to the local police officials from these two AK 47 rifles, grenades and some have been recovered documents which show that both Pakistani.</seg>
<seg id="8">The police is also investigating whether these two belonged to the banned organization Lashkar - e - Pakistan is the last year, was involved in the attacks.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Tea effective treatment of breast cancer</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">A new research revealed that three cup of tea Daily</seg>
<seg id="3">And 50 years of age in women with breast cancer less than one third of the threat.</seg>
<seg id="4">The US state of Florida cancer research center in the was told that in the age of 50 years of such women in the</seg>
<seg id="5">In 37 percent reduction of a drink at least three of the Cup.</seg>
<seg id="6">Research has also said that a large number of women in the age of three or more cups of tea daily from drinking any special in this regard does not benefit.</seg>
<seg id="7">The experts are of the view that this is the presence of these types of cancer, which is the more effective embarrassed against the target of less than 50 years old and women.</seg>
<seg id="8">In the city of Florida State Cancer Center, set up in more than five thousand of these research on women who had was have treatment of breast cancer.</seg>
<seg id="9">Of them between the ages of 20 and 74.</seg>
<seg id="10">The experts of their medical records and life style compare such women with breast cancer who were safe.</seg>
<seg id="11">The experts also came to know that a particular type of cancer, , the tea, and in the reduction of its 66 percent and was held.</seg>
<seg id="12">Almost all of the breast cancer patients there is suffering.</seg>
<seg id="13">This type of cancer and he is more dangerous for this, and this is usually the at this time when we know they are quite advanced.</seg>
<seg id="14">Experts say that daily has gained a cup of tea at least three women age of smoking in as they can reduce the risk of</seg>
<seg id="15">He said that one of the ideas of their daily routines will be included in the body from cancer in a proper.</seg>
<seg id="16">In Britain, about 40, 000 women every year in the diagnosis of breast cancer.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The war in Afghanistan is facing the biggest challenge military:</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">US Defense Secretary Robert has said that the war in Afghanistan is the biggest military challenge facing the United States.</seg>
<seg id="3">Today the US Senate and House of Representatives members of Afghanistan and administration on the Iraq war was briefed about the strategy.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Senate Armed Services Committee, said that the war is not the solution of the issue of Afghanistan, but he added that a number of areas to secure sufficient number of available, of which the Taliban have taken such action.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Why a reduction in the exercise with the age?</seg>
<seg id="2">New research</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="3">In every age the exercise is good for health.</seg>
<seg id="4">It is in the heart of the strong, a reduction in the level of cholesterol diet improve, has diabetes is to help stop and is to slow.</seg>
<seg id="5">Unfortunately, many people in the reduction in the ability to exercise is classified.</seg>
<seg id="6">Experts say that the exercise of our body and mind however it can affect age.</seg>
<seg id="7">The American Medical Association are saying that the exercise is not to come to health problems.</seg>
<seg id="8">Mew Clinic of Dr. into mini says that the increase in age and physical performance and a decrease in a big rise.</seg>
<seg id="9">Dr. Mew clinic medicine in geography.</seg>
<seg id="10">A heart diseases and the ability to exercise of the human being taken in the context of a study to of leadership.</seg>
<seg id="11">The team of doctors to examine the performance of my heart for the use of high to voice.</seg>
<seg id="12">In the heart to pump blood, the rest of the study of the process.</seg>
<seg id="13">The experts said, the left part of his heart that pumps blood to focus on the central part.</seg>
<seg id="14">They came to know the increase the rest in the process of heart disorders.</seg>
<seg id="15">Dr. says that the heart to the process in the rest of the age of defects, with the increase in life and the ability to exercise its influence is growing.</seg>
<seg id="16">Dr. Ken studies.</seg>
<seg id="17">He says that we see it that the impact and it is explained that the exercise was in the heart of the process of the rest of the bad performance of how to be concerned.</seg>
<seg id="18">Sometimes in the process of blood pressure and heart can become a cause of the diseases.</seg>
<seg id="19">If the doctors and patients with heart disorders can still get benefits of exercise.</seg>
<seg id="20">In this regard a detailed report published in the magazine of the American Medical Association.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The possibility of immediate war with no Indian army chief</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Staff of the Indian army chief General Dipak Kapoor said that the immediate possibility of war with Pakistan is not present, however, to defend the interests of the country and the protection of this to ensure to are ready for all the time.</seg>
<seg id="3">General Kapoor has alleged that the assurance and Mumbai attacks in Pakistan, on despite the international pressure, Pakistan, in the words of the soil on the structure of the terrorism not only, but the present situation is active.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said this while talking to reporters in in Srinagar.</seg>
<seg id="5">Army Chief of Staff of the Indian controlled Kashmir, New Delhi under the security situation on the borders and the preparation of the armed forces to observe the one - day visit to Kashmir valley.</seg>
<seg id="6">He was asked that the media reports, according to of the attacks in Pakistan, India toward the in this regard, he made the comment.</seg>
<seg id="7">General Kapoor said that the decision of war or peace issues, is the political leadership.</seg>
<seg id="8">Alleged on the soil of Pakistan while talking about the presence of the terror infrastructure, he said that the Indian army will fight against such elements of the peace process and India to be disrupted on under are weak.</seg>
<seg id="9">He said that on the land of Indian Kashmir for seven to eight hundred militants in which there are about 50 percent are foreigners.</seg>
<seg id="10">General Dipak Kapoor said that with the improvement in the weather to Pakistan and the efforts of the infiltration in Kashmir in May, however, India has extended its vigilance on the borders.</seg>
<seg id="11">He posted in the Indian controlled Kashmir, the possibility of a reduction in the number of wrongdoing by saying that the no compromise with the security of the country.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">God and the world language Mubarak for the world and will be happy.</seg>
<seg id="2">There is not even then, I hope to see relations between Pakistan and the United States are in favor of this change in US.</seg>
<seg id="3">That person who dreams of the Martin Luther King of the world are not consider what to do.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Hussain is also part of the president, as of today to take an oath from every where there is the historical status and also as a history class:</seg>
<seg id="2">Not only to secure their own hands, but these people who heart.</seg>
<seg id="3">The exam will be a majority of them black for the heart of them easy to do not work.</seg>
<seg id="4">Here in South Asia soldiers have been raised to remember that the elected president of the United States, and to remember that the president should practically the president of the United States.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">After some time now, a person of racial, brother of slavery wearing closed on their blood to the country and the United States had reportedly taken and were the most powerful of modern times, the state is the victim of racial discrimination today, a representative of the nation, the president of the United States.</seg>
<seg id="2">This is one of the many people and they have a lot of expectations.</seg>
<seg id="3">On it hopes that the person is not a realistic.</seg>
<seg id="4">If race, religion, like in the world on the basis of the archipelago, a less be successful only if it wins the will of its people.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This decision will change Asia in this policy and meaningful change can be expected.</seg>
<seg id="2">On the relations between Pakistan and the United States.</seg>
<seg id="3">(BBC)</seg>
<seg id="4">Mr. Singh, or any of the world, and to determine the nature of relations, the influential, strong and influence of the Jewish lobby for the country.</seg>
<seg id="5">As far as Pakistan is concerned, the recent bomb blasts in India, Israel and the United States which the aggressive manner in front of the world.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan to become a long all the arrangements of the of the Swat was responsible for the genocide, which was one of the army and the law.</seg>
<seg id="2">Under an agreement he has handed over to the government of Pakistan</seg>
<seg id="3">But unfortunately, the mother of Swat with our governments are treated like.</seg>
<seg id="4">In the end of the increase in the number of schools were also not</seg>
<seg id="5">And there was interest in the construction and development.</seg>
<seg id="6">At present, the girls education and the number of the former is far less than several times.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In the North West Frontier Province, the local Taliban in Pakistan from the educational institutions were made to continues.</seg>
<seg id="2">Most of the schools have been destroyed in the Swat district in which most of the girls.</seg>
<seg id="3">The on the education of girls in Swat Taliban ban has also been announced.</seg>
<seg id="4">Thousands of students are deprived of education.</seg>
<seg id="5">What you think that the girls end the Taliban of what they want to.</seg>
<seg id="6">The government has so far failed to their illegal measures why.</seg>
<seg id="7">You think the government should do.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The question should be said that the ISI and to Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="2">Because of the this game people has come to understand that the army is the the service for the Taliban would not otherwise, for a night curfew in five school curfew how can the people in can be slaughtered in the main area of the city.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">When the writ of the government, not even being given up, these illegal measures by the government to stop how successful?</seg>
<seg id="2">Now the question is that when the armed forces modern weapons, modern technology and set the four Taliban government, it is being control system, why not?</seg>
<seg id="3">This is the answer to that on the one hand, the ' secret on Monday that it is not the end of his arms and neither it is discovered.</seg>
<seg id="4">To sum it all that the Taliban through their black world government &quot; are taking an easy task.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Now the war in Afghanistan 15 years ago.</seg>
<seg id="2">ISI was controlled by the Taliban and the opposition Northern Alliance help was to help, Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
<seg id="3">Then all of a sudden change in circumstances, the Taliban freely</seg>
<seg id="4">And ex - ISI to offer relatively come from the United States has become a friend, former enemy.</seg>
<seg id="5">Now the situation is that the war is continuing, but in the Iran, India and Russia.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">What is the human right and till then that is the same mistake as well.</seg>
<seg id="2">For example, when a thief if it is the time to think that this theft was not a good thing to theft and robbery, this is a curse in the punishment of God and he has also, he said, &quot; the man will not stolen</seg>
<seg id="3">In the same way as Israel to realize that it could not be wrong to and I am responsible for bloodshed of the sentence and then he will get the Gaza Strip, along with the holy will continue.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">!</seg>
<seg id="2">The question that war, terrorism, and to solve the problems?</seg>
<seg id="3">If not, then they promise problems by taking it?</seg>
<seg id="4">It is, that violent war does not solve problems, but their blessing ' more.</seg>
<seg id="5">Pakistan, Afghanistan, Iraq, to secure the success of their movements be adopted which Nelson Mandela in South Africa.</seg>
<seg id="6">The armed struggle, and more than to ' Jihad ' psychological and moral.</seg>
<seg id="7">Kashmiris from taking part in the election of the view that he is willing to accept the point.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Israeli attack on Gaza is the number of deaths has reached nearly 1, 000.</seg>
<seg id="2">International diplomatic efforts in spite of the war has not yet.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to an estimate, starting from December 27, the attacks after the 90 thousand Palestinians left their houses in areas have been transferred to the safe.</seg>
<seg id="4">Meanwhile, relief agencies Zionist Palestinian children in the issue of security between the accusing the Palestinian children said that an entire generation of emotional and psychological problems facing serious.</seg>
<seg id="5">What you say.</seg>
<seg id="6">What?</seg>
<seg id="7">How lasting peace is possible in Gaza</seg>
<seg id="8">Click here for details.</seg>
<seg id="9">(Please note that the print only increased the number in Urdu to the opinions of the type will be published.</seg>
<seg id="10">On the screen for this Alt + shift pressure on board the Urdu) .</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Given a chance to the Taliban.</seg>
<seg id="2">Basit, Peshawar</seg>
<seg id="3">If Taliban began to go to the real Jihad, innocent people who will l.</seg>
<seg id="4">The school girls who?</seg>
<seg id="5">And kidnapping for ransom or a ransom to get the U. S. spy, saying people who to pay?</seg>
<seg id="6">He said the Taliban have a religion or any other nation as did not.</seg>
<seg id="7">Pashtun</seg>
<seg id="8">Pakistan</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">All the Islamic world on Israel to give only threatened to attack Israel United States will be the how you will see that pain</seg>
<seg id="2">The real ceasefire and immediately but will also be talking not only.</seg>
<seg id="3">But to do so bereaved ones where Muslims, to bring the heart.</seg>
<seg id="4">Ahmadi you say that the initiative to as to why the two activity, the BBC of your courage in the forum are the big.</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">On the one hand, the United States says that the efforts will</seg>
<seg id="2">On the other hand the United Nations on the resolution is passed, but practically, both this did not mean that one is favored to crush the Muslims also of the United Nations in fighting.</seg>
<seg id="3">All Muslim countries to the membership of the United Nations immediately finished on the basis of international should and should.</seg>
<seg id="4">Before US, where there are many examples in the United States and the United Nations, and the only promise we are resolutions loss only Muslims only.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">What is the benefit of these when the BBC is not owing to some</seg>
<seg id="2">The press is now buried of blood, especially Muslims on the BBC to be on board.</seg>
<seg id="3">Though it off the right</seg>
<seg id="4">Some independent, far less than the character of this is that the comments by</seg>
<seg id="5">The Muslims.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">You and the Jews in the killing to the Muslims, Jews and the Muslims in you as Muslims and their say to the Muslims and the Muslims</seg>
<seg id="2">(</seg>
<seg id="3">A BBC reporter from a never, never, in the suicide attacks in India, under the pretext of terrorism in a particular racial is being targeted.</seg>
<seg id="4">These remarks against Islam is the favorite word extremism</seg>
<seg id="5">But the extremists who estimate it at the top of your is the comments of the well, which are against Iran in writing about the enemies of the was imposed.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">US to understand that when Muslims could not compete.</seg>
<seg id="2">In the bombing of the people to see, &quot; My heart is not to do so?</seg>
<seg id="3">But the basic fault this violence and murder of Jihad is we give the name of the beautiful which face the Islam and try to meet.</seg>
<seg id="4">When the majority of the Palestinians to recognize the existence of Israel, Hamas has announced that they need to be held or rockets on Israel suicide attack.</seg>
<seg id="5">Both sides are attitude of humanity.</seg>
<seg id="6">The role of the United States and Israel, then we are in favor of cruelty.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">God of the Muslim Ummah to Taufiq, Amen.</seg>
<seg id="2">The terrorists and terrorism to this painful to the action campaign against terrorism, the Nobel Peace Prize to think of that, the real work.</seg>
<seg id="3">Otherwise, such a large scale terrorism without any Sardar backing from and it is possible we all know who they are.</seg>
<seg id="4">In this, such as easy language Gary grandparents, in which it is said that a low.</seg>
<seg id="5">The head of a great corner and also give were also killed.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The injured and dead, for a funeral for the money, and are being asked, and the Arab rulers.</seg>
<seg id="2">Israeli attacks, should be?</seg>
<seg id="3">In fact, the problem is that all leaders of the Muslim countries his army and it's not just think that was his responsibility for aid.</seg>
<seg id="4">He immediately practical steps against Israel.</seg>
<seg id="5">As America and European countries, but the regret of the closure of petrol among them.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">All the brothers and sisters to salute</seg>
<seg id="2">I think in this moment of Hamas to peace in the name of its struggle to give advice to stop and hundreds of thousands of destitute of injustice and they failed to prove the crime.</seg>
<seg id="3">Israel and the supporters of his arrogance and if you are at their zenith, Musa also in their houses because this is nature law will be born in America and the steps of Israel in the Muslims of the suicide bomber in the work of the fertilizer.</seg>
<seg id="4">The power of nations understand the.</seg>
<seg id="5">Abu Abdullah, Pakistan</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Now Hamas and Israel possible so that the blood and should be closed.</seg>
<seg id="2">Mohammad Sarfaraz, Paris, France.</seg>
<seg id="3">They rang said.</seg>
<seg id="4">Suppose that the Hamas is only 100 percent of the truth on the right and oppression &quot; and the &quot; Jihad &quot; against the court in ' conquers ' also wants to be at least, so it must know that they should be doing that if this is my home, then we can not raised.</seg>
<seg id="5">The people who love of God and his Prophet, and love their religion, a claim to love is part of his faith.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">After that of the Muslims of the book ' in the world, the user them to the ground has ordered to God.</seg>
<seg id="2">Lahore, Najib Rehman [p@ki$t@n] * *</seg>
<seg id="3">No, but he has not ordered the order of Islam.</seg>
<seg id="4">But who trying to protest against the their Jihad against the order.</seg>
<seg id="5">&quot; With these people to be trying to the end, until they did not mean at all that but it is not in the jacket, wearing to be exploded.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The murderer of brothers, children, out of the destruction.</seg>
<seg id="2">But from my friends are requested that Israelis not to shelter, they was so strong that they do not recognise any in the world, because of the Jewish state.</seg>
<seg id="3">These are the Shia, Sunni, all the Jewish and they have made progress in the field of development.</seg>
<seg id="4">On the contrary, the condition of the 55 Islamic countries</seg>
<seg id="5">In every field and it is now behind the world that have so that the enemy and they are still waiting for death are.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is necessary that all Muslim countries to be united against Israel, and work together to prepare process.</seg>
<seg id="2">Feroz Magsi, Jhang, Pakistan</seg>
<seg id="3">And it is not a good strategy, and that Israel should accept the latest studies, and development of the world learn to live in peace and China.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Muslims also, there are a lot of land and resources.</seg>
<seg id="5">The need is correct.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">First of all, this aspect is that Hamas and Fatah could not be alliance.</seg>
<seg id="2">Yasser Arafat and Sheikh Yasin as great leaders was killed in a planned way for all of this was that the al - Aqsa Mosque for &quot; Jihad &quot; to the region only the nation could be weak and Arafat, and the roads are not removed, it was impossible.</seg>
<seg id="3">The world is Palestine after the death of the leaders of these two of the moment to moment is how</seg>
<seg id="4">The Jewish lobby and parts of how their upgraded upgraded from the clutches of the lost.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">A Pakistani prime minister in 1974, the owner of the world as it was for the first time in history with all Muslim leaders had come under a roof.</seg>
<seg id="2">Today, the birth anniversary that the nation should pledge that this is not only set up unity among its ranks</seg>
<seg id="3">But other Muslims while also differences of this (the Commonwealth of the establishment of the Islamic Conference) will be increased mission ahead?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This is the one which the half century.</seg>
<seg id="2">This is a result of them.</seg>
<seg id="3">Many times that it is in their own any other to face the worst Aug by forgetting the pressure of the world and paddy.</seg>
<seg id="4">And this is the second face including Iraq, Iran, Pakistan, which are beings in Afghanistan</seg>
<seg id="5">And, most of which is why it knows that that it was carried out only when they only Muslims and Islam and Muslims and religion of Islam because the history tells that Islam is the big on the right path.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Israeli planes from Gaza a series of bombing and missile attacks from December 27.</seg>
<seg id="2">In these attacks so far have more than 100 Palestinians have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="3">After the air attacks, Israeli tanks and armored vehicles ground action will also complete preparations on the border of the Gaza Strip have reached.</seg>
<seg id="4">The UN Security Council unanimously passed Resolution in an emergency meeting of the Palestinian Authority and Israel to immediately stop violent actions to intervene.</seg>
<seg id="5">However, the Israeli officials has said that Gaza Strip for the time it will continue until they are not sure that the rocket attack on Israel would be closed.</seg>
<seg id="6">What is your opinion in correct to say that it is this to the closure of the Israeli action</seg>
<seg id="7">The international community should play its role in this situation is?</seg>
<seg id="8">This aggressive action by Israel in the related to the next elections in</seg>
<seg id="9">The president of the newly elected after assuming the post of any of the improvement in the Middle East situation can be expected.</seg>
<seg id="10">(Please note that the print only increased the number in Urdu to the opinions of the type will be published.</seg>
<seg id="11">On the screen for this Alt + shift pressure on board the Urdu) .</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Muslims in Palestine and the world is a sacred place for the most and the protection of our part.</seg>
<seg id="2">And we should also remember that it is the first proper</seg>
<seg id="3">The United States and India in Israel, and one day for the country, and God's punishment is going to be held on their pakhtun - Sadiq, Sajid</seg>
<seg id="4">When night pretext to.</seg>
<seg id="5">Only when there is a call to prayer (Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Such comments, and explored the BBC, was published.</seg>
<seg id="2">The end of the truth, and that is established.</seg>
<seg id="3">However, the BBC news are correct, but the way the reports.</seg>
<seg id="4">What is the importance of information, and what is to be reduced.</seg>
<seg id="5">Etc.</seg>
<seg id="6">Zaheer</seg>
<seg id="7">Now it is our Pakistani electronic media, especially and also a columnist to now, there are not behind the growing extremism and terrorism, or in the coverage of this ', ' they are in.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The United Nations human rights, which is apparently and peace talks, but the Muslims and to give to and the limits of oppression, and his words to face the same ability to see that Hamas attack when stop this dual policy will leave.</seg>
<seg id="2">Muslim so much cruelty is behind the move if the United States such as those people backing the Jews of the left, the Allah has said it is clear that most this nation life of the nation will pass, and the good life, if they can not spend courage of the United States, and then they see that source of his life.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The world peace and the so - called murdered in the name of the killed fell to prevent it clearly understand that only peace in the world and only to give up justice, is to set off owing to the injustice and genocide.</seg>
<seg id="2">If any of the nation owing to the genocide that can be done and the results can be achieved, the steps taken only after the existence of the Jews but today impossible to find a way of the peak.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to Poet</seg>
<seg id="4">Cruelty is wiped out, and it is growing.</seg>
<seg id="5">Blood is, it Jim. &quot;</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Now everybody who say that terrorism?</seg>
<seg id="2">All of the terrorism, it is not only in Europe that is why all their only their pain.</seg>
<seg id="3">Other people do not have the Muslims of blood or been so low so was not red color of blood</seg>
<seg id="4">And a condolence message from anywhere, why not?</seg>
<seg id="5">Attacks in Mumbai, said the action was seen such as in my house, said that the fire could not see people to share the grief of the people and we do not see any of the Muslim one and I think some</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Lying on the road, fend the dead bodies and injured innocent faces blood in how that it can not find words.</seg>
<seg id="2">The Muslims of helpless on the one hand, people were killed in India, Pakistan, on the whole world was sitting on the evidence that action is otherwise we will.</seg>
<seg id="3">And on the other hand, Israel has publicly genocide of Muslims and the world is silent is unbearable</seg>
<seg id="4">- The God, there is delay, but never darkness and when the storm will end.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The United States, Israel's integrity is a joke.</seg>
<seg id="2">As the issue of elections, the ruling welcomed the public for such activities should be no doubt in the state, particularly Israel, Barak of like the rest of history is evident today, no, not against the U. S. government policy and will not be like the government or the government.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In the debate on the forum, it is clear that sorrow over the death of every one of you, but as a politician to their it has not been ignored.</seg>
<seg id="2">It is said that discussion given life for the sake of democracy and for the sake of the power.</seg>
<seg id="3">Aziz was the American democracy if clearance and ten years until the deal that kept dictatorship in order to leave why?</seg>
<seg id="4">Benazir dictatorship need Pakistan not to come when then unfortunately, then he was cases when they come to Pakistan to release and were ensured of power</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The historical devoted to take up the accusations which is being on this, to say anything is not the only.</seg>
<seg id="2">SANA Khan.</seg>
<seg id="3">Some things are ignoring this thinking that they can not be done.</seg>
<seg id="4">One reader</seg>
<seg id="5">Perhaps you respected the date may not only in Pakistan but (4) head of my friend in countries and seven other countries also read perhaps talk to you as well.</seg>
<seg id="6">Tariq Ayaz</seg>
<seg id="7">&quot; not only to the condition that he not training</seg>
<seg id="8">Green was not in which the defendant photos of water.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Britain has also not to be a Muslim issue, and the invention which the development of Sir Syed.</seg>
<seg id="2"></seg>
<seg id="3">How is our nation of his own party in Shan and writes was at the time, but now allegations and to take the criticism is going on this, one can not say anything.</seg>
<seg id="4">We have a lot of the people.</seg>
<seg id="5">SANA Khan.</seg>
<seg id="6">Some things are be books donkey - way to reach the world is not known.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Although Pakistan after the Mumbai attacks continue dialogue process between India and Pakistan However, India would like to continue the talks.</seg>
<seg id="2">If the war will from both sides, will be the loss of human lives.</seg>
<seg id="3">India has said that Pakistan in Urdu, and it sent to Pakistan and India, but on the other hand, the first when he caught the extremists, said that it is a very big and engineer, but he did not only four party had declared to have it.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">First of all, and the forum's Christian friends of Christmas to Mubarak.</seg>
<seg id="2">A: Forum, Raza, SANA, sister and sister and all Shahida Akram.</seg>
<seg id="3">The war we all do not want peace, but the flowers!</seg>
<seg id="4">The war itself is a problem.</seg>
<seg id="5">War will be the solution of issues</seg>
<seg id="6">Fire and blood will be today.</seg>
<seg id="7">Hunger and will tomorrow.</seg>
<seg id="8">This is for people</seg>
<seg id="9">War, we are better.</seg>
<seg id="10">In her and the US.</seg>
<seg id="11">Shama courage, we are better.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">United States now have very deep relations and India must know that time if the United States to open is donating tactics.</seg>
<seg id="2">The old the United States.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Indian attack in the United States will also be achieved its objectives and India will be spent.</seg>
<seg id="4">Pakistan should clearly announce that the initiative, but we will not compromise the aggression, then this time to the ceasefire and peace will not be unless India completely destroyed or not, whether we are able to manage themselves, why not be destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="5">The Islamic history.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Before this resolution and the people of Pakistan Army, which was given to the message.</seg>
<seg id="2">Compensate attacks in the acquisition of Indian military benefits and diplomatic efforts of the more than it impressed initially, even the the world has put the pressure on Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="3">India not in the United Nations expressed satisfaction over Pakistan's efforts of the Interpol and the head of Pakistan's efforts to India need of the side more than diplomacy '.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This, no two opinion that this is a very brutal.</seg>
<seg id="2">But the question is that, when thousands of Taliban attackers were on Monday the and where the Pakistani army was what?</seg>
<seg id="3">The army should not be said that he has done there in one year</seg>
<seg id="4">Every day, in which thousands of mortar shells of tanks and many of them are Taliban were killed?</seg>
<seg id="5">The ISI I appeal to the Taliban leave the patronage of the and we live in peace in heaven Benazir Swat.</seg>
<seg id="6">And these fake operation.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The United Nations day when Pakistan is not in the resolution of the military intervention in have such against him.</seg>
<seg id="2">Riaz Ahmed Farooqi.</seg>
<seg id="3">First, our extremists and his supporters for his action against all the evidence and reason for the continuous and are being provided day, which was such a resolution, also in the United Nations that our voice is not in favor of</seg>
<seg id="4">Of this resolution and United States, for example, taking into the account of any of its help you power under the spotlight will run.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">On Monday, Sami and his personality and information, we are not aware that the operations were done.</seg>
<seg id="2">Perhaps they were not a revolutionary.</seg>
<seg id="3">Comrade, Nawab Bugti, Dr Najeeb Ullah and thousands of dead bodies of the revolutionaries the enemy's hands.</seg>
<seg id="4">In fact, they are also died.</seg>
<seg id="5">But here, an international game is being played here, the people and be subjected to afraid of the rule is being done.</seg>
<seg id="6">So if we could to create a reason that if not, we will come to the government and it will take over.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The name of religion of Islam, the so - called militants are extremely it is condemnable.</seg>
<seg id="2">These extremists, the supporters of the United States, are seen, but this barbaric actions of grief instead of their tribal traditions which brought the name of the avoiding making clear.</seg>
<seg id="3">And tribal traditions, the name of Islam, of this ghastly action for the building of a heart, can not be.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">I think the people of our army met with these people.</seg>
<seg id="2">When the people that they should move in this time, so much so, it is enough for the then will, but they have to be on the spot if they are there, there are exaggeration.</seg>
<seg id="3">These people are 50 to 70 men so that they held hostage and give our forces continue to occupy the hands of spectators.</seg>
<seg id="4">They are also devoted of God and the army.</seg>
<seg id="5">Pulse is clear that in the country.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Dictator Ziaul Haq, and it's actually during the dictatorship of the qualities and on the contrary to highlight the kinds of and religion with the name of the atmosphere of fear, which is seen to set up a body in this apart from the incident of literature, &quot; and his death will be like after the books, created fear.</seg>
<seg id="2">These people are staying and just and Jalalabad to the fear or as instrument.</seg>
<seg id="3">&quot;!</seg>
<seg id="4">Set where they were to do with it.</seg>
<seg id="5">Fear that the situation became independent.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is surprising that when it is said that it can not be any work of Muslims.</seg>
<seg id="2">We are their or from history and its neighbor.</seg>
<seg id="3">Prophet on the refusal after a closed door of the Prophet, who has set his sight and hugged her husband who was dragged to put the past?</seg>
<seg id="4">They came from outside is.</seg>
<seg id="5">Medina, and the army's offensive on Yazid Karbala and was made of?</seg>
<seg id="6">Motives behind the facts have been accepted without activity is not far away.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">BBC dual policy band.</seg>
<seg id="2">This topic to be better than Bush: &quot; super shoes unjustified, or if it was illegal.</seg>
<seg id="3">&quot; should.</seg>
<seg id="4">, Japan</seg>
<seg id="5">As a human and to the grave to being out from a shame, Poles have been lingering that it has raised its voice against the oppression, and you is lying to the topic of box office.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">For the success of the operation in line with the heart of success depends on the fact that it is the opinion in favor of the common people.</seg>
<seg id="2">It is of the US and Pakistani agencies and on Monday, the victim of this conspiracy.</seg>
<seg id="3">All this forum will be based on Taliban in the opposition because the secret of success in the Taliban have been included, and they are taking actions which could change the opinion of the people.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">I only ask that it days when one of the dead, the army, who were bananas there are target only the people who are also this statement, Taliban bombardment on the whereabouts of the House of the shells, and two children were killed, and her mother.</seg>
<seg id="2">Chowk of what was not know about?</seg>
<seg id="3">Or were watching.</seg>
<seg id="4">Forded hands, we wish God to secure and that the games closed.</seg>
<seg id="5">Also on the end a ruling.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The BBC has was asked the question may or may not be writing a of seeing regret, for example, it asked this question, he said that the present 30, 000 troops in the Swat to do?</seg>
<seg id="2">The army to help fight the Taliban the bodies of all those on the day.</seg>
<seg id="3">Sawati along with the people, the Pakistani army has taken but the media, including the BBC World, has also to be ignorant of the reality, and what is not good.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Pakistani army drama.</seg>
<seg id="5">Every child in the Swat that is that it is a bloody drama.</seg>
<seg id="6">Bus full of drama.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Taliban have the name of the Muslims.</seg>
<seg id="2">In the world if they do not say a true Muslim terrorists in the area of these place to why.</seg>
<seg id="3">, which are hard to become one of the smallest of the gun is not included in the group.</seg>
<seg id="4">Gun of Islam or not.</seg>
<seg id="5">Shame.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The reason for this is not in any religion is not in any family tradition.</seg>
<seg id="2">Including the BBC, the Taliban and the media from different sources related to the comments.</seg>
<seg id="3">But the real situation not only the right to know what is the situation that we know it, because we are tribal.</seg>
<seg id="4">It is a very that it A. S. I. and our own are not raise any of these students is not a bad elements, which are Islam, the Taliban, a Pashtun tribes, religious and tribal traditions, the nation, as we are.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This move to all Muslims with the head of shame.</seg>
<seg id="2">The leader of MQM Altaf Hussain, the ANP and the leadership of the PPP I salute against cancer, which means that are speaking against the Taliban.</seg>
<seg id="3">This is the product of Zia ul Haq, he went to Pakistan, but also destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="4">But I am hopeful that the present leadership will end this cancer.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Mumbai after the attack, said that the attack some extremist elements of Pakistan's hand.</seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan has denied the charges and said that the investigation of India will help in every possible way.</seg>
<seg id="3">India has said that it has given Pakistan a list in which they have given the name of 20 suspected extremists, who are required to India.</seg>
<seg id="4">Pakistan has said that now the list included the head of Jaish - e - Mohammad, Maulana Masood Azhar and that they are not in the government, there is no any information to Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="5">Asif Ali Zardari, the president of Pakistan has rejected the impression that the Western intelligence agencies of Pakistan and the Indian government to provide evidence about the attacks in Mumbai.</seg>
<seg id="6">The president Ajmal Butcher said that it has not been proved that Pakistani.</seg>
<seg id="7">Meanwhile, the prime minister, Manmohan Singh said that Pakistan has warned India relations with better then there is no until the land to be used for terrorism will continue.</seg>
<seg id="8">And the latest developments in India and Pakistan cricket team has cancelled his visit.</seg>
<seg id="9">His political impact on the incidents of sport should occur?</seg>
<seg id="10">You and the future of relations between Pakistan 's</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan, India, the United States will not broken.</seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan will Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="3">So what you and regionalism after have had expected.</seg>
<seg id="4">However, the Muslims of India also good with the time, it has not proved.</seg>
<seg id="5">Chicago,</seg>
<seg id="6">Ms Jinnah, if we continue to work on the vision on, and not of cancer in Pakistan, nor does not with the Muslims in India.</seg>
<seg id="7">But as the height of our mistakes that they could not produce any leader.</seg>
<seg id="8">If we can not, the value of their</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">There are many qualities in the region.</seg>
<seg id="2">God knows them, and when this will come from the development of the region.</seg>
<seg id="3">In the two countries, both the, the Taliban, Shiv Sena, RSS, against the peace process has been prepared.</seg>
<seg id="4">And it does not want peace in the region, these countries will develop with the puppet.</seg>
<seg id="5">You can imagine that this area agreement with Pakistan, India and China will take place in the world.</seg>
<seg id="6">Pakistan, on the punishment of God, which is the dacoits evaders and leader of the impose on the nation.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">God will never on Pakistan, did not affect our country Amen.</seg>
<seg id="2">But just opened his eyes and around the situation to the ground realities and see, you will come to see that the US forces reach.</seg>
<seg id="3">Besides it are coming, the North West Frontier and Balochistan, and before the situation of Karachi in Sindh.</seg>
<seg id="4">In such a situation, a leader of the country is that we could be a united nation.</seg>
<seg id="5">We understand or mercy of Allah.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">I think one of the last war no other way out.</seg>
<seg id="2">Has been a bus.</seg>
<seg id="3">Now, should be R. or the matter.</seg>
<seg id="4">It will not be agenda to solve the issue.</seg>
<seg id="5">Not only a small gross in the other countries of terrorists.</seg>
<seg id="6">Even a great Europe to end last after the fight, as there was.</seg>
<seg id="7">And this war was not great, all of these upto today, India and Pakistan and also the only.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Our almost all the political parties agreed that the troubles in the country of terrorism and sectarian violence should be eliminated.</seg>
<seg id="2">But our military leadership in this work, not sincere on the one hand, the United States and Europe has assured that the terrorism is we are with you in this war on the other hand, the secret of the Taliban to help.</seg>
<seg id="3">And we think now is to determine the direction and only one path, thanks to the election.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">There is no doubt in the fact that of Lashkar - e - Islami in included those in the majority of workers, which is that the disbursement of the banned Lashkar - e - Islami after declaring the party set up in Pakistan with the name of the party were included.</seg>
<seg id="2">However, after these workers given priority to the relief work and now India insisted on at the United Nations has said it also is also a government continue to crack down against them.</seg>
<seg id="3">I think if the Jihadi groups and religious extremism, along with helping religious and relief operations continue, the better.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Organizations in Pakistan in the name of Jihad, who have professional criminals are Paul kept people and these have it ' a, the same to Pakistan, and what we are saying.</seg>
<seg id="2">Now it left no in Pakistan to destroy.</seg>
<seg id="3">In fact, this is not entitled to human.</seg>
<seg id="4">Pakistan foreign miscreants from them without security threat in Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="5">What is still think there is that they should be banned not?</seg>
<seg id="6">Violent place anywhere in the world may not work in a murder.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This news of heart is a thief.</seg>
<seg id="2">This world where religion of Islam that is an important member of the People today it is difficult to live in this world.</seg>
<seg id="3">The non - Muslim can kill Muslims, but also try to take revenge if all the Muslim world, the non - Muslim rulers also with all their leaders get together and sincere and true as far as the pain of the people, who are today our great leader Hafiz Saeed with.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Attacks in Mumbai of India.</seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan has created bitterness between the two countries and the relations in recent years the improvement in a severe blow.</seg>
<seg id="3">Pakistan and India are active in the military and non - military groups to hold responsible for.</seg>
<seg id="4">And coming back to normal relations to be conditional on action against these groups is.</seg>
<seg id="5">The attacks, while Indian security agencies for the Lashkar - e - Taiba held directly responsible for.</seg>
<seg id="6">Again, in this regard is also in the name of party WoW front.</seg>
<seg id="7">This is not the first time that India is a terrorist action in the relations between the two countries were serious.</seg>
<seg id="8">In December 2001 attack on the Indian parliament in after the two neighbors on the brink of war.</seg>
<seg id="9">After that, in 2002 and banned Lashkar - e - the included in the list of terrorist groups.</seg>
<seg id="10">Now the party, of which about security analysts say that the car in a Lashkar - e - Taiba, is that the ban is being demanded.</seg>
<seg id="11">What do you think it should be banned the group or not?</seg>
<seg id="12">Pakistan on its soil is to should take decisive action against extremist groups</seg>
<seg id="13">The party to present ban imposed on India.</seg>
<seg id="14">Pakistan crisis countries can and the peace between the two armed groups of how it is necessary to stop?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The UN Security Council has imposed a ban on the party end is evidence of the Security Council, which seems so hurry?</seg>
<seg id="2">The Security Council not always so activity against the Muslims</seg>
<seg id="3">It says that the witness slowly.</seg>
<seg id="4">If India itself has become a failed state.</seg>
<seg id="5">The army intelligence, and other security institutions have failed the hands of the terrorists, which a 72 - hour long signs of this, and for the failure of India, Pakistan and the entire world has been taken.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">A non be murder in the whole world because it is a double - standards why?</seg>
<seg id="2">Our country, the only welfare the organization.</seg>
<seg id="3">Farooq Furqan, Faisalabad.</seg>
<seg id="4">Until our prophet (PBUH) , the scholars and the people to love and respect to Islam, the religion of peace and expanded.</seg>
<seg id="5">The Muslims have also made progress in every field.</seg>
<seg id="6">This beautiful priestcraft religion, and non discrimination began the conflict and opening a new chapter in before which was not aware of the world.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">. To work with their own interest, but the bill will be based on this action.</seg>
<seg id="2">The United States do not come under pressure.</seg>
<seg id="3">If India is to provide proof, no?</seg>
<seg id="4">Why don't they?</seg>
<seg id="5">And every thing we put it on the charges of why?</seg>
<seg id="6">Even in India, extremists groups and organizations are, it, accusing the people, why not?</seg>
<seg id="7">We have only one terrorist in the world.</seg>
<seg id="8">India in Kashmir, which is what?</seg>
<seg id="9">Israel, which is he?</seg>
<seg id="10">It is true that we are the world's first nuclear Islamic State is, why the quarrel.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan is in its final stages.</seg>
<seg id="2">Abu Dhabi, kamranhassan</seg>
<seg id="3">You are the heart of the matter and also such situations are coming in</seg>
<seg id="4">Now, American magazines published in Pakistan with a new map to the sanctions, and it is also part of this is coming.</seg>
<seg id="5">The U. S. slowly, but now is not very rapidly its grip on Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="6">In this situation, we as a nation did not show of unity, too, if Bangladesh can achieve, and may also do a lot.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Around also condemned the attacks, as they will be less, whether he is in the Mumbai hotel or the hotel in Islamabad and or in Palestine.</seg>
<seg id="2">I am or US, Indian and Israeli.</seg>
<seg id="3">Now the question is that every day in Pakistan, which is a terrorist attack, thousands of people were killed, including Pakistani officials on the entire world is silent why?</seg>
<seg id="4">What was the hotel of the terrorist attack was not?</seg>
<seg id="5">Then why.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Rahman, advisor to the developments in the country and many trunk home, during his tour, Daler. !! !! !! !</seg>
<seg id="2">According to the BBC where Committee) of the United Nations Security Council has imposed a Malik said there is that we have not been banned and many will be only after and considered it</seg>
<seg id="3">Not only this, according to the BBC, the statements of this impression on the wrong with full force has declared that on the order of the arrests are being brought in the process.</seg>
<seg id="4">Instrument, God!</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The ability to say that he wanted to keep or not.</seg>
<seg id="2">The WHO, we are fighting a war.</seg>
<seg id="3">Why are our interests, which we are trying to the entire.</seg>
<seg id="4">Any interference in the affairs of any country is not entitled to.</seg>
<seg id="5">The era of period apparently.</seg>
<seg id="6">It is expected that if justice to the people or ally on the implementation of the free judiciary to respect the democratic institutions and a dictator or the military do not help to establish peace in the third world, including Pakistan and the allies will perhaps be is not acceptable.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan, just to the European and American objectives in.</seg>
<seg id="2">This is Pakistan's population a spite of the prevailed.</seg>
<seg id="3">And it is opposed to the opposition.</seg>
<seg id="4">If the U. S. and its allies are in a democracy, the confidence on the attitude and respects the sovereignty of the state, walked from the region.</seg>
<seg id="5">In Pakistan, said that he is so or.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan security forces in Kashmir under the control of the banned Lashkar - e raided a camp.</seg>
<seg id="2">Mumbai after the attacks increased pressure on Pakistan is that it should speed up action against the extremist organizations.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is alleged that India's Hands of Lashkar - e - Mumbai.</seg>
<seg id="4">American foreign Minister Condoleezza Rice has said that the Pakistani leadership to Mumbai attacks against the responsible for the immediate and practical demonstration of action should be transparent.</seg>
<seg id="5">He said that the attack on the Mumbai extremists, using Pakistani soil.</seg>
<seg id="6">Meanwhile, officials in Peshawar said that the coalition forces stationed in Afghanistan is one of the trucks transporting goods and the airport to has been put in which more than 50 fire trucks were destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="7">Peshawar in 48 hours during the second attack on NATO and US supplies.</seg>
<seg id="8">Meanwhile, Pakistan has banned Lashkar - e - is one of the camp and it even before the to the tribal areas and the armed groups, the non - armed, to which many efforts have been made in weapons and returned to the for the assurance to take any action.</seg>
<seg id="9">The situation is that General Zia - ul - Haq's regime in Afghanistan of the former Soviet Union and the U. S. intervention, Saudi funding starting from the resistance, the armed groups to put an end to the same as the first successful efforts to take back the environment.</seg>
<seg id="10">The question is what it wants Pakistan?</seg>
<seg id="11">It spaces capable of Pakistan?</seg>
<seg id="12">What you say?</seg>
<seg id="13">Click here for details.</seg>
<seg id="14">(Please note that the print only increased the number in Urdu to the opinions of the type will be published.</seg>
<seg id="15">On the screen for this Alt + shift pressure on board the Urdu) .</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">My only a question of humanity is all:</seg>
<seg id="2">If you want your child, you lost relates to the people, it is impossible</seg>
<seg id="3">Saeed, Multan</seg>
<seg id="4">My question and to you that studies from the Islamic studies with east and west, and any logic, signs and philosophy of American attack for the innocent people, including labor and professional service, and the murder of the poor, employees</seg>
<seg id="5">And if you are not in your view, there is an urgent need of reform.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Armed people at this time, it was reported that Russia had to Afghanistan from Pakistan after therefore, these people should be armed.</seg>
<seg id="2">Now, it is feared that the United States rose on the way of Pakistan will run the present US president in his presidential campaign, we have openly expressed non - armed why they do?</seg>
<seg id="3">So that only the United States and India, the Pakistani army to the public any resistance after not face?</seg>
<seg id="4">Yes, if any action may be involved in destructive to Pakistan will only take action against it.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">But unfortunately, it is the government of Lashkar - e - India's right to be declared that Pakistan is involved in this.</seg>
<seg id="2">Lahore, Najib Rehman [p@ki$t@n] * *</seg>
<seg id="3">If it is to be granted that is still not blaming the Pakistan government is correct.</seg>
<seg id="4">And it is also a question whether these terrorists to get any government or the Indian officials did not help the</seg>
<seg id="5">Only a terrorist created or in Pakistan and India and other countries in the world of are not ready.</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The United States starting from Saudi to put an end to the campaign for a request from the dirt that to our society who has to axe.</seg>
<seg id="2">They should also demonstrate how to protest to the United States that under the Saudi in our country and dangerous weapons and called hardline d hate literature and culture spread the virus, which our country of human in the open.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">India and the danger of an attack by the Pakistani army has announced that the Afghan border India, will pay its attention towards the Taliban and the Afghan border, announced that he was badly players and their full planted stressed that India should not attack on Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="2">The U. S. force in the region has been opened, the whole truth.</seg>
<seg id="3">However, India has not threatened to the attack, nor his courage.</seg>
<seg id="4">If the Taliban attacks on US supply the cases.</seg>
<seg id="5">Proved that the Pakistan Army and the government without the support of the United States.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan's Karachi business is all poor areas of Dubai financial center.</seg>
<seg id="2">Hundreds of thousands of empty handed from here, but never on the western border areas when the supremacy of law in nonexistent has taken the attention of Karachi.</seg>
<seg id="3">Now they are dealing with the kidnapping of the city.</seg>
<seg id="4">For the first time for the pakhtoon said to a city, who is the people is being made of the pullers, though the and is necessary.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">A solution, that the Urdu speaking or the Urdu, who speak or learning, or Pashto English learning, and all well.</seg>
<seg id="2">You definitely it is a ridiculous you consider the proposal because of what it does not ridiculous.</seg>
<seg id="3">The reason is that the language?</seg>
<seg id="4">Zaheer</seg>
<seg id="5">In fact, this has proposed to his friends, in which all religious and linguistic class people in childhood, for the time being Yar people laughed on these points.</seg>
<seg id="6">At this time of sectarian and religious these which the condition today was not alive and strong in pick was inside the bus.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is very difficult to understand why and what is happening?</seg>
<seg id="2">What extend the signs are there?</seg>
<seg id="3">Innocent and and the innocent are killed in the fighting.</seg>
<seg id="4">Reasons, which are to Pakistan who are active, and they do not have any nor his country.</seg>
<seg id="5">Karachi and Mumbai, is home to fire home.</seg>
<seg id="6">The government places the change in the name of the earning it the name, as these days, the airport, blood Benazir.</seg>
<seg id="7">What is the meaning of Benazir with Karachi and Pakistan is happening?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The attacks on Mumbai with the peak of the raw to start sectarian riots in Karachi is trying to get it failed to prove that in the past the raw on the payroll of the political elements to work now have a job to resign.</seg>
<seg id="2">Pashto speaking imperialistic plot of the blood and the Indian threats from Karachi to Khyber Sui was given to the Pakistani people.</seg>
<seg id="3">All political, religious, sectarian and national parties, the patriotism of vigorous reaction to all the diplomatic to India, where they have are also provided a chance to think.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The situation in Karachi, and a bad ANP partiality and administration.</seg>
<seg id="2">The administration can control situation in 1 hour, but it was John is being given to it.</seg>
<seg id="3">, police and the pressure to take action because the.</seg>
<seg id="4">Statements are limited to only the political parties to stop its interests and the common interests of the work for the people.</seg>
<seg id="5">As long as political pressure on the administration of the incidents such taking will continue, in order to Pakistan.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In my opinion, the biggest terrorist.</seg>
<seg id="2">And this is certainly no foreign powers, but that do not know who he is.</seg>
<seg id="3">But it is regrettable that if such conditions of the border in any city, the government in which the government did not appear.</seg>
<seg id="4">The government and that the operation of the country, a big and important to save the city from the terrorism.</seg>
<seg id="5">Otherwise, Pakistan had to face a financial crisis.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">BBC Urdu also due to the fear is not writing a truth, whereas the Pakistani media, and the condition of the puppet.</seg>
<seg id="2">The whole truth the English is on.</seg>
<seg id="3">A solution, that the Urdu speaking or the Urdu, who speak or learning, or Pashto English learning, and all well.</seg>
<seg id="4">A ridiculous it would understand the clash but you do not seem ridiculous?</seg>
<seg id="5">The reason is that the language?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In Karachi, a story and the money of the threat of every citizen had finally was from a long time been felt.</seg>
<seg id="2">Where the bus left no stone unturned to the media coming at 50 percent of which was here in four days.</seg>
<seg id="3">The last three nights and fear of them now.</seg>
<seg id="4">The hotel to vacate and those who want to kill meager.</seg>
<seg id="5">On the super highway robbers and the mine are ignorant of the agony of all who will never caught coming to them.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">What do you think the lawlessness suddenly? What are the reasons for this.</seg>
<seg id="2">(BBC)</seg>
<seg id="3">The heart of India's Mumbai the murder of keeping in Karachi, because due to the lack of secure we need is not easy but rather, it to, and this is the reason that the lack of only ', ' the the. .</seg>
<seg id="4">It's obvious that if ' father, with it will take, son to be out of control, it will not be.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Blood, Liaquat Ali Khan, and there was also a very wrong of the Sher writing this era.</seg>
<seg id="2">The tradition of the we will also be</seg>
<seg id="3">John and life and will be made.</seg>
<seg id="4">Maulana tausif Siddiqui</seg>
<seg id="5">It is a matter of regret at this time, the whole country at risk, and we felt in each other &quot;.</seg>
<seg id="6">Siddiqui stated that if Wikipedia.</seg>
<seg id="7">In London, Liaquat Ali Khan you know you can see that belonged to a respectable Punjabi area of the Punjab Province Karnal family.</seg>
<seg id="8">Because of the measures for the refugee from their they are today.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">, it is a reaction.</seg>
<seg id="2">Can be tolerated, its nature.</seg>
<seg id="3">Ijaz Awan.</seg>
<seg id="4">Mr. before it also suggested that in a short span of Jim, collecting tells you that you have real to open the match tomorrow in Karachi today, of the walls of on the wall chalking and posters and are also available.</seg>
<seg id="5">We both are coming.</seg>
<seg id="6">However, the founder of Pakistan, and Pakistan also not spared, they do not have to face any reaction.</seg>
<seg id="7">The heart are the heart of the Pakistan.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">One of Muslim League (N) has also was the eighteenth amendment draft of the making of the party.</seg>
<seg id="2">Prior to this MQM and the Muslim League (Q) the eighteenth collected in the National Assembly and the Senate have been revived.</seg>
<seg id="3">So far, it seems that the eighteenth amendment is a political ploy, and the amendment to the approved is not sincere.</seg>
<seg id="4">This is the reason that so far, or any on the floor of the Senate in favor of the amendment not nor to the House that they forced the amendment.</seg>
<seg id="5">It seems the eighteenth draft of the amendment of the these parties have submitted to the is on Bush yesterday to have been able to say that we have amendment, the government has not taken the speaker.</seg>
<seg id="6">The MQM, an ally of the government, the Muslim League (N) government ally and the near to the Muslim League (Q) party, then how can these parties sincere in the 17th amendment to the end.</seg>
<seg id="7">In this situation, the martyrs an excuse.</seg>
<seg id="8">The People's Party, is in no hurry to end the 17th amendment.</seg>
<seg id="9">Forgotten how no one can think of their own hands.</seg>
<seg id="10">Until the president is not the end of the 17th amendment.</seg>
<seg id="11">It was a survey in our opinion, and it is also true.</seg>
<seg id="12">If the 17th constitutional amendment, then we must not become president.</seg>
<seg id="13">Now, President Musharraf even more because they are with the president is also the chairman of the People's Party.</seg>
<seg id="14">As is the 17th amendment, the president is set up.</seg>
<seg id="15">Political parties to end the 17th constitutional amendment to secure the first president from the presidency will have to be.</seg>
<seg id="16">Do not want the MQM and other political parties.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Our family from most of the senior labor class</seg>
<seg id="2">In childhood, and his uncle, when we see the maternal uncle, etc. , have to retaliate in the heart of God that we want to have one to save from the physical labor.</seg>
<seg id="3">To avoid this daily wrote a letter to the editor of today and we have asked that we should that we do not have to be physically labor.</seg>
<seg id="4">In response, wrote editor, said that the doctors or engineers go to catch such and such articles.</seg>
<seg id="5">Our trend from the beginning and we had also matriculation instead of only through the technical drawings.</seg>
<seg id="6">But the F. C. S. of the force at the time that we had in medical F. C. S. and a doctor.</seg>
<seg id="7">We read and, when it had not play for the subjects of mathematics.</seg>
<seg id="8">We made of his family, and now we are in a good position on which we are all the time to thank God.</seg>
<seg id="9">We remember the time when we talk with his two young sons were trying to take the old home.</seg>
<seg id="10">Just half an hour, while the work was not &quot; just that his younger son spoke to secure that this work has not been created.</seg>
<seg id="11">We said if this is true, then our way and light low of physical labor.</seg>
<seg id="12">He said I am studying was and will also go to my work, but it is not.</seg>
<seg id="13">&quot; We like the one in three said they work for three hours and return home.</seg>
<seg id="14">That means that if the destination of the man and no matter what the reason behind this, then no one couldn't stop to it.</seg>
<seg id="15">Yes, if you do not know that you have to do, then only God Hafiz.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">He says that the dead but also what we do on the first anniversary of evil are seen in them.</seg>
<seg id="2">Benazir Bhutto, for the sake of its interests in the fight list of India to provide the on the one hand, the freedom of movement and on the other hand, the source of the movement of the Indian Punjab to suppress in Kashmir after provided an opportunity to concentrate.</seg>
<seg id="3">Nawaz Sharif and the power of genocide is a part of history, which has been pushed to several years behind the country.</seg>
<seg id="4">Benazir said the exile of Kashmir and the nuclear program on the continued.</seg>
<seg id="5">Benazir Bhutto, Nawaz Sharif, a violation of the agreement with London deal with General Musharraf.</seg>
<seg id="6">Benazir Bhutto said in his term of power, and her husband the opportunity, earning money for this reason, he and Mr. Tan billions</seg>
<seg id="7">Benazir Bhutto's brother was killed in the killer of the far and punishment of children.</seg>
<seg id="8">Benazir said that despite the woman have rights, the fight to avoid the war.</seg>
<seg id="9">Benazir Bhutto has said that his father's body on politics, the same way, now the husband politics are on their body.</seg>
<seg id="10">The government but he killed his father's political to punish the criminals, it will not also registered a case against them.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">East Pakistan from US and in 37 years, our people and the rulers of callousness of the signaling that could not be celebrated their mistakes and that the mourning day on its mentality.</seg>
<seg id="2">It should be that we are making to the 16 days of December, and this kind of measures we that do not finish the incident again.</seg>
<seg id="3">This Day, we, the people of Bangladesh and bonds to send the messages they are trying to bring.</seg>
<seg id="4">The usually file of the commission, and the separation of East Pakistan, while considering the reasons.</seg>
<seg id="5">Trapped in Bangladesh to get back to the secure plan and encourage them to send gifts.</seg>
<seg id="6">But we have information of this, we should be killed.</seg>
<seg id="7">Their brothers and sisters, we are not worried because we have been.</seg>
<seg id="8">A major tragedy should be passed to the next day, then we lost in their normal life.</seg>
<seg id="9">If the East and West Germany were again the similarly, east and west Pakistan can also be one again.</seg>
<seg id="10">We would have a secure both to each other and to sacrifice to come out of it.</seg>
<seg id="11">But the desire to do look in the near future.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">When the news today, was told that the US state governor of corruption was arrested in the</seg>
<seg id="2">The removal to and from the provincial congress as soon as possible, to secure its scrutiny to prepare to take the edit the white man is one of our American colleagues, Pakistan is the knowledge of the situation that US democracy and see what the, it says.</seg>
<seg id="3">In the United States, also with a law, the man is not</seg>
<seg id="4">And your country, the president of Pakistan, which has also dropped, corruption is after.</seg>
<seg id="5">We and our jugular said if the governor who was arrested, what happened in Pakistan, Prime Minister, we once had been covered and was arrested again on the was the second time in the country.</seg>
<seg id="6">In the United States, never happened</seg>
<seg id="7">Pakistan has to break the law, of the country with the guards of the Presidential House, to leave tell me what happens in America?</seg>
<seg id="8">The Chief Justice of Pakistan, it was suspended could not be restored, in spite of what happened in the United States?</seg>
<seg id="9">The fake degree holders in Pakistan was made in the United States, what happened?</seg>
<seg id="10">In 2002, and the American Hans this year after US cellars was Hans and their defeat and was also present.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This picture Zardari from all sides in the dark in spite of being smiled.</seg>
<seg id="2">It is his smile.</seg>
<seg id="3">They understand that the United States are with the government, but they forget that with one year ago, President Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
<seg id="4">The picture, there is a family like.</seg>
<seg id="5">Prior to this, this kind of photo in the newspapers that the president is not a country with three U. S. officials.</seg>
<seg id="6">The United States is working in Pakistan and has now increased more than one and it is his Ghulam new they do not trust on which was released on the earlier.</seg>
<seg id="7">It is also possible that President Zardari for the promised to keeping it has been made.</seg>
<seg id="8">If there is no mature ruling, at least not in the picture their teeth and face the embarrassment of the slavery for it.</seg>
<seg id="9">If this democracy should be implemented picture of are in the minority, the president.</seg>
<seg id="10">The majority of the country to democracy, the ruling is and who is this picture is talking.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Heaven of Pakistan Benazir Suwat also said.</seg>
<seg id="2">According to the government's strategy with the power are being made.</seg>
<seg id="3">But the strength of the people in power and to extend their sympathy for the people to create some not give in.</seg>
<seg id="4">It is necessary that the the power of the government in place of the reasons for the finish.</seg>
<seg id="5">By the end of reasons and the Taliban themselves, it will be removed.</seg>
<seg id="6">ANP on behalf of the government bill at the extent of Swat will serve primarily.</seg>
<seg id="7">But with the survival of the government to pay attention will have to be Economic</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The beginning of General Musharraf it was felt that this nation will get rid of politicians, but changed all the intentions of power</seg>
<seg id="2">In fact because his inclusion in the to understand.</seg>
<seg id="3">The steps and he was expected to end.</seg>
<seg id="4">Bush to the end of their power, he was worried and to deal with the evaders.</seg>
<seg id="5">General Musharraf can control, but the government did not know what is happening.</seg>
<seg id="6">It is the people on the loss of lives, along with the loss of life, with ' enemy ' to a mental patient, we have not only lost</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Frontier Province Swat in the troubled region for more than a year in spite of the continuing military action from the bad situation worse.</seg>
<seg id="2">On one hand, the government writ in this area only in the National Assembly passes a resolution to the extent is left, and on the other hand, Taliban illegal FM radio channel of influence in Swat in it is being.</seg>
<seg id="3">This is the third to ordinary citizens in think that this area in the government, which should be heard.</seg>
<seg id="4">During the operation, the security forces in some gunship helicopters and the claims to the death of many extremists made known, but these killings in spite of the Taliban, not only more stable, but his government was 80 percent, according to an estimate of Swat had been set up.</seg>
<seg id="5">As a result that on the one hand, the government is not ready to accept its failure and on the other hand, Taliban stable.</seg>
<seg id="6">WHO, brotherhood in options.</seg>
<seg id="7">It is said that now how many people have asked the Taliban to a very good because they are savers of religion and &quot; God and fighting against the enemies of Islam.</seg>
<seg id="8">When asked what the reply is very good because that they are the protection of the enemies of the country and.</seg>
<seg id="9">Then he asked that who are the enemies of the country, we have got to the citizens.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">I am surprised that the Pakistani army fought with the Taliban that they could not control a small group.</seg>
<seg id="2">The Taliban illegally to track the FM on Channel could not that I think is very easy.</seg>
<seg id="3">But even then, the FBI and to the entire water with the poison.</seg>
<seg id="4">The girls schools after the school boys have been destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="5">Curfew is set up so that the Taliban easily movements.</seg>
<seg id="6">Today, during the night curfew in eight trucks loaded with the curfew and hideouts of the set.</seg>
<seg id="7">The question is how that curfew in spite of there.</seg>
<seg id="8">Akbar Bugti, the army, in the House and the Taliban to kill.</seg>
<seg id="9">God for any of its army to the Swat that the bus of the people from the clutches of the Taliban and it will prove that the Pakistani Army May on any enemy is.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Hazrat says most in the world on the basis of blood was shed, but I tell you is that if it is not religion, blood not?</seg>
<seg id="2">Pathan, like, and the other tribes, and all what are the production of religion?</seg>
<seg id="3">Never not only to religion, education, and that there is any, it is not like the Punjabi otherwise no refugee is not a religion, if not the world community in fighting and the remaining half of the personal grudge become man drowned.</seg>
<seg id="4">Actually, religion, the moral training to human is bound to come here but the creator of the universe and it has sent here the same order of here, according to live.</seg>
<seg id="5">As a Muslim, I am sure of Islam is a complete true life and religion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The residence in London after a year in every morning on their own first on the relatives of every body knows even though most have never used to find our not news by phone and then I realized that they call us, we have to our phone not to leave.</seg>
<seg id="2">In France, where two years in the coming ups also felt.</seg>
<seg id="3">Why we are not only the hope of phone.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Iraq have, in a few hours in peace, send a problem not only.</seg>
<seg id="2">Mumbai and suspected organizations, within a few hours of work.</seg>
<seg id="3">And danced, where death is to where we are advice about this.</seg>
<seg id="4">Oh and world peace, life is finished.</seg>
<seg id="5">This was really not wait for the end of May.</seg>
<seg id="6">That their right, then the oppressed to use weapons of mass destruction as broad could not even think about?</seg>
<seg id="7">When a father and his liver is being raised by ran it in any part of the heart, then you have a pain of of the battle isn't she?</seg>
<seg id="8">If not, you are entitled to human not only.</seg>
<seg id="9">But black the name of humanity.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Let it proved that this area Israelis thousands of years, the country.</seg>
<seg id="2">It should be that both nations together in love and love each other, but they remain since the west and the Arab countries are in the hands of their choice, for peace, there will never be established.</seg>
<seg id="3">But, now, Iran is also to fight their proxy war from here.</seg>
<seg id="4">Israeli action also stop at the time, then will be started after the incident.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The BBC, the interests of the United States and Israel are linked with hospitality and that is the reason that &quot; enlightenment, under the pretext of ' and the ' a series of left and one - sided and Warid is blind, is '.</seg>
<seg id="2">BBC ' is the only and anyone, and it is the only objective.</seg>
<seg id="3">Sahib this comment is that the idea will be published so that they can facts in a little bit the substance is still remaining.</seg>
<seg id="4">Thank you.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">I do not know how to write a story who in existence, but one thing is certainly every time I drink the blood of the innocent people.</seg>
<seg id="2">Every time there are wars and every time is in the blood.</seg>
<seg id="3">But it is surprising that the 21st century, the man who is firmly under control the general public is silent on this massacre,</seg>
<seg id="4">How this does not feel that it is he presented a worst form of humanity.</seg>
<seg id="5">And it is regrettable that the aspect of the human aspect of the 19th century and will present a picture of human.</seg>
<seg id="6">Anyway, Hyderabad, Deccan</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Dera Ghazi Khan of Pakistan at this time, in the entire country with the winter rains are being.</seg>
<seg id="2">According to the weather a poem of this poem is absent, along with the rain.</seg>
<seg id="3">It also received from you.</seg>
<seg id="4">The year, Bihar.</seg>
<seg id="5">, which has been declared.</seg>
<seg id="6">Never has a reason to work</seg>
<seg id="7">There was never exactly the same day or night.</seg>
<seg id="8">I have never speak the noise.</seg>
<seg id="9">It also received from you.</seg>
<seg id="10">In a note to the night.</seg>
<seg id="11">One by the CIA to be still buried.</seg>
<seg id="12">I have never put off.</seg>
<seg id="13">Never to burn himself to himself.</seg>
<seg id="14">Never gradually in the ICC.</seg>
<seg id="15">It also received from you.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">All these or case, who are, to remain in the country.</seg>
<seg id="2">The people of the sold or temples ringing from there.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is also one of our media, like faster between the leaders.</seg>
<seg id="4">The aim is only and only with the government money</seg>
<seg id="5">People, they are going to talk about it was the biggest ignorance</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It was strange's yesterday afternoon.</seg>
<seg id="2">All of the making the policeman run on the parking not to ask.</seg>
<seg id="3">And, and it was not in the mood to London on illegal vehicles.</seg>
<seg id="4">A plane of the U. S. air one of the plane and land in the river was proof.</seg>
<seg id="5">So far only know that &quot; the terrorists belong to the generation and goose.</seg>
<seg id="6">Perhaps the historic Cold. In New York.</seg>
<seg id="7">The enlarged not.</seg>
<seg id="8">My own half an hour of grief to walk with the outside is being felt.</seg>
<seg id="9">We know that these planes from the people who have been recently jumping into the river.</seg>
<seg id="10">It is happy that all of the People were safe.</seg>
<seg id="11">It is a matter of grief and that the company's planes drown in the crisis.</seg>
<seg id="12">It to see the jersey and was also on the way after seeing that it is closed in the south and then what?</seg>
<seg id="13">) was caught in the rush in return.</seg>
<seg id="14">But thank God that my one hour some point during the only open that I was the exit of 56 Street.</seg>
<seg id="15">In the first two exit, on the lines were not looking for.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan, my Mubarak to you too Eid.</seg>
<seg id="2">Of course faith</seg>
<seg id="3">Khairpur: Mubarak, you also Eid Mubarak.</seg>
<seg id="4">: has two Qurban and it is as though he is given a say</seg>
<seg id="5">Besides this, no way.</seg>
<seg id="6">And this form and himself on the meat is also including to slavery.</seg>
<seg id="7">: the right time.</seg>
<seg id="8">Forum on what happened?</seg>
<seg id="9"></seg>
<seg id="10">The blog suno with two hands in to see.</seg>
<seg id="11">: Mubarak, you also Eid Mubarak.</seg>
<seg id="12">Sir crane.</seg>
<seg id="13">Snow will be disappeared.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">We consider the in a civilized, only on the education of women.</seg>
<seg id="2">The angry not every day to the school and college of women was expressing their views.</seg>
<seg id="3">But most of the way the views they think it was also not proved correct, the CNN news today on Monday, according to the report, all of the Talabani on a school for boys, demolished.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Taliban of the demolished school boys</seg>
<seg id="5">The girls ' school, in fact, following the first ladies were English &quot; while I do not know now, the Taliban are also civilized people and culture say for why they are under</seg>
<seg id="6">It is also a clear and is that Talabani started on this allegation that they are against the education of girls, not right.</seg>
<seg id="7">But they are against the education.</seg>
<seg id="8">May God give power to the Mujahideen, and Pakistan and the government.</seg>
<seg id="9">We imposed on him, it is to help them.</seg>
<seg id="10">Amen Amen.</seg>
<seg id="11">One hundred eighty schools have been demolished.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Born in the Muslims from the very first thing, to property from the Quran in the name of the trend of having to marriage, and many on the fact that the girl in eight years old and adult Aqil, was not only in India, said that the girl's marriage news.</seg>
<seg id="2">On the occasion of marriage was a picture.</seg>
<seg id="3">Some time ago, before the marriage of a dog with a girl was also present.</seg>
<seg id="4">They also see.</seg>
<seg id="5">Humanity in the 21st century.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Today is the era of computers and in every walk of life are increasing.</seg>
<seg id="2">A lot of the people on the intervention of a computer on the number are such that financial affairs.</seg>
<seg id="3">As to the use of credit cards, where you are there to facilitate your private life on the law enforcing agencies, the control of the</seg>
<seg id="4">That only the financial matters such as the use of credit card records to you know you can afford.</seg>
<seg id="5">And in the future when to use the year will be very low, and the benefits will be increased.</seg>
<seg id="6">The crime rate in the World Bank instead of taking the risk of credit card information, the area around it.</seg>
<seg id="7">Now, have also become sources to Friendship</seg>
<seg id="8">The social network, and Web sites to book as, fees, and Mai in popularity in the first level.</seg>
<seg id="9">But you do not think that we are mentally as their network of social works are going to take practical, as far as the people are going on.</seg>
<seg id="10">Similarly, the web site of the match where you have to choice and conform to the list of people who are to play.</seg>
<seg id="11">What do you just as your own life, a person can live?</seg>
<seg id="12">I can not spend for this, it is also said to have a better half.</seg>
<seg id="13">Me that they will be in full.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Perhaps I got some part in mind the very few.</seg>
<seg id="2">Any to say that there is a big thing for me is only the truth.</seg>
<seg id="3">This as was sure to the question of the world know the answer.</seg>
<seg id="4">I also very much fun on it.</seg>
<seg id="5">But only the truth that he was also very possible.</seg>
<seg id="6">That was very confusing there was the need of increasing.</seg>
<seg id="7">In this age it also suffered losses.</seg>
<seg id="8">Therefore, I try to at least lies.</seg>
<seg id="9">A false Lara to do, and he also started with the name of God.</seg>
<seg id="10">And then say when I pray to God that the job.</seg>
<seg id="11">The rest only God knows better.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is a matter of which was far from the evil of religion born.</seg>
<seg id="2">According to the law of both the mother and the children have less to hear.</seg>
<seg id="3">The cost of their responsibility and parents of the children can get.</seg>
<seg id="4">When children be mature, which would have to continue.</seg>
<seg id="5">You correct that is the real problem and teach their relatives, who have turned.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">All our thinking on deeds dominates.</seg>
<seg id="2">Here is also thinking the same work that a new part of the property and otherwise, the father of the process and this is praiseworthy.</seg>
<seg id="3">In the context of our relationship with reference to these establishments have created the social evil</seg>
<seg id="4">, and the concept of marriage.</seg>
<seg id="5">The same beliefs and traditions of which are being family system due to the confusion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In our society if a 50 year old man's wife or husband and wife should be sent where, if you see and should take, and it is good to see it, why not?</seg>
<seg id="2">Our near a Pakistani, and his wife are ten or twelve years ago, has died, and now all the marriages of children, he said the woman after a widow and children, were against them.</seg>
<seg id="3">In my opinion, it is his constitutional right what you say?</seg>
<seg id="4">We have to take the place of our mother, we cannot tolerate the thinking of what kind of thinking?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">I think it's should think that if the children of all the children of weddings after he got married woman from a widow, a wrong?</seg>
<seg id="2">In this way, it also woman support Hekmatyar and he has also been no home to return the</seg>
<seg id="3">Because of their children, world bars any time and will not be able to do.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This is the reason that.</seg>
<seg id="2">Tomorrow, if their wives to serve the old refused to, then what they would do?</seg>
<seg id="3">This is the result of the pressure of the society.</seg>
<seg id="4">When the people living on such fun of the family, father of children on his second marriage to be the embarrassed.</seg>
<seg id="5">Although they should face the situation and said that his father should act in accordance with the teachings of Islam.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is in our society, a curse last 40 - 50 years, we have been fully.</seg>
<seg id="2">A wife, even if it is approved, that between the second but not to the spot.</seg>
<seg id="3">If in the bus after his death, it would have to pay.</seg>
<seg id="4">Mian, along with their conclusion also destroyed and dirt in the society is the source of a major cause also.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Islam strain of Islam which are not our customs and traditions are.</seg>
<seg id="2">For example, Girls, Girls, Education and to keep part of and on marriage.</seg>
<seg id="3">The question is if you are a widow, instead of bringing home a and become satisfied the silence (Yes, widow of in the then she) .</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Indo - Pak subcontinent in Islamabad, and we have accepted centuries ago, but it could not even think to chase the and customs and traditions of Islam to go higher.</seg>
<seg id="2">The men's second marriage, divorce of the woman, a divorced, the honor marks on the and women from the age of married woman, as a result of this philosophy understand the same.</seg>
<seg id="3">And, in western nations, and we have a copy of the curtain in.</seg>
<seg id="4">Islamabad to accept this, it was very difficult to pursue.</seg>
<seg id="5">We are all God's courage and strength.</seg>
<seg id="6">Amen.</seg>
<seg id="7">Urdu, never write difficult.</seg>
<seg id="8">Harmonious Baitul much writing a book.</seg>
<seg id="9">As yet.</seg>
<seg id="10">May Allah protect.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Amir Timor in his book, &quot; Timor &quot; I'm in writing that this secret that if any one found in his life in the army commander in chief of army deployed in the first, then he will not be the failed.</seg>
<seg id="2">But on the other hand, and the situation.</seg>
<seg id="3">It would be better for us, the people are dying if we were to</seg>
<seg id="4">People in any case, the murder of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Made.</seg>
<seg id="2">Today after Isha prayers in the night by the shop of a man who has been in a car, focused their hands.</seg>
<seg id="3">In this way, the man has been forgotten in his wheel vehicle was stopped in the entire family.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said the trend of good in Arabic in the unseen understand that no, said that there is no problem?</seg>
<seg id="5">This trend in Riyadh from here in Medina, in my pocket, but no one has been cut any help to you, please, I said that the brother, situated along with me that I wrote that the it will go away full petrol, but it has little to started getting to work.</seg>
<seg id="6">I had a very angry has threatened to kill her if she protested.</seg>
<seg id="7">Nawab condition, we are also the vehicles for the family demanding the Muslims are along with at least publicized.</seg>
<seg id="8">While it clear viewpoints (Peace be upon Him) to hand down under the with the to demanding.</seg>
<seg id="9">Allah we will (Amen Amen) .</seg>
<seg id="10"></seg>
<seg id="11"></seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Adnan Sami on renowned singer, the wife of the accused to the violence, while a police station in Mumbai.</seg>
<seg id="2">, the police said they were instructed to go to court.</seg>
<seg id="3">Adnan Sami wife said her husband's request that Adnan Sami on continuous violence.</seg>
<seg id="4">Discrimination and inhuman treatment. .</seg>
<seg id="5">Now it has been out of the his case should be registered against Adnan Sami</seg>
<seg id="6">Police have registered the case and instead of saying they were instructed to go to the court the issue is not acceptable by the police.</seg>
<seg id="7">Adnan Sami, in your view on accusation of his wife is correct?</seg>
<seg id="8">This allegation Adnan Sami as the Indian attempt, not?</seg>
<seg id="9">In this regard we are aware of their opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-, Maher.</seg>
<seg id="2">As far as allegation is concerned, no human being can give each other.</seg>
<seg id="3">With the honor is not anything else.</seg>
<seg id="4">The wife and Adnan Sami Adnan Sami, with some even leave my honor was earning money the life of India, is now the neck of the famous psychologist</seg>
<seg id="5">This is their actions.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Washington ...</seg>
<seg id="2">Senior US officials said that the President of Afghan President Hamid Karzai will adopt a</seg>
<seg id="3">In Afghanistan, the United States in the war, instead of the more importance is given.</seg>
<seg id="4">According to the officials, Zai on behalf of the US forces in Afghanistan is being considered as because corruption in the government, business has increased and the strength of the Taliban again and is being collected.</seg>
<seg id="5">American officials said that the US in the Hamid Karzai on some of the people are exertion pressure for the vice president in the WHO and representatives of Pakistan and Afghanistan, and the president Richard Hall.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the strategy of President Bush, who has come forth after every two weeks after Hamid and Zai, a video conference on Afghanistan and its institutions and citizens in the reconstruction of the role of the U. S. was urged.</seg>
<seg id="7">Officials said that the central government as an alternative administration will work with the provincial leaders.</seg>
<seg id="8">Authorities say that Hamid and stressed to the war against corruption from more will give.</seg>
<seg id="9">Hamid Karzai, is facing new elections this year and it is still not clear that he and his colleague for President will support them or not.</seg>
<seg id="10">In Afghanistan, a statement of the U. S. with regard to policy change in the tent, not?</seg>
<seg id="11">The end of the Hamid Karzai is?</seg>
<seg id="12">This is what your opinion?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The one - day matches between Pakistan and Sri series in Sri Lanka Pakistan to 1 - 2.</seg>
<seg id="2">The first one day match in Sri Lanka defeated Pakistan in the next matches, has won two Sri Lanka.</seg>
<seg id="3">The third one day match in national cricket team is very poor performance of the national team, the Sri Lanka only in response to 309 23 runs in over 75 runs on the nose, and thus it had to face defeat.</seg>
<seg id="4">This proves that the result of the series of the national cricket team is not in.</seg>
<seg id="5">Despite the home ground, and all the claims of the national team was defeated, in your opinion, this is what causes.</seg>
<seg id="6">The authorities of what is necessary to pay more attention on sectors?</seg>
<seg id="7">You are not satisfied with the selection of the team</seg>
<seg id="8">How you can defeat the responsibility of the sector will be imposed on the field, batting and bowling?</seg>
<seg id="9">Asked about his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Babar Hussain, Jeddah - country, and it is a matter of regret that the modern era of the also fiefdom cultures are underway for its sovereignty, but its landlord landlord to innocent people who will say they are targeting?</seg>
<seg id="2">Sardar you never any them on time, the government does not take action against them why?</seg>
<seg id="3">When the judicial justice will work</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-, London, the statement of his choice, are also to some our wish is that you should also be given a written statement in the winners of the overturned did not mention the cruel the cranes, because it is the right to order, it is of and the level of Jihad, Mukherjee said they are trying to stay in their reports the statement.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Yousuf, Dubai - country.</seg>
<seg id="2">It is the same people switch are fighting a war for the last 60 years.</seg>
<seg id="3">Now, not only has asked the terrorism, and the main point of the war, compromise and have started talking of defense posts.</seg>
<seg id="4">The first massacre of Muslims are now in the resolve issues</seg>
<seg id="5">However, Pakistan will have to understand the policy</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">London - Khan,</seg>
<seg id="2">This kind of India is creating a situation that the world should be removed from the Kashmir.</seg>
<seg id="3">But Pakistan has always face the reality of the world.</seg>
<seg id="4">The British government now is to understand this terrorism with the name of Kashmir and Pakistan, as from the.</seg>
<seg id="5">While talking with Pakistan and are investing on this issue.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">David British foreign minister has said that the solution of the Kashmir issue will end the Pakistan government should be on the border, to give birth to deal with the dangers of will be an effective manner.</seg>
<seg id="2">It should be recalled that prior to this, the newly elected US President on Kashmir issue have expressed the same ideas.</seg>
<seg id="3">The British foreign secretary in Mumbai, wrote in an article that the war against terrorism is that it is wrong to think of themselves for the challenges facing the people of the risks to the murder of President Bush's policy.</seg>
<seg id="4">David band has said that Pakistan has, to some extremist groups will not show anything.</seg>
<seg id="5">The major powers to resolve the Kashmir dispute and stressed the need to India because of tension in the region to issue to divert attention from the efforts are not?</seg>
<seg id="6">Terrorism in Mumbai, part of this strategy?</seg>
<seg id="7">India terrorism wants to escape from the process of composite dialogue is?</seg>
<seg id="8">Asked about his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Usman.</seg>
<seg id="2">I think they are big powers to Pakistan does not have a complete loss.</seg>
<seg id="3">But it of some measures to keep in control, that Pakistan is a nuclear power</seg>
<seg id="4">Here, if you want to have a revolution.</seg>
<seg id="5">Foreign countries are thinking that Pakistan wants to corner geographic, some political problems are also want to help Pakistan and also want to fulfill their goals.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- A civilian, the U. S. A..</seg>
<seg id="2">He is always beside the tradition that would give a knife in the Ram</seg>
<seg id="3">I think that the bus with a little in the stomach pain and comes to Pakistan, and they seem to be threatening.</seg>
<seg id="4">We are ready to provide all kinds of India to stop its chief Ofgem otherwise we keep his mouth to know the answer.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Faheem siddiquee.</seg>
<seg id="2">Ras, a statement from the United States is the minds of India the same how will know the reality, who is in the water.</seg>
<seg id="3">Hamas attack on Israel is an honor, but that it should stop in Israel, India has also saw India wants to see the same</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Prime Minister Syed Yusuf Geelani has said that the newly elected vice president of the former President Musharraf's uniform and to restore democracy to have played an important role in the government of Pakistan has, for the Sitara - I - Imtiaz with them.</seg>
<seg id="2">Uniform and the restoration of democracy in any political party should not go to credit, the parliament is not a rubber stamp.</seg>
<seg id="3">All decisions will be in the parliament.</seg>
<seg id="4">The prime minister said that Dr Qadeer has closed the chapter.</seg>
<seg id="5">Do you think the public protest against free there is no importance of?</seg>
<seg id="6">The lawyers movement did not play any role?</seg>
<seg id="7">The prime minister statement on what would you like to say.</seg>
<seg id="8">Asked about his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">US President George W. Bush in his farewell press conference, the newly elected president, Barak said that he has many mistakes in his post and Ehud Barak to the right. He.</seg>
<seg id="2">According to the president, as the situation and in the US under the constitution and the law, given its popularity on priority.</seg>
<seg id="3">Today, he said, the are also planning to attack on America, Ehud Barak for to stop these attacks, will be the biggest challenge.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that a large scale destruction from Iraq of weapons of mass destruction do not get my for the biggest disappointment and complete the mission in Iraq to admit I was the biggest mistake.</seg>
<seg id="5">White House in his address to the press conference, the president said that it is my last press conference and participate in the conference, journalists and I thank those who participated in it.</seg>
<seg id="6">Do you think that they will not be repeated mistakes committed by Bush?</seg>
<seg id="7">Admitted to not delay in acknowledgment of the mistakes?</seg>
<seg id="8">Bush's will follow.</seg>
<seg id="9">Asked about his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">US Vice President Dick Cheney says that I want to see Osama bin Laden dead or alive.</seg>
<seg id="2">He said that Osama bin Laden area difficult, and for his organization has been ineffective if Osama bin Laden is dead or alive, the arrested the the organization will have to be abolished.</seg>
<seg id="3">America is determined to arrest Usama Bin Ladin on and continue the search of Osama.</seg>
<seg id="4">Dick Cheney will become the desire of</seg>
<seg id="5">Asked about his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The all rounder Shahid Afridi cricketer as Quaid e Azam trophy in the PIA and Habib Bank, the first day of the match, at the end of the game after a clash with spectators.</seg>
<seg id="2">The UBL Shahid Afridi will play on the ground after the match as soon as he came out of drawing room, a large number of fans gathered around them.</seg>
<seg id="3">On one hand, the picture of him on with Shahid Afridi, goals, said the picture, however, taking the total to spectators on the insistence of Shahid Afridi on the receipt and slapped him in her earlier in each other that they would issue the people there had once taken the</seg>
<seg id="4">Shahid Afridi, after which it said that this issue is being made at that time I was quickly, the prayer.</seg>
<seg id="5">However, I regret to the spectators.</seg>
<seg id="6">Shahid Afridi on attitude what you will say.</seg>
<seg id="7">We should inform their opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has once again alleged that Pakistan is the atmosphere of war.</seg>
<seg id="2">The state terrorism and Pakistan's policy to be used.</seg>
<seg id="3">In New Delhi chief minister while addressing the conference, Manmohan Singh said that the terrorists backing from neighboring countries, especially Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="4">Mumbai of terrorist attacks and the ship and adopt a pair of Indian coast guards were safe.</seg>
<seg id="5">Indian Prime Minister said that the attack in Mumbai the Lashkar - e - Taiba.</seg>
<seg id="6">He further said that the terrorists are using new techniques and modern communication system, we the line of control, it will also strictly follow the infiltration is that any form of terrorism will not be tolerated and it is our policy.</seg>
<seg id="7">The Indian prime minister's allegation on how you see?</seg>
<seg id="8">The internal Progressive movements is reflective of the unrest.</seg>
<seg id="9">India, who at the whims of the threatening attitude is adopted.</seg>
<seg id="10">Asked about his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Zubair Khan, Karachi.</seg>
<seg id="2">This is a great tragedy of that the Palestinians are the same Kashmir but also the situation is not as far as the head of the Council.</seg>
<seg id="3">Organizations who are present in Palestine and Kashmir and that they should continue the war until its and create wealth of every type of aggression continue to face a not a day with one of his martyrdom will bring color.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Israeli air strike on Gaza is continuing, hundreds of Palestinian men, women and children have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="2">The political of Hamas, including the wife and children have been martyred.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Security Council meeting has ended without any decisions.</seg>
<seg id="4">In the meeting, Libya and other Arab countries against Israel presented on behalf of the U. S. opposing the resolution is facing.</seg>
<seg id="5">Many Palestinian civilian population bombing by the Israeli planes.</seg>
<seg id="6">The incidents of Mumbai on the entire world was screaming, but the Israeli attacks on America, including Britain, I do not see any common?</seg>
<seg id="7">The important countries of the Muslim Ummah are silent why?</seg>
<seg id="8">The world's double standards say what you want.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Saeed, New York.</seg>
<seg id="2">In my opinion, the real thing is that our nation they know that their money is being is where the tax imposed by the government to fulfill its responsibilities is interested in electricity and gas crisis and the work will continue.</seg>
<seg id="3">Because the people who elected their role is the most familiar.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan the length and breadth of gas and electricity a crisis situation.</seg>
<seg id="2">On the other hand, gas prices have been increasing in 8 in some cities of the country while the non - availability of petrol is a severe problem for the people.</seg>
<seg id="3">Pakistan's industrial and business circles in the electricity and gas long closure on the crisis of severe reaction on the riots and protests continued violence.</seg>
<seg id="4">The industrialists's ultimatum to stop.</seg>
<seg id="5">The eight to 10 hours of load shedding in Karachi and is found among the citizens.</seg>
<seg id="6">Industrial and life was almost reduced.</seg>
<seg id="7">In this regard, the government institutions and accusations on each other in his position statement.</seg>
<seg id="8">The electricity and gas prices to the taste of the nation, not?</seg>
<seg id="9">To solve the problems of attention is being given why not?</seg>
<seg id="10">The government for the development of national transportation is not seem?</seg>
<seg id="11">To overcome this crisis immediately steps that you will be proposed.</seg>
<seg id="12">Asked about his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Imran, I want to say that just like the people.</seg>
<seg id="2">I wonder if civilian government is the slogan of &quot; the people giving to hurt</seg>
<seg id="3">Get a torment has not of petrol.</seg>
<seg id="4">The government institutions as there is no control.</seg>
<seg id="5">The law and order situation is deteriorating day by day, the mercy of Allah give US country.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">New Year.</seg>
<seg id="2">Last year and type of the year, with regard to terrorism will also be remembered it.</seg>
<seg id="3">President Musharraf President Bush at the end of the era, and the establishment of a democratic government in Pakistan, natural disasters, the earthquake, all over the world financial crisis, in marketing.</seg>
<seg id="4">Now the arrival of the new year, the year you have come to see how?</seg>
<seg id="5">In the geographical situation will bring a political or what color the strategy will be done?</seg>
<seg id="6">The elimination of terrorism in the hope of any progress.</seg>
<seg id="7">Pakistan will be the end of the judicial crisis in</seg>
<seg id="8">Relations between Pakistan and India would adopt?</seg>
<seg id="9">It is expected that the surgical full or war?</seg>
<seg id="10">Are you what to expect from the new year?</seg>
<seg id="11">Asked about his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">US President George W. Bush to the government on eight years after the departure of the white Camp David to camp presidential office so that the White House to have a new president, according to the can be ready the renovated</seg>
<seg id="2">President Bush's eight - year America on the World Trade Center attack the historic destruction, and then the attack on the global war against terrorism in Afghanistan and Iraq, the military action in in various countries, while in this war and the forces of the US war and full use of resources in this were the of the memorable examples of Bush.</seg>
<seg id="3">With the war in the history of the worst economic and financial crisis facing.</seg>
<seg id="4">Do you think the war in the world and what is found.</seg>
<seg id="5">President Bush's policies succeed?</seg>
<seg id="6">The government of President Bush what is your opinion?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Indian government to the Indian cricket team will tour Pakistan to stop.</seg>
<seg id="2">The Indian cricket team's tour of Pakistan, three tests and five one - day matches and a Twenty match play.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Indian cricket board's Vice President, Rajeev Shukla told Geo News while talking to the board, has said that the government was allowed to visit Pakistan between the two countries, however, the current tense situation, it is not possible due to the visit.</seg>
<seg id="4">What the Indian government for the present political situation of the cricket team visited the game from politics is not right to cancel should be kept?</seg>
<seg id="5">The decision of the Indian government is not harmful for cricket?</seg>
<seg id="6">The security situation in India continue worse cricket team visited the Indian team visiting Pakistan cannot investigate why not?</seg>
<seg id="7">What is your opinion in this regard.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Karachi.</seg>
<seg id="2">People who are proud to India</seg>
<seg id="3">The films and videos or there are now lives opened his how you that the people of India's honor.</seg>
<seg id="4">I remember Adnan Sami an interview in which he said was that Pakistan is not my British citizenship</seg>
<seg id="5">Adnan Sami should to be the first time in Pakistan that they honor because there is not any rescue Ras.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Farid Ahmad.</seg>
<seg id="2">Karachi.</seg>
<seg id="3">Mumbai after the attack on the Indian attitude changed.</seg>
<seg id="4">In this situation, Singh said his reaction that they hate Pakistan and Pakistanis.</seg>
<seg id="5">Sami Adnan know that the with sing songs, from where they are now end, there is no need to be in India should here.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Muhammad Alam, Shamshad</seg>
<seg id="2">Karachi, Singh's statement on I would only say that the color also be held.</seg>
<seg id="3">In a statement to the occasion to urge Pakistanis are flying in India, that you appreciate how much is the mentality of you are so.</seg>
<seg id="4">After the incident, and a statement of his hatred is now against the famous Sami are polluted.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">According to a foreign news agency, U. S. on a farewell visit of US President George W. Bush in Iraq, together with Prime Minister Noor Maleki in his office located in Baghdad during the press conference in the present situation, the when an Iraqi journalist, President Bush, while it is &quot; addressing a farewell to kiss.</seg>
<seg id="2">After this, a journalist picked up his Bush expertise to throw, President Bush has already given by his head and leaned on your guarded.</seg>
<seg id="3">To the American flag.</seg>
<seg id="4">Security personnel to the journalists, from the place.</seg>
<seg id="5">On this occasion, President Bush said that I do not know why, the number was 10, I did not face any problem.</seg>
<seg id="6">What do you think this process of the Iraqi people by President Bush expressed his anger was not against the?</seg>
<seg id="7">What you will say on the incident.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In Mumbai, the incidents of terrorism after the relations between India and Pakistan in the tension situation created at this time the serious when the Indian Air Force fighter planes in Lahore and Kashmir sectors, Pakistan's air territory of the violation.</seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan Indian counter action of the air force were forced to go back.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to the sources, both Indian plane armed with weapons and ammunition.</seg>
<seg id="4">The present tense situation in the first incident of its kind.</seg>
<seg id="5">Pakistan Air Force, said that the air force to defend the country is ready.</seg>
<seg id="6">The information minister Sherry Rehman said that Indian officials have acknowledged that the violation of the air limits, however it by mistake.</seg>
<seg id="7">The Pakistan military sources said the incident was described as serious.</seg>
<seg id="8">What you really the air attack on Pakistan, India has the intention to?</seg>
<seg id="9">India's stand that it is correct that it was a mistake or violation of this purpose, the ability of the Pakistan Air Force.</seg>
<seg id="10">The incident happened in tension between the two countries will not become the cause of?</seg>
<seg id="11">Asked about his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Ms Benazir martyred after human rights at the International Award of which was his son and the People's Party and chairman of the Bhutto Zardari has made.</seg>
<seg id="2">President of the Office of the United Nations General Assembly in a ceremony during the meeting of the Pakistan's former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto, the human rights of their services for the award in the field.</seg>
<seg id="3">The UN resolution of the human rights birthday was celebrated on December 10.</seg>
<seg id="4">On this occasion to work for human rights in recognition of the personalities and institutions which are being given the awards Benazir Bhutto in addition to the former Attorney General Luis Clark and throughout the world to work for human rights, the International Organization for Human Rights Watch.</seg>
<seg id="5">On this occasion, the United Nations Ambassador to Pakistani diplomatic Abdullah Haroon and other senior officials were also present.</seg>
<seg id="6">Former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto on receiving the award were what you will say.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Sameer.</seg>
<seg id="2">Chicago.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is true that he was but it, but we should also remember that he has many innocent people of blood shed in Karachi, on which they were proud that it does Naseer the Allah Babar took a very good job.</seg>
<seg id="4">After I have</seg>
<seg id="5">But it is also true that he is his party's senior people were on the way to his son and a representative of the People's Party, this kind of democracy, is it?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Jimmy Noor, this news from the Karachi, it has been proved that the will not give the infidel.</seg>
<seg id="2">But when the iron axe group can not think on the be</seg>
<seg id="3">The way our rulers, he is the secret way some of its members are appointed to the same reason the country.</seg>
<seg id="4">Our rulers to God.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The United Nations Security Council panel, said Hafiz Muhammad Saeed, including three Pakistani citizens and Jamaat - ud - Dawa organizations including the names of five are included on the list of terrorists.</seg>
<seg id="2">The Security Council of the Taliban and al - Qaeda the names of the Pakistanis, who has been in the list of terrorists of the committee approved to Mohammad Saeed, included in the Jamaat chief selector of outlawed organization Lashkar - e - Rehman, chief the head of the Finance Department, Haji Mohammad Ashraf.</seg>
<seg id="3">Apart from this, a Saudi citizen name is also included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
<seg id="4">These organizations in Kashmir, Jamaat ul Dawa, Al Rashid Trust Trust International.</seg>
<seg id="5">The member countries, and the absence of all the organizations, personalities will freeze and a travel ban and assets will be appointed, they will be arrested.</seg>
<seg id="6">They will face cases.</seg>
<seg id="7">Under the impact of the sanctions, the Indian propaganda, not?</seg>
<seg id="8">Mumbai, India without any evidence of the attacks on charges of these organizations, why is it?</seg>
<seg id="9">In India, was not terrorist organizations</seg>
<seg id="10">In India, on minorities in the international organizations to not know.</seg>
<seg id="11">We should inform their opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">And the a spokesman of the arrangement of the Eid and the practice of the Abraham and on the sacrifice of livestock, while the process.</seg>
<seg id="2">On this occasion American dress, at a time when the inflation the political conditions, the poor and according to the preparation of friends in different ways and to congratulate the Eid.</seg>
<seg id="3">We also provided an opportunity are that their loved ones in the form of short messages to the Eid Mubarak congratulated.</seg>
<seg id="4">Eid urge you to also congratulated the verses.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Jilani,</seg>
<seg id="2">Karachi, our rulers should understand this fact that they are against the U. S. and Pakistan are every kind of the all the three are from Pakistan, but a great love.</seg>
<seg id="3">If the war, we will fight the shoulder to shoulder with Pakistan</seg>
<seg id="4">When they will be feeling of love, and only a few will not be obtained from politics, I think the war between the two decisive so that you are expected to be out.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>
