<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="site11_FSC_constrained">
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Support Proposal of France</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A meeting of the committee in the parliament house on Friday in the leadership of the Committee Chairman, Mushahid Hussain Syed, a parliamentary delegation of the representatives of all political parties in the country in which it was suggested that the relief goods sent to Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking to the representatives of the media after the meeting, Mushahid Hussain Syed said that the committee has given by France welcomed the proposal in which it has been said that Israel immediately allow the relief work for affected people in Gaza and in addition to the cease-fire.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said the attack on Israel by describing it as a crime against humanity said that all countries should condemn the attacks</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mushahid Hussain target of criticism to the double standards of the countries of the world, said that the people who are talking against terrorism, but they are now on the attacks on Palestinians by Israel are silent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Chairman of the Senate Standing Committee on foreign affairs of the leaders of the Ummah frosty also targeted criticism.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that the committee has expressed the hope that the newly elected President of the United States, Barak will address the Muslim Ummah during the first 100 days of his government the Gulf created so between the United States and the Muslim Ummah should be abolished.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mushahid Hussain Syed said that the Muslim Ummah and created between the West to take emergency steps not only to solve the long standing issues like Kashmir and Palestine should be made.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Minister of Foreign Affairs country Ammad Khan told the committee that they are going to Saudi Arabia to participate in the meeting of the foreign ministers of the Organization of Islamic countries.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The emergency meeting was called as a result of the attacks on Israel by. He said that Palestine is informed and, in this regard, the government is in contact with the leaders of other countries.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The State Minister of Foreign Affairs said that Palestine should be resolved according to UN resolutions.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Arab countries belonging to the two Journalists had also participated in the meeting and he informed the meeting about the latest situation in Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In Islamabad, on the other hand, the International University students demonstrated against the Israeli attacks on Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="14">The protesters had banners and also keep on which were registered slogans against Israel.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">To Prevent Bird Flu to Avoid</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">American scientists were on the research has come after the experiences.</seg>
    <seg id="3">From experience, it has proved that we were set on the food was less capable of dealing with bird flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Research has proved wrong the old adage that fast in the fever is proven to improve. &quot;</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the scientists, the fever during.</seg>
    <seg id="6">State University, says that the investigation of the cars in the take was found very little ability to fight infection, and they also increased the possibility of taking food, while the normal power against the bird flu virus in the was more.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to Professor, who will soon not only affect the people from bird flu, but they will be in even more time.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Of them, it is also said that those people who have taken the flu vaccine, they should also refrain from during the winter months.</seg>
 </doc>
 
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">For Best</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The show, as the basis of this, and it was put in the Ukraine or civil band and with one or two songs was also included.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This in an old car was kept on the stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The year 2000 was the second most successful show the terms of the profit of 8 million million dollars in which were obtained.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Canadian show, while, visited 24 countries were in only 17 countries, which was the first international tour in the last eight years.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Both of the director of the show was the King of the head of the Union, was also made for the visit.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Established in the year two thousand six has broken the record.</seg>
    <seg id="8">6 in the year 2000, he said, &quot;Anees 100 million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="9">As the third most successful singer declared that the 17 million to 60 million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bruce has been $60 million, 16 million, and the fourth and fifth Police numbers and their part in 12 million came six million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="11">According to this magazine, 8 in North America in the year 2000, very few people attended the songs and concert programs and only the people who were involved in these expensive prices were ready to buy tickets.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In the United States, a 8 percent increase in the price of tickets and show in the most expensive tickets sold 100 three and a half.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Embracing the editor of the magazine, said that in view of the World Economic market, this action was to be a good year for 8 year 2000.</seg>
    <seg id="14">He, nine to the year 2000 and for this year which are issued a year of proving predicted.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Coalition Ban on Education: Taliban</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The location of North Waziristan, Hafiz Gul Bahadur group in Miran Shah and other districts, local Taliban has distributed a pahmphlet in which government and semi-official their educational institutions have been threatened in which the coalition education is being given to boys and girls.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Is that if the coalition until January 5 in the educational institutions was not closed, will be started taking action against them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Pahmphlet is that government aid and other educational issues will be imposed on the identity card of women and for women has also refused to go to NADRA offices in all districts.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On behalf of the local Taliban ban on women&apos;s identity card was announced at a time when about 200 women in offices have been collected form for the identity card for a support programme in North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to local people, the Taliban issued by the pamphleteer read all mosques of North Waziristan on loud-speaker.</seg>
    <seg id="7">However, in the letter, it was not mentioned is that the girls will be imposed on separate educational institutions or not.</seg>
    <seg id="8">After the announcement, according to education or to make the identity card for any woman to go to school or NADRA office was, in the case of the woman and her family will be given legal punishment.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Besides, in the Bannu District Police say that on Sunday, a landmine blast Bannu Road, which is a result of one passerby was killed and one was injured.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Injured admitted to the civil hospital in Bannu.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">&quot;Target Killings, More Bodies Recovered,</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police on Sunday morning, President place areas are green Chowk and Sohrab Khan Chowk, the corpses of two people whose head was separated from the body.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Those killed belong to the Frontier Corps and the police is being told.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Witnesses say that a letter from near the dead bodies, which was also found in which warned that any of the day before 11 am to raise these bodies, they will personally responsible for his death.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Local people say that at 11 am until the bodies are lying in the market, security officials, however, later the two bodies to transfer.</seg>
    <seg id="6">See a dangerous extent increase in incidents of target crane during the last few weeks in the areas around the location and</seg>
    <seg id="7">There is in which civilians including women and security personnel have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="8">So far, according to local sources, more than 30 people in such incidents has been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">So far no organization has claimed responsibility for the killings.</seg>
    <seg id="10">On Saturday, local Taliban spokesman in Swat Muslim Khan told BBC that on Friday, there were three bodies of his colleagues in the bodies in which the body of the Taliban commander Rafi Ullah was also included.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The Muslim Khan said that Rafi Ullah was in the custody of the security forces over the past 15 months.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He said that when a local Taliban do killed, first issued a notice to this, on the other hand, issued in these incidents is found on severe concern in common citizens.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Local people say that in a large contingent of security forces deployed. But in spite of this, the increasing attacks on citizens.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Benazir in Tribute To</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Was recorded in the voice of a rape lance (a way of modern music) now post was also on the Tube.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Five minutes of Benazir Bhutto on the pictures and video have been given.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The 18-year-old where? University student.</seg>
    <seg id="5">His poetry and deep concern.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is being said that he has apparently after his mother to encourage started to sing.</seg>
    <seg id="7">While presented tribute to his mother, he said, that is, you were intelligent and beautiful, did all the work in a way. &quot;</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said about the incident of December 27 that you leave the temple in our shot was in the age of fiftyfour year, we were, three children survived.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The whole nation is hope you and you are present in the heart of all these.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The children of Benazir Bhutto in second place after a 20-year-old Bhutto.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He started in music from interest are quietly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Is that he had expressed a desire to meet award Laureate music producer and Dad through a journalist friend in America before the return of his mother. But the meeting was not been.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Some Sindhi newspapers of the poetry of the translation was published, but his voice being heard through the tube for the first time.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Some workers of Benazir Bhutto and the rich people started the rape lance c.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other hand, the Pakistan People&apos;s Party spokesman Farhatullah Babar has confirmed that the present on the Tube of poetry and voice.</seg>
    <seg id="16">On the phone from Islamabad, he said that it is one of his daughter tribute to the mother with the government of Pakistan, which is TV network has also been issued.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar has said that the program to distribute the CDs, his party has not made at present.</seg>
    <seg id="18">He said that a few months ago, the young year Chairman of his party on the web site before the fee was made a fake bank account or Bhutto Zardari after which have been finished.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ajmal Butcher Is Only Pakistani: Information Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Federal Minister for Information and Broadcasting, Sherry Rehman were sent to the BBC Urdu service in a message S. M. S. Ajmal butcher confirming the citizenship, just so said that further investigations are underway.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Prior to this, the Prime Minister&apos;s advisor Rehman home country had refused to his Pakistani citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that citizens who keep a record of the organization Ajmal had found no record of them.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Could not know about the recent announcement that the government of Pakistan has now changed its stand on what basis while Ajmal butcher of citizenship is confirmed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, according to a spokesman of the Foreign Ministry of citizenship, the Interior Ministry has confirmed.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Prior to this, the BBC Urdu service and a few other newspapers and TV channels had said Ajmal butcher from Farid Kot town of Okara district of Punjab province.</seg>
    <seg id="8">, however, the government was used to.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Now, it is not clear that this is related to the same Fareed Kot Ajmal or any other area.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Also Rocket Fire from Lebanon, Retaliatory Bombardment</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Israeli army and police officials told the representatives of the media is that the Lebanese area were four rockets on Israeli soil, which fell from a town in northern Israel which allowed two people were injured.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The rockets were result from the area of Lebanon in response to the Israeli bombardment on Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It is not clear that this attack, Hezbollah has or behind it, it is the hand of Palestinian groups active in Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Lebanese government has said that he is trying to address that it that those who is behind the rocket attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">BBC correspondent has declared it issued a very dangerous turn for the recent crisis in the region.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the BBC editor for the Middle East, their rocket attacks has increased the threat of war to spread.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In the last few days, it was being expressed their apprehension that the operation in Gaza will not spread anywhere in north to Israel&apos;s border with Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="9">On the other hand between Wednesday and Thursday night, Israel&apos;s air force launched 60 air attacks on the Gaza strip.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Police offices of Hamas, sheepish, weapons, water reserves, the rocket fire places and Hamas weapons closed workers were targeted in these attacks, according to the Israeli army.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Besides air attacks from the battery, the Israeli army and Navy continued the bombardment on Gaza throughout the night.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Palestinian sources said that the air attacks in a mosque in Gaza City was destroyed.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Non that according to the information, the Israeli Army tanks backed by helicopters were air advances towards the area of Khan Yunis.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Over the last 12 days on seven hundred Palestinian who is involved in a large number of women and children have been killed in the fighting.</seg>
    <seg id="15">While on the other hand, the Israeli Army, 11 soldiers were also killed.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Israel&apos;s security forces, it has been confirmed that a top defense officials are going to Cairo to decide the terms of the cease-fire.</seg>
    <seg id="17">A delegation of Hamas is to go to Cairo for parallel talks with the ambassadors of Egypt.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Besides this, the leader of the Palestinian Authority, Mahmoud Abbas is arriving in Cairo on Friday.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">My Heart Is Broken, My Kidney Demanded Back</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Richard said that he had donated them as their spirit to save his wife eight years ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the AFP news agency, Dr. has said that his wife has given the reward for his donation, that they were deceived and to establish relations with others and now refer to divorce.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Dr. said in an interview with a local newspaper daily news said that the alleged has given a hole in my heart that, until now.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Dr. Richard&apos;s lawyer, though, according to Dr. are demanding the return of his kidney, but in fact they want equal subsidies worth of organs.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to his wife, he will present their stand in front of a judge in the next few days.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">140-Year-Old, 9 Kilo Free</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">George, the joint, was held two weeks ago, a sea.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The city of sea food company had purchased it in 100 dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">And immediately had started to use the pictures of their publicity.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, a group, to work for the protection of animals, has demanded to leave as a result of which now it back will be left in the sea.</seg>
    <seg id="6">George was held by the sea in Canada, after which the city crepe and C. food company spent 10 days in the tank.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The age of the weight of this could be.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The manager of the restaurant, said that his intention was not to revive a loss to the tank, it was meant to provide goods to the interest of the consumers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The protection of animals belonging to the organization, said that the decision of the restaurant is praiseworthy and is an example for those who want to keep such rare animals or, in a tank or want to eat him alive decline.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Search for Girl with Help of Mobile</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When the officials came to know about, city police officer and the forces were coming in action.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Officials of the girl child mobile G. P. S. with the help of the present in the direction of the right place.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, street walked this direction with the help of the elections that the baby is in a hotel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Grandmother days a week ago, were taken from the supervision of their legal parents.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Will the police chief told the BBC, he said that he is not returned ever now and then, he went to leave the state.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Police had established contact with Ms. but when according to promise, he did not return, police decided to find it through the mobile phone.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Two thousand five in the United States or the law is that the companies providing mobile service should provide 95 percent of the distance of 67 percent of the distance of 100 meters and 300 meters.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on Visit Of</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Hamid Karzai is the second Indian tour in five months.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is expected that he will talk about the situation after the extremist attacks in Mumbai, during a meeting with Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this visit, he wants to express their solidarity with India and sentiments of the Mumbai attacks on Afghanistan and its people.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Besides extremism during the visit of Karzai, mutual trade will be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The extremism for mutual cooperation between the two countries is expected to be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President Hamid Karzai during his last visit to India had said that the removal of relations between India and Afghanistan would not be let.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He also said that both India and Afghanistan to face the challenge of terrorism and his mercy and assassination activities.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Both countries, the region and the entire world peace and stability is beneficial for all.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The ownership, we think that both the United Nations and the entire world, this can face the menace of terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It should be noted that in July last year, the Indian embassy in Kabul, Karzai for the attack on the intelligence agencies of Pakistan, S. I. was held responsible.</seg>
    <seg id="12">A Chief F. I. S. personnel, including four Indian were killed in the attack.</seg>
    <seg id="13">After the attack on the embassy, Karzai during the visit of Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh had said that the friendship, India and Afghanistan was attacked, we have agreed that its terrorism, we will not allow the removal of relations between.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Mumbai Attack, Special Judge for Hearing</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mumbai police commissioner Hassan Ghafoor has said that only were arrested alive will be under the supervision of the hearing, M. L. has registered a case against the accused Ajmal Amir butcher during the attacks of the extremists on the Mumbai.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Earlier in this matter, has been appointed as the government lawyer.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Ajmal butcher are currently in the custody of the police and hope is that the police will bring admitted the charge sheets against them before January 24.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ajmal butcher have no lawyer to defend himself.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The butcher in a letter written to the Pakistan government had appealed for legal help.</seg>
    <seg id="7">India have delegated the evidences of Pakistani extremists to be included in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Pakistan has accepted that Ajmal butcher Pakistani citizens.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the case, the police Ajmal and his companion Abu Ismail A. T. S. chief, additional police commissioner, Ashok, police inspector Vijay expert, killing six policemen, including his car snatched fled after D. B route, which was later do was held.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The police action was located in the death of Ismail Khan and the police had arrested Ajmal alive.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Ajmal for the prosecution of the case still has not been nominated any lawyer.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The government legal aid cell which lawyer was nominated to the Danish capital, he had refused to take the case on moral grounds.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The two lawyers have taken back its name after protests and opposition of the people of a political party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Constitutional Amendment: &quot;Committee Will Be Formed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Talking to the representatives of the media after addressing a about environmental changes in Islamabad on Tuesday, he said that the meeting of the parliamentary party will be called in this regard in which the committee will be formed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that so far by the Muttahida Qaumi Movement, for the end of 17th amendment, the constitutional amendment bill was presented in the National Assembly and other political parties will also presented a constitutional amendment bill in parliament in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that for the end of the 17th amendment, Pakistan People&apos;s Party has also sent a copy to all the political parties and the committee will also examine the draft.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In response to a question, he said that the balance of power between the President and the Prime Minister will decide the parliament.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Prime Minister said that the Parliament is empowered to all decisions.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In response to another question, he said that the former president to leave the post of the army chief, retired General Pervez Musharraf regarding besides the role of political parties, former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Pakistan People&apos;s Party Benazir Bhutto is also an important role, who urged the international community to deploy uniforms on former President Pervez Musharraf emphasized.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that US Vice President elected who are pro-democracy and Pakistan and their services in, the President of Pakistan has given him the honor of Pakistan &quot;.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In response to a question about the threat of Mumbai after the incident, on behalf of the Indian government to cut all relations with Pakistan Yusuf Raza Gilani said that the Indian Government is the severe pressure of people at this time due to which they give such statements.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Protest Against Dismissal of The</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Of journalists in Islamabad on Tuesday, R. I. U. J., under the auspices of the Islamabad in front of the Press Club, journalists and newspaper workers from the newspapers and TV channels, a large number of employees of media owners and the government&apos;s protest and shouted slogans.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Addressing the demonstrators, the largest organization of journalists, a senior member of the Pakistan federal Union of Journalists, C. R. Shamsi said that until yesterday, the political freedoms were protest on roads with us today, they are sitting in the house of a ruling, but due to a particular fear of newspaper owners, doing nothing for the rights of journalists.</seg>
    <seg id="4">To talk of human rights, he said that the newspaper owners have kept its institutions on the punishment and impress camp where billions of rupees annually, despite workers is very low charges and dismissed the is being their economic murder.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The example of Lahore, a private TV channel, a member of five is our front which was Suicide from four months for not receiving wages, and even today, many workers are spending their lives of tension due to non-payment of the repressive and months salary.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the TV and newspaper owners should be direct action against journalists and a permanent protest in front of the Parliament for the rights of the camp that is needed.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Target of criticism to the Governor of Punjab, Salman operating C. R. Shamsi said that his Urdu newspaper, today, employees is being the wrong side without any notice.</seg>
    <seg id="8">While the daily Jinnah, daily news channel five, business, plus TV and TV today has also dismissed dozens of employees</seg>
    <seg id="9">P. Mazhar Abbas, Secretary General of the F. J., while addressing the protestors said that today, a lot of journalistic organizations throughout the country against journalists and newspaper workers celebrating black day are getting their rights and journalist for black at the Parliament session and will be.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Mazhar Abbas percent of Pakistan are being exploited workers and journalists in the newspapers and TV channels, where they are working without any agreement.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that so far, more than 200 journalists and workers are being expelled from the newspapers and TV channels, and it is feared that the current year, owners will justify the economic crisis with more hundreds of workers dismissed.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas at the time of the movement of journalists would continue for as long as the dismissed employees is not considered, the newspaper workers to determine the implementation of the Wage Board award of the employees of the newspapers and TV channels have been blocked for many months and not the payment of salaries.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The 11-Member Cabinet Took Oath</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the new cabinet, former Prime Minister Sardar Ahmad Khan anti-Muslim Conference of six, two of the Pakistan Peoples Party, Peoples of two of the Muslim League and a minister of the Muttahida Qaumi Movement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">A woman Minister in the 11-member cabinet are also and they belong to Ateeq anti-Muslim Conference.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Ruling alliance has said that the cabinet should be extended in the next week and it is expected that more will be among a dozen cabinet minister, it should be remembered that in the beginning of this month, Sardar Khan his opponents through the lack of confidence, the ministry was removed from the post of Azmi and Sardar Yaqoob Khan was elected new prime minister.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Departments of these ministers will be announced later.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Swearing-in ceremony on the occasion of the Pakistan People&apos;s Party workers raised slogans in favor of former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Virus Affected 35 Million Consumers</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Two thousand eight identified in October for the first time to go up and down, and this is the virus is known by names like.</seg>
    <seg id="3">To deal with the virus had issued a plot, but despite this, nearly 35 million computers and rod have been affected by this.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Experts say that the affected a large number of the computers can be.</seg>
    <seg id="5">To deal with this, consumers need to use, M. S. zero at zero 7, perplexedness.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Said that the virus to affect hundreds of thousands of computers to search for a file, services cork E. S. E., and it is included in the Code.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After this virus in the system D. L. L. it is a kind of file.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This virus is also the name of the file.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The details of the registration of the change.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This virus, which is used to create an issue after the active, H. T. T. P. Sarwar, as has come forth and machine point change.</seg>
    <seg id="11">After this the files from the web site of the down.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Said that the virus has affected the computers in various countries of the world.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In these countries, China, Brazil, Russia, India, the United States and Britain.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">On Indian Information,</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Saturday after a meeting in the Interior Ministry, while talking to representatives of the media, he said that given by India to the</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this matter will help to the investigation.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that Pakistan is an independent country and from any country in the investigation on the information received from India a</seg>
    <seg id="5">Increasing will not accept.</seg>
    <seg id="6">India, he said that the information received by the other information are also.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Interior Advisor said that the law enforcing agencies, members of an outlawed organization was taken into custody under suspicion glitch peace</seg>
    <seg id="8">The innocent people should be released while it will take action against them, and if they find any evidence against some people in</seg>
    <seg id="9">In response to a question, he said that the arrested a person will not be handed over to India and according to the laws against these people will take the same action.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that action against these people, FIA has been under the law.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In response to a question, he said that Indian law enforcing agencies involved in the Mumbai incident, people have information about 42 days, so he is hopeful that the international community, including India, will give some time to Pakistan for investigation on his heart.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He again repeated the offer of the government that Mumbai joint team should be formed for the investigation of the incident.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It should be noted that a three-member team was formed under the additional director general of FIA is that the Mumbai attacks by India</seg>
    <seg id="14">The investigation on the information is being given to the Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Pakistan&apos;s High Commissioner to India, Shahid Malik met President Asif Ali Zardari, in which the President has made it clear that if any Pakistani individual or group, it was found involved in the Mumbai attacks, according to the international law, action will be taken against any will not be handed over to India and the Indian leadership to India about the people involved in the incident about are constantly being put pressure on Pakistan.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">, Anything Is Possible in United States,</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mr. will take oath as President of the United States on January 20.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In Washington, the US President addressing a music concert by standing on the construction of the building in the memory of Sri Lankan</seg>
    <seg id="4">While Mr. that, the United States is facing the most serious of several generations and he is hopeful that the United States will control on these problems.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Had to end the tradition of slavery in the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But even with Mr. said that time and route would be difficult to solve the problems facing the country.</seg>
    <seg id="7">&quot;but despite this, I am hopeful that the dream of this country will remain alive.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, the United States is pouch with a severe financial crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Swearing-in ceremony for the extraordinary steps are being taken.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The organizers believe that 20 million people will be involved in the ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On Monday, is a national holiday in the United States because the same day great standard of human rights, and Martin King was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Martin Luther King was black.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tribute to Martin, Determined to Work,</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Martin Luther King was killed in the nineteen hundred</seg>
    <seg id="3">The tribute to Dr. King and the Americans said that they should work together to fulfill the promises of this nation.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The oath taking ceremony of the new president on Tuesday in Washington on the other hand, the people on the occasion of the presidency preparations are being a gathering.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that the chairmanship of the president to take this historic close to 20 million people will be collected in Washington.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The start of the day on Monday at a medical center in northern Washington visit, where he had met the injured US soldiers after they were set up in a shelter for the homes and paint on a wall.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Talking to reporters, said: &quot;The present crisis of which we are in difficulties and which many people are surrounded, then we will not sit.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that Martin King has spent in the service of their more people.</seg>
    <seg id="9">That said, &quot;today, when we are respect for his memory, this day is that we should be and stay. It is the day that we should act.</seg>
    <seg id="10">On Tuesday, he said that the ceremony will be on the same path that several thousand people of Martin Luther King, I dream about it, listening to nineteen hundred were gathered.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In his speech, Martin King had said that the day will come when people see their color, discrimination would not be allowed.</seg>
    <seg id="12">BBC Mathew Price says that injustice aspect of history is that day Martin came 24 hours before the day when the first black President of American history will take oath of his office.</seg>
    <seg id="13">For many people in the southern states of the United States, was presided over by Dr. Luther King will be the dream of.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Additional Political Agent</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The additional political agent 10 days ago from South Waziristan unknown.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Sources say that the official Mullah Nazir group of local Taliban had kidnapped.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the local administration at 4 pm on Tuesday, Amir Latif near additional political agent of South Waziristan, a tribal jirga has reached the Wana Scouts camp.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, he has not revealed that the additional political agent who had been kidnapped.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, local people say that the political agent got Nazir group had kidnapped the local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The Amir Latif was kidnapped at the time when they were going from Wana.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On January 11, two thousand nine in South Waziristan tribal area, seven armed kidnapping, including the additional political agent Amir Latif driver honor.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the official, kidnapping cars had disarmed guards present in the car before and after the additional political agent were taken to be installed in a car.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Additional political agent, according to the local administration after the kidnapping of the security forces in South Waziristan tribal areas and half of all check posts have been cordoned off and was given to those coming and going strong searched was the last one week and officials had also imposed a ban on US economic.</seg>
    <seg id="11">8 December two thousand up to the political agent of North Waziristan Asmat Ullah was kidnapped at the time when he was going to Bannu to celebrate Eid holidays. and after a few days in North Waziristan, the Tehsildar Amanullah was killed two people, including the unknown veil.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">In Court of British</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A 42-year-old British citizen has admitted that he was the US military website.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Embracing Asperger patient. It should be noted that there is only one way to Asperger patients of work is madness.</seg>
    <seg id="4">His lawyers say that if they were handed over to the United States, fear is that he will try to suicide.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Government lawyers, however, say that doubts about the health of are very limited.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Lord justice and Justice Simon said that the decision has given permission to that they can give the request of British seen in court.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Embracing lawyers had adopted the position in court that if embracing was removed from his home and family, they can committed suicide</seg>
    <seg id="8">He further said that it did not consider the Home Secretary.</seg>
    <seg id="9">But government lawyers say that the Home secretary had used their powers.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Has never deny the US military to web site is not.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Embracing the two thousand in one and two American computer system was due to which the US Government has caused a loss of 8 million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Embracing the US Navy and NASA system including 97 computer was.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Embracing, however, said that he has not made any bad intentions but they were seeking information about natural deeds, which, in his opinion, the American government was kept secret.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Embracing mother Janice said that they are happy with the decision.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Lawyer said, &quot;It is the right decision.</seg>
    <seg id="16">This case is continuing with two thousand two and finally struck a right decision.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Commander Killed in Kashmir: Two</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Deployed in Jammu, a spokesman of the Indian army&apos;s northern command, Lieutenant Colonel told the BBC: &quot;24 rifles, and the youth of Jammu and Kashmir police received information that haus in Tehsil of Doda district in the jungle hiding siege. The place where the armed extremist sitting.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He fired on the army and two armed extremist were killed in a retaliatory action.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The spokesman said that two militants were killed in 12 years in the district is also active restricted district commander of Hizbul Mujahideen Zahoor-ud-Din who was an expert in explosive blast.</seg>
    <seg id="5">With this from last year, according to the army, which has been identified as Sajjad Hussain had been associated with the extremists.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to the rural areas is still continuing operation because of them there more extremists, the possibility of the presence of the army said that in the first phase of the operation, two Kalashnikov rifles were also recovered.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Yesterday, the head of the police of the province Kumar coop declared the most peaceful year so far this year while the year 8 statistics issued.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Also was no violence in the Assembly elections is worth mentioning that in seven phases in November and December.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In these elections, 13 and a half more than 100 candidates participated.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It should be noted that Hizbul Mujahideen is active in Jammu and Kashmir for the last 18 years.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The government has for the first time in July, which was announced after talks between the government of India and the commanders.</seg>
    <seg id="12">, however, only ended fire within 15 days.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Later, several senior commanders of Hizbul Mujahideen were killed in an different.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On Thursday, Pakistan&apos;s famous daily, the news, the extremist groups living in Pakistani Kashmir had written about that Lashkar and Hizbul Mujahideen has decided to review the Kashmir policy.</seg>
    <seg id="15">It should be noted that the policy of both organizations so far, it was that the Kashmir issue can be resolved through armed resistance.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Dera: Explosion on a Gas Pipeline</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police officials Monday mountains from the gas field to the 18-inch pipeline of Qatar was from the blast.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This pipeline is the direction of Sui plant.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Meanwhile yourself, spokesman of the outlawed organization Baloch Republican army appears to the Baloch, a person has claimed responsibility for the attack on behalf of the organization.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In the fourth gas pipeline explosion has been.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On Friday in Dera Allah Yar, a 18-inch Qatar pipeline had been destroyed, which was issued to the repair work on Sunday morning.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Sui Southern Gas Company in Quetta, General Mushtaq Siddiqui has said that the supply of gas to the pipeline will be started after noon.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This pipeline is see our way Quetta.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Pilgrimage and other Quetta three days in the areas where there is a severe shortage of gas on one hand Snow is continuing, and the temperature fell down, and on the other hand, heaters and stoves cool to.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Besides in Dera Bugti, there has been an explosion in a motorcycle in the property market, but according to police, the explosion has not been any loss of life.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Party Administrator For</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Party of e center, about 25 kilometers away from Lahore in the school.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hostel of Hospitals, schools and students are also included in the center.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Punjab Law Minister Rana Sanaullah Khan has said that the appointment of surveillance in the center of the party has been brought to this process so that there will not affect the work of welfare institutions.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Party leader Hafiz Saeed Khalid according to Walid center located in hospitals, schools and other social institutions for the supervision of a senior government official has been appointed as the Emperor Babar administrator, while in the center, according to him, in the police force has been increased.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The UN Security Council has imposed ban on the party, after which Pakistan to locate in the center of the action against the federal government in the country, and other leaders including party leader Hafiz Saeed has been detained by the government of Punjab. Also on behalf of the federal government against the party is the continuation of the proceedings.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Emperor Babar is from D. M. G., District management group.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Hafiz Walid Khalid said that Commissioner inspected different parts of Lahore division Khusru Pervez Khan on Sunday came along with the police and civil administration in the center and Center. Khalid Walid condemned to appointed administrator in the center of the party on behalf of the government and said that the government already activities due to the patients in the hospital, located in the center and there has been a reduction in the number of children in school.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Meanwhile party, according to a press release of the party leader Hafiz Saeed, the General Secretary of the United Nations trade and silence of the committee for the name of Taliban in which they have written a letter to the Security Council by the end to the ban imposed on party has appealed.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It was said in the letter that its decision to ban the party on behalf of the Security Council is an injustice and party no connection with terrorism, but it is engaged in welfare work.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Edhi Relief Mission of Gaza</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After passing through many stages of required to get permission for entering Gaza, he could succeed in reaching Egypt so far from New York.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Talking to BBC Urdu service from Cairo, he said that he still could not reach Gaza, because Egypt and Israel have been standing many obstacles.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that I came here eight days have been and is still was not allowed to go to Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In Cairo at this time, and I hope that tomorrow will be allowed to go to Gaza to meet.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Giving details, he said: &quot;I was invited only 7 days to go to Gaza before and after a month in my insistence on the Pakistani authorities to help me and it will leave Gaza, but on the condition that only one time in a single meaning.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that they are with his son and daughters and they want to the relief work in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">&quot;I came with some money.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Egypt&apos;s Red Cross has given a check of $1 million and 10 thousand dollars cash are also given so that they send relief goods in Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Four More Ministers in Cabinet, Yesterday</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Four new Federal Ministers include two Muttahida Qaumi Movement and two Jamiat-e-Ulema-e-Islam Fazlur Rehman, the members of the group.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The new Ministers took oath from President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Swearing-in ceremony of Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani, the members of the federal cabinet also present</seg>
    <seg id="5">With the inclusion of four new ministers in the federal cabinet, Federal Minister, Minister of State and the total number of advisers has been.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Two ministers of the MQM are Farooq Sattar and Babar Ghauri and Jamiat Ulema Islam are Prime Swati and Maulana Fazlur Rehman Group Ataur Rehman.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Yet, the departments of these ministers have not announced.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Farooq Sattar, convener of MQM are while the MQM Senator Babar Ghauri and his term is being ended on March 10.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Prime Swati Azad is in richest Senator, and many of them were elected as Senator.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Maulana Ataur Rahman, a member of the National Assembly and younger brother of Maulana Fazal ur Rehman.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It should be remembered that important posts, all four advisers are not members of the national assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It should be noted that on November 3, two thousand were 8 to 22 new ministers and 18 Ministers of State were included in the cabinet, was being thought at this time, the MQM that MQM members will also be included in the cabinet, however, due to differences in the distribution of ministries was not included.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Baluchistan, Pipeline Blew up.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police, this 18-inch pipeline of Qatar on Monday which is different in the Sui Gas plant and it is the unknown people to blow up the early morning.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Besides this, yesterday in Sui well No. 3 was completely destroyed by the explosion and a gas pipeline near Dera Allah Yar was harmful to the explosion.</seg>
    <seg id="4">These explosions and the responsibility of the organization Baloch Republican army spokesman has accepted on behalf of his organization.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Two thousand nine would start the year in Baluchistan, there has been an increase in the incidents of violence.</seg>
    <seg id="6">So far this month, dozens of gas pipelines from the blasts have been while rail cars and people belonging to the Punjab province has increased attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Balochistan Chief Minister Nawab Aslam, although they have expressed concern over the incidents and the exchange of information with the police and intelligence agencies have been ordered so far, the prevention of these incidents could not be possible.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Billion Dollars Approved a Package of Economic Rehabilitation</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">President of any member has not voted in favor of the plan, any belonging to the party.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The members said that the economic plan is very expensive, &quot;and will not prove effective.</seg>
    <seg id="4">This package in the house representatives in favor of the 200 and 100 votes in opposition.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Economic rehabilitation of this plan is to be presented in the Senate next week where the power, the Democratic Party is a little majority.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The party is being expressed concern that due to strong opposition by the approval from the senate will not be easy.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After the approval of the plan of economic rehabilitation in the house representatives stressed the members said that the political differences should not be obstacles in the path of this important project.</seg>
    <seg id="8">, the President said that this plan, about which he expressed hope that the next month will take the shape of law for making a manufacturing environment in the country, which would be helpful in promoting trade in the US will be.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Under this plan, for the common men and traders community two hundred seventy-five billion dollars in loans out of ten thousand and five hundred 40 billion roads, bridges, schools of serve, unemployment and new technology will be given to the research.</seg>
    <seg id="10">In Washington, the BBC correspondent Richard has said that the political differences was determined, to a new political culture recognizant so little but debate on the economic package has once again created bitterness in the political basis.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Party members in the House of Representatives declared the bill proposed by the government as a waste of money to the government and said that it will not get any help in creating new employment.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He stressed on the bill proposed by his party in which has been given more attention on disengagement.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said through his package of employment in the investment much less than can be created.</seg>
    <seg id="14">He said that the construction of the plan to flourish in the immediate employment can create more</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">In Israeli President, Turkish Prime Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Rajab Tayyeb has been almost, the Israeli President said that the blood of many people in Gaza and they see this sorry that people can fit on the justification of the army on behalf of the Israeli daily.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. said: &quot;&quot; I think that you are probably resolved their guilt for using such words and he raised his voice but you have killed people and I am to remember their children who were killed near the beach.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Perez said that the tragedy of Gaza is not Israel, Hamas, which has been set up a dangerous dictator ship there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">By a BBC correspondent says that in the World Economic Forum before it did not come to watch the scene.</seg>
    <seg id="6">, however, later said that they are the honor of the President, and they are also due to which they do not yell, but he was saying something which was far from the truth.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Turkey is their sugarcane grams Muslim countries which have diplomatic relations with Israel, but the last few years is found in the tension.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Attack in Pakistan Were Not Plan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Talking to the Indian TV channel, N. D., Wajid Shamsul Hasan said that the Pakistani investigation report of the Mumbai attacks will be issued soon..</seg>
    <seg id="3">Last November, more than 100 people were killed in the attacks in Mumbai.</seg>
    <seg id="4">India has said that the responsibility of the attack on the extremist group Lashkar-e-.</seg>
    <seg id="5">India has also said that Pakistan, state elements, were involved in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After the Mumbai attacks, affected the relations between the two countries.</seg>
    <seg id="7">High Commissioner Wajid Shamsul Hasan has given the first statement about the Pakistani investigation from which it is through indication that can be made in the report of the investigations.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wajid Shamsul Hasan said: &quot;as far as their investigation car arrived on the result, the use of the land of Pakistan has not.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It can be a place and, Britain is also not.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The two places (Pakistan and Britain) were about which I was concerned.</seg>
    <seg id="11">India and the international community has made enough pressure on Pakistan to take action against the officials of the Mumbai attacks. Pakistan has said that it has arrested dozens of people in action against groups, allegedly involved in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Wajid Shamsul Hasan said: &quot;We are not trying to put on the screen.</seg>
    <seg id="13">We believe in to action on the facts.</seg>
    <seg id="14">To the world our investigation.</seg>
    <seg id="15">With (Investigation) results, we will try to satisfy India.</seg>
    <seg id="16">He defense of the delay in the investigation, said that this kind of material to collect, and understand what it is that time to experiment.</seg>
    <seg id="17">The High Commissioner Wajid Shamsul Hasan said that India to present their day was started in.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Leader of Black Elected</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the sixth round of elections in the Republican Party, Michael steal the victory in a vote by the council were votes.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the elections for the post of Party Chairman steal candidate votes while former chairman from the competition in the second stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The reporters said that the chairman of the Republican Party candidate for five who were his stand in the most moderate leader Michael steal as they are made.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After the victory in his address, Michael steal said, &quot;We will want to abandon their friends and rivals with a hole in it, but the people are going to say that you come with us, he would be ready to be removed from us. Michael steal from my land is where they have been living Deputy governor.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Two thousand six, he got the time when they were standing in the election for a seat in the Senate.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But the Senate defeated in the elections after they were given as the Chairman of the Committee of the party.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Now, after being elected Chairman of the party, the efforts of the country-wide campaign of Republican party will be in his head.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He will use new technical for the election on the promise that he will give a new reason to party and conservative party supporters to continue the party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Jammu in Presence of Jaish-E-Mohammad and Lashkar-E-Indian Claim</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">There are reports of the militants in Jammu district.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Official Agency on receiving secret information, according to the army and the police cordon off the area and started did.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Started during the clash in which four militants, two soldiers and one policeman was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the picture, clashes were issued to meet the last information and to face Jaish-e-Mohammad and Lashkar-e-linked militants are present in the area for further reinforcement of the army has been sent there.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Nominated by the coalition government during a meeting with the Chief Minister Omar Abdullah and his own party, a leader of the National Assembly on behalf of the conference, the formal information about to us.</seg>
    <seg id="7">National Conference ally, the Congress party has also informed the governor about the support of Omar Abdullah.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Omar Abdullah yesterday the oath as the Chief Minister of the state would be assured.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It should be remembered that the recent municipal elections in the house of a national conference members twenty eight come get seats and become the biggest party. It should be noted that separation had parties of the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Congress, which were obtained 17 seats, with the national conference to agree a coalition government.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Today Srinagar on the arrival of the party welcomed the Omar Abdullah with a warm astrologer.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On this occasion, Omar Abdullah has said that he will play their role to make the talks between the Indian government and separatists militants possible, however, to coming to power of the new government and the holding of elections in India, it will not be possible.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Role of European Union for Peace in Middle East</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Government should be viewed with respect, reconcile efforts to stop the war in the Middle East is decisive in the role of the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the delegation leaves or efforts are equivalent to hand in this work.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The European Commission spokesman amadeu altafaj said that every effort is worth appreciating through which the European Union may help in a joint message to the war parties.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The extent of the official statement, is going to be all right.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But in reality, the European Union is presented in an unfortunate picture of civil warp.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President of the Union, on the role of the Republic is already weak.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Over the internal dispute has kept it a bus.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The attitude of the French President, on the other hand, it is like they are still serving the responsibility of the chairmanship of the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Even though France has the presidential term of six months.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Want to play a role and they can also, but he is not allowed.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The most ridiculous situation facing the French foreign minister Bernard kouchner.</seg>
    <seg id="13">They are included in the delegation led by the foreign minister of the Republic are schwarzenberg.</seg>
    <seg id="14">That about the Middle East war on him, both foreign ministers are giving different statements.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Schwarzenberg could not win it until the European Union did not show harmony based on the same position on the diplomatic Front, says that Israel has the right of their defense when that this war near doesn&apos;t in the categories of defense. On the other hand, Germany has kept has also sent a special ambassador Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="16">. The proof of this is the attitude of Israel, which gives no importance to Europe reconciliation efforts.</seg>
    <seg id="17">For the European Union, because this is a golden opportunity to show some time due to the policies of the United States George W. Bush has failed in the Middle East.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Financial Crisis: Billion Leaves German Industrialist Suicide</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Living area in Southern Germany, has left a very big business group, behind her.</seg>
    <seg id="3">But until some time ago, the German citizens did not know much about them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Then, when they give loans to their industrial group near the talks for several weeks with the banks have also become a topic of the future of the group were also to be imposed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The group had to bear the loss of several hundred million euros due to the financial crisis after the purchase of shares of the German maker institutions.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Then, the financial institutions to this group essentially require refused to give new loans worth between 700 million and one billion euros, came under severe pressure.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Some time ago, the bank group were then ready to provide loans on an emergency basis, but that a small industrialist who arrived at the place, the annual income of their industrial group had become about 30 billion euros, their capitalism power could not bear the deprivation.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The death of his father when his family business kept on lines, while it has also developed very soon.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He has kept his company name ratiopharm that today is very successful and very large drug manufacturing company of Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Some years ago, after the tremendous success of the form to the drug organization was between 5 and 6 billion euros worth of business and it is still the annual income of 1. 8 billion euros. The group named several large institutions like from the cement in which construction equipment to prepare for the purchase of vehicles to prepare the company is also included.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Group throughout the world, the number of employees is about 100,000, and its assets in the form of a drug manufacturing company was always get the special importance.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In his life, it was said many times: &quot;We have four generations while pharmacy.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Now the organization is arranged with my children and I hope that this organization for just a few hundred years, I will remain in the same family.</seg>
    <seg id="14">After the suicide of banks has given approval of the interim loans worth 400 million euros for his group vem, but the condition is that vem will pass on the form, so that the group&apos;s financial situation can be improved on a long term basis.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Thus, after the death of the group, they will not that he was ever.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Crime Rate in Foreign People in Germany</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Latest statistics from the face of the crime rate of 220 foreigners between 2004 to 2007.</seg>
    <seg id="3">21 less than 9 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Has been coming to 4 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to state minister herrmann, it is just an apparent positive changes.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said: &quot;It is intended to be kept that is necessary to get German citizenship is increasing the number of foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Therefore, it should also be explained in statistics to the perpetration of the crime, although the German citizen, but it is a foreign background.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Herrmann said that his province 2010 criminals to collect statistics about the time it would also keep in view.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Besides in the province is being thought on these lines.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Cdu belonging of home affairs Senator christoph ahlhaus said: &quot;in a scientific manner, when the research is human beings cannot already prepared their own results, but it depends on these figures is come after the research.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Ahlhaus attention by a report of the provincial office of the anti-crime was presented to the parts of the city, which was prepared in 2006 and which was discovered it in bergdorf alleged that here is how many percent of the participation of foreigners in the crime.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Here came to know that the results of</seg>
    <seg id="13">Of the crime rate is low in comparison with the crime in all provinces.</seg>
    <seg id="14">In contrast, when the rate of crime in youth during 2006 in Berlin were reviewed, it emerged that the ratio of the youth to foreign background 44.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Was 7 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Germany&apos;s other political parties, the Party of government, for example, spd environment linkspartei arm of the party is against this proposal that the crime statistics do together, this information should be collected, that time is what German foreign citizens of background.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Want Early Withdrawal of Forces from Gaza:.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Focus the complete withdrawal of forces for a permanent and lasting cease-fire agreement is essential.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamas and Israel has announced the cease-fire on Sunday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The Islamic militant group Hamas has announced a cease-fire on Saturday, said that within a week, the Israeli forces should leave completely from the Gaza Strip and have been cordoned off the Gaza Strip should be abolished.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On the other hand, Hamas leader Ismail has said that the war in Gaza, Israel has been possessed by the God.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that war in Gaza, Israel has failed to achieve their goals.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Earlier on Sunday in the Egyptian city of Al shame, a meeting of the leaders of the European and Arab countries which was held in the immediate withdrawal of Israeli forces from Gaza was demanded.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It was decided in the meeting that the Gaza soon for an international relief conference will be held.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In the meeting, the German Chancellor also participated.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Israel and Hamas continued for three weeks tomorrow, 13 Israeli, including at least 13 100 Palestinians and 10 soldiers were killed in the war.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the other hand, the Palestinian president Abbas has stressed to the United National government in Palestinian areas.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Name of Germany Video Message of Al-Qaeda</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">30 minutes of a person in the video, wearing black color palm, mouth, holding a gun in his hand and is giving a message to the German government.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This person is introduced by the name of Abu Talha and is talking in the German language.</seg>
    <seg id="4">All of this video message Arabic are also present.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On the screen of a video, and has been registered in the history of October 2008.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In this message from the German government, it has been said that such a large number of troops deployed in Afghanistan and the country has been expressed the belief that the attack, it will not be easy, and not pin?</seg>
    <seg id="7">Tell themselves independently on Germany, although the person who has not given the threat of attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Among NATO allied forces in Afghanistan at this time, the number of German soldiers about three and a half thousand.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Last year, the German parliament in October 1000 more troops to Afghanistan has given the approval of the law.</seg>
    <seg id="10">By the Germany, this is the first message.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Monitoring the prominent expert on terrorism matters relevant to lders, says: &quot;with regard to this message recently outside the German embassy in Kabul to the suicide attack, it is proof that we should take it seriously in every condition.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Over the last few years is continuing video messages on the Internet and such messages were also after the attack.</seg>
    <seg id="13">On Saturday, the responsibility of the suicide attack outside the German embassy in Kabul, the Taliban Military organization has taken.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Most German newspapers and observers are watching transition to a message to the attack.</seg>
    <seg id="15">&quot;They are targeting Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Fundamentalist Muslims, Germany&apos;s Afghan policy are looking to be negative.</seg>
    <seg id="17">The German government not only in Afghanistan but also in the Middle East accuses to adopt a policy.</seg>
    <seg id="18">And because they are more, Germany as its target.</seg>
    <seg id="19">Meanwhile, the German government has said that the German intelligence agencies before coming to publicize the video was aware about it.</seg>
    <seg id="20">German Federal Anti-crime organization is busy in the examination of the video message.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Assumed Post of President.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this perspective, the American people, on one hand, the whole world has been associated with different expectations.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Now, as the president of the United States, are being received messages of congratulations from all over with these expectations are also coming in.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this regard, the German Chancellor expressed confidence on the new US President.</seg>
    <seg id="5">&quot;I believe it is that on the basis of a deep friendship and partnership between the Federal Republic of Germany and the United States hi, we can solve the problems.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Russian prime minister Mir Putin says that are shown on the owner of a serious and open heart and this is a good thing.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Thus, the policies of former U.S. President George W. Bush is facing criticism.</seg>
    <seg id="8">However, his administration is certainly appreciated China for giving the movement to play more constructive role at the international level, while China about the new US President has said that he would have to work for a strong military ties between the two countries.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Chinese expert active in the German city politics says:</seg>
    <seg id="10">&quot;in this perspective, I believe that in the coming weeks and months and his economic team will lay down the tremendous pressure and the Beijing government will be forced to adopt a better and market relevance to the exchange rate for the Chinese currency.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The former US administration has made further relations with India.</seg>
    <seg id="12">These relations where can be taken, about this in New Delhi, the American studies Professor Raj says: &quot;Now we have more coming close strategic partnership in the ship but one night, could not bring any change.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Message in the name of the Pope also emphasized to promote the atmosphere of peace and cooperation in the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Provincial Elections in Iraq</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After a year, the first important elections in the war-stricken country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In provincial elections for 14, have landed in more.</seg>
    <seg id="4">To maintain law and order situation during the elections, eight thousand police and soldiers have been deployed in Iraq.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In view of this danger, that no bomb or any such important day and scare a attack all the borders of Iraq should not be only one day before, sealed on Friday were given.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Besides, the airport have been closed and stressed and has imposed a ban on public transport.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to reports, due to a ban on transport, are not in the traffic on the roads and Iraqi children have been seen playing football on the roads.</seg>
    <seg id="8">With the security situation during the recent Iraqi elections, on the one hand, it will be realized that in the year after the withdrawal of American forces from Iraq, local agencies are also taking the reigns of the country will find it or not, on the other hand, political analyst as an experience which estimated that the Iraqi people are ready to what extent democratic way to bring a change in the country.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Provincial elections are being held in the help of the United Nations and about eight hundred international observers are to review the electoral process.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Whole Day Today in Iran, Day Was Celebrated with Respect and Honor Memory of a Great Sacrifice of Hazrat Imam Hussain (25)</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On this occasion, the meetings organized and participated in large numbers in Nabi Mukarram () and their (25), Iran meet today presented his condolences to the ratio of the martyrdom of Imam Hussein (25), son of Prophet Mohammad Akram () to participate in the meetings of the fresh memory of sacrifice is behind the example in the field of Karbala of Hazrat Imam Hussain (25) and Azadar in memory of giant sacrifice in the field of Karbala and on a large scale and, according to the Mehr news agency report in all small and big cities including Tehran, the capital of Iran, Syed Hazrat Imam Hussain (25) was celebrated with great respect and reverence.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Retreat of Israeli Troops from Gaza Area of Palestinian Mujahideen // Matchless</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency Urdu service in Gaza according to the right of the day by Israel also urban population continued bombing on Gaza, Israel&apos;s air, ground and naval attacks so far in Palestinian people were killed and others were injured.</seg>
    <seg id="3">275 innocent at martyrs are also included in the Arab leaders who embrace, death on treason and the so-called international human rights organizations.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Today, Gaza shrouds were Israeli soldiers from the area have forced to America and Israel are showing great firmness and perseverance and support the power of faith and martyrdom are harassing assonance life on the enemy</seg>
    <seg id="5">If Egyptian President Hosny sinister treason is not Hamas and Israel Bahadur Mujahid demands when away from defeat, four have been surrounding the Muslim Palestinians but the Israeli siege, along with Egypt, which is the most terrible incident of Arab history</seg>
    <seg id="6">On the other hand, the governments of Saudi Arabia and Jordan are to provide political and economic assistance to Israel and Gaza giving treason with unarmed Muslims and with the Israelis.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The United States Will Adopt a New Strategy with Iran</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Elected President of the United States, according to a report of the Mehr News Agency has said in a conversation with A, B, C. news channel that they will adopt a new and modern strategy on the issue of Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Said that &quot;Iran will be a very big challenges for the US Government.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Said that the Islamic Organization Hamas and Hezbollah&apos;s Iranian support and concern over Iran&apos;s nuclear program.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But he will not continue US President George W. Bush&apos;s policy on Iran and will adopt a different policy in connection with the relations with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Said that he will emphasize on their real purpose completely clear, mutual respect and the desire of the talks.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Have also said that in the past, in the wake of talks with Iran before have not put any conditions.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the interview, he expressed the hope that his administration will be working on this new strategy with regard to Iran, rapidly.</seg>
    <seg id="9">About the Middle East crisis, said that they are shaping a special team in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="10">For peace efforts in the Middle East start work after the January 20.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">US Bush Incompetent and President Bush Has Acknowledged Its Mistakes in Last Press Conference.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Regarding the Mehr news agency Associated Press, has noted that U.S. President George W. Bush has acknowledged several of its mistakes and crimes in the last press conference of his term.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Addressing a press conference at the White House, President Bush said that they have compared the feelings of goodwill of the newly elected President, but that will be the biggest for a possible attack on the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the completion of the mission in Iraq and social security reforms were their mistakes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush has said that he made that some 100 for the protection of the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In response to several questions were asked about the ongoing Israeli aggression in Gaza, President Bush said that Israel has a right to defend yourself, according to them, Hamas is not a right to defend himself and the world like Hamas should not raise their hands on Israel and the United States should flatten strangled victim instead of the tyrant</seg>
    <seg id="7">Inefficient and ineffective, President of the United States said that Hamas weapons should not be provided the United States and Israel are providing the world&apos;s most deadly and devastating weapons of Palestinians are being massacred in Israel to benefit from American weapons, Bush praised the pro-Israel Arabs and termed the friend of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Bush expressed embarrassment at some crimes held in Abu Ghraib and jails.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Observers say Bush war crimes on the case should be established and the organizations to do this work will be a very big on their humanity.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Ahmadinejad, Iranian President Expressed Regret on Silence of Leaders of Arab Countries.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report of the Mehr News Agency has said that Iran&apos;s president, Dr. Ahmadinejad has been fixed by Israeli aggression on Gaza and criticism on the silence of the cruelty of the leaders expressed regret.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The origin of the Arab countries and the head of Israel&apos;s barbaric action on Gaza on silence while expressing the Palestinian people lettuce has said that Israel is Palestinian children, women and the common citizens as its target of violence and the Arab and is also not issued a statement.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmadinejad is that all the Arab countries to be united against Israel and Gaza Shar the oppressed Muslims of Israel and its cruelty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ahmadinejad King of Saudi Arabia to Clarify Its Position in Human Genocide by Israel in Gaza.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report of the Mehr news agency, President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad, the ruler of Saudi Arabia, the name of the country, Abdullah said in his message that the Muslim king of Saudi Arabia has been quiet on human genocide in the Gaza strip and the killing of innocent children and women in Gaza General silence Islam encourage financial constraints</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmadinejad has said in the message that you about the right position and the support of its enemies and so that it should be clear by differences in front of casting efforts failed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmadinejad said in his message that you know is that 19 days, Israel has been balance on human genocide in Gaza, in Gaza, the Israeli Government is badly massacred in these circumstances, the silence of leaders like you are raised the morale of Israel is a barbaric bombardment on the houses, mosques, schools and hospitals are massacred innocent innocent children.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Ahmadinejad from the country, Abdullah said that non-Islamic countries like Venezuela and have taken concrete steps against Israel, you can expect from these countries.</seg>
    <seg id="6">President Ahmadinejad success in Gaza that the Palestinians step will.</seg>
    <seg id="7">And oppressed will be possessed on the cruelty and this is the promise of God.</seg>
 </doc>
 
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Osama Will Continue in Palestine</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the report of the Mehr news agency, Hamas representative in Lebanon, Osama, speaking with the French news agency said that one-sided ceasefire by Israel is against the efforts of the international comprehensive ceasefire, he said until the present in Gaza will continue until this time, on one hand, the cease-fire will be meaningless</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that a hand to accept the conditions of cease-fire with Israel&apos;s failed attempt to avoid defeat has said that if Israel wants the continual peace that it to end Hamas</seg>
    <seg id="4">The Hamas leader in Lebanon made it clear that the rest of the Israeli army in the Gaza strip live in the one-sided ceasefire if Israel will continue resistance against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Addressing a conference in Beirut in solidarity with the people of Gaza Osama demanded the European countries severed relations with Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Hamas leader said that the martyrs and the injured was the increasing number of our aims and courage and will be raised.</seg>
    <seg id="7">On the Palestinian people, he said that a rock in the war against the enemy continue resistance.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">In North Waziristan Tribal Region of Pakistan, Taliban Has Killed Six People.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency has information about writers that two Afghan civilians in the North Waziristan tribal region of Pakistan, the Taliban and four Pakistanis sounded murder on charges of spying.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to reports, the local people are four corpses in Tehsil Chowk area of the district on Tuesday morning, who was shot and killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">While two bodies are received from President place which had been thrown in a market of the market.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Dead bodies have also received letters were written in Urdu in which it has been claimed that they were the deceased spy.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Two weeks ago, the President of North Waziristan place in two Afghan citizens were killed on charges of spying.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In the last 12 days, 15 people have been killed in the charges of spying for the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be noted that in South and North Waziristan during the six years, more than 100 people have been killed in the charges of espionage on the Taliban is that they are involved in such murder cases.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Expected Signed Order to Stop Notorious Jail Term Of</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Mehr news agency quoting the sources noted that the American president today signed the order of the notorious jail term to be closed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">New US President Hussein has started to import a level on the promises of his election campaign.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this connection, the President has instructed to make a plan for the withdrawal of US forces from Iraq, while today the American President to stop the notorious jail term of the order will be signed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that the president are going to sign today as the order under which will be closed within the cell within a year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Besides this, the White House to review ways of investigation from suspected terrorists with prisoners and also ordered the ban on it is likely that there will be.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President has started work on the first day of his presidency to fulfill the promises of the election and was first taken to make transparent process and achievement of his government.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Observers say that the American President of the United States at the international level but they have started efforts to protect the deteriorating reputation because when it is very difficult to get success in America on the support of the government of Israel is bound to the United States if any good work could not be expected to save their reputation in the world, then it is Israel&apos;s hand to be deprived of this crime and should not be involved in.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tony Blair Insisted on Need to Include Islamic Organization Hamas in Talks</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Mehr news agency noted with regard to the British newspaper The Times that British Prime Minister Tony Blair has stressed the need to include Hamas in the Middle East peace process.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the newspaper, Tony Blair said that it is important that a way should be found through which Hamas in the Middle East peace process should be brought on the Bush only to talk with Mahmoud Abbas and Hamas to ignore their house on a terrorist organization was also severely criticized, it should be noted that the western countries are public and Nizami power of Hamas steam by now, it was to be included in the talks and interpretation before they consider Hamas a terrorist organization, who is the defence of their country from the occupation of the others Azad is an elder and struggle which thief at home and country like Israel, the government has kept the occupation from 60 years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Murder of Baluchistan Traders in Karachi, a Complete Strike in Quetta</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Balochistan in Karachi on Thursday against the killing of four businessmen there was a complete strike in Quetta and some other areas.</seg>
    <seg id="3">During this, all the business centers remained closed while the traffic was less than usual.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The appeal of the protest strike was Baluchistan, Association of the National Awami Party and Jamiat-e-Ulema-e-Islam, who alleged that these traders from the Karachi police alleged firing was killed when he reached the showroom of their vehicles on Tariq Road in his car.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The President of the Association has demanded that the people involved in the cars were arrested and action should be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Immediately about the incident, however, was not stand in front of the Karachi police.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Killed four traders who belong to the frontier city garden.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Security arrangements were made on behalf of the government on the occasion of the strike on a large scale and police officials were deployed in important places throughout the city.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Senior Commander of Hamas Was Killed in Israeli Attack</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Of Israel, a senior commander of Hamas was killed in the attack.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This is the death of other important personality of Hamas in attacks on Israel in the Gaza strip a week.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Hamas officials have said that Abu situated in the east of Gaza City on Saturday, killed in localities.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hamas Alam, were killed on Thursday in another attack in Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Syria living in exile leader of Hamas, Khalid has expressed determination to take revenge and warned Israel against the ground attack on Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Thousands of Israeli soldiers and tanks are deployed on the border of Gaza and they are waiting for orders of daily army.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The appeal of the cease-fire. But the United States has said that its forces on Gaza or not to decision to depend on Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="9">US President George W. Bush said in his weekly speech on radio Hamas accused of incitement to violence and terrorism declared to the rocket attacks on Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He has said that the United States is doing work for a ceasefire, but a bilateral deal will not be acceptable.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Three Bodies Recovered in North Waziristan,</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani security officials said that the three men in the tribal region of North Waziristan bodies were found.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is believed that they were given the death sentence.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The bodies are found near Miran Shah, the central city of North Waziristan and are receiving such letters with them, in which these men have been accused of spying for the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officials have said that they found a dead body in the local probably is the man who was kidnapped last week.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the strategy with bullets remaining two bodies of Afghan people.</seg>
 </doc>
 
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Elected U.S. Vice President Joseph Reached Pakistan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Foreign Minister welcomed the elected U.S. Vice President</seg>
    <seg id="3">Elected Vice President of the United States, Joseph has arrived in Islamabad on Friday with his delegation on a visit to Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Minister Shah Mahmood Qureshi and senior officials of the US Embassy, welcomed him.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Are with us in this visit.</seg>
    <seg id="6">U.S. Embassy press officer lo told the voice of America that the newly elected President will hold talks with Pakistani leadership on various regional issues during his visit, however, he has avoided disclosing further details.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the sources of the foreign office, Joseph besides senior government officials, the head of the army general Ashfaq Pervez will also meet.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is expected that these meetings in important bilateral and international issues in addition to the war against terrorism will exchange views on related issues.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Joseph were given to Pakistan</seg>
    <seg id="10">After reaching Islamabad Joseph met with the President, Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In the meeting, the President they close ties between Pakistan and the United States on his role in establishing &quot;given to honor of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Joseph, it should be noted that the last year of the US Senate Foreign Relations Committee Chairman Senator as together with Pakistan in a bill, which was introduced by the United States during the next five years to increase three times and in a non-military aid to 7. 5 billion dollars is recommended.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Former President Pervez Musharraf&apos;s Uniform, Played an Important Role in Talks, Prime Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Yousuf Raza Gilani and who (file PHOTO</seg>
    <seg id="3">Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani said that elected Vice President of the United States, which has been playing an important role in former President Pervez Musharraf&apos;s uniform, to leave the post of the head of the army, and the substantial support for democracy in Pakistan&apos;s</seg>
    <seg id="4">. Yousuf Raza Gilani made this statement while speaking to journalists at Karachi Ship.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He said that the &quot;pro-Pakistan&quot; or are pro-Pakistan leader and he has presented a bill to the aid of dollars for Pakistan as the Chairman of the foreign affairs committee of the U.S. Senate.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Of the missile attacks to be US spy planes in Pakistani territory, once again, to allow the Prime Minister of Pakistan said such attacks were condemned such attacks in national territory, so he could not give any permission is not any kind of agreement with the US government and the MQM on them is a matter of the independence of Pakistan</seg>
    <seg id="7">He also expressed the hope that the new government in the United States after coming to will change in the policy of the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="8">(file photo)</seg>
    <seg id="9">Yousuf Raza Gilani said that the government has a major success to the terrorists from the tribal separate from but what is to be made by the missile attacks and terrorist tribes are prove harmful for government efforts to meet.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that the international community does agree with the stand of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The Prime Minister further said that if no reliable evidence should be given, Pakistan forces will take action in their own areas.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The Prime Minister about the Mumbai attacks, its stand Yousuf Raza Gilani said that if India should provide evidences, it will be on the basis of the investigation and proof of involvement of get it according to international law, action will be taken against.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Rahman from Britain tour of the country and the MQM leader Altaf Hussain, in response to a question about the meeting, the prime minister said his country Rehman have been allowed to London.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Quetta, DSP Including Four Police Officers Were Killed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A file PHOTO</seg>
    <seg id="3">An important highway road of Quetta on the firing by unidentified persons, a DSP, Deputy police, including four police personnel were.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Riding in a jeep on Wednesday morning two DSP, a sub-inspector and two constables were going to the police training center located on the road that seryaab unknown attackers riding on a motorcycle near the Degree College started firing on the police jeep from which Mehdi sub-inspector and a constable died on the spot, while a DSP Hasan Ali died after reaching hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hospital sources say that severely injured the other DSP Ghulam condition is critical and they are struck shot in the head and neck.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After this incident, the police surrounded the area, yet it is that no one has claimed responsibility of the incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">In United States and Indian Software Engineer&apos;s Death</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">One belonging to the United States in Andhra Pradesh and software the unknown attackers shot and killed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Living in two days ago in the state, unknown attackers shot. The died during medical treatment in hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was employee of the computers and was serving as a jet Airways in the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In the past one year, belonging to the Andhra Pradesh seven students have been killed at the hands of anti-social elements in the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In the United States to go to higher education and employment for the purpose of increasing the students in the province has created concern in their thousands of families whose children are living in the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It should be noted that the higher education and a better future for the United States in Andhra Pradesh is given priority.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the statistics of the American Consulate in Chennai, South India every year for us visas are receiving 100,000 most, 40 percent are from Andhra Pradesh.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Meanwhile, the provincial government has begun efforts to bring the body of the deceased Hyderabad.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The United States Remain Vigilant Against Enemy Attacks: Bush</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">US President George W. Bush, in his last weekly speech stressed that they remain vigilant against enemy attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Bush has said that still the biggest threat to the Americans, there is a possibility of a terrorist attack. and he warned that the enemies of the country are waiting with patience and they were under attack again.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Shoulder, the President said the United States should definitely they should never absent from their safety.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush expressed best wishes for the next President Barak, who will take his post on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The newly elected President, Barak looked light on the historical importance of the ceremony of swearing in his speech on Saturday Radio on behalf of the Democratic Party.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that the ceremony is a practice that a leader is a very deep connection with American greatness of the peaceful transfer of power to the other leaders.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mr. has reminded that many people in the world that they could not imagine the leader of the struggle or without powers will be deprived from Pakistan.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Raiwind Sharif Brothers and Meeting of Federal Interior Minister, Exchanged Views on Political and Security Issues</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The biggest of the opposition and the ruling party in Punjab, the leader of the Pakistan Muslim League (N) Nawaz Sharif and Federal Interior Minister Rehman Raiwind on Sunday between the country was a meeting in which the Chief Minister of Punjab, Shahbaz Sharif was also present.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to local media, Rehman Malik was brought any important message of the leadership of the Pakistan People&apos;s Party as possible.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, speaking to journalists after the meeting in a country in this regard did not reveal any detail and only said that regarding the political affairs, he has talked of the politics of consensus, and briefed the leadership of P. M. L. N on the situation after the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words: &quot;so far as much action has provided information about it.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Not that there has been a big operation in Punjab and the Punjab government and is still need the help of the Punjab government, which has formed a team.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Rehman Malik said that the media, then, are not reported every day, but the leadership of P. M. L. N is daily exchange. On the other hand, the spokesman of the Pakistan Muslim League (N), Pervaiz Rashid avoided disclosing anything about political issues in the talks, and so has said that he was the person who tell a country telling.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be noted that a meeting of the Interior advisor to the leadership of the Pakistan Muslim League (N) has been this time when that government in the summer, warm politics province belonging to the Punjab anti P. M. L. Q more Administrators from a press conference with the governor of Punjab Salman P. M. L. N, administrators, belonging to the Pakistan Peoples Party, rejecting criticism of the actions of the provincial government, the Punjab Governor object on inclusion in this matter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Speech Is Pleasing for Pakistan: President Zardari</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">It is fortunate for the people of Pakistan and it welcomed the opening address of the new president of the United States, Pakistani President Asif Ali Zardari has said that his side to advance the relationship of mutual interests and respect with the Muslim world.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In a statement issued on Wednesday, he said that the American president reiterating the determination of high principles and values by the people of the world, the hope of a better future.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the statement, President Zardari said that with the help of the international community, America is undoubtedly put important responsibility of finding a new way of peace and development in the 21st century and happy.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It should be noted that the president had said in the opening address after taking oath on Tuesday that the United States wants the new progress with the Muslim world, which is based on mutual respect and mutual interests.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He assured the people of poor countries was that the United States should work together with them so that there is social development and reduce poverty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Has Appointed a Special Representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Richard Hall of the United Nations for the former Hall for Pakistan and Afghanistan, has been appointed as special.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The hall in agree had played an important role in the peace agreement.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The hall said that they are ready to advise the President on matters of Afghanistan and Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He said that it is not an easy task.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the history of the two countries is very different.</seg>
    <seg id="7">For the Middle East, George will try to cast life in the Arab-Israel peace talks has been elected.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The former senator and he had played a role in to establish peace in Northern Ireland.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Speaking at the State Department today said that the situation of the Middle East is very complicated, unstable and dangerous.</seg>
    <seg id="10">But despite this, the United States will never back out from peace efforts there.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghanistan: Voter Registration in Danger</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Afghanistan&apos;s election commission has said that he is concerned about the security in some areas of the South due to the delay in voter registration.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In southern Afghanistan near the voter registration for the presidential election to be held started this week.</seg>
    <seg id="4">But the Commission has said that until the security situation will not be better in some areas of the province, could not the voter register themselves.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Increase in violence from last year in the areas of the South, where Taliban rebels have increased their attack on Afghan forces and international forces are given.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Meanwhile, Afghan forces and international forces has said that he killed at least during clashes between Wednesday and Thursday night in two lines of Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">NATO has said that its forces had killed 22 militants in eastern Khost province near the border of Pakistan and ground attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Earlier, the Afghan defense ministry said that the Afghan forces in the province had eight rebels were killed and two injured.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is not clear whether the Afghan authorities have the reference of this incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Frontier Province Government Has Rejected Demand of Ban on Education of Girls in Swat</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Frontier Province officials threatened to impose a ban on girls&apos; education by Taliban fighters in Swat is rejected by saying that &quot;this announcement is against both the law and Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Education Minister of the Frontier Province on Sunday, Sardar Hussain Babar said that the government revive such efforts will not be successful.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the efforts of the extremists is that children in our region will be deprived of education.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In these words: &quot;these people could blow up security schools and children are trying to.</seg>
    <seg id="6">While well aware of the atmosphere of fear and panic, he said that the provincial government is trying to make it clear that the land of any power could not stop the promotion of education.</seg>
    <seg id="7">One day ago, Maulana Fazal, Taliban-led militants demanded has put a ban on the education of girls in the educational institutions of Swat and threatened that violation will be destroyed to institutions.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the last 15 years, despite the ongoing military action in Swat educational institutions around the militants instructed the explosives destroyed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Destroyed as a result of the educational institutions to thousands of girls and boys in education have been deprived of the facility.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Strict Security Arrangements on Occasion of Republic Day in India</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The sixtieth Republic Day is being celebrated on Monday in India, thousands of soldiers have been posted in every occasion, strict security measures and the country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">During the occasion of the Republic Day military parade in New Delhi, weapons, aircraft and other military equipment is of the exhibition.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Officials say the security arrangements under the anti-aircraft battery and &quot;also have been posted&quot; and the police to keep strict vigil on the routes of the parade, the American president congratulated India on this occasion.</seg>
    <seg id="5">And Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, who was a heart operation on Saturday also the message of the desire of the early recovery.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Is believed that yesterday, the Indian police had claimed to kill two suspected Pakistani militants after fighting in the outskirts of New Delhi.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to local officials, the police have also recovered AK 47 rifles, grenade and some papers from these two people who do show it that both are Pakistani.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The investigation of the police is also what is both belong to the outlawed organization Lashkar-e-Pakistan, which was involved in the Mumbai attacks in November last year.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tea: Effective Treatment for Breast Cancer</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">It has been said that three cup of tea in a new research</seg>
    <seg id="3">Drinking less than 50 years old is less than a third of the risk of breast cancer in women.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Cancer center in the US State of Florida in this research, it has been revealed that less than 50 years of age for breast cancer tumor in women</seg>
    <seg id="5">In at least three cup of tea is to be reduced to 37 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In research, it was also revealed that a large group of women from three or more cup of tea daily drinking is a particular advantage in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Experts think that, because of the presence of such factor in these particular types of cancer, which is more effective against who the target of the General Omar women have become less than 50 years.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Cancer center set up in the city of Florida state was the research on more than 5,000 women who had got the treatment of breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Them were between 20 and 74 years.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Experts had to compare their medical records and style of life with such women who were safe from breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The experts also came to know that a particular type of cancer,, its as the outstanding, and it was until the 66 percent reduction.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Is almost every tenth patients suffering from this kind of breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="13">For this type of cancer is more dangerous because it is in the depth and it is not known at this time, usually when he has enough spread.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Experts say that regularly, at least three daily cup of tea drinking than age can reduce the risk of breast cancer in women as outstanding</seg>
    <seg id="15">They say that tea to be included in their daily routines as a daily beverage will create appropriate against cancer in the body.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Every year in Britain is approximately 40 thousand women in the assessment of breast cancer.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">War in Afghanistan Is Biggest Military Challenge Facing United States.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">US Defense Minister Robert has said that the war in Afghanistan is the biggest military challenge facing the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Today, the members of the US Senate and House of Representatives on Afghanistan and Iraq war was giving a briefing about the strategy of the administration.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Told the Senate Armed Services Committee that only war is not a solution to the problem of Afghanistan, but he further said that many areas safe for making a number of military action are not present, which the Taliban, take advantage of them.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Reduction in Exercise with Age Why?</seg>
     <seg id="2">The New Research</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="3">In every age Exercise is good for health.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It is your heart Form Powerful regard, reduction in the level of cholesterol, weight is proving less assistant, is used to help prevent diabetes and silence does slow.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Unfortunately, many people are moving with the reduction in the ability to exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The experts say that exercise can affect our body and mind heedful but at this age.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The American Medical Association say that exercise is not to be presented many health problems.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Dr. pay clinic mini cudgel says an increase in age is a major cause of lack of exercise and physical performance.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Dr. teaches medicine in the clinic.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He has a large age of heart diseases and human being made with regard to the ability to exercise the leadership of a study.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The team of doctors did use high Ahmad of voice to review the performance of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In which the heart to pump blood, its closeness study done to the rest of the process.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Experts will concentrate their attention on the left part of the heart, which is a central part of blood to pump.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They found that age is increased with the rest of the heart to increase the Editorial in the process.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Dr. says with the rest of the heart are to be significant defects in the process and its impact on the ability to exercise with the increase in the age is growing.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Dr. cane were included in the study.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They say that we see it was that this thing is compulsory and effective and it was clarified that the bad performance of exercise can be much concerned with the process of the rest of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="18">The sometimes blood pressure is causing Editorial in the process of heart diseases.</seg>
    <seg id="19">If doctors and patients should work together with regard to the evil effects of the heart, despite the increased age, they can also get the benefits of exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="20">The detailed report has been published in the magazine of the American Medical Association.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">No Possibility of Immediate War with Pakistan: Indian Army Chief</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Indian army chief General acquitted has said that the possibility of war with Pakistan immediately present, however, to the defense of the country and to ensure the protection of the interests of this fact are ready to give all the time.</seg>
    <seg id="3">General camphor has alleged that assurances and active in the Mumbai attacks, despite international pressure on Pakistan, in his words, not only is there as well, but the structure of terrorism on the soil of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said this while talking to reporters in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The head of the Indian Army land was on a one-day visit to the Kashmir valley of New Delhi to review the overall security situation and preparation of the armed forces on the borders of Kashmir.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He was asked a question that According to media reports about the Mumbai attacks, Pakistan has rejected the evidence presented by India, has made them about this comment.</seg>
    <seg id="7">General camphor said that the decision of the issues of war or peace will be political leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Allegedly, while mentioning the presence of the infrastructure of terrorism on Pakistani soil, he said that the Indian Army will be competing with such elements were under the peace which seeks to destroy and to weaken India.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He said that on the land of Indian Kashmir to seven to eight hundred are present in which about 50 percent are foreign.</seg>
    <seg id="10">General burner camphor said that along with the improvement in the weather in the efforts of infiltration from Pakistan and Pakistan-administered Kashmir, the may, however, India has increased vigilance on borders.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said the possibility of reducing the number of troops deployed in Indian-administered Kashmir were rejected that no compromise can be made with the security of the country.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Mubarak, the language of the world and should be congratulated for</seg>
     <seg id="2">This change in the relations between Pakistan and America, though it is hoped, not change direction. To what extent are in our favor.</seg>
     <seg id="3">That person, who are of Martin Luther King of the world...</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Hussein is also part of the name is also bear the oath as President of today, where from every angle, as is rigorous examination at</seg>
     <seg id="2">Not only their own hands, but all those people who have heart.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is also a test will be of a color to the heart of his government not easy to work.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Telephone: 020 7239 7025 Fax: 020 South Asia are young, establish maintain that they are elected President of America and keep that the president America practically President.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now, after some brothers closed slavery as a racial such person wearing his own mother country were brought to America and remove the blood of the most powerful state, is today the victim of racial discrimination, a representative of the nation, President of America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">From this one person, many people have kept committed many expectations.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Those who love it is necessary that this person not force.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If race, religion in the world to reduce hatred as a successful. It will be for those who love it.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This change Asia will filled and a meaningful change in this policy could be expected.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the relations between Pakistan and the United States will be.</seg>
     <seg id="3">(B B)</seg>
     <seg id="4">Mr. man, or a contested and for the entire world, and the relations of their, trillion bo, influential, strong and capable of influence is not only lobby.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And as far as Pakistan is concerned, in connection with the Mumbai blasts, India, Israel and America triangle is aggressive in front of the entire world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After creation of Pakistan for a long time enough for all of the responsibility of Swat which was a regular army and the law.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He arrange Swat under an agreement handed over to the government.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But regret that our governments have treated as mother with the Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Just was not increase in the number of schools after the end of the government of the Swat in Swat</seg>
     <seg id="5">Nor and there was shown a great interest in the development.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In the present era, education which was obtained to reduce their number several times from the previous era.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In North West Frontier province of Pakistan, local educational institutions by the Taliban is continuing to make the target.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Most schools have been destroyed in Swat district in which most of the girls.</seg>
     <seg id="3">So, not only the Taliban has also announced a ban on girls&apos; education in the Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thousands of students are being deprived of the education.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you think that is the end of the Taliban want to get.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Until now the government failed to stop these illegal actions was why.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Do you think the government should do.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The question is that it should be a I. and Pakistani..</seg>
     <seg id="2">Because it is now the people of Swat has come to understand that the army is there for the service of the Taliban, not for killing them otherwise only a night in five school can be among the people in the city&apos;s main square of slaughter can.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Swat when the government established the writ. that was not being. The government to stop these illegal actions will be successful?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now the question is it was found that when armed forces, modern weapons, and spying system where everything is with the government, it is not being four Taliban control.</seg>
     <seg id="3">His answer on his head, is that that is not a secret hands of weapons, they would come to an end and is not. It is not.</seg>
     <seg id="4">For works is that the work of Taliban, their Kale, international colonialism, it is easy</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now 15 years ago, the war in Afghanistan was issued</seg>
     <seg id="2">I. A was to control the Taliban and help was the opposition Northern Alliance which was to help Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Then suddenly started coming in front for the achievement of the Taliban</seg>
     <seg id="4">And it also offered to I. came, the enemy, you know, a former friend.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now, the situation is that the war is still continuing, but also to help in the Iran, India and Russia.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As long as human beings would not create the feeling and that right and wrong, what is there to live only to human mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For example, when a thief for stealing is if it appears that this idea at this time, is not a good thing to theft and robbery is a curse, it is also correct and he is &quot;from God, he will not steal human</seg>
     <seg id="3">Similarly, until Israel should not be feeling that I was wrong, I and bloodshed and this will get the punishment until then, they will remain in Gaza holy played with blood.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Courtesy!</seg>
     <seg id="2">The question is that war, armed, solve the problems of the terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="3">If not, then they are taken by the problems?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Way, it is true that the war does not solve problems but further, Barkat, in them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Palestine, Afghanistan, Iraq, to the same model to which have in South Africa.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The armed struggle to more moral struggle and jihad &quot;.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Kashmiris in part comes into view is that he accepted the danger..</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The third week of Israeli attacks on Gaza is issued and the number of deaths has reached near 1000.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Yet despite the international diplomatic efforts could not be cease-fire.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Starting from 27 December, according to an estimate, after the attacks, so far 90 thousand Palestinians left their homes have been moved by the safe areas.</seg>
     <seg id="4">On the other hand, the relief agencies to the issue of the protection of Palestinian children accuses of committing has said that an entire generation of Palestinian children will be facing serious psychological and emotional problems.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You are saying.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Should be?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Lasting peace in Gaza, How is that possible?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Click here for the details</seg>
     <seg id="9">(grace note that the number of subjects increased only in Urdu to go to the opinions of the letter will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="10">For this point on the board of alt+shift and Urdu.)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Taliban occasion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Basit, Peshawar</seg>
     <seg id="3">Shine go if the Taliban to take real Jihad were innocent people who will.</seg>
     <seg id="4">School who?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And for kidnapping for ransom or get no ransom, saying spy the people who?</seg>
     <seg id="6">The Taliban, Islam is so damaged as any other nation or religion has not.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The Pashtun,</seg>
     <seg id="8">Pakistan,</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Together, all the Islamic world to attack on Israel would you (if only give the threat that Israel&apos;s father hit America will be how</seg>
     <seg id="2">And not only of the cease-fire but also be cease-fire.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But.. honour our Muslim rulers so heart and where.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Any Ahmad Ahmadinejad say that you are your courage in the BBC forum of the initiative and two big.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">On one hand, the United States says that the cease-fire.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, a resolution on the UN resolution is passed, but practically on both did nothing, it is also fighting for the United Nations as a means to crush the Muslims that is over.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Immediately the membership of the United Nations, all the Muslim countries should end religious and international organization should the basis of his.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Before us, where there are many examples of the United States and the United Nations about the front only promises and resolutions are or loss was only of Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Their benefit. When the BBC is not find some publishing</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now all journalistic principles where even blood fruitlessly chiefly Muslim, on the BBC to be on board.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The knowledge of right itself</seg>
     <seg id="4">The United States is that it is a matter of time, some by themselves, to</seg>
     <seg id="5">By the Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In you and in the difference is so they are martyred Muslims themselves are saying, and you like Muslims living in their say the Muslims and Muslims to</seg>
     <seg id="2">,,, [syja786],,,,</seg>
     <seg id="3">BBC coffee for a long time, sometimes in India suicide attacks in sometimes targeted to a particular faith in front of terrorism is being</seg>
     <seg id="4">These remarks against Islam is the word extremism</seg>
     <seg id="5">But who is extremist fitly from comments on this idea, you are writing against Iran in which has been a means of blasphemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Our Muslims when understand that could not face with a sword.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Unarmed people in the bombardment of Israel should have not tears of blood, the heart?</seg>
     <seg id="3">But fault is this corruption, murder and destruction which we give the name of the jihad and the beautiful face of Islam are trying to meet.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When the majority of Palestinian will accept the existence of Israel, Hamas have required that was rockets on Israel or suicide attack.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Both sides are monody.</seg>
     <seg id="6">America and the role of the United Nations, then we supports the atrocities of Israel.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">God give a of the Muslim Ummah,,</seg>
     <seg id="2">Terrorism, the terrorists and the real action of this distressing prize of the campaign against terrorism also that the real work, are doing the same.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise such large scale terrorism. Any Sardar of AIDS is possible and it is are those who are all know.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Easy, in some of the language in the that is to see that it is said that.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Tremendous should also and bomb was also killed on the head.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Funeral for the dead, and to give, are Arab leaders and is being asked.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Israeli attack, should be?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Actually, this issue is that all the heads of Muslim countries, including Saudi negligence, are not in the army is the bus nor any defense plan is that giving aid, they are aware that the responsibility of the whole ended.</seg>
     <seg id="4">As a practical steps against Israel should.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The closure of such countries and the car but in their grief.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All the sister!</seg>
     <seg id="2">Hamas in this time of difficulty in the name of peace, to abandon its struggle on the advice of thousands and thousands of with no judicial and is tantamount to prove unsuccessful.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If Israel and its supporters are on their peak, will also be created in their house, because it is a natural law measures Muslims in America and Israel are working in the fertilizer to created a suicide bomber.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The bacchanalian in power, he is not coming to understand.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Abu Abdullah Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now, Hamas and Israel to compromise should be closed so that blood and desert.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Mohammad Sarfaraz, Paris, France</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rang said.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Duty are that Hamas is on the right truth. 100 and &quot;against oppression,&quot; Jihad &quot;and in Kandahar, then also wants to be, at least, so it must be known that if not home, then left.</seg>
     <seg id="5">People who love God, the love of the Prophet, and his love for are claimed, people to love their becomes!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After Muslims, people are book, water in the world, the page creation years ordered by God.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Rehman, [p@ki$t@n]</seg>
     <seg id="3">G. is not ordered but not&apos; invitation of Islam &quot;order.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But against is the order of jihad against them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Until this time with these people &quot;not be until they end - but it is not possible for it means that having exploded in go-</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Brothers, is the destruction of the murderer of children.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But admits that yesterday was not shelter, that today, they were so strong in the world is not of a request from Ching friends because all are a.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Not in them, not Sunni, are all bus and he has every opportunity of development in every- up.</seg>
     <seg id="4">On the 55 Islamic countries have recently?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Behind in every opportunity, and now it is the world that have been so that the enemy are beating them and they are awaiting death.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is necessary that all Muslim countries to be united and work together to prepare action against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Feroz Magsi, Jhang, Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">And this is a good strategy and not to accept that Israel. The Studies and development of the world and to live in peace and China.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Muslims have also are also very and sources.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is the correct use.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First, it is the most terrible aspect is that Hamas and could not in the alliance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Like these huge organized and Arafat could be killed as it was to have been that the only intrepid nation for the Aqsa mosque, Jihad, to the region&apos;s weak. and until Arafat and are not removed from the way. It was impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The world is that after the death of Palestine is moment by moment,</seg>
     <seg id="4">And lobby moment to moment to strengthen its went to most.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In 1974, the owner of a Pakistani Prime Minister of this world view was that all Muslim leaders with attendance at 100 in the first time was taken under a roof.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today, on this. It is a very difficult task that this nation should promise that not only its launched in alliance established</seg>
     <seg id="3">Remove the differences of Muslims but while its (Commonwealth of Islamic) unfinished mission would be forward?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is a party which is half a century has been the</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many of which the mouth.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is many times that any other for your own good you only bad and and paddy is the</seg>
     <seg id="4">This and the second highest in Iraq, Afghanistan, Iran, Pakistan, human beings are said</seg>
     <seg id="5">And because it, which is that Islam is than everyone who knows that it will only remove round of Islam, Muslims and Muslims and practical Islam only when he was rescued. At big tells us that Islam has made on the path.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The process of bombing and missile attacks on Gaza by Israeli military planes is issued from 27 December.</seg>
     <seg id="2">So far more than three hundred Palestinian citizens have been killed in these attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now, after the air attacks, Israeli tanks and armored vehicles ground to complete the preparation of the action have reached the border with Gaza.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Demanded to stop violent actions immediately to Israel and the Palestinian Authority through a unanimous resolution in an emergency meeting of the UN Security Council.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Israeli officials, however, said that it is time for its operation in Gaza will continue until he is sure that rocket attack on Israel would be closed.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In your opinion, what Israel is correct to say that this is an attempt to defend the integrity of Israeli action?</seg>
     <seg id="7">This situation is to play its role in the international community?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What independently of the aggressive action is with the next elections in Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="9">The newly elected President of the United States could be expected of any improvement in the situation of the Middle East since taking office?</seg>
     <seg id="10">(grace note that the number of subjects increased only in Urdu to go to the opinions of the letter will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="11">For this point on the board of alt+shift and Urdu.)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">County Palestine is a sacred place for Muslims and for the protection of our element.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And we keep it also is the first attitude</seg>
     <seg id="3">Find a day fail to America and Israel, India is because it is to the country, are made only for breaking and God certainly torture on these unbelievers-Sajid Sadiq,</seg>
     <seg id="4">&quot;When tears rationales is cabin night</seg>
     <seg id="5">Call when there is only prayers &quot;(Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Such comments, BBC research published by the discovery.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Finally, scepticism and impression, is to set up.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The BBC is only correct. But the real- news is the way.</seg>
     <seg id="4">How- to have and how to reduce the news.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Where.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The, Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="7">Now that our Pakistani, especially and column writing from any of the growing extremism and terrorism are not in or on it now, &quot;despite the&quot; in-beam seen.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It will leave contested said the United Nations, which is apparently is to the human rights and peace, but the intensity of cruelty and violence on Muslims and hearing the words from his mouth to see that Hamas should stop attack as long.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Muslims on such cruelty is if America is like these people should leave the backing of Jews, God has clear: that this nation will pass the life of the nation, and this nation will not spend life ever if the courage is America&apos;s backing of them and then that of the -</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To those who fell murder in the name of so-called and peace of the world, it clearly understood that peace in the world only justice &quot;may set up is off no judicial and genocide.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If genocide could find any nation have ended and the results of the election will be made after the actions of Jews will not only be continued existence, but a kind of high today is impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">According to him</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is wiped out,....</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is, blood....</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Who now who will say that terrorism.?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Come in all Categories of terrorism. It is not only its all its feel the pain is</seg>
     <seg id="3">Other people have been the blood of Muslims and human beings are not or are so inexpensive. Such was not the red color of blood.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And now also a message came not?</seg>
     <seg id="5">The trial in the action of the Mumbai attacks was like Ching began his fire in your home is that the pain of the people are not next and it comes not in any pain, some may be a Muslim.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Lying on the road, and injured and how innocent faces resistance in the blood do that words are not available.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Helplessly wail of Muslims came has demanded that action, otherwise we will do without evidence on Pakistan, the entire world is that a hand in India, people get killed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And on the other hand, Israel publicly are the genocide of Muslims and the world is not tolerating is silent</seg>
     <seg id="4">- God have not and when it will end the city.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Effects of America, Israel is a joke.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Talk was wrong, head of the elections for the public power thus. There is no doubt in this is particularly Israel remaining till today, at the witness is a matter of no ruling and not come back against colonialism is white or black, that is only colonialism.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">From the ongoing debate in the forum, it is clear that the sorrow of the death of any kind, but these have not been ignored.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is for the debate that has given a life of democracy or for power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If democracy was Aziz, and kept to leave that to 10 years in Musharraf&apos;s policies?</seg>
     <seg id="4">And then Pakistan not required when hit. Unfortunately, he then Pakistan routed when they had cases of power and release.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Take human beings is being raised by the allegations on this, it is not the only a few reminders.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Sana Khan,</seg>
     <seg id="3">Some ignored the are his thoughts and that some of them could not be.</seg>
     <seg id="4">A and Qari</seg>
     <seg id="5">Mrs. you read in its four friendly countries and seven other countries in about not only in Pakistan but (Sir) at the person will talk to you.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The Tariq,</seg>
     <seg id="7">&quot;is not. of which they are not from train</seg>
     <seg id="8">Was not happy living in the image of the cypress armpit.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Britain has also to them not to be a Hindu and Muslim. The development of the issue.</seg>
     <seg id="2">,,,, and,</seg>
     <seg id="3">How much is a feeling in the style of our own nation and his party controls are only have time, blind but now, every human beings take intellectual raised by the allegations are being criticized and say something on this, there is not the only.</seg>
     <seg id="4">A development. We have the people.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sana Khan,</seg>
     <seg id="6">Some are ignored the are his thoughts and that they could not be some burden-way books &quot;is not stupid Alam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Although Mumbai disturb the ongoing negotiator process between India and Pakistan after the attack, has been created so we want to continue the talks to Pakistan and India.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If the war will talk, both sides would be the loss of human lives.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India has said that Pakistan was held in Mumbai attack is urban and it has sent a letter written to Pakistan in Urdu, but on the other hand, India, first, when the extremist held, said that this is a great engineer, but after that, he said, it only four parties have declared this point of view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First of all, Mr. Forum and the friends of Christmas.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Forum: Sahib, A. Raza, sister Sana, sister Shahida Akram and all courtesy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We are to the course of peace but not war!</seg>
     <seg id="4">War, itself is a problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The resolution of the war will give</seg>
     <seg id="6">Fire and blood today will</seg>
     <seg id="7">Hunger and will give tomorrow</seg>
     <seg id="8">The knowledgeable people</seg>
     <seg id="9">War, is better.</seg>
     <seg id="10">You and in our compound</seg>
     <seg id="11">Candle were earlier, better.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">India-US relations are now have very deep and India know that time when America Pakistan Open cheated.</seg>
     <seg id="2">America is also the old.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Indian attack in the form of America will also get their objectives and India also will be spent.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan should announce that we will not. But clear was a matter of cease-fire, then peace and reconciliation by that time will not be completed until India or destroyed and not the occupation. It is whether we ourselves Cried for that should go to destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">At Islamic.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Before this resolution, the Pakistani people and the army was the message they give..</seg>
     <seg id="2">In compensating the attacks, she is getting extraordinary diplomatic and military benefits of Indian efforts are affected than droll making it even on the initial strong international reaction, now the world has reduced pressure on Pakistan..</seg>
     <seg id="3">They are not in the noise of India, making use of the United Nations expressed for Pakistan&apos;s efforts and the efforts of the head of the Interpol to admire the need for India to the embassy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">On this matter, no two opinions that this is a very brutal action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But the question is that when thousands of Taliban Samiullah Monday on the attackers were, where the Pakistani army was and was doing?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Accountability of the army should not be in a year that he has been there?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Every day, in which thousands of the mortar and cannon shells are from many Taliban are killed?</seg>
     <seg id="5">In the ISI appeals that the patronage of the Taliban to leave and we Swat like heaven to live in peace.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Closed and the fake operation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the United Nations during the day when Pakistan not only have some of the military intervention in the resolution was passed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ahmed Farooqi</seg>
     <seg id="3">First, we are being made to provide all evidence and justification for its action against extremist and his only and not in our favor, that day which was also presenting a resolution, the possibilities are also a voice in the United Nations.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And hypothetically was in this resolution to be passed, the example of America in front, there is no power under self help. Both will run.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Of God and we and information that it&apos;s not..</seg>
     <seg id="2">He was not a revolutionary.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Way, Nawab Bugti, Dr. God and thousands of dead bodies of was in the hands of the enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Died, they are also to take action.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But a, an international is being, Telephone: 020 7239 7025 Fax: 020 people barbarism and brutality is being afraid of governance.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Occupying government so that the justification that could have created such cruel and, if not, we will come.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the name of so-called the religion of Islam is condemnable.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Supporters of these extremists are on the oppression of the United States, England, but instead of grief over the brutal actions like this, they give the name of the tribal traditions, clean border are fish.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Tribal traditions cope close ever with the name of Islam, the heart of any person for this kind of brutal action could not have it.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, the people of our army to get these people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He felt that when they do move to move, so in this time, is frequent, it will be enough for, but so far to the occasion if they are also there, there are darn cycle.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What these people are so powerful that they are abducted 50 70 men, and our army is seeing as the spectators keep hand on hand.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are also human beings, and the army.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is obvious that some of the pulse.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Like, dictator like contrast to highlight and mode of God from the period of time, and to set up the atmosphere of fear in the name of religion is seen in this body will be after the death of their and, besides the incident. The books are not created fear.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And it is people just and dignity and the Jalal for this fear as a tool or are doing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">,!</seg>
     <seg id="4">Fire from Hell where it to you.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Fear that itself became the situation,</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Is when it is said that it could not be the work of any Muslim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We are only at their own or witnesses are not reconciliation.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wisal refuses after on fire. see how the closed door of the daughter of the Prophet, and her husband who walked with was put in critical?</seg>
     <seg id="4">. They had come from outside?</seg>
     <seg id="5">On the army and Karbala. and. was laid?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Accept facts are made without motives were far was not out..</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC&apos;s policy demanded closed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Super hit better than this subject titled: &quot;Bush was justified if the shoes or illegal?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Should, was</seg>
     <seg id="4">, Japan</seg>
     <seg id="5">Some shame and a man from the grave by taking out from that it has been raised voice against oppression, and you think of was the topic of the box office.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">For the common people and that is dependent on it depends on the other side of the border line of the opinion is in favor of what.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Is this step and Pakistani bomb and in person are while the victim of a conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now, in this forum will be based on the Taliban opposition because the to have been included in the Taliban secret. And they are taking measures which could change the opinion of the common people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Then only in this question is that when his body for a whole day was restructuring, the army. The statement that he has only target the common people, there are also some so they are &quot;bombardment on the whereabouts of Taliban, house shells, two children and their mother, were killed.&quot;</seg>
     <seg id="2">That was not know about this Chowk in?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Or fun were?</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are already hand manipulation and credit and prayer that God is closed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">End you are also a ruling on.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The question was asked by the BBC is sorry to see superficialness of those writing may be reasonable, for example, a question has been asked not to have that 30 thousand troops present in Swat?</seg>
     <seg id="2">The bodies of those who help the army to fight the Taliban are always on poles throughout the day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Swati green step with the people of the Pakistani army, who had made 100, but also the world media, including the BBC, the real truth and what is not good.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Pakistani army is drama.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Swat that every child is that it is a bloody drama.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Bus drama.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Taliban. The name of the Muslims is bad.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In the whole world if true Muslims say not to them, these terrorists in their area to find a place.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who are they would have a hard job from which would not have been included in the group of them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Islam is not with the power of the gun or sword.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Shame demanded.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">For this is not in any other religion not in any other.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All including the BBC about the Taliban and tribes do their from different sources.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the situation is not that time is the situation. The address on. We know because we are tribal.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In Summary, it is that it is a, they include a I. C. A., RAW, and our own. No students is not tribal their rebellions are elements who are defamed Islam, Taliban, schools, Pashtun nation, tribes and tribal.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This move, the head of the Muslims were nonsense. shame.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In response to the leader of the A. P. P. P. and the service to be used against the talk against the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is, they were themselves, but Pakistan were also destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But in the end the present that I will take.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the Mumbai attacks, India said that behind these attacks, Pakistan is the hand of some extremist elements.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan has denied the charges and said that they would extend all possible help in the investigation of India.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India has said that it has given a list to Pakistan in which they are given the names of 20 suspected extremists, who wanted to India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now, Pakistan has said that head of the Jaish-e-Mohammad, Maulana Masood Azhar included in the list are not detained and the government of Pakistan has no information about them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Before this, the President of Pakistan Asif Ali Zardari has rejected the impression that Western intelligence agencies and the Indian government has provided evidence to Pakistan regarding the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">About Ajmal butcher, the President said that it was not yet proved that they are Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Meanwhile, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has warned Pakistan that its relations with India until then there would be no better until the head of the land will be used for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="8">And the latest progress in India has cancelled the cricket team visited Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="9">These political incidents should take effect on the sports?</seg>
     <seg id="10">You have the future of the relations between Pakistan and India</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan not broke America will not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan itself Pakistani will.</seg>
     <seg id="3">So communal and after you expect...</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jinnah has also with Muslims has proved that it is not a good time.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Yasmin, Hires</seg>
     <seg id="6">If Mrs. Jinnah Sahib lived continued work on the vision, not provincialism, and priestcraft cancer spread in Pakistan nor with the Muslims in India, it is treatment.</seg>
     <seg id="7">But our mistake is that they could not create a leader of such stature.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The amount of their heroes if we cannot,</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In this region, are very.</seg>
     <seg id="2">God knows when wisdom will come and with the blessing of the consensus, this region will progress.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Found in both countries, Pandit, Taliban, R., anti-peace.....</seg>
     <seg id="4">And that it is not willing to provide peace with the development of the region so these countries puppet dance is being.</seg>
     <seg id="5">. You can imagine. That agree with this area of Pakistan, India and China will have a place in the world.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Pakistan is that of God, the thieves, robbers and in on the nation..</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">God on Pakistan, our country should never came, no fire.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Mr. but just opened its surrounding circumstances and facts, you will come to see that where forces are reached.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Besides it national issues are not coming to be correct the situation in Karachi, North West Frontier Province, Balochistan and Sindh are in front of you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The situation in the country is of a trial that we could make a United Nation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Or, we move on form.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Ching not a remedy without a final war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A bus has been.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now the matter should only be be R. or cross.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Hypocritical his talks will not solve the problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Not only a small marginal terrorism in other countries.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Europe to the end, as only after the last fight in the war.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is it has not been in war, and it is also the till today, Pakistan and India have been doing it.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Our entire it are agreed that the country should be removed from the terrorism and communal.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But our military do not be sincere in this work, had a hand, America and Europe that is the act of terrorism in this war, we are with you, on the other hand, the secret of the Taliban are to help.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We now think and its direction is to choose the path of their people and only one, Automic</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no doubt in the fact that the majority among the party is only those members of Lashkar-e-that-were included in the party set up by the name of Jamaat-e-Pakistan after cater as null and void.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After that, however, these workers have given priority to the relief work and now India&apos;s insistence upon the United Nations has also declared null and void it and the government of Pakistan, continue to crack down against them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, if the hardline groups left religious extremism, religious and relief activities continue, better.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Pakistan, there are organisations who keep young military crimes Paul young people on the name of Jihad? and they are saying, big, are those who have to go to Pakistan and..</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now it is not leave no stone in Pakistan to be destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In fact, it is not entitled to human beings.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan were free from the rebels without national security in danger.</seg>
     <seg id="5">. Even now, it is the capacity of thinking is not that they should be banned?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Any place in the world of work not only murder cases.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The heart by this news is a thief.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is how the world where God&apos;s name, an important member of Islam that today for the take it is difficult to live in the world.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Can Muslim and non-Muslim, but if Muslim should also try to take revenge, along with all the non-Muslim world, all our together the pain of sincere and true religion to do the same with the treatment of those who are doing today with our great leader Hafiz Saeed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The accusation of Mumbai attacks in India.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan has been created bitterness in relations and is a severe blow to the improvement in relations between the two countries in recent years.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India is continuously active military and non-military groups in Pakistan is responsible</seg>
     <seg id="4">Coming back to normal relations and to take action against these groups is being 10.</seg>
     <seg id="5">While Indian security agencies has settled force directly responsible for the Mumbai attacks</seg>
     <seg id="6">Again and again in this regard, even in the name of the party.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is not the first time that a terrorist action in India due to the relations between the two countries, be serious.</seg>
     <seg id="8">After the attack on Indian Parliament in December two thousand one, the two neighboring arrived on the brink of war.</seg>
     <seg id="9">In 2001, after the two thousand two banned Lashkar-e Tayyaba and it was included in the list of terrorist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Now the party, about which the security analyst says that is the new shape of Lashkar-e-in fact, ban is being demanded.</seg>
     <seg id="11">You think in the group should be banned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="12">The Pakistan should take decisive action against extremist groups active on its soil?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Imposed on the party to present India.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Pak crisis can get out of the way for lasting peace between the two countries and how it is necessary to stop the armed groups?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The UN Security Council has imposed a ban on the party, the end of the Security Council, which are proof that have seemed so?</seg>
     <seg id="2">. the Security Council No activity against Muslims not?</seg>
     <seg id="3">It are saying that the plaintiff witness slow!</seg>
     <seg id="4">Next, then India itself has become a failed!</seg>
     <seg id="5">Of which, the army and other institutions are have failed, who are dance for 72 hours at the hands of a few terrorists and India accused Pakistan of his failure to put the entire world is giving deceptive.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Be a dissident murder in the entire world is taking Noise - his double?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Aziz only, the country, the welfare organization - - - - - - - -.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Furqan Farooq, Abdul,</seg>
     <seg id="4">Until our (than), scholars and the love and respect for the people, peace Islam. spread and.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Muslims also in every opportunity of development.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Benares and pagan in this beautiful climed captured us started and riot started opening a new chapter, which had not known before the world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">... Mr. desire to do. But his action on his bill.</seg>
     <seg id="2">America do not come in.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If India is distressing should provide proof?</seg>
     <seg id="4">They not?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And for every thing we put on?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Also in India, extremist groups and organisations are not defeat ban on them, his people?</seg>
     <seg id="7">. We are only a terrorist in the entire world?</seg>
     <seg id="8">India who is in Kashmir, they have?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Israel is that they have?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Is, it is true that we are the first Islamic, are fighting.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is now in the final stages.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Kamranhassan, Abu Dhabi</seg>
     <seg id="3">You is due to heart and some conditions are also looking only such</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now, these magazines published in Pakistan with a new opportunity to go to that is a part of this connection and it is also the view is coming.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Slowly, but not now very are doing to strengthen its grip on Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In case if we the people is not a demonstration of unity and the unity of the nation, that if the can become, and also be a lot.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Scare around the attacks should also be condemned, it is less, whether they are in a hotel in Mumbai or in Islamabad hotel and then or in Palestine.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Such terrorists, where they are also should be removed, whether they are Pakistani, Indian or I am and.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Becomes it is now the question is that every day, which would have been a terrorist attack in Pakistan, people are not killed, they are the whole of the Pakistani officials are silent?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Have hotel have been was not a terrorist attack?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Then cried.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Foot home Rehman Malik Sahib, said G., and how many were are!</seg>
     <seg id="2">B, where, according to the UN Security Council (a) has imposed a ban on the party, there is the country has said that we have not imposed only after much consideration and thought it be.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Not, according to the BBC, the same person, he gave the impression that the country is declared the wrong with intensity that terrorists, some say, are being brought in the process.</seg>
     <seg id="4">, God!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Ability to keep or not or it is not to say that.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistani what we are fighting the war.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And our interests are also to which we all try and.</seg>
     <seg id="4">One is not to interfere in any foreign affairs.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Era of apparently come.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It is expected that if the justice to the people, or upon implementation of its independent judiciary institutions respect. and a dictator or do not help the military, including peace will be established in Pakistan and which perhaps is not acceptable.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan, and is a doctor in the submission of the objectives.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is, despite the opposition of a dominant population of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And this is further anti-emotions.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If democracy and its allies are in confidence, settlement be walked from the region to respect the sovereignty of leaving the attitude.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In Pakistan so itself is that he or she should.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Pakistan-administered Kashmir, security forces raided a suspected camp of the banned Lashkar-e-.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Increasing pressure on Pakistan after the Mumbai attacks is that they should speed up action against extremist organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India is accused of the Mumbai attacks is in the hand of Lashkar-e-.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The American Jews Lisa Rice has said that the Pakistani leadership should be a practical demonstration of transparent and immediate action against officials of the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They say past Mumbai attacked the extremists to use the Pakistani soil.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Meanwhile in Peshawar, officials say that the allied forces deployed in Afghanistan, one of the trucks taking goods and base unknown armed men fire, which has been imposed more than 50 trucks were destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the second attack on NATO and American supplies during the 48 hours in Peshawar.</seg>
     <seg id="8">During this period, raided a suspected camp of the banned Lashkar-e-and earlier have also been several attempts to disarm the armed groups from Karachi to the tribal areas, which has long been assured to give compensation to those to return the arms and took no action.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Conditions are giving that General Zia-ul-Haq in the period of the former Soviet Union and the Afghan intervention of the Saudi American funding as a result of resistance from the beginning to the end the armed groups to Pakistan before 1980 as environment to take back the efforts were not successful.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The question is what Pakistan wants to do?</seg>
     <seg id="11">It is in terms of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="12">What do you say</seg>
     <seg id="13">Click here for the details</seg>
     <seg id="14">(grace note that the number of subjects increased only in Urdu to go to the opinions of the letter will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="15">For this point on the board of alt+shift and Urdu.)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">My only a question of all is:</seg>
     <seg id="2">If you come with their children, they lose they give you, it is impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Saeed, Multan</seg>
     <seg id="4">And my question to you that studies from Islamic studies to the East and West, no logic, and philosophy for the attack, the murder of innocent people including, labor and employment, young is allowed?</seg>
     <seg id="5">You and if the answer is not in his view is in dire need of reform.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Armed people have been at this time, it was feared that Russia after Afghanistan, Pakistan armed bust so these people should have been.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, when it is feared that America will run climbed on Pakistan through which are the current President has openly expressed in his presidential campaign, we do armed foreigners to these people?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The only so that America or India may not face any public resistance after the Pakistani army to?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Yes, if they are involved in any in any action, Pakistan will only take action against it.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">But it is a pity that the Government of India has become a matter of the declared that it is involved in Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Rehman, [p@ki$t@n]</seg>
     <seg id="3">If it accept. Be that Lashkar-e-involved is still not time for the Pakistan Government.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And it is also a question that these terrorists should not get the help of any government or to Indian officials.</seg>
     <seg id="5">. Terrorists are only have created or in Pakistan and India and in the countries of the world are not?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">That America Saudi from beginning to end the campaign for application from them. Now, it has to be rubbish by which our society.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Protest with them. that what America and Saudi under dangerous weapons in our country and the so-called jihadi hatred and culture of the virus, which open the human slaughter in our country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the danger of attack by India, the Pakistani Army has announced that he will give attention to the army from the Afghan border India and that his announcement of the Taliban, the Afghan border were badly and their whole insisted that India should not attack Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Been opened the whole reputation of power in the region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Although India has not given the threat of attack, nor his courage.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Was no provisions Taliban attacks on the whole.</seg>
     <seg id="5">America without the support of the government of Pakistan has proved that the Pakistan Army and some not.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Karachi, Pakistan&apos;s business center all-weary areas of Dubai.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Hundreds of thousands of empty hands, sometimes not, but when the supremacy of law in the western border areas has been the attention of Karachi has taken.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now they are fixed for the kidnapping of the city.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First is attached to the Pakhtoon said, who is making an alien to the people of the city, though it is need of solidarity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is a solution of the problem, that is, or the Urdu speaking people or Urdu speaking people, or all the English, and good.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You it a parody you, the cause of the collision. not?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because of the violence that language?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The, Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="5">Mr. in his childhood in his friends in which all religious and class people were included in the bar. They were given, on people laughed at these things.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At this time, the condition of these linguistic and religious C. alive today and not pick being inside the spot inside the bus.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We do understand that it is not only and is?</seg>
     <seg id="2">. The?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Innocent and who are being killed in a crime?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The reasons are in front to Pakistan to do the same. It is the most active and which are not, and is not a country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Karachi or Mumbai house has started the fire from the house.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And it is only in the name of the government and in the name of that, they are now-a-days, the blood.</seg>
     <seg id="7">. The meaning of. Who is with Karachi and Pakistan?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At the peak of the Mumbai attacks of trying to start sectarian riots in Karachi by raw failed to prove it is that in the past, raw working on its role the elements are now have to resign from the job.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pushto speaking the hard work it was confined to blood injustice and the Indian from Karachi..</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the political, religious, linguistic and national parties from Hub full diplomatic etiquette, the reaction to India where there are plan also provided a chance to thinking that.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The responsibility of the deteriorating situation in Karachi and A. P. and administration impartiality is fast.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Can control the situation in the administration but is John it was being agency.</seg>
     <seg id="3">, police and due to the pressure of the parties does to take action.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Alliance to the are limited to statements, parties should abandon their interests and to work for the interests of the common man.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Until the pressure on the administration to keep such incidents will, God in his order to Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Ching in the biggest terrorist people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And in this, There certainly is that they are at work, but not know who?</seg>
     <seg id="3">But unfortunately, this is that if they are in a city of the border, the government there. But what does when it is not in the North West Frontier Province, the government can seem helpless.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government should be a big and important city of the country and to save from terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Otherwise, Pakistan will be facing a major financial crisis.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC Urdu writing any while the condition of the Pakistani, and also not true for fear.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The whole truth is present on the BBC.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is a solution of the problem, that is, or the Urdu speaking people or Urdu speaking people, or all the English, and good.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Because of the collision, a mock if you will, but you have not ridicule?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Because of the violence that language?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A cruelty in Karachi, and the money was finally fear that every citizen had a feeling for a long time.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Walked to where the bus which he leave no stone coming on the 50. who has been in four days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Last three shine and insecurity is also now.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And the empty hotel to the killing. Those boss</seg>
     <seg id="5">On the super highway robbery to the mine and cutting all the agony of God are unaware that will never caught coming to them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What are the reasons for the unrest in this suddenly you think</seg>
     <seg id="2">(BBC)</seg>
     <seg id="3">India&apos;s heart ten &quot;the murder in front, Exploring the cause of the disorder in Karachi we set is definitely not required but completely, and it is the reason that it was only because of the blood, chaos.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Obviously, the fact is that if the father, with a wish-wash will then that, &quot;run out, run out of control was not the.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Blood, Ali Khan, and a person was also the wrong time is writing his</seg>
     <seg id="2">Elderly, we will also</seg>
     <seg id="3">Giving John will give life.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Faizan,</seg>
     <seg id="5">This time is a matter of regret, the whole country is at risk and we are in each hand.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mr. has stated that if wikipedia.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Currently in Ali Khan, know that you belong to a respectable Punjabi of Karnal area of Punjab province.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Refugee today because the measures for these migrants&apos; own.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The reaction, is only.</seg>
     <seg id="2">To his hands, could have tolerated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Ijaz Awan</seg>
     <seg id="4">Mr. earlier that up one night, collecting Jim also tells you, that are being open to you today in the form of Karachi on the wall and posters of harassment.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Both, we are coming.</seg>
     <seg id="6">, the founder of Pakistan, and Pakistan should also not spared,, not had to face any reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Backwards on the Pakistan military are heart.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It was a Muslim League (N) has also made a draft amendment handed over to people&apos;s party.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Prior to this, the MQM and Muslim League (Q) have deposited the draft of the amendment in the National Assembly and Senate.</seg>
     <seg id="3">So far, it seems that the amendment is a political ploy and no one is not sincere in to approve this amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why is that so far no one has forced nor house is not in favor of the amendment on the floor of the assembly or senate lamentation that he should accept the amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Like the feel that they have secured a kerosene chandelier depositing the draft of the amendment that we have been able to say that yesterday, the Speaker had deposited the amendment is not only the action.</seg>
     <seg id="6">MQM&apos;s coalition government ally of the government, the Muslim League (N) and the Pakistan Muslim League (Q) amendment to have the party, then how can these parties to end amendment I am sincere.</seg>
     <seg id="7">These, a color martyrs in the name of reason.</seg>
     <seg id="8">People&apos;s Party, it is no hurry to end the 17th amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="9">How can a good thinking of their hands.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Until President are 17th amendment is not the end.</seg>
     <seg id="11">The US was the opinion of the majority in a survey and is also true.</seg>
     <seg id="12">If 17th amendment is to end, then President never comes.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Now, because they are more powerful person with President Pervez Musharraf, he is also the Chairman of the People&apos;s Party with a president.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Until they are President 17th amendment is set up.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Political parties to end the 17th amendment will have to dismiss the first President to preside over the house.</seg>
     <seg id="16">It is not to the MQM nor the other parties.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Our family&apos;s most senior labor belongs to the class.</seg>
     <seg id="2">To create the same desire and when in childhood, we see his uncle, uncle and the defeat in the heart that God save us from the physical labor wages.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To avoid this, we wrote a letter to the editor of the daily today after the matriculation and asked that we should do that we do not have to physical labor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Editor wrote in reply that Dr. or engineers to become and ((essays catch fire.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Our trend was started by the same, and we have also read as Technical drawings instead of in the matriculation.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But at the time of the entry in the S. C. forced the big brother that we in the medical and Dr. S. C. &quot;.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We have only one month and when some also play, and they had not taken the subject of account.</seg>
     <seg id="8">-- fear from physical labor has made us engineers and now we are in a good position in many of his family, on which we live pay thank God every time.</seg>
     <seg id="9">This it came to US when we were trying raising the carpet of the old home with his two young sons.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Now work was not even half an hour that small son spoke &quot;deadline, it was not created this work.&quot;</seg>
     <seg id="11">We said if it is true, then our words, read and physical labor, John lo.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Son read it, then I am also read and I will go to my but this work is not done.</seg>
     <seg id="13">As we all three had ended in three hours they work and returned home.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Take say means is that if the man goal determine whether behind it, which is also at work, then a couldn&apos;t stop it to the floor.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Yes, if you have to know that is not only, then you are only God Hafiz.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Don&apos;t say that Murray, bad, but we will be on the first anniversary of Benazir are seen only in these abuses.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir has provided the occasion of the list of Sikhs in Kashmir after India India provided by Sikhs ran over freedom of movement on one hand and on the other hand, because the movement of the Punjab to concentrate fully fighting the war of independence for their interests.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And the power of Nawaz Sharif is a part of the daily history push by several years back to the country.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir continued negative statements on Kashmir and nuclear program during the in exile.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Benazir Bhutto, Nawaz Sharif, the violation of the agreement with a deal with General Musharraf.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Benazir has given the opportunity in their husbands openly money during their power and due to this reason that Mr. metal known</seg>
     <seg id="7">In the era of Benazir, his brother was murdered and the murderer of which are still giving children from punishment.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In spite of being the woman avoided fight the war of women&apos;s rights.</seg>
     <seg id="9">The way of Benazir politics on the body of his father, similarly, now, their husbands are politics on his body.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Benazir received government two times, but they did not punish the culprits of the political murder of his father, have also registered a case against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To separate East Pakistan from us, were a year and our people and leaders mourned not feeling that someone at the end of the day, and not mourning on their mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It should be that we, on December 16, the day was celebrated as a warning and thus do the hardships of such an accident happening again is not developing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This day, we sent messages to the people of Bangladesh and tried to bring them again.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Ruling open the file of the commission and to consider the reasons for the separation of East Pakistan in this.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Stranded in Bangladesh Beharis plan to bring back, and encourage them to send them gifts.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But we have been a sense in our neighborhood, there should be we now have no information about it.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We are not thinking of his sister brothers because we have been.</seg>
     <seg id="8">A major tragedy should be passed the next day, then we are lost in their normal life.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Which would like East and West Germany were again in the same way, East and West Pakistan can also be a again.</seg>
     <seg id="10">We can again if both come out of the shell of a second sacrifice staff and self-love.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But this does not look desire is fulfilled in the near future.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Today when the news was told that the governor of the US State kin was arrested in corruption charges</seg>
     <seg id="2">And to remove it governorship provincial Congress as soon as possible to the scrutiny of the edit take to the preparation of the US, one of our colleagues, of which Pakistan is deep and look at the situation of the US pride that look democracy, it says.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the United States, a man with a law is not past</seg>
     <seg id="4">And a your country is Pakistan which is made after giving the president also dropped corruption charges.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Our vessel fun and we have said, if a governor in America has been arrested in Pakistan, US, one night, the prime minister was arrested by hanging a time and the second time was Badar country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It was in the United States?</seg>
     <seg id="7">In Pakistan, departure from the Presidential House with the guard of breaking the law of the country, the United States, sometimes it was?</seg>
     <seg id="8">In Pakistan, the Chief Justice that it was suspended, despite public support, he still could not be restored, what was it in the United States?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Fake degree holder in Pakistan was made, what was it in the United States?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Hear the US poor and it there was and along with his defeat was on.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In this picture, President Zardari smiled despite being surrounded in Americans from all sides.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It from his smile.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They are understanding that the United States is with the government, but they are wrong that the same people a year ago with General Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Has this picture, such as a family.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Prior to this, never such photographs in the newspapers, that a President with three US officials.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It is the work of the United States has been increased in Pakistan, and now more than one together, it is forcing or there is no trust that these new Ghulam who was on the first.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is also the president of Zardari promises to keep, it was made.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If any sensible government would, at least in the picture on the faces of slavery and its no tooth would definitely evident embarrassment.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If the principle of democracy should be implemented on this picture, President Zardari are in the minority.</seg>
     <seg id="10">According to the majority of the country&apos;s democracy and he is ruling and who is this picture is talking.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Heaven Benazir Swat also called of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">So far, according to the government strategy dialogues are being made with the use of force.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But power and to increase the power of the people to create sympathy for them is not giving some besides.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is necessary that the use of force in place of the government should end the reasons.</seg>
     <seg id="5">By the end of the reasons Fazal God and the Taliban itself will be ended by itself.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The ANP would cause of Swat solution to the extent of the bill on behalf of the government.</seg>
     <seg id="7">But along with the Shariah, the government will also consider the economic</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">General Musharraf started, it was settled that the nation will get rid of corner if entitled policies but the power change all these intentions with CNN</seg>
     <seg id="2">Who also to the attacks &quot;Oh&quot; in the inexhaustible in understanding.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And those measures was expected, he ended.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Elimination of Bush, they began to think of the end of their power and thieves in given.</seg>
     <seg id="5">General Musharraf can still control the army, but the present government was not only know that that is going on.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Or be Swat army does not control and bombing &quot;enemy does on poor people, along with the financial loss, as the enemy, the mental given, not only the enemy we</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Swat in the troubled region of North West Frontier Province for more than a year despite issued conditions worse than the military action is going to happen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On one hand, the writ of the government in this area only Condemnatory resolution passed in the national assembly has been reduced to the extent of the illegal FM radio channel, and on the other hand, Taliban&apos;s influence is more being used in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Third hand civilians thought in this opinion is that the practice which is the rule of this should be heard in the area.</seg>
     <seg id="4">During the operation of the security forces in Swat about gunship helicopters and the bombardment of the battery groups claims. The death of many extremists know, but despite these killings, not only have more stable, but the Taliban rule, according to an estimate, Swat was established on 80 percent.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Its failure as a result that on one hand, the government is not ready to fool, and on the other hand, Taliban stable.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Who, without options in the city.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In Swat, now it is said that any response, asked how the Taliban are people got very good Defender of religion because they are fighting against the enemies of God and religion, and &quot;.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Then was asked that the army is coming, got the answer to that very good because they do, the security of the country and is, against the enemies of the country.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Then was asked that the religion and who are the enemies of the country, we got to citizens.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I am surprised that the Pakistani Army with the Indian army, how will that he could not control a small group of Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Traveling on the Taliban as illegal FM channel could not track that in my opinion is very easy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But even then, the FM poison with the water and schools.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the girls schools. Now the school of boys are being destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is alleged that Taliban easily be able to movements.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Today during the night curfew has made trenches into the outskirts of eight trucks during the curfew.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The question is that they reached out there despite the curfew.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Akbar Bugti murder in the house, the army and the Taliban does.</seg>
     <seg id="9">God is for the army can understand that a bus of Swat people expelled from the grip of the Taliban and it will prove that the Pakistani army containing any enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Hazrat are most blood faiths in the world has been on the staff, you tell me that if religion is not. his blood is not harm?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Punjabi, Pathan, black and white, enviable and other tribes of religion. It is Everything?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Education must not only religion, Mr., it is not a Punjabi is that there is not any of the white would have no religion, otherwise, if not half and caste community in fighting the people become hostility.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Actually, but only human beings does morally bound train. And it is not our choice, but the creator of this world, it has to be, and it is to live according to the same order.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a Muslim, I had to meet it is Islam is a complete. and true religion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Residence in London to a every morning in the years after the first of all his relatives does know the bar also have a telephone and issue our News. Then I am not feeling that our call would not call we have left. &quot;</seg>
     <seg id="2">Two years to live in France has also felt in...</seg>
     <seg id="3">Regimen people have hoped. We only by phone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pass in a few hours, about Iraq, peace, there is no problem to the army.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Mumbai ban on immediate condemnation of the attacks and suspected organizations, is the work of a few hours.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And where death is then to dance on this, we are advised advice.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Oh and world peace here, life is being ended.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What really waiting for the end of, not happening.</seg>
     <seg id="6">So again a victim could not even think about their right to use the weapons of mass destruction to catapult as larger?</seg>
     <seg id="7">His heart when a father of raised happens, it is also a wave of pain in any part of the heart?</seg>
     <seg id="8">If not, then you are not only entitled human.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But a black spot in the name of humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If it is proved that it is also country area for thousands of years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But, it is that both nations together in each other and love, but they are in the hands of the West and Arab countries, it could not establish peace without their will for ever.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But now, Iran also wants to fight its war.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Action was also stop on a temporary basis, then one would start after the incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC the interests of the country are linked with America and Israel, and that is the reason, bright, it in the front, &quot;with a group of Warid was and blind, propaganda, and it is.</seg>
     <seg id="2">BBC is the only,, and just as it is the purpose and interaction!</seg>
     <seg id="3">Mr. is that votarist published this comment. So that some idea is that the facts in the BBC is still remaining a little bit of humor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Automic.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Who did not know this story written in existence, but it is certainly a thing every time in the blood of innocent people, keep.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In every time and are being and every time in the blood is flowing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But is that it is a matter of century, it is of a man who is very civilized ourselves day and head the common is silent on this murder, common</seg>
     <seg id="4">To this does not feel that what is happening, they are presenting a bad shape.</seg>
     <seg id="5">, it is unfortunate and sad aspect is that it is coming aspect of human beings. in front of a century and human would.</seg>
     <seg id="6">,, Deccan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At this time, in the whole country along the Dera Ghazi Khan being of winter.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to weather a poem is ready, along with the discipline rain).</seg>
     <seg id="3">The rain also you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Was the year, Bihar.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Who was stay, as.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It was coming so that to</seg>
     <seg id="7">It was never conquered day night</seg>
     <seg id="8">Never noise are sometimes silence C..</seg>
     <seg id="9">The rain also you.</seg>
     <seg id="10">A night in a memory</seg>
     <seg id="11">One was buried C. ash</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sometimes it was that instead.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Sometimes burnt themselves to himself</seg>
     <seg id="14">In the gradual grief.</seg>
     <seg id="15">The rain also you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All these leaders are being one who want to take the case, what, in the country or less.</seg>
     <seg id="2">People with tooth-paste or lemon peel is destructive of Temples.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One, our media is also unlawful like rulers.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The purpose is only collect money from the government, and some not.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This great ignorance was illiterate people, he is to talk about it</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Yesterday afternoon was a strange adventure.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All of the police on the other hand, on the other hand, it is being run not ask parking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And, and nypd traffic should be illegal Park vehicles that was not in the mood.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Was there was proof that a plane was really only a plane of the U.S. air and land in the river.</seg>
     <seg id="5">So far only know that &quot;terrorists&quot; belong to the generation of birds goose.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Was a historic cold of New York.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This amount is not.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Itself is attached to jaw pain to walk out of my half an hour.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Establish a guess that these people were jumping in the river from the plane would have been recently.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Is a matter of joy that all the people are safe.</seg>
     <seg id="11">And it is unfortunate that the aircraft of the company was drowning in this crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="12">In all this was looking to see the way like the West side and was also seen that the South is still closed in the what?</seg>
     <seg id="13">G. was stuck in the same rush in return.</seg>
     <seg id="14">But thank God that I had only opened some measure during an hour, that I was receiving 56 Street exit.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Not, in the first two exit struck on the lines were to be seen.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Buffet, my Pakistan: A Mubarak you Eid Mubarak.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Faith: of course</seg>
     <seg id="3">: Khair Mubarak, you should also Eid Mubarak.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sarah is: in sacrifice has taken two fowl, and like that is Jahanzeb has telling</seg>
     <seg id="5">In addition to this, and no way.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And being on this form, including hides and meat is hardly make themselves also diminish.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Cork networks: the right to take time.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The Forum was?</seg>
     <seg id="9">,,,, and,</seg>
     <seg id="10">Hark, two hands to see,.</seg>
     <seg id="11">: A Mubarak, you also Eid Mubarak.</seg>
     <seg id="12">G. used a crane.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Snow will be disappeared.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We feel free, non-civilized Swati Talabani only on the education of women, who remain.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This every day or not, the women&apos;s school and college anywhere were demolished and expressing them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But most of the views, was not even think to be correct, according to the news of CNN today on Monday of time Barkat Talabani faction of the boys, a school was demolished with explosives.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Swat, the Taliban demolished school of boys.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Girls in school, the famous English word &quot;ladies first&quot; process, the first were also demolished, people still do not know the Taliban and non-civilized culture weary with ferocious say why are under?</seg>
     <seg id="6">From this thing is also clear that Talabani faction and the allegation that they are only against the education of girls, is not correct.</seg>
     <seg id="7">But if they are against the education.</seg>
     <seg id="8">God-given the mujahideen and power, and the infernal government</seg>
     <seg id="9">Who is imposed on us, it causes to help them. &quot;</seg>
     <seg id="10">, Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Now one hundred eighty two schools have to be demolished.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muslims born before a permanent thing is to be wise and adult in this tradition, and many subtle that girl eight years to marry the Quran in the name of tradition, property, collecting, in India, that was not only less frog with the marriage of the girl was in the news.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the occasion of the marriage of the bridegroom was a picture.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Some time before the marriage of a girl with a dog was too fresh.</seg>
     <seg id="4">See the bridegroom.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Humanity in the 21st century is scarce.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Today is the era of and the intervention of a computer is growing in every walk of life.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people on the increasing intervention of a computer, many are like that on financial issues.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The use of the credit card to where you are you from the private life of the grip of the law enforcing agencies also better.</seg>
     <seg id="4">That only financial issues such as the use of credit cards from the record of your address can be imposed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And when the real inflation in the future will be very low to use the benefits and will be increased.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Similarly, in the world of crime, instead of taking the risk of bank blew up a credit card information are sought.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Similarly, now to friendship have also become sources</seg>
     <seg id="8">, social net working like web sites, new fees and Mai popularity and in the first place.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But do you not think that mentally resigned as the social net works, we are going to happen, practically, so that people are going to take away.</seg>
     <seg id="10">In the same way, the web site of the match, where you like, like other people, which suits Mullah, the list of the people has been showing you.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Now what can you just spending their lives with another person as his?</seg>
     <seg id="12">In it could not ask for this, Jeevan colleague says the better half.</seg>
     <seg id="13">The defects that are in me that they should meet.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I got only a small part in mind.</seg>
     <seg id="2">From childhood, there was also a big saying is very true for me.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As was sure, knows the answer to every question of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I also on this very fun.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But only he was a true assessment which may be possible.</seg>
     <seg id="6">That is very confusing false of what was necessary.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In this age, it also raised the loss.</seg>
     <seg id="8">That is why I try lies at least.</seg>
     <seg id="9">A false don&apos;t Lara and he also attached with the name of Allah.</seg>
     <seg id="10">And stronger already say when pray to God that work to fulfill.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Of the situation, only God knows better.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a problem that has been created due to the distance from religion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Religion and Pakistan, according to the law, both innocent children should be with the mother.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The cost is the responsibility of his father and the father can get children.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Then when children will be affected, that continue to live with it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You is correct that the real problem Aziz are friends and relatives who taught signs.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Thinking is rampant on all our deeds.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Here is working the same thinking that will create a new part in the property of the father, and is opposed this, otherwise, the process of their father is appreciable and forgery.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These spasm about our relationship has created social evils.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And widow, the concept of marriage is being done.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This senseless beliefs and unfair traditions are due to which the family system is the victim of the conflict.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In our society, if the wife of a 50-year-old man should be dispatched as aha, if a husband or a wife and the second marriage, it is good to be seen as not?</seg>
     <seg id="2">We were near a Pakistani uncle, his wife, 10, died 12 years ago, now to the marriages of all children, after he was married to a woman, a widow, children were against them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my view, it is their legitimate right, you are saying?</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are there to take the place of our mother, this we would not tolerate the thinking is what kind of thinking?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, the offspring of these Sahib should think that if all children&apos;s marriages after he had married a widow woman to a wrong, then what?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Like this, the widowed woman was also received support and he received the uncle Assume a house.</seg>
     <seg id="3">, because their children to be their world were busy and he will be on time.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Is the reason barbarousness.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Tomorrow, if their wives refused to serve the people, then they will be?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Is the result of the pressure of the society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When people are such family fun on such a move, children based on father&apos;s second marriage to be embarrassed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Even though they should face the situation and should say that his father was a process to the eyes of Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is a curse in our society in the last 40-50 years, we have been fully.</seg>
     <seg id="2">To a wife, it is accepted that Mian forbidden to be used, but that no other marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If the bus is to give, even after his death.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Its conclusion with Mian does also destroyed and also a major cause of pollution developments in society.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Strain of Islam, Islam is something we really do like those who are our practice and tradition.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Official, and education for girls, for example, keep on marriage and the like.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Instead is you bring home the question, Mr. big widow himself to leave the house of a widow, on top of him, by loudness become quiet and satisfied (yes in the stomach of a widow again distorting bouncer).</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the subcontinent, Pakistan and India, we have accepted Islam, centuries ago. But this ignorantly thought to be very important to follow Islam to practice and tradition and not be released until today.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Absurdity to the second marriage, divorce, interpretation of defamation, divorce untouchable to other women, like men, marriage is only due to this thinking with the result of the slyness of the dignity of the woman married to a woman on the spot and his great age of men.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And a copy of the Western nations, and we in the continent and as obsolete.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is easy to accept Islam, it was very difficult to follow.</seg>
     <seg id="5">God, we all the courage and 1971 Atta.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Urdu write so difficult, was never.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Bait. So you should write.</seg>
     <seg id="9">A very.</seg>
     <seg id="10">, Hafiz.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Amir Timor in his book, &quot;I am Timor&quot; is that I have found in his life, it was revealed that if a commander in chief of the army would be in the first line, the army will never failed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But, on the other hand, the situation and.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It says people, is only to die for us, we have</seg>
     <seg id="4">People in a murder, &quot;</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The good,</seg>
     <seg id="2">Tonight after the prayer of Isha prayers in the shop by a man in a car who has engaged in his hand.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the way this man has been forgotten in the car stopped in his entire family was settled.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It said that in Arabic is not that good side said that there is no problem?</seg>
     <seg id="5">He said in Riyadh that here in Medina, but no one has sought to cut my pocket, you are a charity to help forgive demanded brother, because the individual riyals in an event that my first stressed that the petrol consolidated to leave, but it has barely started.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Big anger me the very threatened..</seg>
     <seg id="7">This condition is. We also to Muslims for the family member of vehicles are treated at least.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Clear and Hadith (this God him)) under the better down to beg.</seg>
     <seg id="9">God we should make (Amen, Amen)</seg>
     <seg id="10">,,,, and,</seg>
     <seg id="11">,,,, and,</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">On the Renowned singer adnan sami, his wife reached a Mumbai police station while accused of torture</seg>
     <seg id="2">The police station, he instructed to go to court.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Adnan sami&apos;s wife had filed against her husband that adnan sami continuous violence on them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Institutional and non-human behavior have been set.</seg>
     <seg id="5">So now it has been out of their tolerance should be filed a case against adnan sami</seg>
     <seg id="6">Instead of a case, the police, saying they instructed to go to the court that the issue is not police is not.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Adnan sami in your views on the accusation of his wife is correct?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Adnan sami to the allegation of the Indian effort, not?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should inform their opinion about this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">- Adam, Sanghar, Mehr.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As far as charges is concerned, it can be imposed on any other man.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There is no thing in respect of</seg>
     <seg id="4">Adnan sami are some of the present wife and adnan sami leaving behind their respect life, the money was India, now the same fame embraced it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is the issue of its</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">, Washington.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Senior US officials say that the President about Afghan President Hamid Karzai will adopt a tough stand</seg>
     <seg id="3">About Afghanistan, America has been given much importance to the war instead of development in the new strategy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Officials say that Hamid and Zai obstacle in the achievement of American goals in Afghanistan is being considered because the government is corruption, the drug trade has been increasing and the strength of the Taliban are being collected again.</seg>
     <seg id="5">American officials said that in the American administration, Hamid Karzai on some more pressure for the people who are pushing include representative Richard Hall of the Vice President and the President about Afghanistan and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that the strategy has come after President Bush, who was a video conference with Hamid and Zai, after every two weeks and they were stressing on the American role in the reconstruction of Afghanistan and the civic institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Officials say that the administration of the central government will work with the provincial leaders as alternative.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Officials say that they Hamid and Zai will emphasize more on the war against corruption.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Hamid Karzai is facing new elections this year, and it is still not clear that and his companion for the chairmanship will support or not.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The statement of the American officials presented a change in U.S. policy regarding Afghanistan tent, not?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Is going to end the era of Hamid Karzai?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What is your opinion about this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the series of three one-day matches between Pakistan and Sri Sri Lanka defeated Pakistan 1-2.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In the first one-day match, Pakistan has faced with defeat to Sri Lanka, but the next two Sri Lanka won.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The performance of the national cricket team in the third one-day match is very poor, only 23 overs in response to Sri Lanka&apos;s national team runs on the nose and warning that it faced defeat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">As a result of the series, it is proved that the performance of the national team is not continuity.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Despite all the home ground and national team was facing defeat, in your opinion, what are the reasons?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Authorities on grain departments need to pay more attention?</seg>
     <seg id="7">You are satisfied with the selection of the team?</seg>
     <seg id="8">You will put the responsibility of the defeat on which sector, fielding, batting or bowling?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should inform their opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">- country Babar Hussain, Jeddah, is a matter of regret that today they are targeting innocent people from the villa officials ignorantly such cultures are continuing their landlord landlords oppressively sovereignty of the modern era, who will say?</seg>
     <seg id="2">No, you have to be at the time, the government does not take action against them?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Judicial Justice when work came</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-rosy, London, the statement of their choices are you prefer these are our desire is that something you should not write truth like statement over again because no crane, ahead of the brutal Lord is ordered to say the right thing, and this is equally Jihad statement said that the change in the reports to be tried.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">- country Yusuf, Dubai.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All this is the axis of those Kashmiris are fighting the war of independence for the last 60 years.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No one has not been asked, now they have caught the war of terrorism and extremism, compromise started cleaning things.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Common was the first murder of Muslims are now in the issues</seg>
     <seg id="5">However, Pakistan will have to understand the policy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-Asad Khan, London</seg>
     <seg id="2">India created this kind of situation is that the attention of the world should be removed from Kashmir</seg>
     <seg id="3">But Pakistan has always India the face of the reality of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now, the British government to understand this is why the Indian occupied Kashmir by the name of terrorism from Pakistan notorious eyes are stealing</seg>
     <seg id="5">And talk on this issue with Pakistan, they are</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The British Foreign Minister David got the band has said that the resolution of the Kashmir issue will end terrorism on the Pakistan border, could lead to deal with an effective way to the dangers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It should be noted that prior to this, the newly elected US President have also expressed similar views on the Kashmir issue.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The British Foreign Minister, while talking to the media in Mumbai subject has written that the war against terrorism is wrong about the dangers facing himself out for President Bush&apos;s policy was to kill people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">David received the band has said that Pakistan should not show any leniency for extremist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">By big powers to focus on the need for the resolution of the Kashmir issue, India due to the tension in the region trying to divert attention from the issue, is not?</seg>
     <seg id="6">In Mumbai, terrorism is not part of this strategy,?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is India wants to escape from the process of composite dialogue by basis terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="8">His opinion about me.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-Usman Aftab.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In my opinion, they are big powers are not to complete loss to Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">But they know that Pakistan is a nuclear power, are thinking of some measures to keep it in control</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here want to create a situation of revolution</seg>
     <seg id="5">The foreign countries are thinking that Pakistan want to corner to help Pakistan as political, geographical, some problems can also want to meet their purpose and also</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">- a citizen, USA.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Mouth is always the Hindu tradition that beside a knife in Ram on</seg>
     <seg id="3">I think that a bus is therefore in the stomach pain shortly, and he to threaten Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are ready to every kind of India, Chief of the Army to keep his mouth closed, otherwise we know answer breaking mouth</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fahim Siddiqui.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Summit is being imposed, the statement from the enormity of the United States of America is very bad, but now India is also the same mind, after the attack, some reality will know who is in much water</seg>
     <seg id="3">Hamas on Israel is attacked, but a shame that it wants to see Israel, India also saw India to do the same.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Prime Minister Syed Yusuf Gilani has said that American, the newly elected vice president has played an important role in former President Musharraf&apos;s uniform and to restore democracy, ruling Pakistan-Imtiaz to him for the government.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In uniform and the restoration of democracy, a political party should not credit, the parliament is not a rubber.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All decisions will be taken in the parliament.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Of the Prime Minister said that Dr chapter has been closed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You think was no importance of public protest against the findings?</seg>
     <seg id="6">The lawyers movement did not play any role?</seg>
     <seg id="7">The statement of the Prime Minister, what would you like to say.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Should inform their opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">They give advice to the newly elected President, Barak in his farewell press conference, U.S. President George W. Bush has said that he has many mistakes over his post and Barak to take the right.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I have as President, according to the US Under the constitution and the law and steps, American interests given priority on its popularity</seg>
     <seg id="3">Barak to stop these attacks, he said the enemies of America are still planning to attack on America, will be the biggest challenge.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He said that Iraq was my biggest mistake to widely accepted is the biggest disappointment for me do not get the weapons of mass destruction and to complete the mission in Iraq.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Addressing his last press conference in the White House, the US President said that this is my last press conference to participate in the conference and I thank journalists and other associates who have participated in it.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you think that they will not repeat the mistakes that Bush did?</seg>
     <seg id="7">No delay in to admit the mistake?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Bush will follow the advice of?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should inform their opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">US Vice President Dick Cheney has said that I want to see Osama bin Laden dead or alive.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He said that Osama bin Laden has been printed in a hard and tough areas and he has been ineffective for his organization, if Osama bin Laden dead or alive, it also arrested in this organization of this will have to be abolished.</seg>
     <seg id="3">America is determined to arrest Osama and the search for Osama should continue the pain.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Cheney&apos;s desire to arrest Osama will be fulfilled?</seg>
     <seg id="5">His opinion about me.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All rounder cricketer like Shahid Afridi PIA and Habib bank in the Quaid-e-Azam Trophy, the first day of the match, after the end of the game was a clash with spectators.</seg>
     <seg id="2">UBL on the ground after the match Shahid Afridi as drawing came out of the room, a large number of fans have gathered around them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It has earlier rap receipt of the application of a picture with their retention by the spectators on one occasion on which Shahid Afridi, he said, to take this picture tomorrow, spectators, however, insists on the Afridi came in the matter that they have all the people present there got appeasement times.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After that the Shahid Afridi said that this issue is being made at this time, I was the speed of the</seg>
     <seg id="5">However apology from the spectators will,</seg>
     <seg id="6">What you on this attitude of Shahid Afridi will say.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We should inform their opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has once again alleged that Pakistan was the environment of the war is giving</seg>
     <seg id="2">Terrorism and Pakistan is used as a state policy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Addressing a conference of chief ministers in New Delhi, Manmohan Singh said that terrorism is backing from neighboring countries, especially Pakistan,</seg>
     <seg id="4">Mumbai attacks terrorists had adopted the sea route and the Indian coast guard is safe from it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian prime minister said that the Mumbai attack in November Lashkar-e-Tayyaba.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He further said that terrorists are using new techniques and modern communication system, on the Line of Control, we will also increase strictly there is interference, he said that terrorism will not be tolerated any form, and this is our policy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This allegation of Indian Prime Minister to see how you?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Like the internal movements of Indian anxiety Mazhar?</seg>
     <seg id="9">India on what signals threatening calls were made to behave?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Should inform their opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">- Zubair Khan, Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is a very painful tragedy that Israeli Palestinians are massacred, on the other hand, Kashmir is the same situation but not to louse on the head of the council.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As well as the organizations which are present in Palestine and Kashmir that they must continue fighting for their freedom, and they continue to face any aggression while creating a not one day of his martyrdom will bring color stronger</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Israeli air strike on Gaza is still continuing, hundreds of Palestinian men, women and children have been killed so far.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Important political wife of Hamas, including children have been martyred.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the other hand, the security council meeting ended without any decision.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Libya and other Arab countries against Israel in the meeting on behalf of the resolution presented by the opposition is facing.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Many the Israeli bombing of the Palestinian civilian population is underway.</seg>
     <seg id="6">All over the world, the incidents of Mumbai was broke out but the Israeli attacks on a common in the murder, including America, Britain, no?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are important countries of the Muslim Ummah are silent?</seg>
     <seg id="8">The double standard of the world, what would you like to say.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-Saeed, New York.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In my opinion, it is clear that our most people are illiterate, they not only know that their money is being where the government fulfill its responsibilities and a tax because it is in the interest of the electricity and gas crisis would remain so.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because the people who have elected, they are all aware of the role</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All of Pakistan and electricity and gas in the shape of the crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="2">, on the other hand, the prices of gas from January 1 made non-availability of petrol in some cities of the country, while there has been a due to severe problems for the people.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Pakistan&apos;s industrial and business circles in the long closure of electricity and gas on the crisis of severe reaction, violence and demonstrations are continuing violence,</seg>
     <seg id="4">Industrialists have an ultimatum to stop the factories.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On the other hand, citizens from 8 to 10 hours load shedding in Karachi is found in anxiety.</seg>
     <seg id="6">About industrial life has been live.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Government institutions are accusing statement and their stand on each other in this regard.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Talk to increase the prices of electricity and gas with the nation is not a joke?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Why attention towards the resolution of the issues is not being given?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Wheel jam of the development of the country, the government would view is not there?</seg>
     <seg id="11">To overcome this crisis, you will propose what steps immediately?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Should inform their opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-Imran, Madina Munawara, I want to say that such people rendered ruling.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Me, it is surprising that the government of the people for the people giving the damage</seg>
     <seg id="3">Secretly gas petrol will not get a torture.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is no control on the government institutions</seg>
     <seg id="5">The day on the law and order situation is written, his mercy upon this country &quot;</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The New Year.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And political tumult last year was the year of downhill and Faraz, with regard to terrorism, it would be remembered.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rain and the establishment of a democratic government in Pakistan, unexpected disasters, earthquake in Baluchistan, the financial crisis in the world, marketing of separation from the power of President Musharraf and the end of a 8-year-old era of President Bush, shoe on Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now is the arrival of the New Year, you see how the coming years?</seg>
     <seg id="5">You will bring political or geographical situation, What color near the strategy will be?</seg>
     <seg id="6">The hope of any progress in the elimination of terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="7">The judicial crisis in Pakistan will be ended?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Pak-India relations will adopt this?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Surgical or full, there is a possibility of war?</seg>
     <seg id="10">New Year, you are linked to the expectations?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Should inform their opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">President after years on the US Government to fell off by white people were transferred to the Camp David presidential camp office, so that the White House, the new president at that time he insisted that according to the wishes of and be prepared,</seg>
     <seg id="2">President Bush&apos;s eight-year-old era in America in a historic attack on the World Trade Center and destruction, and then attacked the global war against terrorism, under the military action in Iraq and Afghanistan, the forces of various countries in this war and US the full use of resources in this war were a memorial examples of the Bush era.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This war itself faced the worst economic and financial crisis in the history of America.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You think in this war, the world has found crew and what?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Succeed of President Bush&apos;s policies?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What is your opinion on the government of President Bush?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian government has stopped the Indian cricket team tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Indian cricket team tour Pakistan in three tests and five one-day matches and a 20 to play the match.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Indian Cricket Board Vice President of talking to GEO News, said that the board has asked for permission from the government of Pakistan tour of the present tense situation between the two countries, however, was not possible due to the visit.</seg>
     <seg id="4">To cancel the visit of the team by the Indian government to justify the present political situation is the correct step, game should not keep separate from politics?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Decision of the Indian government is not harmful for cricket?</seg>
     <seg id="6">The security situation in India cricket team tour to continue its visit to Pakistan, the Indian cricket team, why not?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion about this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-Salman, Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The people who feel proud to India.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And his films, or their video there have been opened his eyes now should be that the people of India how you do respect</seg>
     <seg id="4">I remember a inter elections of adnan sami in which he said that Pakistan is not my British citizenship.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan sami, must be the first rest in Pakistan because thee respect there was not suitable.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-Farid Ahmed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">, Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Mumbai was changed the attitude of Indians after the attack.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Singh, did the reaction in this case is that they are hate Pakistan and Pakistani</seg>
     <seg id="5">Be know that the adnan sami songs with cow are now where they were headed, adnan sami was the stay in India, there is no need to come here</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Mohammad Shamshad Alam,</seg>
     <seg id="2">In Karachi, Singh&apos;s statement only will say that he is also change color like cameleon</seg>
     <seg id="3">The statement from the ratio of the occasion and what Pakistanis opening eyes that you in India is how much importance to understand the mentality.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Their hatred confidently and statement has been increased after the incident of Mumbai now against the famous Sami poison throw up.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">According to foreign news agency, the American President Bush visiting Iraq&apos;s farewell with Prime Minister Noor al-maleki, ridiculous situation was during a press conference in his office located in Baghdad when an Iraqi journalist said while addressing President Bush, &quot;the dog is a farewell kiss.&quot;</seg>
     <seg id="2">After this, the journalist has thrown his side of a shoe bring down, Bush, President Bush gave shoe levels already leaned his head with expertise and guarded yourself.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Second shoe making the American flag.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Security personnel to the journalist, were taken from the place.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On this occasion, President Bush has said that I don&apos;t know why it did it was,, I was no problem.</seg>
     <seg id="6">You think in this process was not expressed anger against President Bush on behalf of the Iraqi people?</seg>
     <seg id="7">On this incident, you will ask?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Mumbai, the incidents of terrorism in the relations between India and Pakistan after the tension created adopt serious situation when the Indian Air Force planes and Kashmir sectors in Lahore, Pakistan&apos;s air of the violation of the limits.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Due to the action of the Pakistan Air Force planes were forced to go back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">According to the sources, two Indian planes were ruffle with arms and ammunition and bombs.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the first incident of its kind in the present tense situation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan Air force has said that the Air Force is fully prepared to defend the country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Information Minister Sherry Rehman said that the Indian authorities have acknowledged that the violation of the air routes was, however, it was a mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan&apos;s military sources has termed the incident as serious.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Do you think is really in the intention of the air attack on India and Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Do as India&apos;s stand is correct that the violation was by mistake or the purpose of the capacity of the Pakistan Air Force?</seg>
     <seg id="10">This incident would not cause a further increase in tension between the two countries.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Should inform their opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Martyred at hart after Benazir Bhutto Zardari was by his son and Chairman of the People&apos;s Party has received the international award of human rights.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The President of the United Nations office in a ceremony during the meeting of the General Assembly was in Pakistan&apos;s former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto, Nawaz this award in recognition of his services for their human rights.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Birthday was celebrated of the human rights resolution by the United Nations.</seg>
     <seg id="4">On this occasion, the work for human rights in acknowledging those personalities and institutions are being given honors these besides Benazir Bhutto, former US Attorney General Luis Clark and to work for human rights throughout the world, the International Organization Human Rights Watch.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan&apos;s ambassador at the United Nations, Abdullah Haroon Hussain and other senior Pakistani diplomatic officials were also present.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto to have received this award on what you will say.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-Sameer.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Hires.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is true that he was but we also remember that this Nasirullah Babar has done a good job that he has the blood of many innocent people in Karachi, on which they were not proud.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Just after.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But it is also true that he has his party&apos;s senior people Nazar manner, and his son, the elected representative of the People&apos;s Party, this is how democracy?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-Noor, Karachi, the news of the Quran, it has been proved that the dissident dissident will support only.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But until the iron axe-not could not cut it on the hatchet</seg>
     <seg id="3">The way our rulers are coming on the country because this is something that they are their secret way.</seg>
     <seg id="4">God give instructions to our rulers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Of the UN Security Council, the Panel gave the name of Hafiz Mohammad Saeed, including three Pakistani citizens and Jamaat-ud-Dawa and five organizations included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">These include Jamaat-ud-Dawa Mohammad Saeed, operations chief of the outlawed organization Lashkar-e-witty Rehman, Head of the Finance Department, Haji Mohammad Ashraf Al-Qaeda and Taliban committee of the Security Council has approved to include the name of those Pakistanis in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Besides this, the name of a Saudi nationals is also included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="4">These organizations include Jamaat-ud-Dawa, guard Kashmir, Al Rashid Trust Trust International.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Member countries immediately vitality will freeze all assets of personalities and organizations. They will be arrested and will be imposed on the journey.</seg>
     <seg id="6">They will face the cases.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It restrictions under the influence of Indian propaganda, not?</seg>
     <seg id="8">India without any evidence are accused of the Mumbai attacks on these organizations are imposed?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is not present terrorist organisations in India?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The atrocities on minorities in India, did not know by international organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="11">We should inform their opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A spokesman of the Eid and does and Sunni Muslims on Eid-ul-Azha, animals on the process.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Uproar on the political situation in the era when inflation is on the rise, I do this and poor preparation of Eid, according to all their strength, and different ways to his associates are on Eid greetings.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We are also provided an opportunity through you that give congratulation of Eid in the form of short messages to their loved ones.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Of Eid, you can also through verses.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Murtaza Jilani,</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi, our leaders should understand that they are doing the same operation against whom they are appreciative of Pakistan who are every kind of cruelty, but Pakistan do love</seg>
     <seg id="3">If the war was, along with the Pakistan will fight</seg>
     <seg id="4">When they will feel the love, only protest will not get some politics, in my opinion, there is a possibility of a decisive war between the two so leave.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>

