<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="site04_single_constrained">
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The proposal of the support of France </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">A session of the Committee on Friday in Parliament House, the chairman of the committee under the chairmanship of Syed Mushahid Hussain, in which about this suggestion that he of relief goods, all the political parties of the representatives of a parliamentary delegation Palestine. </seg>
<seg id="3">After the meeting, the media, while talking to representatives of Syed Mushahid Hussain said that the committee of France by the proposal is welcomed in which it was said that Israel immediately ceasefire, and in addition to this, in the Gaza Strip for affected people to the relief works. </seg>
<seg id="4">He has by Israel to attack on the crime against humanity said that these attacks all countries condemned should </seg>
<seg id="5">Mushahid Hussain has double standards of the countries of the world to the target of criticism, said that terrorism against the people who are talking but he now Israel to the attacks on why they are silent. </seg>
<seg id="6">Foreign Affairs in the Senate Standing Committee on the Chairman of the leaders of well. also made the target of criticism. </seg>
<seg id="7">He said that the new committee expressed that the United States is the newly elected President Barak his government of the first one hundred during the days of the Muslim Ummah [community] Muslim so that the United States will address a Muslim and Muslim ummah [community] between the Gulf should be. </seg>
<seg id="8">Syed Mushahid Hussain has said that Muslim and the West of the Muslim Ummah [community] between skill gap might not only in the for emergency steps should be like Palestine and Kashmir, but the long standing problems. </seg>
<seg id="9">Minister of State for External Affairs of the country Imadud Khan has said that the committee of the Organization of Islamic countries of the foreign ministers of the meeting to participate in Saudi Arabia. </seg>
<seg id="10">The emergency meeting, Israel, as a result of the attacks on has been called in He said that the Palestinian is informed and, in this regard, the government of the leaders of other countries is in touch with. </seg>
<seg id="11">Of External Affairs Minister of State said that the Palestinian resolved according to the UN resolutions. </seg>
<seg id="12">The Arab countries belonging to two journalists had also attended the meeting and he said in the meeting of Palestine about the latest situation. </seg>
<seg id="13">Meanwhile, in Islamabad international University students of the Israeli attacks on Palestine staged a protest against the. </seg>
<seg id="14">The demonstrators were carrying banners and also take its on which slogans against Israel. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Flu to avoid to avoid </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">American Scientists of the research on were tests. </seg>
<seg id="3">From this proved that the food at flu virus were in dealing with the less. </seg>
<seg id="4">The old research a problem halved the wrong has proved that in fever, it is better to. </seg>
<seg id="5">According to the scientists fever during his present suffering. </seg>
<seg id="6">State University investigations say that the infection to fight the capability of a successful, and he also likely to die, while the food to the flu virus against in power. </seg>
<seg id="7">Professor According to the people from bird flu affected not only very soon, but they will be recovering in the even more will take time. </seg>
<seg id="8">He has also said that the people of vaccine has already taken they also winter during a few months to avoid. </seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">2222 for the best </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">This to show of India, Kennedy, the basis and this was drawn in of Ukraine or civil and alongside band Justin with a two song was. </seg>
<seg id="3">This in a car also had been kept on the stage. </seg>
<seg id="4">The profit of 2, 2222 of the most successful show, in which 222 million dollars get. </seg>
<seg id="5">Canadian show, 22 countries, has visited while only 22 countries in which they were of the past eight years in the world was the first visit. </seg>
<seg id="6">Both of the director of singer show King, who have,,, the Union of his visit, also. </seg>
<seg id="7">Have heard the two thousand six established at their own record broken. </seg>
<seg id="8">In 2222, he has six in 2222, 222222, 222 million dollars. </seg>
<seg id="9">The third bone adventure has declared the most successful singer, which has 22 crore 22 lac dollars. </seg>
<seg id="10">Bruce has 22 crore 22 lac dollars earned by the fourth and the fifth and their part in six lakh 22 million dollars. </seg>
<seg id="11">According to this magazine eight in 2222 in North America very few people and obscene programs in, and the people participated in the tickets to buy groceries at was ready for. </seg>
<seg id="12">The United States in a ticket in the price of eight per cent and show of in the most expensive ticket 2, 222. </seg>
<seg id="13">Magazine of Gary editor said that the international economic recession in the perspective of singers of two thousand eight to hear a good proved to be a year. </seg>
<seg id="14">He has a U - 2, 2222 and for this year of which are good issued to the prediction of the year. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Coalition education ban on the Taliban: </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The President of the North Waziristan Miran Shah and other place in the tehsils Hafiz Gul Bahadur group of the Taliban Transvaal, a local distributed in which the government and non - government their educational institutions in which has been threatened boys and girls mixed education. </seg>
<seg id="3">Transvaal, stating that if on January 2 to mixed educational institutions were not stop, action against them will be started. </seg>
<seg id="4">Transvaal, stating that the government, and other educational matters of identity cards for women and order will be ban on women in all counties NADRA offices on also wrong. </seg>
<seg id="5">Local Taliban on behalf of the women of the ban on the order of identity card was announced at such a time when in North Waziristan support programme in the offices of NADRA for almost two hundred women identity cards for making form collected. </seg>
<seg id="6">According to the local people of Afganistan, issued from North Waziristan Transvaal, all of the mosques on was read </seg>
<seg id="7">However, in a letter to mention that has not been the girls ban on different educational institutions also will be or not. </seg>
<seg id="8">According to the Transvaal, after the announcement of education or identity cards to any woman school or NADRA office of the country, in case the woman and the family members of the Shariah will be punished. </seg>
<seg id="9">Apart from this, district in Bannu police say that on Sunday, Bannu Mrannshah road on a landmine explosion in which is a passerby were killed while one is injured. </seg>
<seg id="10">The injured Bannu was admitted in the civil hospital. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">,,, the Target King more bodies recovered </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the police, on Sunday morning, President of the areas at Chowk and green Wahab Khan Chowk, two bodies were recovered from which was removed from the head. </seg>
<seg id="3">Those killed in the Frontier Corps and the police to being told. </seg>
<seg id="4">Witnesses say the dead bodies of near a letter from also found in which warned that was also a dead bodies to 22 am before he raised his death will be responsible for themselves. </seg>
<seg id="5">Local people say that for 22 dead bodies were found in the market was after security personnel in two bodies and shifted. </seg>
<seg id="6">President place and around in the areas of during the past few weeks in the Target king incidents dangerous to increase in </seg>
<seg id="7">Who is in the common citizens, including women and security personnel have been killed. </seg>
<seg id="8">According to sources, the local till now this type of incidents in more than 22 people killed. </seg>
<seg id="9">So far, these killings organization has accepted the responsibility of the. </seg>
<seg id="10">On Saturday in local Swat Taliban spokesman Muslim Khan told BBC that on Friday, the dead bodies in three his colleagues were in which the Taliban commander Rafi, the dead body of the also included. </seg>
<seg id="11">Muslim Khan said that the last one and a half months, Rafi in custody of the security forces. </seg>
<seg id="12">He said that when a local Taliban killed, issued a notice to the first, while on the other hand, in these incidents in the ordinary citizens. </seg>
<seg id="13">Local people has said that in a large number of security forces have been deployed but, in spite of this, citizens in attacks on the rise. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Benazir of were in the </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Voice of rape was recorded in a music (a way of music) now Tube also on the post. </seg>
<seg id="3">Five minutes on the songs of Benazir Bhutto and pictures video. </seg>
<seg id="4">22 - year - old Edinburgh a student of University. </seg>
<seg id="5">They poetry and cooperating equally. </seg>
<seg id="6">It is being said that he has apparently his mother to encourage after songs started to sing. </seg>
<seg id="7">He had undignified the said while that you were very intelligent and beautiful, you have a in every way. </seg>
<seg id="8">The incident of December 22, he said that you the temple at the age of 22 years, we, three children in the deceased leave. </seg>
<seg id="9">The entire nation is disappointed. you and your heart of all of them are present in. </seg>
<seg id="10">Benazir Bhutto, children of 22 - year - old Bilawal Bhutto after number. </seg>
<seg id="11">He in music from the beginning with interest. </seg>
<seg id="12">It is said that he had undignified the return to home of America in a journalist friend of Ramazan. award developed producer and music with had expressed his meeting, but it could not be. </seg>
<seg id="13">The poetry Sindhi translation of some newspapers have also published but his voice for the first time the Tube through the Sunni being. </seg>
<seg id="14">Benazir Bhutto, some of the people and to the workers of rape music having CDs of started. </seg>
<seg id="15">On the other hand, the spokesman of the Pakistan Peoples Party Farhatullah Babar has confirmed that the present on the Tube songs of poetry and voice. </seg>
<seg id="16">He has from Islamabad on the phone, said that it is a sad his daughter courageous mother and paid homage to the government of Pakistan, which is also on TV network has been issued. </seg>
<seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar, has said that the songs of CDs etc. among program to his party had not at all. </seg>
<seg id="18">He said that a few months ago fees book on the web site of his party thirty year comity of Bilawal Bhutto Zardari fake account, or was the end. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Pakistani Ajmal butcher is: Information Minister </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Federal Minister for Information and Broadcasting, Sherry Rehman, BBC Urdu service to send a message in S. M. S. Ajmal butcher citizenship confirming is so said that more investigations are underway. </seg>
<seg id="3">Prior to this, the advisor to the Prime Minister of the country of their home Rehman has refused to Pakistani citizenship. </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the record of citizens institutions them with NADRA Ajmal no record of. </seg>
<seg id="5">The latest announced about could not know that the Pakistan Government has now its stance on the basis of while Ajmal butcher citizenship. </seg>
<seg id="6">However, according to the spokesman of the Foreign Ministry Ajmal butcher of the Interior Ministry. </seg>
<seg id="7">Prior to this, the BBC Urdu service and a few other newspapers and TV channels has Ajmal butcher belong to the Punjab province of Kot district Okara Fareed from town. </seg>
<seg id="8">However, the government to. </seg>
<seg id="9">However, it is not clear that this Ajmal of the same Farid, is concerned, or any and from the area. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Also fired rockets from Lebanon, after the bombing </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Israeli army and police that the media representatives of the Lebanese area has said that the Israeli on our soil four rockets in the town of North Israel a in which two minor people were injured. </seg>
<seg id="3">The area of from Lebanon at the rockets were in response to believe the Lebanese Israeli bombing. </seg>
<seg id="4">It is not clear that this attack Hezbollah did, or behind this Palestinian groups active in Lebanon. </seg>
<seg id="5">The Lebanese government has said that it to is trying to that those who is behind the rocket attacks. </seg>
<seg id="6">The BBC correspondent in the region, it has issued a recent crisis for a very dangerous. </seg>
<seg id="7">BBC for editor of the Middle East, according to these rocket attacks by spread to the threat of war has increased. </seg>
<seg id="8">The last few days of being expressed that the operation in the Gaza Strip and Lebanon in north of the border with Israel not to be. </seg>
<seg id="9">On the other hand, on Wednesday, on Thursday night between Israel and air force of the Gaza Strip on 22 air attack. </seg>
<seg id="10">According to the Israeli army in these attacks of Hamas, the offices of the time, weapons, water, the sites to stop weapons and Hamas workers were targeted. </seg>
<seg id="11">Air attacks, in addition to the Israeli army and Navy also believe the bombing on Gaza, the whole night. </seg>
<seg id="12">Palestinian sources said that the air attacks in Gaza city in a mosque, has been destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="13">Unconfirmed reports of the Israeli Army tanks, who air get help from a helicopter was Yunus Khan of the area of. </seg>
<seg id="14">The last 22 days from the fighting in seven hundred Palestinian women and, in which a large number of children have been killed including </seg>
<seg id="15">While on the other hand, the Israeli army 22 soldiers were killed. </seg>
<seg id="16">The security forces of Israel has confirmed that one of the most defense officials of the planning to Jang conditions of the Cairo are being. </seg>
<seg id="17">A delegation of Hamas, from the ambassadors of Egypt Cairo parallel talks. </seg>
<seg id="18">In addition to this, the leader of the Palestinian Authority Mahmood Abbas also are reaching Cairo on Friday. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">My heart is broken back up, my </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Dr. Richard has said that he has eight years ago, his wife for them to save the lives of their as. </seg>
<seg id="3">News Agency, according to the AFP, Dr. has said that his wife of his kidney donation for this apart from their fraud and relations with any and established for to divorce and now. </seg>
<seg id="4">Dr. a local daily newspaper News In an interview with the alleged said that my heart hole in which till now. </seg>
<seg id="5">Dr. Richard According to Dr. and their of, but he kidney subsidies worth of equality. </seg>
<seg id="6">His wife according to his stand in the next few days, a before the judge will present. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">140 kilo, 2 - year - old Azad </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">George, Joint given to the two weeks ago, they were arrested from a sea. </seg>
<seg id="3">The city of food, the company has purchased 222 dollars in it </seg>
<seg id="4">Immediately and pictures of their of I used to started. </seg>
<seg id="5">However, animals for the protection of working group, a beat up, has demanded to, as a result of which, now it back in the sea, should be left. </seg>
<seg id="6">George in Canada, which was the sea, they were arrested from the city of food and the company tank spent in 22 days. </seg>
<seg id="7">The age of this is to be of weight. </seg>
<seg id="8">Restaurant manager said that these plans to any loss to tanks and it was not in the interest of the purpose of the consumers of goods to provide. </seg>
<seg id="9">The protection of the beat up belonging to say that the decision of the restaurant is commendable and for those who is an example for a rare or, in the tank or want to keep them alive and food. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Mobile with the help of the search </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">When the officials about found out of the city, and the police officer of a extinguish the forces. </seg>
<seg id="3">Officials of mobile present in the GP S. with the help of the place of it. </seg>
<seg id="4">However, street interview with the help of know that he is in a hotel in her. </seg>
<seg id="5">A week ago grandmother day of the parents of their legal from the supervision of. </seg>
<seg id="6">The police chief of told the BBC, he said that he never now and will not back in the state and then he has left. </seg>
<seg id="7">Mrs. police has contacted but when the promises he has not back, the police of mobile phone through it decided to search. </seg>
<seg id="8">Two thousand five in the United States or law is that the mobile phone companies to provide the service of 222 meter nearing 67 percent and 222 meter nearing of 95 percent of the location. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on a tour of India </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Hamid Karzai five months in the second Indian tour. </seg>
<seg id="3">It is expected that Prime Minister Manmohan during a meeting with the extremists in Mumbai, the situation after the attacks in will hold talks. </seg>
<seg id="4">This visit, during the Mumbai attacks on Afghanistan and emotions of the people of India and with their solidarity. </seg>
<seg id="5">Karzai during the visit of extremism apart from the mutual trade will be discussed. </seg>
<seg id="6">From for mutual cooperation between the two countries on the. </seg>
<seg id="7">India during the last of their tour of President Hamid Karzai said that terrorism to India and Afghanistan relations between our will. </seg>
<seg id="8">He also said that both India and Afghanistan to terrorism and cruel and attempts activities. </seg>
<seg id="9">Both countries region and the entire world peace and stability of all beneficial for the. </seg>
<seg id="10">We think that this his defeat to both countries and the entire world to unite to only the menace of can counter terrorism. </seg>
<seg id="11">It should be remembered that last year in July Kabul India in the attack on the Embassy of Pakistan for Karzai has said that secret agencies ISI was held responsible. </seg>
<seg id="12">In this attack, a F. I. S. officials including four Indian were killed. </seg>
<seg id="13">Embassy after the attack on the Karzai during the visit of Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has said that the attack, India and Afghanistan on the friendship between the attack, we have agreed that we terrorism your relationship between this would not allow. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The attack, Mumbai easiness for special judge </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mumbai police commissioner Ghafoor Hasan said that the Mumbai on extremists during the attacks were alive only the accused arrested Ajmal butcher, Amir filed against the issue of the easiness under the supervision of. </seg>
<seg id="3">Before this, in this matter to the government lawyer has appointed. </seg>
<seg id="4">Ajmal butcher at present is in police custody and hope that the police is being before 24 January against them into sheet will charge. </seg>
<seg id="5">Ajmal butcher have to defend himself for a lawyer. </seg>
<seg id="6">The Pakistan Government has written in a letter butcher legal help. </seg>
<seg id="7">Pakistan, India to Mumbai attacks in Pakistani militants for the evidence of the road. </seg>
<seg id="8">Pakistan has accepted that Ajmal butcher Pakistani citizens. </seg>
<seg id="9">According to the case, Ajmal police and his companion Abu Ismail T. A. S. chief, additional commissioner, police, Ashok expert of Police inspector, including six policemen killed after his car ran away after snatching after B, who were in the time of was arrested. </seg>
<seg id="10">The police in the death of Ismail Khan was and police has arrested Ajmal alive. </seg>
<seg id="11">The case was represented by Ajmal for any lawyer is still not. </seg>
<seg id="12">The government has the legal aid cell which lawyer Danish soles nominated moral he had refused to take on the basis of the case. </seg>
<seg id="13">Two lawyers have a political party of the people and opposition protests after his name. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Constitutional amendment:, the committee will be, </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">On Tuesday in Islamabad on environmental changes in while addressing a seminar addressing the representatives of the media persons after talking to He said that in this regard, the parliamentary party will be in the formation of the committee will be. </seg>
<seg id="3">He said that the Muttahida Qaumi Movement by the end of the 22th constitutional amendment, for the constitutional amendment bill was presented in the National Assembly while other political parties also in this regard constitutional amendment bill will be presented in the parliament. </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the 22th constitutional amendment of Pakistan Peoples Party has also all the political parties to also has sent a draft of the constitution and the committee will also. </seg>
<seg id="5">In response to a question, he said that the President and Prime Minister of between the balance of power of parliament will. </seg>
<seg id="6">The Prime Minister said that the parliament to all decisions in existence. </seg>
<seg id="7">In response to another question, he said that the former President General Pervez Musharraf retired from the office of army chief of political parties in the role of the former Prime Minister and Chairperson of Pakistan Peoples Party Benazir Bhutto, who is also important role He urged upon the international community, former President Pervez Musharraf on Uniform for stress. </seg>
<seg id="8">He said that the elected U. S. Vice President of Pakistan and the pro - democracy and their services in the President of Pakistan, they depose the position of Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="9">Mumbai after the incident, the Indian government of Pakistan with every kind of relations to the threat of about in response to a question, Yousuf Raza, said that the Indian rulers at this time, the people are under extreme pressure he such statements. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Journalists Protest against the dismissal of </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Islamabad on Tuesday, the journalists, J. U. come under the aegis of the Islamabad in front of the Press Club, journalists and newspaper workers TV channels and newspapers from employees of a large number of the media the owners of the government and the protest and shouted slogans. </seg>
<seg id="3">Addressing the protestors, journalists, the biggest Organization, Pakistan Federal Union of Journalists, senior member C. R. Shamsi said that the politicians, roads protest with our rulers Bin today, they were sitting in the house, but newspaper owners of a particular - due to the fear of the rights of journalists for some are not </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that human rights to newspaper owners of their institutions and the jails produced a camp, where the annual included in spite of billions of rupees to the workers and dismissed charges are less to their economic murder is being. </seg>
<seg id="5">The example of this Lahore a private television channel, five our in front of a member of the four months, which is not receiving was committed many members, and even today, and forced months due to lack of of life. </seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the TV and newspaper owners should direct action against journalists and the rights of the parliament for a permanent protest in front of the camp of need. </seg>
<seg id="7">Governor Punjab C. R. solar Salman to the target of criticism, said that the Urdu newspapers, today, who without any notice on hand is being. </seg>
<seg id="8">While daily Jinnah, daily news channel, five business, plus TV today and TV has also dismissed dozens of employees is </seg>
<seg id="9">F. P. J. U., Secretary General of the Mazhar Abbas Addressing the protestors, said that today all over the country in the press organizations newspaper reporters and workers of Black Day against journalist by are while for the production of their rights in the parliament session on bawlers tied black bandanas will be. </seg>
<seg id="10">According to the Pakistan Mazhar Abbas percent of newspapers and TV channels and workers of journalists exploited being without any agreement, where they are working. </seg>
<seg id="11">He said that till now more than two hundred workers to journalists and newspapers and TV channels being, while it is feared that the current year owners economic crisis to further hundreds of workers and dismissed. </seg>
<seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas said journalists movement will continue until the employees suspended until the newspaper, not considered wages, the workers of the seventh award to wage board the implementation of newspapers and TV channels, of the employees of several months has not stopped the salaries. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">22 - member cabinet has taken oath </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">New Cabinet in the former Prime Minister Sardar Ahmad Khan Atiqur of anti - Muslim Conference, six parties of Pakistan Peoples Party of two peoples, two of the Muslim League and the United National Movement of a minister are included. </seg>
<seg id="3">A woman in the 22 - member cabinet minister also and they belong to Atiqur anti - Muslim Conference parties. </seg>
<seg id="4">The ruling alliance has said that next week in the cabinet, will be extended and it is expected that a dozen more cabinet minister should be included in it should be remembered that at the beginning of this month, Sardar Khan Atiqur his opponents through the lack of confidence ministry was removed from the post of Yaqoob and new Prime Minister Sardar Khan was elected. </seg>
<seg id="5">These ministers after the departments will be. </seg>
<seg id="6">Swearing - in ceremony on the occasion of the workers of the Pakistan Peoples Party of former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto in favor of slogans. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Virus from thirty five lakh consumers affected </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Two thousand on October 2, for the first time in the identified the virus, and the bats up and is known as the names. </seg>
<seg id="3">The virus Microsoft to deal with a Peach Pass was issued, but, in spite of this, some computers and thirty five million have been affected by this. </seg>
<seg id="4">Experts say that the number of affected the computers a wet. </seg>
<seg id="5">This to deal with the consumers of Microsoft, M. S. zero at zero, 2 Peach Pass need to use. </seg>
<seg id="6">Microsoft has said that hundreds of thousands of computers to file of the virus, E. E. S. a search of, and this is included in the Code. </seg>
<seg id="7">After this, the virus of in the kind of the file. </seg>
<seg id="8">The file this virus is the name of the production, </seg>
<seg id="9">Then registry of the details of the team. </seg>
<seg id="10">This virus active after a problem, which is TT H. P., Sarwar emerged as comes and the point of the team. </seg>
<seg id="11">After this from the web site of the files download. </seg>
<seg id="12">Microsoft has said that this virus in various countries of the world computers. </seg>
<seg id="13">These countries in Brazil, Russia, China, India, the United States and Britain are included. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Indian, on the information, </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Saturday, the Interior Ministry, in a meeting of the media after talking to He said that by India to </seg>
<seg id="3">In this matter to the investigation will help. </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that Pakistan is an independent country and on the other hand, India received from their information on the investigation in any country, no </seg>
<seg id="5">Dictation will not accept. </seg>
<seg id="6">He said that India received information, in addition to other information have also. </seg>
<seg id="7">Interior Advisor said that the law enforcing agencies have a banned organization of 124 members are under custody in anti peace has been </seg>
<seg id="8">And if some of these people against any proof of their, action will be taken against while innocent people to be </seg>
<seg id="9">In response to a question, he said that the arrested a person to India would not be handed over and Pakistani people against these laws will be According to the same. </seg>
<seg id="10">He said that these people to take action against FIA under the law. </seg>
<seg id="11">In response to a question, he said that the Indian law enforcing agencies in Mumbai, the individuals involved in 42 days; therefore, they have information of new India is that the international community, including their for investigation for some time. </seg>
<seg id="12">He said the government again repeated this offer to the Mumbai that a joint team was formed. </seg>
<seg id="13">It should be remembered that additional director general FIA, under the leadership of a three - member team was formed which is that India from Mumbai attacks </seg>
<seg id="14">Pakistan to information on the investigation. </seg>
<seg id="15">In India, the High Commissioner of Pakistan, Shahid Malik, President of Asif Ali Zardari, met with the President has made it clear that if any Pakistani individual or group involved in Mumbai, has been found against According to the laws of the country, action will be taken to India would not be handed over, while the Indian leadership involvement in the people to India to put pressure on Pakistan. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">In some, the United States is also possible, </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Mr. on January 22 of the President of the United States will take oath. </seg>
<seg id="3">The President of the United States in Washington Ibrahim Lankan in the memory of the construction of the building standing at music while addressing a </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the United States, many of the most serious is facing and he is confident that the United States will control on these problems. </seg>
<seg id="5">The United States has Ibrahim Lankan in the end of the tradition of slavery. </seg>
<seg id="6">But with Mr. said that the country in solving the problems faced by the time and way would be difficult. </seg>
<seg id="7">But, in spite of this, on the hope that this was the dream of the country will remain alive. </seg>
<seg id="8">The United States of Iraq and Afghanistan wars of a severe financial crisis. </seg>
<seg id="9">Swearing - in ceremony for the extraordinary steps are being taken. </seg>
<seg id="10">It is believed that the organizers of the 22 million people will participate. </seg>
<seg id="11">On Monday in the United States National holiday is because the same day of human rights, great runway Martin King and killed. </seg>
<seg id="12">Martin King black. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Jahan. Martin, to work for the determination of the </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Dr. Martin King to also, in 2222. </seg>
<seg id="3">Dr. Jahan. King and the Americans, he said that the nation of his promises to work together to. </seg>
<seg id="4">On the other hand, in Washington on Tuesday on the new president of the President of the people on the occasion of the grand gathering of preparations are being. </seg>
<seg id="5">It is expected that the President was to see this historic for 22 lac people will be collected in Washington. </seg>
<seg id="6">On Monday day of North in Washington, a medical center in from where he American soldiers were injured in a meeting with the homes to set up a shelter in and a wall on color. </seg>
<seg id="7">While talking to reporters said: the present crisis, which we are and difficulties in which many people Rass have been discharged after we can not. </seg>
<seg id="8">He said that his Martin King more serve the people in. </seg>
<seg id="9">Said that today when we remember their respect, this day stay that we do not think it, and this is the day that we. </seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the ceremony of the same way on which will be on several thousand people King Martin, one of my dream for hearing is also in 2222 was collected. </seg>
<seg id="11">In his speech Martin King had said that they will be the day when these people for the discrimination will not be. </seg>
<seg id="12">BBC Matthew price are saying that the history of ironic that on Martin from that day is 22 hours before the history when the US President their black will take oath. </seg>
<seg id="13">The United States in the south of many people for was presided over by, Dr. King dreams will be diminished. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Additional political agent is </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Additional ten days before the political agent from South Waziristan Unknown wear. </seg>
<seg id="3">Sources say that official to local Nazeer group of the Taliban had kidnapped. </seg>
<seg id="4">According to the local administration on Tuesday evening at South Waziristan near four additional political agent Aamir Lateef a tribal jirga Wana camp. </seg>
<seg id="5">However, he has not revealed that additional political agent who had kidnapped. </seg>
<seg id="6">However, the local people say that political agent of local Nazeer group of the Taliban had kidnapped. </seg>
<seg id="7">Aamir Lateef at this time, when he was kidnapped from Wana tank. </seg>
<seg id="8">January 22, 2222 the reconstruction of South Waziristan tribal area in seven armed masked men invaded additional political agent Amir Latif, including the driver kidnapped. </seg>
<seg id="9">According to the official kidnapped a have already present in the armed guards and after additional political agent to help in a car and from there. </seg>
<seg id="10">According to the local administration additional political agent of security forces after the kidnapping of South Waziristan in the tribal areas and semi - check posts of all cordoned off and of severe search was being and the last one week officials have also imposed ban on economic Wana. </seg>
<seg id="11">2 December up to two thousand of North Waziristan political agent Asmat Ullah also at this time, when he was kidnapped was to celebrate Eid holidays for were going to Bannu, and after a few days in North Waziristan Tehsildar Amanullah, two people including unknown masked men invaded was killed. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">In the court of winning the British </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">22 - year - old British citizens has admitted that he has the US military website. </seg>
<seg id="3">Asperger Gary patient it should be remembered that Asperger of the patient only one way to mob mania. </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that if the lawyers of these handed over to the United States, fear that he will try suicide. </seg>
<seg id="5">However, the government has said that the lawyers of Gary of health of apprehensions with reference to have less. </seg>
<seg id="6">The Lord of justice and Mr. Justice Simon has said that the final decision to become the British court that he is reviewed in. </seg>
<seg id="7">The court has become in working conceding that if his house and family removed, they can suicide </seg>
<seg id="8">He further said that he has not consider the Home Secretary. </seg>
<seg id="9">But the government has said that the lawyers of Home Secretary use its powers. </seg>
<seg id="10">The American army has never become the web site of. </seg>
<seg id="11">Two thousand has also become a and two American in a computer system was due to the loss of 2 million dollars. </seg>
<seg id="12">American Marines and NASA has become a computer system, including 97 to. </seg>
<seg id="13">However, conceding has said that he has no courage to wrong, but they have not been natural general information about who were trying to find in his opinion, the US Government has kept secret. </seg>
<seg id="14">The mother of Gary Janice said that they are happy with this decision. </seg>
<seg id="15">Gary of lawyer said, it is the right decision. </seg>
<seg id="16">This case two thousand two from and eventually a right decision. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Two killed, the commander of the Kashmir: </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Jammu posted in North command of the Indian army spokesman Lieutenant Colonel told the BBC: 22 Rashtriya Rifles, the soldiers of Jammu and Kashmir police said that on receiving information about the Tehsil In Gandwah Doda district in a place where the armed has besieged the extremist were sitting. </seg>
<seg id="3">He fired on the army and counter action in two armed extremist were killed. </seg>
<seg id="4">The spokesman has said that two militants were killed in 22 years in the district of Hizbul Mujahideen active banned Tehsil commander Zahoor - ud - Din the land mine explosion in expert. </seg>
<seg id="5">Along with this, Sajjad identified as was the last year, according to the US army from extremists associated with. </seg>
<seg id="6">According to the forest area in the operation is because according to him more extremists, the presence of the army has said that the operation in the first phase of the fire two rifles were also recovered. </seg>
<seg id="7">Yesterday, the head of the province Kumar has eight years of facts and figures while this year, the most peaceful year. </seg>
<seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that in November and December within seven stages of the Assembly elections in a violence. </seg>
<seg id="9">In these elections 2. 22 more than 222 participated. </seg>
<seg id="10">It should be noted that the last 22 years, Hizbul Mujahideen active in Jammu and Kashmir. </seg>
<seg id="11">The opposition has for the first time in July one - sided coercive was announced, after which the government and the opposition commanders India talks between. </seg>
<seg id="12">However, only within 22 days of the finished. </seg>
<seg id="13">Later, the Chief of Hizbul Mujahideen many commanders were killed in different. </seg>
<seg id="14">On Thursday, daily of Pakistan, news of Pakistan in the extremist groups about wrote that Lashkar - e - Taiyba Mujahideen and the opposition has review policy on Kashmir, it has been decided. </seg>
<seg id="15">It should be noted that the two organizations of the policy of was that the Kashmir issue through armed resistance to be solved. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Dera Bugti [Baloch nationalist leader]: gas pipeline explosion </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to police Loti gas field, Pirkoh Qatar of the 22 - inch pipe line from making explosion. </seg>
<seg id="3">The direction of the plant, Sui gas pipeline project. </seg>
<seg id="4">Meanwhile, the Baloch banned organization of the army spokesman to the Baloch, a person named telephone to claimed responsibility for the attack. </seg>
<seg id="5">In the fourth gas pipeline has been making. </seg>
<seg id="6">On Friday in Dera Allah Yar, Qatar, a 22 - inch pipe line was destroyed by the repair work on Sunday morning to. </seg>
<seg id="7">In Quetta, Sui Southern Gas Company of the general manager Mushtaq Siddiqui has said that this Gas pipe line of after afternoon will be started. </seg>
<seg id="8">The pipe line of Quetta. </seg>
<seg id="9">Quetta Ziyarat and other areas in three days gas from acute shortage of an snowfall is continuing, and the freezing point, the temperature has and on the other hand, the heater and stoves and cool survived. </seg>
<seg id="10">Apart from this, in Dera Bugti, and market in the blast in a motor cycle, but according to the police, this explosion from any loss. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">For the administrator of Jamat - e - </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Jamat - e - of - center from Lahore about 22 kilometers Murid in. </seg>
<seg id="3">This center in hospital, and School students of the hostel. </seg>
<seg id="4">The minister of law Punjab Rana Sanaullah Khan has said that Jamat - e - center in the supervision of the appointment of this for with there is so that the work of welfare institutions by. </seg>
<seg id="5">The Amir of Jamaat - e - Hafiz Saeed son - in - law, Khalid Walid According to hospital in school, and other welfare organizations for the supervision of a government officer Babar to the Chief Administrator has been appointed as while according to them in the center in the number of police also increase has been made. </seg>
<seg id="6">The UN Security Council has imposed ban on of Jamat - e - Pakistan, after which the federal government has throughout the country to take action against the Amir of Jamaat - e - Hafiz Saeed and other leaders, including the Punjab government has been center in by - appointed to the federal government on behalf of the party of the proceedings against the continuation of. </seg>
<seg id="7">Babar concerned, D. I. G. M. district management group. </seg>
<seg id="8">Hafiz Khalid said that Walid Commissioner division Khusro Pervez Khan Lahore on Sunday, police and civil administration with center in various parts of the center and inspected the Khalid Waleed has by the government in the center of Jamat - e - as to condemned and said that government already activities because of patients in the hospital situated in the center and school in a reduction in the number of children. </seg>
<seg id="9">On the other hand, the Party of According to a press release, the Amir of Jamaat - e - Hafiz Saeed, the Secretary General of the United Nations of Dei romance committee for the Taliban and the name of a letter written in the Security Council on behalf of the party of the ban imposed on to end. </seg>
<seg id="10">In a letter it was said that the security council by Jamat - e - ban on one - sided decision is an injustice and Jamat - e - terrorism has no connection with, but it is busy in welfare works. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Edhi Relief Mission on Gaza. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In the Gaza strip the need for permission to many stages from till now, after the passage of Egypt from New York to succeed in. </seg>
<seg id="3">Cairo, the BBC Urdu service while talking to He said that Gaza is still they could not reach because Egypt and Israel have many obstacles. </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that I came here eight days and Gaza is still not allowed. </seg>
<seg id="5">At this time, in Cairo, and it is hoped that the Gaza to get permission to will be. </seg>
<seg id="6">He said: details, I first Gaza to only 2 days for a visa was and after in my insist on Pakistani authorities have my help and one month of stalls, but this on condition that only one time, I will single Gaza. </seg>
<seg id="7">He said that these with his son and daughters, are in the Gaza Strip and they want to the relief work. </seg>
<seg id="8">In some money, to come. </seg>
<seg id="9">Egypt of the Red Cross, a check of one lakh dollars and 22 thousand dollars so that they are also given cash in the Gaza Strip send relief goods. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The cabinet ministers, yesterday in four more </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Four new federal ministers in two Muttahida Qaumi Movement and two Jamiat - e - Ulema - e - Islam Fazal ur Rehman, the members of the group. </seg>
<seg id="3">New ministers from the President of Asif Ali Zardari, administered the oath. </seg>
<seg id="4">Swearing - in ceremony in Prime Minister Yousuf Raza, the federal cabinet members of the present </seg>
<seg id="5">New ministers of the four inclusion in the federal cabinet minister, with the federal minister of state and secretaries of the total number. </seg>
<seg id="6">The MQM in two ministers and Farooq Sattar, Babar Ghauri and Jamiat - e - Ulema - e - Islam Fazal ur Rehman Group of Prime and Maulana Atta Ur Rehman. </seg>
<seg id="7">His ministers departments have been announced. </seg>
<seg id="8">Farooq Sattar convener of the MQM, while Babar Ghauri, Senator of MQM and the period of 22 March. </seg>
<seg id="9">Prime Azad was elected as Senator and he is the most Amir Senator. </seg>
<seg id="10">Maulana Atta Ur Rehman, member of the National Assembly, Maulana Fazal ur Rehman, and younger brother. </seg>
<seg id="11">It should be remembered that holding high posts secretaries of four members of the National Assembly, are not. </seg>
<seg id="12">It should be remembered that three two thousand 2 November 22 new ministers in the cabinet ministers of state and 22 were included, the cabinet that was being of MQM members will also be included in the distribution of ministries However, due to differences MQM not. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">In Balochistan, the pipeline given up </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the police, this 22 - inch pipe line, Qatar, which is Pirkoh has in various fields of Sui gas filtration plant, the is unknown persons and the early morning blew up. </seg>
<seg id="3">Apart from this, Sui last days in number three to completely blast destruction and Dera Allah Yar, near a gas pipeline has been sent to the loss. </seg>
<seg id="4">These explosions the responsibility of the banned organization Baloch of the army spokesman Baloch has to accept. </seg>
<seg id="5">Two years in Balochistan nine thousand break incidents of violence in has increased. </seg>
<seg id="6">This month till now, dozens of Gas pipe lines, making and rail cars and Punjab province, people belonging to the increase in attacks on. </seg>
<seg id="7">Balochistan Chief Minister Nawab Aslam although these incidents, has expressed concern over the police and secret agencies, information transfer Orders issued to these incidents, but now the prevention of could not be possible. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">222 billion dollars of economic rehabilitation package Manzoor </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The President of this project in favor of any party belonging to any member has not vote. </seg>
<seg id="3">Members of said that this plan, economic, is very expensive and the world will not be. </seg>
<seg id="4">The representatives in this package in favor of two hundred while a four votes in its favour. </seg>
<seg id="5">Economic rehabilitation of this project next week to be presented in the Senate, where the Democratic Party little majority. </seg>
<seg id="6">Are feared that party severe opposition from because of the Senate approved by the will not be easy. </seg>
<seg id="7">The House of Representatives in the economic rehabilitation plan after approval of members has said that the political differences this important project in the path of this. </seg>
<seg id="8">The President said that this plan, in which he expressed hope that the next month, law to the situation in the country will take a equipment to create propitious environment in would prove helpful in which the US will promote trade in Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="9">Under this plan, common men and traders community for two hundred seventy five billion dollars in the limit of loans and five hundred 22 billion roads, bridges, 22 thousand schools stage unemployment, and new capability of research for will be. </seg>
<seg id="10">In Washington, the BBC correspondent Richard has said that the political differences to moral, a new political culture, but was determined to economic discussion on this package has once again bitterness in political basis. </seg>
<seg id="11">In the Congress party members of the proposed bill government money can worsen and said that the new job by in creating will not get any help. </seg>
<seg id="12">He has his party by the proposed bill stressed on the extended in which the attention. </seg>
<seg id="13">He said his package of less than in the investment of employment, more from can be created. </seg>
<seg id="14">He said that the construction of the project advertisement taxes extended to immediately employment certainlywon can create more </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Israeli Prime Minister in the bitterness, President </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Rajub Tayyab has nearly Israeli, the President said that many people in the Gaza strip of blood shed Sikh has been and this may sorry that people on behalf of the Israeli army operation on the justification of the word can also rang. </seg>
<seg id="3">Mr. said: I, it seems that you may feel guilty for their economies words are using and he also raise voice to the people, but you have killed in these children, and I am the beach near who were killed. </seg>
<seg id="4">Perez has said that Gaza of Israel is not Hamas, which has established a dangerous dictator. </seg>
<seg id="5">One from a BBC correspondent says that the World Economic Forum in the first ever in the scene. </seg>
<seg id="6">However, after in Erdgan made He said that the President of respect and he also due to which they not yell on some but they were saying he was away from the true. </seg>
<seg id="7">Turkey them from the area in Muslim countries, which is diplomatic relations with Israel, but the last few years in tension. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The attack, in Pakistan not plan, </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Indian TV channel, N. D., while talking to Wajid, Shams - ul - Hasan said that the Pakistani Mumbai attacks of the investigation report will be issued soon. </seg>
<seg id="3">Last November in Mumbai, the attacks in a more than 22, 222 people were killed. </seg>
<seg id="4">India has said that the responsibility of the attacks on - extremist organization. </seg>
<seg id="5">India has also said that the Mumbai attacks in Pakistan, state, elements were involved. </seg>
<seg id="6">Mumbai attacks after the relations between the two countries are affected. </seg>
<seg id="7">High Wajid, Shams - ul - Hasan Pakistani investigation from the first statement that the that of the investigation report in. </seg>
<seg id="8">Wajid, Shams - ul - Hasan said: car their investigation, as far as a result, arrived on the use of the land of Pakistan is not. </seg>
<seg id="9">A place, Britain, and it is also not. </seg>
<seg id="10">The two (Pakistan) and Britain were concerned about me. </seg>
<seg id="11">India, and the international community has Mumbai attacks against responsible for action is enough pressure on Pakistan made Pakistan has said that this attacks in Mumbai, allegedly involved in action against groups of dozens of people in to custody. </seg>
<seg id="12">Wajid, Shams - ul - Hasan said: by this, we are not try. </seg>
<seg id="13">We believe in to action on the facts. </seg>
<seg id="14">Our investigation Manzoor income to the world. </seg>
<seg id="15">We (Investigation) to satisfy the India will try to. </seg>
<seg id="16">He said Pakistani the delay in the investigation of the Defense said that this kind of material to collect, and this bitterly criticized Iran to time. </seg>
<seg id="17">High Wajid, Shams - ul - Hasan said that India its to in 22 days. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Also, the leader of the black elected </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Republican Party in the elections, the sixth in Michael has won the one who votes in votes. </seg>
<seg id="3">In the party chairman in the elections for the candidate for the votes while former chairman, in the second stage, from the competition. </seg>
<seg id="4">Reporters said that the Republican Party, the chairman of the candidate for the of five stood were in the most moderate leader accepted. </seg>
<seg id="5">The victory after Michael in his address said we their friends and opponents with a to say that you are being with our but the people in this country created away from We will want to be ready Michael my land is concerned, from where he Deputy governor. </seg>
<seg id="6">Two thousand six in time when he was known for one seat of the Senate standing in the elections. </seg>
<seg id="7">But in the election of Senate lost after a political party of the Chairman of the Committee on. </seg>
<seg id="8">Now, the chairman of the party elected after the Republican Party of the country - wide campaign the efforts of the head of his in - will be. </seg>
<seg id="9">He said the election on this promise that he raised a new party will and conservative Parast supporters from the party, when for new technical will use. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">And in the presence of Indian claim </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Nizamat of Poonch militants in the present of information. </seg>
<seg id="3">According to the government counterpart on receiving secret information, the army and police has surrounded the area and security started. </seg>
<seg id="4">During this clash started in which four militants, two soldiers and one police officers were killed. </seg>
<seg id="5">Clashes counterpart, according to the information received till the last were ongoing and in the area and associated with the militants have to face more Bharatiya for the army sent there. </seg>
<seg id="6">During this mixed on behalf of the government, the Chief Minister nominated Omar Abdullah and his party, national conference on behalf of the leader of the assembly to us about the formal. </seg>
<seg id="7">National Conference of the Congress party has also Governor Omar Abdullah with the support of the. </seg>
<seg id="8">Omar Abdullah yesterday, the Chief Minister of State of oath as will be assured. </seg>
<seg id="9">It should be remembered that the recent elections state in the national conference, 22 members of the assembly seats in hit by a largest party is it should be remembered that the separation of the 2222 elections. </seg>
<seg id="10">Congress, which 22 seats, national conference with coalition government to agree to. </seg>
<seg id="11">Today Srinagar on the arrival of the party has Omar Abdullah of more with. </seg>
<seg id="12">On this occasion Omar Abdullah has said that the Indian government and separatists of talks between the possible to play their role in India will However, holding elections and the new government power to it will not be possible. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Peace in the Middle East for the role of the European Union </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the government, the war in the Middle East to stop the reconciliation efforts in the European Union is a decisive role. </seg>
<seg id="3">According to the viewpoint, or the efforts of the delegation in this work are hand. </seg>
<seg id="4">The European Commission spokesman has said that he is commendable to the European Union, through which the message of joint war in the parties to get help. </seg>
<seg id="5">Official statement, as far as well. </seg>
<seg id="6">In fact, but the European Union scene found a picture of earthquake's sorrowful. </seg>
<seg id="7">The President of the Union on the role of check they already. </seg>
<seg id="8">From the internal respect him helpless. </seg>
<seg id="9">On the other hand, the French President attitude, as he is still it is the responsibility of the European Union, presided over by. </seg>
<seg id="10">France, although their presidential term of six months. </seg>
<seg id="11">Role and they want to also, but he is not allowed. </seg>
<seg id="12">The ridiculous situation of the French Foreign Minister. </seg>
<seg id="13">They are included in this delegation led by the foreign minister of check they are. </seg>
<seg id="14">This was that this war in the Middle East Both foreign ministers are different statements. </seg>
<seg id="15">Are saying that Israel should have the right of its defense when near that this war in Defense. Meanwhile, said a special representative to the Middle East has to the European Union based on the same viewpoint harmony, it does not diplomatic at it could not win </seg>
<seg id="16">This is a proof of Israel, which is the behaviour of Europe reconciliation efforts to no importance. </seg>
<seg id="17">The European Union for some of the golden opportunity to the United States George W. Bush, due to the policies of in the Middle East has failed. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Financial crisis: billionaires German industrialist commit suicide of </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">South Germany in the area of living behind him a very big business, group. </seg>
<seg id="3">But some time ago, the German to common citizens in these more were not know. </seg>
<seg id="4">When their industrial group loans 30 near the banks of talks with for many weeks, and they have to DOC they also become a topic of the future of the group also dark. </seg>
<seg id="5">The group, the German Kar institutions after the purchase of shares of financial crisis due to the loss of several hundred million Euro had to. </seg>
<seg id="6">This group has once again financial institutions must take one billion and 700 million Euro between new loans refused, under extreme pressure. </seg>
<seg id="7">Some time ago, the bank group on an emergency basis ready to give loans were, but one small industrialists, on the place of industrial group that these were the annual income was 2. 30 billion euros, investment irresponsible power could not bear the deprivation. </seg>
<seg id="8">After the death of his father when his family over the business letters on it very soon development. </seg>
<seg id="9">He has kept the name of the company which of Germany extremely successful and large medicine manufacturers company. </seg>
<seg id="10">Some time to the drug agencies of business and five worth 2 billion euros between and it was still 1 -8 billion euros income is a form of after the success of the group has many big institutions to purchase, in which the construction equipment to the cement from the vehicles to named company. </seg>
<seg id="11">Group in the world, the number of employees of one lakh and this is in the form of a medicine manufacturers company has special importance. </seg>
<seg id="12">His life in many times said it was: we while four generations. </seg>
<seg id="13">Now this institution of my children is in and I hope that this institution is still a few hundred years of my family in. </seg>
<seg id="14">The Banks have committed suicide after the group for worth 400 million Euro interim loans approved, but it is the condition that form, so that this group will be for the financial condition of the long term on the basis of better. </seg>
<seg id="15">Thus the death of the group, after which he will not he never. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Germany in foreign people in the crime rate </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The latest statistics from 2004 to 2007 between foreigners crime rate of 22. </seg>
<seg id="3">2 21. per cent decrease. </seg>
<seg id="4">2 per cent to have. </seg>
<seg id="5">The Minister of the province with According to this is a positive changes. </seg>
<seg id="6">He said, this it be kept German citizenship, it is necessary that the foreigners. </seg>
<seg id="7">Therefore, it is also in statistics should be committing an offence that although the German, but this is the background of foreign. </seg>
<seg id="8">Said that his province from 2010 criminals about the facts and figures acquire the crusading will also. </seg>
<seg id="9">Apart from the province in on the lines thought is being. </seg>
<seg id="10">Belonging to the Interior Affairs, Senator, said: in a scientific when research, people of their choice already have not can but it depends on these statistics about the research after. </seg>
<seg id="11">The provincial office crime prevention of a report by 2222, drew attention in 2006 and has been prepared which was part of the city in the late was here that how many of foreigners in crime is 2. 22 per cent. </seg>
<seg id="12">To that of foreigners here </seg>
<seg id="13">The crime rate in all parts of the province of the crime. </seg>
<seg id="14">On the contrary, Berlin when in 2006 during the youth of crime rate was reviewed, it that the foreign background the rate to 22. </seg>
<seg id="15">2 percent. </seg>
<seg id="16">However, Germany of other political parties, for example, environment of the party of the party of this proposal is against the crime that the facts and figures together, while this information also collected that how the background of the city, the German foreign. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Withdrawal of forces from the Gaza strip as soon as possible to: </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Not insisted has complete withdrawal of forces for a stable and permanent Treaty is essential. </seg>
<seg id="3">Hamas and Israel have a ceasefire on Sunday. </seg>
<seg id="4">The Islamic Militant Organization Hamas for a week ceasefire announced said that within a week of Israeli forces completely from the Gaza Strip and the Gaza strip the end. </seg>
<seg id="5">On the other hand, the leader of the has said that in the war on behalf of Israel to God bless victory. </seg>
<seg id="6">He said that in the war targets in Israel has failed. </seg>
<seg id="7">Prior to this, Egypt in Sharm El - Sheikh, on Sunday, and Arab countries of the European leaders of a meeting was held in with Israel immediate withdrawal of forces from was demanded. </seg>
<seg id="8">It was decided in the meeting that as soon as soon as possible, for the relief of an international conference will be held. </seg>
<seg id="9">In the meeting, the German Angela Merkel also attended the meeting. </seg>
<seg id="10">Hamas Israel and three weeks, the war in at least 22 and 22, 222 Palestinians yesterday, including 22 Israeli soldiers were killed. </seg>
<seg id="11">On the other hand, the Palestinian President, Abbas has in Palestinian areas has stressed on the government to make. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The name of Germany video message of Al - Qaida </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">22 minutes of this video cycle in a black person, the color of the mouth, wearing, and German gun in a message to the government. </seg>
<seg id="3">The person himself with the name of Abu Talha was introduced is conducting a German in and language. </seg>
<seg id="4">This video message of Arabic all are also present. </seg>
<seg id="5">The case of the series Abu Hamza. Regardless of price discount on a video is, and the date of a in October 2222. </seg>
<seg id="6">In his message, the German government in Afghanistan, it has been said that such a large number of Army deployed in the country and the expressed is that it will not be attack, it cannot, and it is not pin? </seg>
<seg id="7">To tell the person, although on the threat of Germany indirect attacks. </seg>
<seg id="8">At this time, the allied forces in Afghanistan, NATO German included in the number of troops almost three thousand. </seg>
<seg id="9">Last year, a further German parliament in October 2222 troops to Afghanistan, has also approval of the law. </seg>
<seg id="10">Germany to Abu Hamza. Regardless of the first to meet this is a message. </seg>
<seg id="11">Terrorism related affairs to the expert, the message to say:, in Kabul recently, the German embassy outside the suicide attack is proof of the fact that we in serious condition. </seg>
<seg id="12">The last few years on the Internet messages from North video is issued before and after the attack. </seg>
<seg id="13">On Saturday, the German embassy in Kabul outside of the suicide attack the responsibility of the Taliban military organization. </seg>
<seg id="14">Most of the German newspapers and this attack on the message from the north. </seg>
<seg id="15">, Germany, they are targeting. </seg>
<seg id="16">Germany, materialist Muslim of Afghan policy in negative. </seg>
<seg id="17">He German government not only in the Middle East Afghanistan but also to adopt the policy of biased. </seg>
<seg id="18">And so Germany more its target are. </seg>
<seg id="19">Meanwhile, the German government has said that this video of publicly before the German secret agencies about this knowledge. </seg>
<seg id="20">The Federal Anti - German crime of the message of video is busy in. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The US president ship. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In this context, the American people, on the one hand, entire is different from the expectations numerous. </seg>
<seg id="3">Now, President of the United States congratulations from all over the messages of are being received from these subject expectations are also come. </seg>
<seg id="4">In this regard, the German Chancellor has new US president expressed confidence. </seg>
<seg id="5">I believe that the Federal Republic Germany and the United States of our friendship between the United States and on the basis of problems we can resolve the. </seg>
<seg id="6">The Russian prime minister Vladimir Putin has said that a serious and open the owner of be and on this is a good thing. </seg>
<seg id="7">Thus, the former U. S. President George W. Bush policies facing criticism. </seg>
<seg id="8">However, their the administration of China on international level more constructive role to the movement to be appreciated while the new US President about China has said that he between the two countries strong military relations for will have to work. </seg>
<seg id="9">The German active in the Chinese city expert political says: </seg>
<seg id="10">In this context, I am confident that the coming weeks and in the economic and his team tremendous pressure and will Beijing government for a Chinese currency market and flexibility to exchange from rate to forced will. </seg>
<seg id="11">Former US administration has also relations with India to further. </seg>
<seg id="12">These relations, where can take this in New Delhi in the US studies Professor Raj say: we are now strategic partnership in near have overnight, but no one can not change. </seg>
<seg id="13">Pope has also in the name of message in an atmosphere of peace and cooperation to promote has stressed on the. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The provincial elections in Iraq </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The year 2005 after this war, the country in the first elections are important. </seg>
<seg id="3">The provincial elections in 440 for more than 14, 400 have landed in. </seg>
<seg id="4">During the elections of the law and order situation to maintain the 222222 police and army deployed in Iraq. </seg>
<seg id="5">In view of this danger that such important explosion or a day and a terrorist attack would not all of Iraq, only a day before the borders have been sealed on Friday. </seg>
<seg id="6">In addition, the index closed airport and imposed a ban on public transport. </seg>
<seg id="7">According to information, transport ban on due to the traffic on the roads in the facts and Iraqi children play football on the roads. </seg>
<seg id="8">During the recent elections of Iraqi security situation on the one hand, it will be that the year 2011 the US forces in Iraq after returning from the local agencies the reigns of the country will be or not, on the other hand, the political analyst it a experience of Punjab, which are assessed from that the Iraqi people through democratic process in the country to change how far. </seg>
<seg id="9">The United Nations in the help of provincial elections are being held and eight hundred international observers electoral process. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Today, the whole day in Iran, the Day of Hazrat Imam Hussain () of great sacrifice in the memory of respect from was celebrated </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency, according to the report of the capital of Iran Tehran all small and big cities, including Syed Hadhrat Imam Hussain (in) to a large with respect and was celebrated on this occasion, the meetings and Majalis Aza in a large number of Mukarram Nabi (and) to different (at the martyrdom of his condolences to meet the son of Iran today Mukarram Nabi (and) Hadhrat Imam Hussain (in Karbala) in the field of the great sacrifice in the memory of and is mourning Hadhrat Imam Hussain (in Karbala) in the field of the example of the memories of and large - scale and rallies in the crowd. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Gaza Israeli soldiers from the morale of Palestinian // mujahideen, for example, should </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency, the Urdu service According to the Gaza Strip in favor of the Battle of the day, Israel by the civilian population bombing continued on Gaza, Israel, air and water attacks in the ground so far 880 people were killed and 3700 Palestinians have been injured </seg>
<seg id="3">In the martyrs at 275 innocent are also who betraying and Arab leaders of the international human rights organizations, the so - called on the death of all in. </seg>
<seg id="4">Gaza today, shrouds insecure. has to retreat from the Israeli troops on the evidence and faith and the power of a support and steadfastness of Jewish, and the enemy to are Hayat </seg>
<seg id="5">If the Egyptian President Hossni of betraying are not Hamas Sunni and Bahadur Mujahid when Israel to defeat away from four have been but the Israeli siege with Egypt has also Muslim siege of Palestinians have Arab in the history of Pakistan, which is most tragic incident </seg>
<seg id="6">On the other hand, Saudi Arabia and governments of Urdan Israel to help has caused political, economic, and the Gaza Strip with treachery against the unarmed Muslims and with Israelis are giving </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The United States with Iran new strategy will week </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency, according to the report, the United States has elected president, ABC news channel, talking to Iran, he said that on the issue of the modern and adopt a new strategy. </seg>
<seg id="3">Iran has said that the U. S. government for a very big challenges. </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the Islamic Organization Hamas and support Iran and the Iranian nuclear program is concerned over. </seg>
<seg id="5">But he Iran in the present policy of the US President Bush will not and relations with Iran in different policy will adopt. </seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the real objective to completely clear while respect and mutual talks on the desire of will urge. </seg>
<seg id="7">In the past also have said that the talks with Iran in any conditions attached to not be. </seg>
<seg id="8">During the interview he expressed hope that the administration of Iran on this new strategy, fast process. </seg>
<seg id="9">The Middle East of crisis has said that in this regard, a special team are </seg>
<seg id="10">East, in the establishment of peace efforts for 20 January, work. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">American President, George Bush, the US President Bush incompetent and the last press in its mistakes has admitted </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency Associated Press from is that the US President George W. Bush said during a press conference in the last several mistakes, and their crime has admitted. </seg>
<seg id="3">The White House, while addressing a press conference in President Bush has said that the newly elected President of goodwill of feelings are, however, to the United States that it would be possible to stop the attack on. </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the mission in Iraq and social security reforms the completion of his mistakes. </seg>
<seg id="5">President Bush has said that he has 222 anything for the protection of the United States. </seg>
<seg id="6">Israeli aggression in the Gaza Strip with reference to a number of questions in response to President Bush has said that Israel should have the right of its defense of Hamas to defend himself is not right hand and Hamas on Israel and the United States should not out of the world as oppressor instead of the oppressed of strangled should </seg>
<seg id="7">The United States of unfit and the President said that Hamas weapons should also not to the United States, Israel, and the most of the world and deadly devastating weapons is providing Palestinians massacre of Israel in the US weapons from Israel is Bush has also praised the Arabs Nawaz and a friend of Israel. </seg>
<seg id="8">Bush and Abu Ghraib prison in some crimes expressed shame. </seg>
<seg id="9">Analysts say Bush on war crimes case should be and organizations, which will work to their humanity on a big Ahsan. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Iranian President Ahmadi Nejad President Arab countries of silence by leaders expressed their is </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency has said that according to the report, the President of Iran, Dr. Nejad had on Gaza, Israeli aggression and the oppression of the leaders of silence on criticism forty Balochistan. expressed sorrow over. </seg>
<seg id="3">He Nejad Arab countries and their summits on Gaza, Israel brutal on surprised expressing Israel has said that the people of Palestine is Palestinian children, women, and the common citizens barbaric is targeting and Arab even has also not issued a statement. </seg>
<seg id="4">President Ahmadi Nejad said that Israel against all the Arab countries unite Gaza and the oppressed Muslims of Israel and the cruelty of miscreants from. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Ahmadi Nejad of Saudi Arabia Badshah, in the Gaza strip by Israel to human genocide in his should be </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency, according to the report of the President Mahmood Ahmadi Nejad had ruler of Saudi Arabia, Abdullah the name of the country in his message, has said that the Muslims of the Emperor of Saudi Arabia in the Gaza Strip on human genocide in the Gaza Strip and innocent children and women massacre of while pushing the silence of Islam encourage has caused </seg>
<seg id="3">President Ahmadi Nejad had said in the Gaza Strip on that you in the right position and supported clear order enemies differences in front of the efforts of the failed to be </seg>
<seg id="4">President Ahmadi Nejad said in his message that you know that 19 days with Israel in the Gaza Strip on human situation is innocent and massacre of innocent children is their houses, schools, hospitals and bombing on Gaza is in the Zionist government badly murder is in these circumstances, you like leaders to silence by Israel boosting </seg>
<seg id="5">President Ahmadi Nejad had said that the country Abdullah and non Islamic countries like Israel against solid steps, you are, from these countries are with the expectations of the </seg>
<seg id="6">President Ahmadi Nejad said that in the Gaza Strip success of the Palestinians had. </seg>
<seg id="7">And the oppressed victory will be described as oppressor and on the basis of Allah. </seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Usama Bin Ladin in Palestine resistance will teach will continue </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency, according to a report of Usama Bin Ladin in Lebanon Hamas representatives of the French News Agency, talking to, has said that Israel by one - sided comprehensive planning international war against the efforts of the cease - fire when he is said to be present in the Gaza Strip will by a ceasefire, will be meaningless </seg>
<seg id="3">He said that by a ceasefire defeat to avoid an attempt to Israel has said that if Israel stable peace that it wants to end the conditions of Hamas with the US authorities will have to accept </seg>
<seg id="4">Hamas leader in Lebanon has made it clear that the Gaza Strip in the rest of the Israeli army, if Israel has one - sided the cease - fire, against resistance will continue. </seg>
<seg id="5">Beirut in the Gaza Strip with unity, while addressing the conference, Usama has with European countries 2222. severing ties with Israel. </seg>
<seg id="6">Hamas leader said that the martyrs and increasing the number of our objectives and courage and would. </seg>
<seg id="7">He said that the Palestinian people on the enemy in the war against government a resistance. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Pakistan in the tribal region of North Waziristan, the Taliban six people to murder is </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Reuters, the Mehr News Agency has reported that the tribal region of North Waziristan in two Afghan citizen to the Taliban and four Pakistanis accused of spying in murder them. </seg>
<seg id="3">According to reports, the local people, on Tuesday morning, Tehsil area of Tehsil Chowk in four bodies are and killed. </seg>
<seg id="4">President place while two bodies are Mrannshah received a market in the market was into. </seg>
<seg id="5">Dead bodies have written in Urdu lines have also in which has claimed that spying. </seg>
<seg id="6">Two weeks ago, the President of the North Waziristan also Mrannshah place in two Afghan nationals to accused of spying was murdered in. </seg>
<seg id="7">In the last 22 days to the United States for fifteen people were killed on charges of spying. </seg>
<seg id="8">It should be remembered that in North and South Waziristan during six years, more than 222 people accused of spying had been killed in Taliban on this kind of murder cases are involved. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The time of notorious jail to stop the order of signed </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Sources, the Mehr News Agency has reported that the US President today the time to stop the notorious jail signed will </seg>
<seg id="3">New US President Hussain his election campaign of the promises level as well. </seg>
<seg id="4">In this connection, the President has American army from Iraq for the return of the plan, while today, the US president of time to stop the notorious jail signed will. </seg>
<seg id="5">It is expected that the president on this order to today under which one year imprisonment of civil within will be closed. </seg>
<seg id="6">In addition to this, the White House with suspected terrorists on how to review and prisoners from the ban on the orders of the words also is likely to be. </seg>
<seg id="7">The President has his on the first day of the election of work to fulfill the promises and started the process of his government and the steps to ensure transparency. </seg>
<seg id="8">Analysts say that the US President has at the international level, the United States to save the credibility of the efforts of the started, but they get success in this is very difficult because of the United States, Israel, until the government on the support of our till this is a good work not expect if its reputation in the world, the United States wants to save from Israel, it should be deprived of this and should not participate in the crime. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Tony Blair Islamic Organization Hamas talks in stressed upon the need to </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency times of the British newspaper reported that the British Prime Minister Tony Blair has in the Middle East peace process of Hamas to include, has emphasized the need. </seg>
<seg id="3">According to newspaper Tony Blair has said that it is important that a way should be searched for, through which Hamas to the Middle East peace process will be brought to the Bush on Mahmood Abbas to talk with Hamas and ignored to severe criticism of it should be clarified that the Western countries have Hamas Nizami and power and now it has been included in the talks, while talking to the earlier he to a terrorist organization Hamas diminished from was a terrorist organization, which is its defense of your home to others of free from the struggle of which is the house of the country and Israel, as the government has occupied sixty years possession from forward. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Karachi The traders of Balochistan in the murder of a complete strike in Quetta, </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Four traders of Balochistan in Karachi on Thursday, against the death of Quetta and some other areas in a complete strike. </seg>
<seg id="3">During this, all the business centers remained closed when that traffic also was less than usual. </seg>
<seg id="4">Protest strike the appeal of the Association of Balochistan, Pakhtun Khwa Milly Awam Party, and Jamiat - e - Ulema - e - Islam, was, alleged that these traders Karachi police alleged firing at the time when they were killed in a car on Tariq road, their vehicles residential showroom. </seg>
<seg id="5">President Abdul delayed Kakar demanded that situated involved in the police have arrested the action will be taken against them. </seg>
<seg id="6">However, this incident in Karachi on the stand of the police. </seg>
<seg id="7">Killed four traders of the Frontier city from Chaman. </seg>
<seg id="8">On the occasion of the strike on behalf of the government on a large scale of security arrangements were all over the city and important places of the police was appointed. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Israeli attack in of Hamas senior commander killed </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Israel a attack in a senior commander of Hamas, was killed. </seg>
<seg id="3">The Gaza Strip in Israel, one week from Hamas attacks in the second important personality. </seg>
<seg id="4">Hamas officials said that Abu on Saturday in east of Gaza City situated in partially were killed. </seg>
<seg id="5">Israel and a Hamas attack on Thursday in the confectioner were killed. </seg>
<seg id="6">In Syria living in exile of Hamas leader Khalid Ali to take revenge expressed the determination and the Gaza Strip on the ground attack against Israel, has warned the. </seg>
<seg id="7">The Gaza Strip on the border of Israel thousands of military and tanks and they are military orders are waiting for. </seg>
<seg id="8">The United States has appealed to the cease - fire, but said that Gaza is on its army to or not decision to depend on Israel. </seg>
<seg id="9">US President George Bush says public radio said in his speech on the weekly Hamas violence on for the objectionable material. However, accused of Israel and after rocket attacks on her as terrorism. </seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the United States is working for the cease - fire, but will make everything single will not be accepted. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">In North Waziristan, three bodies recovered </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Pakistani security officials said that in the North Waziristan tribal region three men dead bodies were found. </seg>
<seg id="3">Suspected Taliban that they were given to death. </seg>
<seg id="4">The bodies of North Waziristan central city near Miran Shah and his with such were in his men for the United States was accused of spying. </seg>
<seg id="5">The officials have said that in a dead body of a local probably, which is the last week. </seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the remaining two bodies ridden with bullets Afghan nationals. </seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">U. S. Vice President elected Joseph reached Pakistan </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Foreign Minister elected U. S. Vice President welcomed </seg>
<seg id="3">The United States of elected Vice President Joseph on a tour of Pakistan, along with her delegation on Friday, has arrived in Islamabad. </seg>
<seg id="4">The Foreign Minister, Shah Mahmood Qureshi and high officials of the US Embassy has welcomed him. </seg>
<seg id="5">The US in this tour. </seg>
<seg id="6">The US embassy officer of press them, the Voice of America told that the newly elected President during his tour, the Pakistani leadership from various regional issues will hold talks on However, he further details. </seg>
<seg id="7">According to the sources of the foreign office Joseph, high government officials of Army Chief Gen Pervez Ashfaq Kayani will also meet. </seg>
<seg id="8">It is expected that these meetings in important bilateral and international affairs in the war against terror cases related to exchange views on. </seg>
<seg id="9">Joseph Hilal - e - Pakistan, who was the </seg>
<seg id="10">Islamabad after reaching Joseph, President of Asif Ali Zardari, met. </seg>
<seg id="11">In the meeting, the President of Pakistan and the United States have close relations between them to set up on the role of the honor of importance. The Hilal - e - Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="12">It should be remembered that Joseph last year, the US Senate Foreign Relations Committee Chairman Senator as with a bill was introduced in Pakistan for the next five years, the United States during a non - military aid in three times and 7. 5 billion dollars to recommend. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Former President Pervez Musharraf, in uniform, has played an important role, Prime Minister Gilani </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Yousuf Raza, who (file photographs and </seg>
<seg id="3">The Prime Minister Yousuf Raza, has said that the United States, the elected representatives of the Vice President Pervez Musharraf, the former president of the uniform, the office of army chief, has played an important role in force in democracy and also for the help of a </seg>
<seg id="4">. Yousuf Raza made the statement Karachi Ship Yard must talking to journalists on the. </seg>
<seg id="5">They said that the Pakistan - or the leader of Pakistan and they are as the US Senate Foreign the Chairman of the Committee of Pakistan to 15 billion dollars of aid to the bill. </seg>
<seg id="6">Pakistani in American spy fighter planes from the missile attacks have once again condemned the Prime Minister of Pakistan said such attacks allowed to run afoul of their us with the government is not any kind of agreement, and if the sovereignty of Pakistan is an issue for the national attacks in such as allowed can not </seg>
<seg id="7">They also give this expressed that the United States in the new government after change in the policy of the United States. </seg>
<seg id="8">(file photographs) </seg>
<seg id="9">Yousuf Raza, said that the government has a major success terrorists from the tribal from However, followed by the fighter planes to the missile attack government efforts to be harmful and terrorists are tribes. </seg>
<seg id="10">They said that the international community agree with the stand of Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="11">The Prime Minister further said that if any reliable evidence, Pakistan should be given forces themselves in their areas will action. </seg>
<seg id="12">The Prime Minister in Mumbai attacks on his stand Yousuf Raza Gilani has said that if India should provide the evidence, on the basis of investigation and will be proof of their involvement of the country against, according to the law, action will be taken. </seg>
<seg id="13">The visit of the country Rehman, Britain and charged of Altaf Hussain, the leader of MQM with in response to a question about the Prime Minister said in the National to their country from London. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Quetta, DSP including four police officers were killed </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">File photographer </seg>
<seg id="3">A highway, Quetta important road on firing by unknown persons with a DSP, Deputy police, including four police officials. </seg>
<seg id="4">On Wednesday morning, a jeep in two DSP, a sub - inspector and two police constables training center of were road near degree college on a motorcycle rider, unknown attackers police jeep started firing on which the sub - inspector Mehdi and Constable Sibghatullah, were killed on the spot when that a DSP Hasan Ali died after reaching the hospital. </seg>
<seg id="5">Hospital sources say that severely injured other DSP Ghulam fleet condition is also and may head and cervical in bullet. </seg>
<seg id="6">After this situated in the area and the police have taken the responsibility of the incident has accepted. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The United States in a and Indian engineer of the death of software </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The United States in Andhra Pradesh belonging to a and software to by unknown assailants shot dead. </seg>
<seg id="3">The 26 - year - old arrested in two days before the state in the attack killing. Unknown gunmen shot dead in hospital during the medical aid has died. </seg>
<seg id="4">He was an employee of the computers and in the United States jet in. </seg>
<seg id="5">In the past year, Andhra Pradesh, belonging to the United States in seven student at the hands of social elements have been killed. </seg>
<seg id="6">The United States in Higher Education and Employment for the production of the students of deaths in the province, thousands of families in has is of children have lived in the United States. </seg>
<seg id="7">It should be noted that a better future higher education and for in Andhra Pradesh, the United States preferred. </seg>
<seg id="8">The American Consulate in Chennai, according to facts and figures from South India US visas for every year one lakh for are in which more than 40 per cent to Andhra Pradesh. </seg>
<seg id="9">During the state government has onto the dead body of the deceased, Hyderabad to bring the efforts of the started. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The United States attacks against anti - Bush says public are heading: </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">President George Bush says public last week and in his speech that the United States has stressed on the enemy attacks against heading. </seg>
<seg id="3">Mr. Bush says public said that the Americans are still for the terrorists and the attack, there is a possibility of and He warned that the enemies of the country with patience and they are waiting to and again. </seg>
<seg id="4">The President said going to the United States never must also their safety state should be. </seg>
<seg id="5">President Bush says public next president Barak also for the best friend on Tuesday, who expressed his post. </seg>
<seg id="6">The newly elected President Barak Democratic Party has, on behalf of the radio on Saturday in his speech swearing - in ceremony of light on the historical importance. </seg>
<seg id="7">He said that it is a tradition ceremony of other leader, a leader of the transfer of power in the peace of the greatness of us with a deep link. </seg>
<seg id="8">Mr. has reminded that all over the world in many people that they can also not the leader of the new for tussle with or without powers will be deprived of. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Raiwind in Sharif brothers and the Federal Interior Minister of Affairs, political and security exchanging ideas on </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The opposition biggest, and the ruling party in Punjab, the head of the Pakistan Muslim League - Nawaz Sharif, and the Federal Interior Minister of the country on Sunday between Raiwind in the meeting, the Chief Minister of Punjab in "Shahbaz Sharif were also present. </seg>
<seg id="3">According to the local media country possibly of Pakistan Peoples Party leadership of any important message had. </seg>
<seg id="4">However, after the meeting, speaking to journalists, with reference to this country has did not give any details and only said that political affairs, with reference to translate the consensus of the politics of the Mumbai attacks, and after the situation on the n the leadership of the briefing. </seg>
<seg id="5">In their words:, so far as action is about the information provided. </seg>
<seg id="6">To make sure that a major action in Punjab and the Punjab government and is still in the team formed in writing the Punjab government also need help. </seg>
<seg id="7">Malik said that every day, told the media, but the n the leadership of the exchange of daily. Meanwhile, the spokesman of the Pakistan Muslim League (N), Pervez Rashid has to in connection with political affairs, and some They said that Mr. Malik, so the sessions was saying. </seg>
<seg id="8">It should be noted that the leadership of Pakistan Muslim League (N) from the interior of time is that when warm summer politics in the province of Punjab government opposition L. P. M Q belonging to the Governor of Punjab, more than 20 administrators have a press conference with Salman P. M. the administrators, on behalf of the steps taken for the criticism of the provincial government, rejecting the Pakistan Peoples Party belonging to the Governor of Punjab in this matter on inclusion also objection. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The speech of Pakistan is heartening for: President Zardari </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Pakistani President, Asif Ali Zardari, the United States, the new president of the opening address welcome, has said that the acceptance of the Muslim world with mutual interests and respect of the talks and the people of Pakistan for is a welcome announcement. </seg>
<seg id="3">On Wednesday, in a statement issued by the They said that the US by the president and chief of determined all over the world, the people of a a better future. </seg>
<seg id="4">According to the statement, the President said that the United States Zardari on the international community with there is no doubt in the 22st century peace, prosperity and development of finding new of important responsibility. </seg>
<seg id="5">It should be noted that the President said Tuesday his oath taking an oath after the opening address, said that the United States was in the Muslim world with new, which is mutual interests and mutual respect.. </seg>
<seg id="6">They poor countries of people assured them that the United States was working with so that there social development and poverty reduction in. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The President of Pakistan and Afghanistan has taken appointed as a special representative to </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Richard Hall, The UN for former hall to Pakistan and Afghanistan for special Jang has been appointed as. </seg>
<seg id="3">The Bosnian Hall in peace agreement to important role. </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the hall, Afghanistan, and Pakistan on affairs of the consultation of the President. </seg>
<seg id="5">He said that it is not easy to work. </seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the two countries in the history of a different. </seg>
<seg id="7">The Middle East for George was elected to the Arab peace talks in Israel will try to. </seg>
<seg id="8">Former Senator and he has to maintain peace in Northern Ireland role in. </seg>
<seg id="9">Today, the State Department while talking in the Middle East has said that the UN very complex, and is dangerous. </seg>
<seg id="10">But, in spite of this, the United States lasting peace efforts there will not be seen deviating from behind. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Afghanistan: voter registration in danger had </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Afghanistan of the Election Commission has said that he is about the security concern because of South in some areas of the voter registration delay in. </seg>
<seg id="3">In southern Afghanistan near about the presidential election voter for the registration of this week was started her. </seg>
<seg id="4">But the Commission has said that until the security situation better will not be Halmand province, in some areas of the voter themselves not registered. </seg>
<seg id="5">South of the areas in the past year, there has been an increase in the violence, where the Taliban rebels Afghan army troops and international on their attack increased. </seg>
<seg id="6">Meanwhile, the Afghan army troops and International has said that he said on Thursday and the mid night of Afghanistan in several clashes during at least 22. </seg>
<seg id="7">NATO has said that his forces of Pakistan near the border of Eastern province in Khost and ground attacks in 22 militants were killed. </seg>
<seg id="8">Before this, the Afghan defense ministry said that in the province Afghan army has to eight killed and two injured. </seg>
<seg id="9">It is not clear that whoever came Afghan officials of the incident is. </seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The province of the Frontier government has Swat girls in the education of the ban on the demand of rejected </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Officials in the Frontier Province Swat Taliban militants on behalf of the female education to ban on the threat of this rejected is that the law, and both is against Islam. </seg>
<seg id="3">On Sunday, the education minister of Frontier Province, Sardar Hussain Babar further said that the government that such efforts will not succeed. </seg>
<seg id="4">They said that he is trying to that our children in the area of education. </seg>
<seg id="5">In their words: theft, these people hiding schools and children to the girls are. </seg>
<seg id="6">Fear and panic an atmosphere of mentioning, they said that the provincial government, this well indeed wants to made it clear that no power with the land of possible to stop the promotion of education. </seg>
<seg id="7">A day before the leadership of Maulana Fazal hotels Taliban warriors have from 15 of Swat had educational institutions in the girls` education on demanded and threatened that violation institutions will be destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="8">Swat, in spite of military action during the past one - and - a - half years of nearly 150 educational institutions militants explosives by the ruined. </seg>
<seg id="9">Educational institutions to as a result of thousands of the number of girls in the boy and education of have lost their. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">In India Republic Day on the occasion of the strict security arrangements </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">On Monday 22th in India Republic Day is being observed, this occasion every strict security arrangements and thousands of troops deployed in the whole country. </seg>
<seg id="3">On the occasion of the Republic Day in New Delhi, during the military weapons aircraft and other military equipment the exhibition. </seg>
<seg id="4">Officials say that the security arrangements under the anti - aircraft and also and police have been deployed on the routes of keeping a strict eye on the US President on this occasion, India has congratulated the </seg>
<seg id="5">Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh on Saturday, which the heart of the operation was the early recovery of the message of also. </seg>
<seg id="6">Yesterday, the Indian think that the police have arrested two Pakistani suspected militants fighting in the outskirts of the New Delhi after the killing of. </seg>
<seg id="7">According to the police, local officials from both these people AK - 47 rifles, a grenade and recovered documents which are the that both are Pakistani. </seg>
<seg id="8">Police also investigate it is that both of them with his organization of Pakistan banned Lashkar - e - Taiyba from the last year in November, Mumbai was involved in attacks. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Tea: breast cancer effective treatment of </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">A new research in it has been said that three daily cup of tea </seg>
<seg id="3">From drinking women aged 50 years in breast cancer risk of more than one - third. </seg>
<seg id="4">The US State Florida Cancer Research Center in the in it has been said that 50 years of age such women in breast cancer of </seg>
<seg id="5">In 37 per cent reduction is at least three cup of tea. </seg>
<seg id="6">In the research also said that the women of the three large age or more Cup daily from drinking tea in this connection, particularly not benefit. </seg>
<seg id="7">Experts think that this because of tea in the presence of cancer, which is of special against more effective which Therefore, 50 years of age women. </seg>
<seg id="8">State Florida established in the city of cancer center in five more than 22222 women on the research, who has been breast cancer of treatment. </seg>
<seg id="9">Their under the between 20 and 74 years. </seg>
<seg id="10">Experts, the medical records and life style of such women who were safe from breast cancer. </seg>
<seg id="11">Experts to also came to know that a certain types of cancer, tea, has set its and 66 to 66 per cent decrease. </seg>
<seg id="12">Breast cancer patient of the tenth every kind in this. </seg>
<seg id="13">This kind of cancer for more dangerous than in depth because he is usually and this is the time when it has spread. </seg>
<seg id="14">Experts regularly that the number of tea daily from drinking Cup at least three women age in breast cancer may reduce the risk of a </seg>
<seg id="15">He said that a tea daily for their daily routine to include body from cancer against appropriate created. </seg>
<seg id="16">In Britain, about 40 thousand women in the year of breast cancer. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">A war in Afghanistan, the United States faced the biggest challenge: Gates, military </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The US defense secretary Robert Gates, has said that the war in Afghanistan, the United States faced the biggest challenge military. </seg>
<seg id="3">Today Gates, the US representatives, the members of the Senate and Afghanistan and Iraq war on the administration of a briefing about. </seg>
<seg id="4">The Senate Gates, the armed services committee told Jang that the only solution to the problem of Afghanistan but they further said that many areas to make sufficient number of forces are not, "lifted the benefit of the Taliban action. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The decrease in the age of exercise, why? </seg>
<seg id="2">New research </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="3">Exercise in all for good health. </seg>
<seg id="4">It to the heart is strong, cholesterol levels in, weight, is to prevent diabetes and to slow. </seg>
<seg id="5">Unfortunately, many people in up with the reduction in the ability to exercise. </seg>
<seg id="6">Experts say that by exercise our body and mind. However, this affect the age. </seg>
<seg id="7">The American Medical Association that the number of exercise not to health presented many problems. </seg>
<seg id="8">The Mayo clinic of Dr. pay says that the increase in Umar exercise physical and performance of a major cause. </seg>
<seg id="9">Dr. clinic molested her. She taught in medicine. </seg>
<seg id="10">He has a heart diseases, and at the age of exercise of the ability to take a study the leadership of. </seg>
<seg id="11">A team of doctors has heart to review the performance of the voice of high wave reached to use. </seg>
<seg id="12">In which the heart pumps blood to, the rest of the process of studies. </seg>
<seg id="13">Experts have left their attention on the part of the heart pumps blood to Pakistan, which is part of the central. </seg>
<seg id="14">They know that Umar up with heart rest in the process of defects in is. </seg>
<seg id="15">Dr. says that with the heart of rest in the process of further deteriorate are significant and Umar with increase in exercise to the impact on the increasing. </seg>
<seg id="16">Dr. were included in the cane this study. </seg>
<seg id="17">They say that we see that it is compulsory of united, and explain that exercise bad performance of the hearts of the rest of the process of how much with. </seg>
<seg id="18">Sometimes blood pressure defects in the process of heart diseases can. </seg>
<seg id="19">If the patient and Dr. the heart of should work together in spite of age, he also of exercise can get benefits. </seg>
<seg id="20">In this regard, a detailed report American Medical Association magazine published in. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Pakistan with immediate Jang the possibilities of not: Indian military chief </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The head of the Indian army personnel Dipak General has said that Pakistan with immediate Jang the possibilities of present worth, however, the defense of the country and to the interests of the protection to ensure rendered great sacrifices for all the time. </seg>
<seg id="3">General alleged that assurances and attacks in Mumbai, as a result of the international pressure on Pakistan, in spite of their words, the land of Pakistan on the infrastructure of terrorism not only of the present situation is active. </seg>
<seg id="4">They said this in Srinagar, talking to reporters in. </seg>
<seg id="5">The Indian army, the head of the New Delhi hotels Kashmir Total security situation and the borders of the preparation for the armed forces to review of the one - day visit to Kashmir. </seg>
<seg id="6">From the question, he was asked that According to media reports, Mumbai attacks in Pakistan has presented by him promptly after exhausting is rejected by this, in their of comment. </seg>
<seg id="7">General has said that the war in the affairs of the peace or what the decision of the political leadership. </seg>
<seg id="8">On the land of Pakistan on the infrastructure of terrorism the presence of mentioning, they said that the Indian army such elements with the competition will be to sabotage the peace and India to weaken on. </seg>
<seg id="9">They said that the Indian Kashmir on the land of 2 to 2, 222 militants are present in the foreign about 22 per cent. </seg>
<seg id="10">General, Dipak said that the weather improvement in the hotels of Pakistan and Kashmir infiltraion from the efforts of the in May, however, India has increased on borders interaction from its employees. </seg>
<seg id="11">They hotels in Indian Kashmir [USK], the number of forces in the possibilities of Oh by saying that the reaction of the agreement with the security of the country cannot be. </seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The language of Allah and to be, </seg>
<seg id="2">Although, is not even then thicker are and of wild extent in this change in favor of our are </seg>
<seg id="3">That person, who Martin of the dreams of are giving to do. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Which is also a part of the Hussain Today, the President of taking oath as to every where there is a test is also testing </seg>
<seg id="2">Not only their himself but all these people who has heart. </seg>
<seg id="3">It will also examination of a white for the government set a heart easy to work. </seg>
<seg id="4">South Asia found the soldiers are set to remembered that they are elected President of and listen to the President that the President of the practical. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Now, after the starts from a person race on brother, they are closed slavery of their country from which were brought and blood has Rozaba term of the most powerful state of the world, the same racial discrimination today is a victim of the nation of such a representative of the President. </seg>
<seg id="2">This from a person has many expectations are, </seg>
<seg id="3">This supporting people that the person is not being measure. </seg>
<seg id="4">If the world in generation, religion on hate there as that only, then it will be a love of those who won something. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">On this change Asia will without this policy in meaningful change it may be expected. </seg>
<seg id="2">Relations between Pakistan and the United States will be on this change. </seg>
<seg id="3">(b) C. B. </seg>
<seg id="4">Indian Prime Minister, or any, and be kept and the relations of my kharab,,, strong and influential influence of lobby only. </seg>
<seg id="5">And as far as Pakistan is concerned, Mumbai bomb blasts in connection with the recent visit to India, Israel, and the entire irrefutably proves aggressive in front of the world. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">After the creation of Pakistan also for quite a long time Swat, all the management of Swat, which was a regular army and the law. </seg>
<seg id="2">He has a agreement of Swat, under the management of the government to do with </seg>
<seg id="3">But it is regretted that the governments of Swat had with our mother or treatment. </seg>
<seg id="4">The government of Swat Swat in schools after the end of the increase in the number of was also not completely </seg>
<seg id="5">And there is no interest in Sukkur and development. </seg>
<seg id="6">The present era in their education to gain the number of the previous era manifold. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan in the North West Frontier Province of local Taliban on behalf of the educational institutions of the target is continuing. </seg>
<seg id="2">The most school in district Swat, which have been destroyed in most of the girls. </seg>
<seg id="3">So the Taliban Swat, not only in the girls` education ban on announced. </seg>
<seg id="4">Thousands of students of education are deprived of. </seg>
<seg id="5">You did it seems that the girls by Taliban what want to. </seg>
<seg id="6">The government so far their illegal steps were unable to stop why. </seg>
<seg id="7">You should be in the government. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It should be question that the Pakistani and to do. </seg>
<seg id="2">All the people of Swat game that are now it is that the army of Taliban service for the killing of for not otherwise in a night five school how can the people in the city of slaughtered in the Chowk, how can. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In Swat writ that when the government is not being set up, Pakistan continued their government to stop illegal steps in? </seg>
<seg id="2">Now the question that when the armed forces, and recovered weapons, Rozaba modern technology and spying system, the government is, four Taliban control, are not? </seg>
<seg id="3">The answer is that his head, Al, a secret of the that neither their weapons ends and that it had been arrested are not </seg>
<seg id="4">Get it is that the Taliban of his black, through international, work are easy </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Now 22 years ago, the war in Afghanistan was </seg>
<seg id="2">I. Taliban to control the I. was help, while the opposition was Northern Alliance, Russia, India and Iran was giving help. </seg>
<seg id="3">Then all of a sudden change in the situation in front of the Taliban to </seg>
<seg id="4">The and also to America has offered to dollars Therefore, a former friend enemy. </seg>
<seg id="5">Now the situation is that this war is now, but also to help in the same Iran, India and Russia are </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Until people in this in and not to feel that is wrong and then to human being to the same mistake. </seg>
<seg id="2">For example, a thief when stealing for if this is the time to think that come to not good theft, and this is a cause, and he is also in the fear from God be, human theft, they will not </seg>
<seg id="3">In the same way, when the Israel not to be wrong and that I am over while of blood and this will be punished till in Gaza while blood shed with India were banned. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Norms! </seg>
<seg id="2">Question that this war, armed, terrorism is to solve the problems? </seg>
<seg id="3">If not, then he which problems of the? </seg>
<seg id="4">It is correct that the Jang, the way to solve problems in these also does not, Barkat, puts. </seg>
<seg id="5">Palestine, Afghanistan, Iraq to the same as the model to in the South. </seg>
<seg id="6">The armed struggle more moral struggle, and jihad. </seg>
<seg id="7">In part of the people from the danger, it appears that he has accepted the. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Israeli attacks on Gaza, the third week and the number of deaths, one thousand has reached. </seg>
<seg id="2">International diplomatic efforts in spite of war has so far not is </seg>
<seg id="3">According to an estimate, 22 December started after the attacks, till now 22 thousand Palestinian their house, left to the safe areas. </seg>
<seg id="4">On the other hand, the relief agencies Palestinian children heavily overburdened with the protection of the case of Palestinian children, has said that an entire generation serious problems facing psychological and emotional. </seg>
<seg id="5">What are you. </seg>
<seg id="6">Should be? </seg>
<seg id="7">In the Gaza Strip lasting peace? How is it possible? </seg>
<seg id="8">Details of Click here </seg>
<seg id="9">Please note (see the comments due to the number of Urdu only in the comments published will be. </seg>
<seg id="10">For this on the Board on under select Urdu) </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Taliban occasion. </seg>
<seg id="2">, </seg>
<seg id="3">The real to them. If Taliban to wage jihad, were innocent people who will. </seg>
<seg id="4">The school who? </seg>
<seg id="5">And ransom kidnapping for ransom or not, spy TV said people who pay? </seg>
<seg id="6">These Taliban Islam is a big loss Shaeba, as the nation has not Shaeba, religion or. </seg>
<seg id="7">Pashtun </seg>
<seg id="8">Pakistan </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">All the Islamic world by Israel to attack only if the threat of only then will give you that Israel Abba worth of how much will be quite </seg>
<seg id="2">Immediately and war of not only simply ceasefire, but will also be. </seg>
<seg id="3">But what our ruling Muslim satisfied heart, liver, so where. </seg>
<seg id="4">No Ahmad Nezhad to say that you only initiative, two of BBC Forum in your bravery of our. </seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">On the one hand, the United States is planning to the Jang that will, </seg>
<seg id="2">On the other hand, the UN resolution on the resolution, but both did not, a means the same employment is that to crush the Muslims for the United Nations should also fighting. </seg>
<seg id="3">All the Muslim countries to UN membership immediate end religious and on the basis of its international organization. </seg>
<seg id="4">Many examples are our in front of the United States, where in the United Nations and only promises and only resolutions are only Muslims in front of loss. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">What is the use of the BBC when some politics is not </seg>
<seg id="2">Now, all the press principle Fallujah buried blood 2/22 Muslims, BBC on be. </seg>
<seg id="3">The right believe accounting </seg>
<seg id="4">Some, to speak of extremists, less bright example of this is to comments that) </seg>
<seg id="5">On behalf of the Muslims. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">You and in the difference in so He is saying, Muslim and as you are Muslims in their to say the Muslims and Muslim </seg>
<seg id="2">[syja222] </seg>
<seg id="3">To BBC never suicide attacks in India, never in the garb of terrorism in a particular racial to him, is being </seg>
<seg id="4">These remarks against Islam favourite climbing word of extremism is </seg>
<seg id="5">But extremists who is that the comments you are well against Iran, in which the writing on the words of under a kidnapped. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Our understand that when the Muslims from not face. </seg>
<seg id="2">Israel bombing of the unarmed people in the heart of blood eligible cried, tears not do? </seg>
<seg id="3">But this conflict fault, murder and destruction is the name of jihad, which we face of Islam and beautiful to. </seg>
<seg id="4">When the Palestinian Israel has accepted the existence of Hamas, they need to do that Israel rocket or at the suicide attack. </seg>
<seg id="5">Both sides attitudes soldier. </seg>
<seg id="6">The role of the United Nations and then we support the atrocities of Israel. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">God give a of,, </seg>
<seg id="2">The terrorists and terrorism of this action quite from terrorism the hands of a Nobel also Thoughts Example: that the real work,. </seg>
<seg id="3">Otherwise what large scale terrorism without difficulty Sardar of capability and it is the who are all know. </seg>
<seg id="4">In this easy , in the same language culprits, it is said that after sunset, which is to. </seg>
<seg id="5">A of on were also and also started. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">For W for shrouds were among the dead, and they are Arab and asked the ruling is being. </seg>
<seg id="2">The Israeli attack, should be? </seg>
<seg id="3">This issue in fact is that all the Muslim countries, including the heads of Saudi negligence in them are not his army and nor any defense bus this plan that they are aid and the responsibility of their whole. </seg>
<seg id="4">Immediately, and practical steps against Israel should. </seg>
<seg id="5">America and of such countries but unfortunately, the absence of these. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">All the sister! </seg>
<seg id="2">My but in this time of difficulty in Hamas peace on the name of their struggle to stop it, and hundreds of thousands of with injustice and failed to prove. </seg>
<seg id="3">Israel and its if their, at the peak of his house also receive law will be born in America and Israel is the nature of Muslims in the suicide bomber fertilizers born to work. </seg>
<seg id="4">The power of in are not. </seg>
<seg id="5">Pakistan Abu Abdullah </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Now Hamas and Israel to compromise and so that the blood and should be closed. </seg>
<seg id="2">Mohammad Sarfaraz, Paris, France, </seg>
<seg id="3">Completely said rang. </seg>
<seg id="4">Duty and are that Hamas right on the fact that 222 and,,,, jihad against the from Bargah in this is to be,,, at least so, it should be known that if has House, then not imparted living. </seg>
<seg id="5">People who love from God, love to the Prophet, and their love to follow the claim, from love to his part is! </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">After the Muslims of the book, the people are not, in the world, the order of Allah that it is </seg>
<seg id="2">Ur Rehman, </seg>
<seg id="3">G not ordered them, but it is not the invitation of the hands of Islam is </seg>
<seg id="4">But people who against he is against the order of jihad </seg>
<seg id="5">These people from the Paletinian to barrage when he does not end after - but it means that is not at all, wearing would be - in </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">With utmost pain, brothers, children of the destruction of the murderer. </seg>
<seg id="2">My friends but it is requested that the head of the place, he was not so strong in any of the world that all do not recognise all. </seg>
<seg id="3">In these, not the bus, Sunni and he has dense and development of every quite like. </seg>
<seg id="4">On the contrary, 55 Islamic countries is what? </seg>
<seg id="5">Every behind dense and now it is such that is that the enemy into his death and they are waiting for. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is necessary that all the Muslim countries united and get ready against Israel. </seg>
<seg id="2">,, Pakistan </seg>
<seg id="3">This good and a strategy that Israel, and not to accept this Rozaba studies, try to look and development of the world and peace and China from eyes. </seg>
<seg id="4">The Muslims have also and sources also. </seg>
<seg id="5">There is need to use Karachi. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The first most tragic aspect that it is not in Al - Fateh Hamas and unity. </seg>
<seg id="2">Arafat and as a grand Shawl. The to look for what it was that the Al - Aqsa mosque, for jihad, to the nation of the region, the only gains to weaken the what can be and until and Arafat to remove this is not impossible. </seg>
<seg id="3">The world is eligible that these two after the death of Palestine moment is how often moment </seg>
<seg id="4">And how often lobby moment, it [US] trap. to their strong from most governments. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In 1974, the Prime Minister, the owner of the world as was the first time that 222 percent in the absence of all the Muslim leaders under a roof had been taken. </seg>
<seg id="2">Today, this they do on the day of the nation that it is difficult to work was that not only in their ranks alliance </seg>
<seg id="3">The differences of Muslims, but she also it (Islamic Commonwealth htm) between the mission of forward will be? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is a half century, which is the </seg>
<seg id="2">The mouth of many are </seg>
<seg id="3">Many times in which it their mouth any other from the good and bad of the world and paddy is </seg>
<seg id="4">And other the mouth of Iran, Afghanistan, Iraq in Pakistan are equal eating </seg>
<seg id="5">And which all more with Islam, which is that it knows that when it was also he only Muslims and Islam and Muslims and Islam and practical only follow closing will receive is witness that Islam has big ruknuddin's are on the path </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Israeli planes on behalf of the bombing and missile attacks on Gaza, the process of 22 December. </seg>
<seg id="2">In these attacks so far more than three hundred Palestinian citizens have been killed. </seg>
<seg id="3">Air attacks after Israeli tanks and seven vehicles also ground operation preparation of Gaza on the border of have reached. </seg>
<seg id="4">The UN Security Council has an emergency meeting in through a unanimous resolution, Israel, and the Palestinian Authority to immediately violent activities, has demanded to stop. </seg>
<seg id="5">However, the Israeli authorities say that he at this time the Gaza Strip in to action will continue until they are not rocket attack on that Israel will be closed. </seg>
<seg id="6">You in the opinion of Israel is correct said that this action Israeli defense integrity is trying to? </seg>
<seg id="7">This situation in the international community role? </seg>
<seg id="8">This aggressive action of indirect with Israel in the next elections? </seg>
<seg id="9">Does the United States of the newly elected President of the Middle East, after taking the improvement in the situation could expect? </seg>
<seg id="10">Please note (see the comments due to the number of Urdu only in the comments published will be. </seg>
<seg id="11">For this on the Board on under select Urdu) </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Things to the Muslims of Palestine by the world for liaison is a sacred and its protection is our part </seg>
<seg id="2">And it also listen to the Kiblah, he is the first ordinary </seg>
<seg id="3">India and Israel to have a day all it is only a loss of the country, and they are for the wrath of God on the is certainly - Sajid Sadiq, </seg>
<seg id="4">When the from Kutty night is </seg>
<seg id="5">When without any only to the prayers is (Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan) </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> comments, the BBC and published. </seg>
<seg id="2">The end of the impression, and also set up. </seg>
<seg id="3">BBC, the correct, but only are quite like the news of the. </seg>
<seg id="4">How to - is quite like to know how the news and less. </seg>
<seg id="5">. </seg>
<seg id="6">Chughtai </seg>
<seg id="7">This now our Pakistani, particularly in the column and also a from her that it was not increasing of extremism and terrorism in the writing on, or, in his are seen </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The United Nations said is apparently, human rights and peace is simply of Muslims, but the new and coercion and his words to hear about that Hamas attack when to stop this dual will progress. </seg>
<seg id="2">Muslim so strongly cruelty, is being if such people radical backing left, may Allah has clearly said that the nation is she spent the life of the nation and the nation will never not, if the life has backed at, and then that his was Karachi - </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The world so - called murder at the name of peace and it was to those who are only peace in the world that only hands and Justice begin to set up the checking injustice and suicide. </seg>
<seg id="2">If the genocide to have any nation to what can be and achieve favorable results can ruknuddin's, after the steps taken by the Jews of not only be maintained existence, but a kind of its peak today is impossible. </seg>
<seg id="3">According to a poet, </seg>
<seg id="4">Cruelty is increasing, it is their </seg>
<seg id="5">Blood is long, it is </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Now, who will say that terrorism? </seg>
<seg id="2">What it may also be covered by the terrorism not only in their own pain all their it is </seg>
<seg id="3">People do not or are the only then gets reputable of what was not a </seg>
<seg id="4">And now were also not been a message? </seg>
<seg id="5">Attacks in Mumbai, the proceedings of the plight was as my home in the fire was that of Afaaq and do not solve this difficulty to solve it may not be a Thoughts Example: </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Bodies lying on the road, injured and innocent blood in condemned how words that not get - </seg>
<seg id="2">The Muslims of helplessness on a weeping is that India, and people are in the entire world on Pakistan and evidence is that we will otherwise action! </seg>
<seg id="3">Israel openly and on the other hand, the genocide of the Muslims of the world, and it is not silent </seg>
<seg id="4">God - have some and when it is not Nagri, will be ended. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">As of Israel is a joke. </seg>
<seg id="2">It was on the power of the elections, head of the public to use of this in a) Israel, particularly the rest of Barak, no witness is not against the ruling and may not be fairer or Kala is he is. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In the debate on forum, it is clear that the death of all of the grief, but they do not ignore. </seg>
<seg id="2">It was the discussion is that for the sake of democracy has given life or for the sake of power. </seg>
<seg id="3">If democracy, met investors and to ten years that the Musharraf in, leave kept? </seg>
<seg id="4">And then Pakistan could not when the need to energy Unfortunately, then Pakistan when they go to court cases of power and visited the feasibility </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistani took to the allegations is being on this, not only the to say anything. </seg>
<seg id="2">Sana Khan </seg>
<seg id="3">Some had ignored is imparted this thinking that some of these can not be. </seg>
<seg id="4">A and Qari </seg>
<seg id="5">Perhaps, Mrs. you have not only in Pakistan but) (head of his four - friendly countries and seven other countries also read in Whatever happens of you. </seg>
<seg id="6">Tariq </seg>
<seg id="7">, which is not that he is not training from </seg>
<seg id="8">Was the green of living in contradict, of which </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">He has also not and a Hindu - Muslim frequently been issue, which has the development of Karachi. </seg>
<seg id="2"> </seg>
<seg id="3">How much is our nation cruel and his party in Shan write, not only are now, but every Pakistani intellectuals, took to the allegations and is being criticized on this, not only the to say anything. </seg>
<seg id="4">We development has many people. </seg>
<seg id="5">Sana Khan </seg>
<seg id="6">Some had ignored is imparted this thinking that they can not be some - way using relaxation techniques. hands from the world is not donkey - </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">After the attack, although Mumbai between Pakistan and India in the ongoing process so we created the India - Pakistan talks. </seg>
<seg id="2">If the war will discuss, from both the sides of human lives. </seg>
<seg id="3">India has said that the attack in Mumbai, they were arrested and Pakistan is the Urdu in a letter sent by writing to Pakistan, but on the other hand, India has when the extremist arrested, said that this is a very big Engineer But after that it only four party have declared the it is. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">First, Sahib forum and friends of Christmas Mubarak. </seg>
<seg id="2">Forum: Sahib, Raza, sister Sana sister Shahida, Akram and all norms. </seg>
<seg id="3">We all of the five Jang flowers of peace, but not want to! </seg>
<seg id="4">Jang, itself is a </seg>
<seg id="5">Jang what the resolution of the issues will </seg>
<seg id="6">Today, and blood shed and will </seg>
<seg id="7">Yesterday, hunger and will </seg>
<seg id="8">For this knowledgeable people </seg>
<seg id="9">Jang, it is better </seg>
<seg id="10">You and in our </seg>
<seg id="11">Shama similar, is better </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">India relations are now have a deep and India knows that time on Pakistan to openly fraud. </seg>
<seg id="2">The old. </seg>
<seg id="3">When that the Indian attack in its objectives and also will also on the will of India. </seg>
<seg id="4">Pakistan should announce clear that we will not initiative, but the peace and compromise, then the ceasefire, at this time, until India not to be completely destroyed on this or not, whether it for, we not destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="5">Islamic. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This resolution before the Pakistani people and the army has message, which it was given. </seg>
<seg id="2">Compensate attacks in an extraordinary diplomatic and military benefits of Indian affected more artery. it was the first, the world are strong reaction on the contrary, Pakistan has now the world at reduced. </seg>
<seg id="3">India are very important. the noise to the United Nations in kind of Pakistan on the efforts of the appearance of the Interpol and the head of the Pakistani efforts to India is the need of more Embassy,,. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This, there is not that this is a very ghastly action. </seg>
<seg id="2">However, the question is that when thousands of Taliban on Monday, Sami, on the attackers were, where the Pakistan Army and what was? </seg>
<seg id="3">What the army should not accountability that he said in a year there? </seg>
<seg id="4">The number of thousands of every day, which they believe mortar fire in and out of their with Taliban are? </seg>
<seg id="5">In an appeal to the Taliban that leave for the supervision of Swat Benazir in heaven and we live in peace. </seg>
<seg id="6">And the fake operation. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The United Nations in closer to the day when the military intervention in Pakistan not only to the plight of the resolution have called. </seg>
<seg id="2">Ahmad Farooqi </seg>
<seg id="3">First, then our extremist and their to take action against all evidence and justifications for the continuous are being provided state. and stronger day, which also Amin a resolution, the possibilities are also a that the United Nations in our voice in favor, not </seg>
<seg id="4">Suppose and this resolution to some, in the example of in any power under self help and that will not run. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Al - and from information and that we do not of this. </seg>
<seg id="2">Perhaps, he was not a revolutionary. </seg>
<seg id="3">The way, Nawab Bugti, Dr. Allah and thousands of dead bodies of the enemy. </seg>
<seg id="4">He is also, died. </seg>
<seg id="5">But, as a an international image, and it is being the women of the people of rule is being made. </seg>
<seg id="6">So that the justification for having could be that if we do not, investigates everywhere across come on the government and humanity. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The name of religion of Islam in the so - called it a is condemnable. </seg>
<seg id="2">These extremists, the supporters of the United States of oppression, but this to be a huge actions on instead of they tribal traditions for the elimination of clean avoiding. </seg>
<seg id="3">Tribal area of fingers traditions and never Islam with the name of the like this ghastly action for living a heart, have not. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In my opinion, our army from the people of these people. </seg>
<seg id="2">He noted that when a these people, this time, in the country, it is IEP for so, but he will be on the occasion, to remove the if they are also there, the people are time has passed. </seg>
<seg id="3">These people are such that fifty 22 brave men hostages and our army hand strongly hands to keep the spectators like. </seg>
<seg id="4">He also of the Pakistani army and are also. </seg>
<seg id="5">It is obvious that clean in some Kala. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Karachi, time of God and the qualities of contrary to highlight the kinds of and with the name of religion of the fear of the atmosphere, which will be set up in the dead body of the incident of the country, and after, what will also consider using relaxation techniques. fear born. </seg>
<seg id="2">And people just and and Jalal is with the instrument or as. </seg>
<seg id="3">,! </seg>
<seg id="4">From where you to this is </seg>
<seg id="5">Karachi fear that that a case, </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">When it is the way it is said that the work not Muslims. </seg>
<seg id="2">We are from their or neighbor and go. </seg>
<seg id="3">After Wisal to stop on the door of Rasool has set in and her husband put in the rope who was to? </seg>
<seg id="4">What they say outside came from? </seg>
<seg id="5">Muslim's on the army is spread himself and Karbala of international and do you do? </seg>
<seg id="6">The facts accepted this might have motives round that are not made. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">BBC at dual policy closed. </seg>
<seg id="2">This topic more better super topic 22, in: Bush were or, if legitimate illegal? </seg>
<seg id="3">, should be </seg>
<seg id="4">Japan, </seg>
<seg id="5">Some shame and a man from the grave pole from Pakistan will kidnapped that it has been raised its voice against repression, and you box office of the topic is. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The border of him and the other side of the line of suffered depend on it depends on the opinion that the common people who is in favor of. </seg>
<seg id="2">This step and Pakistani has Jame and the conspiracy of. </seg>
<seg id="3">Now this forum in all the Opposition criticized the Taliban will receive secret based on the Taliban have to be included in the steps and common people who are the opinion of the change. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In the conference, only this question is that the day when a crossing the dead body to the army, who do what he was the only people who are also there are some as well. on the bombing of the Taliban came crashing House, 2 children, were killed, and his mother. </seg>
<seg id="2">Do this Chowk was not know about? </seg>
<seg id="3">Or eligible? </seg>
<seg id="4">We hand on the result and are that God It stopped. </seg>
<seg id="5">You also end of a ruling. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">BBC, he was asked the question reasonable may not be writing of sorrow and, for example, this is a question asked that Swat did not present in the 22 thousand army to? </seg>
<seg id="2">The army also Taliban fight of dead bodies on all day, crossing. </seg>
<seg id="3">The people of Pakistan army, green with step be 222, but the media, including the BBC has also the reality of the world with courage and not good. </seg>
<seg id="4">The Pakistan Army, drama. </seg>
<seg id="5">Swat child that is that it is a drama. </seg>
<seg id="6">For the bus will drama. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">These the Taliban and the name of the only Muslims. </seg>
<seg id="2">The entire world in a true Muslim if not to say, in the area of terrorists, to. </seg>
<seg id="3">Which are a which are leaving the hard work of gun for not included in the group. </seg>
<seg id="4">Islam or of gun to not been. </seg>
<seg id="5">Shame. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This not in the justification of religion is not in. </seg>
<seg id="2">BBC, including all the Taliban and the tribal people of different sources from his commentary are </seg>
<seg id="3">But situation that not know that it is always situation, we know what we all tribal. </seg>
<seg id="4">It is that it is a game that hold A. C., RAW [Research and Analysis Wing], Mosad, and our own the I. are not included it is not a student of their tribal trouble, the Taliban elements who Islam, seminaries, nation, Pashtun tribes and tribal to. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This act of all Muslims shame reprehensible. </seg>
<seg id="2">In the leader of a Hussain, P. and division of the to which the against Taliban against it. </seg>
<seg id="3">It is the, he himself to Pakistan, but also destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="4">But in the present that this will end the. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">India has said that after the Mumbai attacks of these attacks behind the extremist elements of Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan has denied the charges and he said that every possible in the investigation of India will help. </seg>
<seg id="3">India has said that Pakistan is a list, in which these 22 suspected extremists, which is the name of India. </seg>
<seg id="4">Pakistan has said that the list in the head of Maulana Mohammad Azhar Masood and these are not the detainee about the Pakistan Government is not any information. </seg>
<seg id="5">Before this, the President of Pakistan, Asif Ali Zardari has rejected the impression that the Western secret agencies and the Indian government to Pakistan from Mumbai evidence about the attacks have been provided. </seg>
<seg id="6">The President has butcher Ajmal said that it was not prove that they are Pakistani. </seg>
<seg id="7">Meanwhile, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has warned that Pakistan is the relations between India and then to not when there of terrorism for use. </seg>
<seg id="8">And, the latest in India and Pakistan cricket team has postponed his tour. </seg>
<seg id="9">His political impact on the incidents of Sports pressing circumstances.? </seg>
<seg id="10">You relations between Pakistan and the future of what? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan will not have not. </seg>
<seg id="2">The Pakistani Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="3">So sectarianism and after you do expect. </seg>
<seg id="4">The Muslims of Jinnah has also do not good with this time has proved. </seg>
<seg id="5">, </seg>
<seg id="6">If the vision of Ms Jinnah on work, not, and the cancer in Pakistan and India in the Muslims of the behaviour. </seg>
<seg id="7">But our mistake of like that his order is not a leader. </seg>
<seg id="8">If we value of our heroes can not, </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In this region, expertise. </seg>
<seg id="2">God when it will come, and solve this region will develop. </seg>
<seg id="3">The two countries in got Pandit, the Taliban,,,,, the peace of the anti - were that are ready. </seg>
<seg id="4">And not to that of peace with this region will develop, therefore, these countries puppet Kashmir is being. </seg>
<seg id="5">Do you can imagine that are agree with this area of Pakistan, India, and China do the place in the world. </seg>
<seg id="6">Pakistan, which is the wrath of God, evaders, dacoits and hanged otherwise the news and imposed on the nation. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">May God be our country Pakistan never also affect,. </seg>
<seg id="2">But a attiya's Sahib opened its surrounding the conditions and see the facts, you will then that forces where reached. </seg>
<seg id="3">Besides it, foreign affairs also are not coming in NWFP, Balochistan, and Sindh in the situation in Karachi are also you. </seg>
<seg id="4">Quite a situation in the country, which we should be able to make a nation. </seg>
<seg id="5">Or, we give their mercy. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">My last but a war, without a not. </seg>
<seg id="2">A bus has. </seg>
<seg id="3">Now R. or across the issue should be possible. </seg>
<seg id="4">The talks hypocritical to resolve the issue. </seg>
<seg id="5">Not only a small in other countries of terrorism. </seg>
<seg id="6">Finally, Europe, the grand last fight after as had been. </seg>
<seg id="7">And it is not a grand Jang, today also to Pakistan and India are very. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Our entire under this agree that the country are to be terrorism and sectarianism should be removed. </seg>
<seg id="2">But our military in this work, it not sincere in a hand, Europe and the guarantee of terrorism is that this war, we are with you, and on the other hand, the Taliban secret also help. </seg>
<seg id="3">We think is now and its direction and only a way to choose, </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">There is no doubt in the fact that Jamat - e - is included in the majority of Lashkar - e - Taiba of these workers, which is banned Lashkar - e - Taiyba disqualified after the Jamat - e - Pakistan set up with the name of party, were included in the </seg>
<seg id="2">However, after the these workers to the relief work, and now India strongly insist at the United Nations and it also has declared the Pakistan Government and crack down against their will continue. </seg>
<seg id="3">In my opinion, if this jihadi groups religious extremism and religious and relief activities continue, better. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan in the organisations who work in the name of jihad crime work, Paul its people and their of this, the same big, who are Pakistan and say what to do. </seg>
<seg id="2">Now it to in Pakistan are not no effort. </seg>
<seg id="3">The real Muslim man, it does not entitled to. </seg>
<seg id="4">Pakistan with Pakistan might have security in danger. </seg>
<seg id="5">Now what it also has a capacity of thinking that they should be banned, that? </seg>
<seg id="6">The place in the world, were not only to murder their work. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This news heart a thief. </seg>
<seg id="2">This world where of Islam that an important member today also taking for this, it is difficult to life in the world. </seg>
<seg id="3">Non - Muslim killed, but if the Muslim to take revenge also try to non - Muslim, all of the world with all our rulers also hypocrite gujral's views together true religion, pain and sincere to with it, who are today our great leader Hafiz Saeed with. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Mumbai attacks of hanged in India. </seg>
<seg id="2">In the bitterness between Pakistan and has been created the relations between the two countries in recent years in the severe blow. </seg>
<seg id="3">India continuously active in Pakistan military and non - military groups is responsible for </seg>
<seg id="4">And back to normal relations of these groups from taking action against conditional is being. </seg>
<seg id="5">While the Indian security agencies for attacks Mumbai Lashkar - e - Taiyba directly responsible is held </seg>
<seg id="6">In this connection, again in the name of party. </seg>
<seg id="7">This is not the first time that India is in terror action due to serious relations between the two countries. </seg>
<seg id="8">Two thousand December in one of the Indian Parliament after the attack on the two neighboring Jang on the brink of. </seg>
<seg id="9">After this, 2222 in two Lashkar - e - Tayyaba, and terrorist groups has been included in the list of. </seg>
<seg id="10">Now party, about which the security analysts say that the real Lashkar - e - Taiba of new Aqal, demanded the ban is being. </seg>
<seg id="11">You think in this group on a ban should be or not? </seg>
<seg id="12">Pakistan on our soil, the extremist groups active decisive action against should? </seg>
<seg id="13">What party to present the ban on India. </seg>
<seg id="14">Pakistan crisis safe and lasting peace between the two countries to be closed armed groups of how much is essential? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The UN Security Council of the Jamat - e - has imposed a ban on the end of the Security Council, which are evidence on what to do so there? </seg>
<seg id="2">What the Security Council against Muslims, however, he not vigilance? </seg>
<seg id="3">The plaintiff that are slow to witness! </seg>
<seg id="4">Afaaq itself, India has become a failed! </seg>
<seg id="5">The army, and other organizations have, which are a few at the hands of terrorists 72 hours of Kashmir, and India on this failure of Pakistan and the entire world to. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">A murder be called the entire world in noise is double - it,? </seg>
<seg id="2">The country, met only, welfare organization - - - - - - - -. </seg>
<seg id="3">Furqan, Farooq Islamabad chose </seg>
<seg id="4">Until our Prophet (), and the people kidnapped, love and respect to follow in peace and spread well. </seg>
<seg id="5">The Muslims have also every forum development in Karachi. </seg>
<seg id="6">This beautiful follow the features in which the individuals Momin and called the conflict and started a new chapter of opening the first know which started from the world, not reduced. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Mr. desire to salute. From your bill but this action on its own. </seg>
<seg id="2">In of not come. </seg>
<seg id="3">If India is quite evidence, to provide? </seg>
<seg id="4">He, not? </seg>
<seg id="5">And all the accused, we have? </seg>
<seg id="6">In India, the extremist group and organisations, these are not ban on, for the people? </seg>
<seg id="7">What the entire world, we are in a terrorist? </seg>
<seg id="8">In India, which is he? </seg>
<seg id="9">Israel, which is he? </seg>
<seg id="10">The fact that this is the first Islamic world, we are,, are Jhagra. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan is now in its final stages. </seg>
<seg id="2">, </seg>
<seg id="3">You to the heart of these  and is also seen in some circumstances are coming </seg>
<seg id="4">Now, magazines cranny in Pakistan with the new plans to what is published and of part of the same. </seg>
<seg id="5">Slowly but not very information from their strong grip on Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="6">If we back in the people as a nation of unity and do not agree if it, Bangladesh, and can become a lot. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The terrorist attacks of also condemned, Mumbai, whether they are or hotel in Islamabad hotel in and then or in Palestine. </seg>
<seg id="2">In this way, terrorist where be eliminated, whether they should be, Indian or be and. </seg>
<seg id="3">Now the question is that every day born in Pakistan, which are a terrorist attack, people are, officials, the entire world, is silent? </seg>
<seg id="4">What was the hotel on what terrorist attack was not there? </seg>
<seg id="5">Then,. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Interior Rehman of the country, and how many G. are! </seg>
<seg id="2">According to the BBC, where the UN Security Council (a) of Jamat - e - has imposed a ban on, Mr. Malik has said that we have not of the ban, and many [Legal Framework Order] only after the what can </seg>
<seg id="3">BBC, not only According to my Sahib has also this impression it as wrong with all the kidnapped is that the terrorists, any to be brought on, in are. </seg>
<seg id="4">, Allah! </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The ability to or not to say that it or not. </seg>
<seg id="2">The Pakistani how we are fighting a war. </seg>
<seg id="3">Also, and our interests which we are demanding the entire try and. </seg>
<seg id="4">The any national issues in to as is not. </seg>
<seg id="5">The era of apparently. </seg>
<seg id="6">If the people of justice to the expected ally or be independent judiciary stress on the implementation of institutions and respect for the help of a military dictator or not, the world, including Pakistan, which will be set up in peace and the is not acceptable. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan, only and objectives of God in it. </seg>
<seg id="2">It is a population of Pakistan was despite. </seg>
<seg id="3">And this is the anti - more emotions. </seg>
<seg id="4">If democracy and its allies have confidence, who are attitude to respect the sovereignty of from the region can. </seg>
<seg id="5">In Pakistan is so that they are or. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan under the security forces in Kashmir has banned Lashkar - e - Taiyba alleged raided a camp. </seg>
<seg id="2">After the Mumbai attacks pressure on Pakistan is that he extremist organizations should take action against. </seg>
<seg id="3">India is accused of that Lashkar - e - Taiyba attacks in Mumbai. </seg>
<seg id="4">The US State Condoleezza Rice has said that the Pakistani leadership from Mumbai attacks against responsible transparent and immediate action should be a practical demonstration. </seg>
<seg id="5">He said there is no doubt that the attack on the Mumbai extremists use of Pakistani soil. </seg>
<seg id="6">Meanwhile, in Peshawar officials say that the allied forces in Afghanistan, at the goods trucks and a base unknown armed men fire, which has been more than 22 trucks have been destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="7">In Peshawar starts hours during the NATO and American attack on the second supplies. </seg>
<seg id="8">During this with has banned Lashkar - e - Taiyba alleged raided a camp and prior to this, the tribal areas from Karachi to armed groups to disarming many efforts have been in back to the compensation and no action has assured the eradication of. </seg>
<seg id="9">The situation that General Zia - ul - Haq in the period of the former Soviet Union of the US and Afghan intervention of Saudi funding beginning from resistance, as a result of armed groups in give birth to Pakistan to 222 2222 before as environment back to the efforts to not succeed. </seg>
<seg id="10">The question is, it wants to Pakistan? </seg>
<seg id="11">Pakistan It is capable of? </seg>
<seg id="12">What are you? </seg>
<seg id="13">Details of Click here </seg>
<seg id="14">Please note (see the comments due to the number of Urdu only in the comments published will be. </seg>
<seg id="15">For this on the Board on under select Urdu) </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Only a all my question is: of </seg>
<seg id="2">If you their children, he lost) you to come, it is impossible </seg>
<seg id="3">, </seg>
<seg id="4">My question that you to and from the middle of Islamic studies, and the West to say any logic, and the US attack of innocent people, including labor and his work of the murder of to? </seg>
<seg id="5">And, if the answer is not in your of reformation is an urgent need of. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">What was the armed people at this time, it was feared that Russia Afghanistan after providing Pakistan should therefore, their armed people to do. </seg>
<seg id="2">Now, it is feared that Pakistan will run on which the current President in his presidential campaign have openly, we are these people, an armed try? </seg>
<seg id="3">Only so that India or Pakistan Army to any kind of resistance not face? </seg>
<seg id="4">Yes, if there is any action involved in Pakistan, only this action against. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">But unfortunately, this is the holy Lashkar - e - The government of India has to be hopeless declared kidnapped is that it is involved in Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="2">Ur Rehman, </seg>
<seg id="3">If we should be melodies that it is involved in the holy Lashkar - e - Pakistan, then the government not always it. </seg>
<seg id="4">And it also a question that these terrorists should do no government or an Indian officials of energy not get help? </seg>
<seg id="5">What or terrorist only in Pakistan and India are ready and she countries of the world are not ready in? </seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Saudi beginning from the campaign to end their from the application that for this caused to our society stained. </seg>
<seg id="2">They also how to protest that under the Saudi in our country and dangerous weapons and the so - called US jihadi culture and the virus, which our country in the open human slaughtered. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">On the other hand, India to attack the threat of the Pakistani army after this announcement, he said that the army from the Afghan border on the other hand, India will pay attention to the Taliban and the announcement that he Afghan border badly and the entire emphasized that the attack on India and Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="2">In this region force all head annually. </seg>
<seg id="3">Although India did not attack threatened nor his courage. </seg>
<seg id="4">The United period of supplies Taliban attacks on the whole. </seg>
<seg id="5">Proved that the Pakistan Army and the government of Pakistan might not some support. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Karachi Pakistan Business financial center of all the poor areas of Dubai. </seg>
<seg id="2">Hundreds of thousands of found from hand, but not return to the Western border areas in India. the supremacy of law is the attention of the Karachi has. </seg>
<seg id="3">Now they of this city of kidnapping are bent upon. </seg>
<seg id="4">The first time is said to the Pakhtoon, who is a answers to the people of the city is being made, although integrity is necessary. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">A solution of the problem, then it is that Urdu speaking people; or, or let; all Urdu speaking people, or let the English, and good. </seg>
<seg id="2">You know it as a from the because you do not hold? </seg>
<seg id="3">That is the reason violence language? </seg>
<seg id="4">Chughtai </seg>
<seg id="5">Mr. it from quite in in his friends and religious in every class people were tripped frequent, on the people on laughed. </seg>
<seg id="6">This time, linguistic, and religious, which is the condition of today, if not reduced and strong within within a bus was reduced. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It seems that are not only, and what is happening? </seg>
<seg id="2">What are the? </seg>
<seg id="3">How innocent and crime in were being? </seg>
<seg id="4">For Pakistan, which are in pieces to the same are active and all this, which are not in the country, and the country is not. </seg>
<seg id="5">Karachi or be Mumbai to fire has condemned the house. </seg>
<seg id="6">The government is only places and the name of the name of are included in to, or that airport, roads, the blood. </seg>
<seg id="7">What are the meanings of Karachi and Pakistan with? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Mumbai attacks on the RAW [Research and Analysis Wing] from Karachi in riots linguistic starts failed to this of trying to prove that RAW [Research and Analysis Wing] in the past, the payroll of the working on the elements now have connections to resign. </seg>
<seg id="2">Speaking to labourers; blood of 2/22 and Indian has from Karachi to the Sui was Waqt. </seg>
<seg id="3">All political, religious, linguistic, and national parties of patriotism with full reaction to the Indian diplomatic norms approach there are plans to a - makers and what is also provided. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In the situation in Karachi and A. P., and asked partiality would like. </seg>
<seg id="2">The situation in 1 asked control can John, but it has to be given a </seg>
<seg id="3">Police, and shikargahs parties pressure due to take action. </seg>
<seg id="4">Alliance is simply to only statements, parties are limited to their interests and common people of the interest of the parties should work. </seg>
<seg id="5">When asked to say, pressure on such incidents will, Allah according to Pakistan in its order. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In my but the biggest terrorists are the people. </seg>
<seg id="2">In this and have no for are always, but that he is not know who? </seg>
<seg id="3">But it is regretted that if the plight of any situation in the city government, the fate of what does not in NWFP, but when it, then the government can make helpless. </seg>
<seg id="4">The government should be found of the country and a big city and important to save terrorism. </seg>
<seg id="5">Otherwise, Pakistan a big financial crisis, it will be. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The BBC Urdu, also fear were not write truth Ha while Pakistani condition, and also. </seg>
<seg id="2">The entire true BBC English is on. </seg>
<seg id="3">A solution of the problem, then it is that Urdu speaking people; or, or let; all Urdu speaking people, or let the English, and good. </seg>
<seg id="4">You know it will hold a from the reason, but you do not hold? </seg>
<seg id="5">That is the reason violence language? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Karachi in a story of money and finally, which the fear of every citizen to feeling. </seg>
<seg id="2">The bus to where he has no stone coming on the 22 per cent who is found in four days. </seg>
<seg id="3">The last three them. fear and is now. </seg>
<seg id="4">Who hotel and those who meager killing. </seg>
<seg id="5">On the Super Highway and and while all of the cut of God, who are unaware that they had been arrested will come. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">You think suddenly in the lawlessness reasons for this. </seg>
<seg id="2">(given) </seg>
<seg id="3">India the hands of keeping in view the murder of lawlessness in because we need of completely, but it is not easy and this is the reason that the lawlessness, only on the blood of due to Karachi. </seg>
<seg id="4">It is obvious that if, father, with no, his son, will be out of, lost his temper as he saw Saleemullah, out of control of will not be. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Blood Ali Khan, and there was also Sahib is wrong era, it is a </seg>
<seg id="2">Elderly people, we will also </seg>
<seg id="3">John by giving him, John bil. </seg>
<seg id="4">Faizan </seg>
<seg id="5">It is very sorry, the entire country close at this time, and we are in Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="6">He said that if the. </seg>
<seg id="7">Www in Ali Khan, see you know that the province of Punjab, Karnal area of a well - respected Punjabi them.. </seg>
<seg id="8">These steps to old fortresses of Muhajir today Karachi because their detest them. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The reaction of the, is. </seg>
<seg id="2">Their, what can be tolerated. </seg>
<seg id="3">Awan, </seg>
<seg id="4">Before this, that Mr. up in overnight from the long and happens, explains what you that the open you today Karachi tomorrow on the wall and posters quite in being. </seg>
<seg id="5">We both of the coming. </seg>
<seg id="6">Pakistan, and founder of Pakistan, and not spared, a reaction should not face. </seg>
<seg id="7">On the contrary, the same Pakistan instead of her stomach strongly heart. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">A Muslim League (N) was it has also made eighteenth amendment draft of Peoples Party. </seg>
<seg id="2">Prior to this, the MQM, Muslim League (Q) and eighteenth amendment of the draft of the National Assembly and deposited in the Senate. </seg>
<seg id="3">So far, the same eighteenth amendment that it is a tactic of political and there is no also this amendment in the resolution is not sincere. </seg>
<seg id="4">This is the reason that so far, or on the floor of the assembly of the Senate this amendment in favor of her and not the house is that he was forced to this amendment approved. </seg>
<seg id="5">It is eighteenth amendment of the draft of his party has deposited with the total, Jharkhand, is to be able to say that we have amendment, submitted was speaker, the government has not only action. </seg>
<seg id="6">The MQM, Muslim League (N) government disclosed ally of the Muslim League (Q) and have to the 22th constitutional amendment, Jamat - e - then how can the parties to end the 22th constitutional amendment, sincere in. </seg>
<seg id="7">The color, and in the name of the martyrs. </seg>
<seg id="8">The Peoples Party, in the 22th constitutional amendment, is not to quickly. </seg>
<seg id="9">Any how, thinking of their own hands. </seg>
<seg id="10">When the president to end the 22th constitutional amendment, are not. </seg>
<seg id="11">One of our in the survey of the majority, and is also true. </seg>
<seg id="12">If the 22th constitutional amendment to end, then the President never. </seg>
<seg id="13">Now, he also with President Pervez Musharraf person because they are more powerful president ensures Peoples Party is also the chairman of. </seg>
<seg id="14">President until the 22th constitutional amendment. </seg>
<seg id="15">The political parties to end the 22th constitutional amendment, President to the President, will have to leave. </seg>
<seg id="16">It does not to MQM is not and other political parties. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Our family of the most senior labor class with </seg>
<seg id="2">In his childhood and when we uncle, maternal uncle and others to look for, in the heart that Allah we want to save the physical labor from wages. </seg>
<seg id="3">For this we have the editor of daily living a letter written and asked that we after matriculation physical labor that we do not have to. </seg>
<seg id="4">Editor said that in a doctor or engineers and to become an subjects they take him. </seg>
<seg id="5">Our trend from the beginning of matriculation and we have also instead of technical drawing only. </seg>
<seg id="6">But at the admission at the time of the elder brother, was forced that we in the medical and Dr. S. C. F.. </seg>
<seg id="7">We have only one month only when read and also not play, the account of the subject of. </seg>
<seg id="8">Physical, Labor fear from US engineers and now we made his family many good position on which we have to every time of God. </seg>
<seg id="9">This time we remember when we his two young sons of the house with old allowed were trying to. </seg>
<seg id="10">Now work half an hour also was the son said that it is the same deadline this work was not. </seg>
<seg id="11">We have said if it is true, then our as well and read physical labor from the Colonization of them. </seg>
<seg id="12">Son said, I read in read and I will also not my, but this work. </seg>
<seg id="13">As we all three hours in a job and home. </seg>
<seg id="14">Means to say that if the destination was to whether the reason behind this, it always floor to stop. </seg>
<seg id="15">If you know that is not only to you, then what is the only Allah Hafiz. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Are saying that died bad, but what to do we first death anniversary of Benazir on their in the evil eye. </seg>
<seg id="2">Benazir for the sake of its interests of freedom fight the Sikhs the list of India to provide a hand to the freedom movement crushed and on the other hand, India to suppress the movement of Punjab after Kashmir in full attention to the chance. </seg>
<seg id="3">Nawaz Sharif and the power of its history which is part of the country to push of the year. </seg>
<seg id="4">Benazir exile during the Kashmir and the nuclear program on statements. </seg>
<seg id="5">Nawaz Sharif, Benazir London agreement with violating the deal with General Musharraf. </seg>
<seg id="6">Benazir rule in his husband openly some cash money and given the opportunity to be known as he tin </seg>
<seg id="7">Benazir in which the brother of the murder of the murderer punishment to children. </seg>
<seg id="8">A woman Benazir despite the rights of women fight. </seg>
<seg id="9">The way, Benazir his father, the dead body of the politics of her husband and now their on the dead body of politics. </seg>
<seg id="10">Benazir two section government but he received their father political murder of criminals, was also registered against the United States. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">East Pakistan from US, year and the people of our rulers and indifferent of extremists see that this day celebrated and not to mourn their mistakes. </seg>
<seg id="2">, that we should December 22 - day to celebrate the hardships and that this accident Ghazwa again. </seg>
<seg id="3">This day we Bangladesh people to accept the messages of and send them try. </seg>
<seg id="4">The ruling to open the commission and the separation of East Pakistan in the reasons for the consideration. </seg>
<seg id="5">Trapped in Bangladesh Beharis to bring back to the promotion of them and encourage the same gifts to send them. </seg>
<seg id="6">But we have even our die in any of the information we now. </seg>
<seg id="7">We thought of his sister brothers are not because we have been. </seg>
<seg id="8">A big tragedy through the next day, then we lost in your life. </seg>
<seg id="9">If the way the eastern and Western Germany again a, in the same way, the eastern and Western Pakistan can also be a. </seg>
<seg id="10">We can be a if both the same each other, sacrifice and not to come out of the tribes. </seg>
<seg id="11">But it is in the near future. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Today, when it was said in the news that the US submitting the governor of the state in the first corruption charges has been arrested </seg>
<seg id="2">And it from the same provincial Congress as soon as possible acts to to take, he is a US white men, our colleagues of Pakistan on the situation of the US is that the episode of democracy, it. </seg>
<seg id="3">The man from the United States in a law is also not </seg>
<seg id="4">A your country and the President of Pakistan, which is also corruption charges dropped after a. </seg>
<seg id="5">Our, Rugby, and if we said in a governor was arrested, our in Pakistan, the Prime Minister, overnight arrested the accused was once again on the second Badar and the country. </seg>
<seg id="6">In the United States never happened? </seg>
<seg id="7">Pakistan, then the country of law breaking of the guard, along with the Presidential House, in the United States never what happened? </seg>
<seg id="8">In Pakistan due to the Chief Justice, it has been said that despite of public support is still not been restored in the United States, what happened? </seg>
<seg id="9">In Pakistan with the degree holder has been made in the United States, what happened? </seg>
<seg id="10">It US laughed laughed cellars and also agree with their lost. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The picture in Zardari from all sides, the President in spite of being "Rass. </seg>
<seg id="2">It appears by his smile </seg>
<seg id="3">They are with the United States that his government, but they are forget that the people with a year ago, Pervez Musharraf. </seg>
<seg id="4">It has been picture, such as any of the family. </seg>
<seg id="5">Prior to this, the newspapers in not photographs of former President with a three American official. </seg>
<seg id="6">It is the job of the United States in Pakistan has increased and now more than one to get it is being or their new Ghulam no trust, which he was on the first. </seg>
<seg id="7">It is also possible Zardari also compelling President of keeping to arrange this. </seg>
<seg id="8">If a strongruler., at least this picture in their teeth projects and not on the face of slavery of shall be clear. </seg>
<seg id="9">If the principle of democracy on this picture fails, President Zardari are in minority. </seg>
<seg id="10">Democracy According to the majority of the country, the ruling and who is the first picture. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Heaven Benazir Swat of Pakistan is also called. </seg>
<seg id="2">So far, according to the government of the strategy of power with the spy mania rising. </seg>
<seg id="3">But the power of the people in power and sympathy for them and create some not. </seg>
<seg id="4">It is necessary that the power of the government in place of the reasons for the end. </seg>
<seg id="5">For the elimination of Fazal - ullah and Taliban themselves by themselves will be removed. </seg>
<seg id="6">ANP, on behalf of the government per bill of Swat had to resolve will cause. </seg>
<seg id="7">But the Shariah of along with the government to pay attention on economic will be </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">General Musharraf from the start of the nation, perhaps, it was that this hospital have all our will be rid of power, but all of his courage change with </seg>
<seg id="2">The manufacturing and they were in combining quite precious to take in the </seg>
<seg id="3">And he was expected steps which ended. </seg>
<seg id="4">Bush, these were the end of the thinking of Pakistan. and in evaders. </seg>
<seg id="5">General Musharraf, then the army to control the present government, but can only do not know that is being. </seg>
<seg id="6">The Bajaur or be Swat army to control the bombing and not on the people is financial loss, along with the loss of enemy, to the mental set the enemy, we not </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The North West Frontier province of the troubled region Swat in more than a year from military action despite the situation with the adversely are being. </seg>
<seg id="2">On the one hand, the writ of the government in this area, only in the National Assembly resolutions resolution to the extent has, and on the other hand, the Taliban of illegal FM radio channel, Swat influence in more than. </seg>
<seg id="3">The third by the common citizens in the US believes that in the area of its activities, which is the same of Sunni. </seg>
<seg id="4">Security forces of Swat in action during about gunship helicopters and believe from many of the death of extremists claims made know, but these killings of the Taliban, despite more stable are not only, but their activities, According to one estimate, Swat had set up on the same percent. </seg>
<seg id="5">As a result, the that on one hand, the government is not ready for the failure of legally and on the other hand, the Taliban stable. </seg>
<seg id="6">In the beach, who are in any citizen. </seg>
<seg id="7">In Swat, now it is said that a asked that the Taliban response, how the people are very good because they are savers of religion and, God and religion, against fighting enemies. </seg>
<seg id="8">Then he was asked that the army is like that to, because he is a very good, and protection of the country are enemies of the country, against. </seg>
<seg id="9">Then, he was asked that the religious scholar and who are the enemies of the country, we got to citizens. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In that the Indian army of the Pakistani Army, how will they fought with a small group could not control. </seg>
<seg id="2">The Taliban illegal FM on the track could not to the channel that in my opinion is very easy. </seg>
<seg id="3">But even then, the whole of FM and died with poison. </seg>
<seg id="4">Schools of boys. After the school destroyed is being. </seg>
<seg id="5">Curfew is considered so that the Taliban easily mobility be able to. </seg>
<seg id="6">Today, during the night curfew eight trucks loaded with curfew during the outskirts of the entered Independent set. </seg>
<seg id="7">The question is that he curfew spite of how. </seg>
<seg id="8">The army Akbar Bugti at home, murder and the Taliban. </seg>
<seg id="9">For this, the Army must that of Swat helpless people from the grip of the Taliban and the Pakistan Army to prove that any where the enemy. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Hazrat question in the world are most of blood religions on, I have been saying that if you do not do religion, bloodshed, it would not be? </seg>
<seg id="2">Punjabi, Pathan, fairer and Kala Mahsood, and other tribes do nothing religion? </seg>
<seg id="3">Do not, Mr. religion, not only the education that there is not any fairer Kala any Punjabi Muhajir any religion if not otherwise it would not have been fighting in the world community and half of hostility impurities, with the rest of the people. </seg>
<seg id="4">Actually, religion, only the moral training and it is bound they found with his own, but the creator of the world has not been found the long recorded sales message and it is the same as the order of According to live. </seg>
<seg id="5">As a Muslim I of Islam is a complete religion and life is true. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In London as residence after years of every first in the morning on his relatives of does have never know the bar also phone by a news not taken again I feel that our them to call alleging Pakistan is also not said we want to. </seg>
<seg id="2">Two years in France has also in you feel the exit. </seg>
<seg id="3">We, the people not only to phone. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In Iraq have, in a few hours, a ongoing peace troops, no problem. </seg>
<seg id="2">Mumbai attacks of better and suspected organizations strongly condemned the ban, a few hours of work. </seg>
<seg id="3">And then of death, where is the advice we are. </seg>
<seg id="4">Oh and international peace here, life is ending. </seg>
<seg id="5">It really waiting for not. </seg>
<seg id="6">So that any oppressed their right to as the widespread destruction weapons to use of could not even think? </seg>
<seg id="7">When a subject of their beloved raised, then run is also a part of the heart of pain in a wave worth? </seg>
<seg id="8">If you do not always entitled to human, not only. </seg>
<seg id="9">But on the name of black stigma humanity. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It, it has proved that thousands of years large area of the country. </seg>
<seg id="2">Be it, then it is that both the United together in all know and love of her, but since the West and Arab countries, are in the hands of these to the wishes of the peace might have not found. </seg>
<seg id="3">But now, Iran also found to fight with their proxy war. </seg>
<seg id="4">Action on any also stopped, then after the incident will be started. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">BBC the interests of the country and associated with the pro - Israel and is the reason that the bright, under the pretext of this,,, comprising of a to and blindly, and their propaganda,. </seg>
<seg id="2">BBC, just, is fulfilling and only the purpose of this and! </seg>
<seg id="3">He is that you of this comment published on should be so that the idea that BBC in the facts of the very little so far. </seg>
<seg id="4">. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Who did not know how this story write in mind, but it is a time in the innocent people are, blood </seg>
<seg id="2">In every time and time was blood had. </seg>
<seg id="3">But way of this century is that the people, who is how civilized now a days and the common silent on this murder, </seg>
<seg id="4">This is how to feel that he, which is a form of the liaison to. </seg>
<seg id="5">Sorrowful and tragic aspect, then it is that the Beatles human beings this aspect of the century and a man in front of the will to do may. </seg>
<seg id="6">, Deccan, </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">At this time, Dera Ghazi Khan, along with the country in the coming winter rain. </seg>
<seg id="2">According to the weather, this is a poem present with discipline of famous rain. </seg>
<seg id="3">The rain, you are also </seg>
<seg id="4">Who are years, Bihar </seg>
<seg id="5">Stay, who are as </seg>
<seg id="6">Such as they have never </seg>
<seg id="7">Never board. It was only right night </seg>
<seg id="8">Never noise are silence are </seg>
<seg id="9">The rain, you are also </seg>
<seg id="10">A night in a </seg>
<seg id="11">One still buried. known to the </seg>
<seg id="12">Sometimes it was that the limit </seg>
<seg id="13">Never with the burned </seg>
<seg id="14">Never gradually in are </seg>
<seg id="15">The rain, you are also </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">All the rulers should seek a case, who run country are reporting, or not. </seg>
<seg id="2">People or the import of temples have to. </seg>
<seg id="3">A, our media also unlawful myth. The rulers. </seg>
<seg id="4">The aim is only and it is only with the government and not some money. </seg>
<seg id="5">People, they are being a to talk about this ignorance a </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In the afternoon strange tomorrow. </seg>
<seg id="2">On the other hand, the police of race on the other hand, it is not to ask the parking area. </seg>
<seg id="3">And, and also in the mood was not that vehicles on. </seg>
<seg id="4">There was that of a U. S. Airlines plane has become really only in their land and River. </seg>
<seg id="5">So far only are so that terrorists of birds with the generation. </seg>
<seg id="6">Yesterday, perhaps historic cold in New York. </seg>
<seg id="7">This does not mean. </seg>
<seg id="8">My own half an hour of turns out to the pain. </seg>
<seg id="9">The fact that these people who have come from the ship in the river, the condition will be. </seg>
<seg id="10">Is a matter of satisfaction that most of the people were safe. </seg>
<seg id="11">And it is that the company vessel, in this crisis. </seg>
<seg id="12">See the side of the West to see and see that was also South is closed, then what did in? </seg>
<seg id="13">G in the return of the same rush caught. </seg>
<seg id="14">My has a trip during the English well, opened same that I get only 56 of the street. </seg>
<seg id="15">The first two, not in this on the lines were not to. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan: a Makki, my Mubarak you to Eid greeting. </seg>
<seg id="2">Of course: faith </seg>
<seg id="3">A Mubarak, Shagufta: you to Eid greeting. </seg>
<seg id="4">In, Sara: Two has and is Qurban and is Jahanzeb, as he has has </seg>
<seg id="5">Apart from this, and there is no way. </seg>
<seg id="6">And this form at the meat itself is also to take off, including skin. </seg>
<seg id="7">: network in the right to take time. </seg>
<seg id="8">Forum on what happened? </seg>
<seg id="9"> </seg>
<seg id="10">Blog to hear of two hand to look in the,. </seg>
<seg id="11">Malaysian: a Mubarak, you to Eid greeting. </seg>
<seg id="12">Sir G. used crane. </seg>
<seg id="13">The snow disappeared will be. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">When we Talabani free in civilized thought, which only on him. the education of women. </seg>
<seg id="2">The angry every day some women of the school and college and demolished their was expressing. </seg>
<seg id="3">But most of like it not be correct, CNN, according to the report of this today, on Monday, in the days when boys, Barkat Talabani has a school with the demolished. </seg>
<seg id="4">The Taliban, Swat boys school have demolished </seg>
<seg id="5">Girls school, the famous in English the ladies first on the practice of the first were demolished, people did not even now, the Taliban and non - civilized culture everywhere across the world. say why? </seg>
<seg id="6">This one and the same that when Talabani on this allegation that they are against the female education, is not correct. </seg>
<seg id="7">But, they are against the education. </seg>
<seg id="8">Pakistan, these mujahideen and given the power, and the government superpower </seg>
<seg id="9">We imposed on the, it is in the founded with the help of. </seg>
<seg id="10">Amen Amen. </seg>
<seg id="11">Now a school severed demolished. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Muslims in the first talk to a permanent, on the name of any property from the Quran marriage to, and many of the mysterious eight years that the girl in Aqil and adults is low, was not that in India, frog who married with the girl news. </seg>
<seg id="2">On the occasion of the marriage has a picture. </seg>
<seg id="3">The same from a dog, some time ago, the latest also marriage with the girl. </seg>
<seg id="4">He also. </seg>
<seg id="5">Humanity in the 22st century is not available. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Today is a period of my life and interference in the field of increasing. </seg>
<seg id="2">Many people to the computer increasing on many are like that financial matters. </seg>
<seg id="3">Where the credit card to use relaxation you are you as the life of private law enforcing agencies, the grip of the also is better </seg>
<seg id="4">Now that only financial issues like the use of credit card records of you can. </seg>
<seg id="5">And in the future, when the actual to use a would be reduced the benefits of this and will be increased. </seg>
<seg id="6">In the same way of crime in the World Bank of threat to stop instead of information, blew up a credit card. </seg>
<seg id="7">In the same way, now to also sources have become </seg>
<seg id="8">Social network, working as websites, book Mai fees and popularity in the first. </seg>
<seg id="9">But you that we mental as their network of social works are, on the people are so far. </seg>
<seg id="10">In the same way, certainly the web site of the match, where you like to other people to the match was people belonging to the list of showing you. </seg>
<seg id="11">Now you just as their life and a person can? </seg>
<seg id="12">In the for this reason, Jeevan for half also better. </seg>
<seg id="13">Me that I am in which they meet. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">I think it in some little. </seg>
<seg id="2">A big from childhood, which also say the fact only for me. </seg>
<seg id="3">In the same way as the world believe was reply to the question is known. </seg>
<seg id="4">This also on a joke. </seg>
<seg id="5">But it is true, which was also keep flying possible. </seg>
<seg id="6">Many people are spoken intricacies, what was. </seg>
<seg id="7">In this age from this fact. </seg>
<seg id="8">Therefore, it is false to at least. </seg>
<seg id="9">A false Lara and what they also with the name of Allah and. </seg>
<seg id="10">And when write and pray to Allah that the job. </seg>
<seg id="11">The rest of the situation, only Allah knows better. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This issue, which is a from religious nearing due to created. </seg>
<seg id="2">Ordinary religion and Pakistan According to the law both mother of innocent children should be. </seg>
<seg id="3">He spent his father is responsible for the father and children. </seg>
<seg id="4">When children be adult, which have you want to remain. </seg>
<seg id="5">You have the right is that the real issue and which are under the quality K </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Jagirdar thinking all our deeds. </seg>
<seg id="2">Here the same thinking that is working in the properties of the father of a new and this will be opposed is otherwise these, the father of this process, and follow is commendable. </seg>
<seg id="3">Our relationship with reference to these engulfed social evil has created </seg>
<seg id="4">Widow, and the marriage of the concept of the people. </seg>
<seg id="5">The elite beliefs are being and traditions, because of which the family system. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">If our society in a 22 - year - old man, the wife of a husband or wife if and where to be married, he should take it with good, why not seen? </seg>
<seg id="2">Our near a Pakistani, his wife ten or twelve years ago, died were now, all children of after he got married woman from a widow, children, only against them. </seg>
<seg id="3">In my view, the Shariah has the right to do you have? </seg>
<seg id="4">Our mother of our are no place to this, we would not to think the kind of thinking? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In my opinion of their own this should think that if all of the children to after he said Bloomberg, a married woman widow, to be wrong? </seg>
<seg id="2">In this way, the widow also get the support and he was also a house was taking the get </seg>
<seg id="3">These children, because of their world were busy will be and they will be worth time. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This is because of. </seg>
<seg id="2">If the total of his old has refused to serve, then he? </seg>
<seg id="3">This is a result of the pressure of the society. </seg>
<seg id="4">When the people on such a such a laughing stock for the launch of the family, their father on the second marriage is being so far </seg>
<seg id="5">Although they face the situation and said that his father According to the wishes of the process of Islam. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This is a cause of our society in which we last 40 - 50 years in a. </seg>
<seg id="2">A wife to this, Mian Manzoor that is unlawful but does not to other diseases marriage. </seg>
<seg id="3">If the bus in, after also to. </seg>
<seg id="4">Mian along with their life and they also in the society always spread of a major cause. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Islam chadar of Islam, some does not like the same we are our tradition. </seg>
<seg id="2">For example, the rehabilitation Bani, girls and education from wells married on a string. </seg>
<seg id="3">The question is your home to bring the big Sahib widow instead of the house of a widow, on the back from the if the of (yes, and satisfied with the widow of stomach, then in). </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan and India in the first centuries, we have accepted this thinking, but not to chase from today and tradition to welcome only with Islam. </seg>
<seg id="2">The second man marriage to divorce, of the clinic, divorced woman, married on the honor and a man of his old woman married with the woman of both the result of this is due to the. </seg>
<seg id="3">And, and a copy of the Western nations and we in the curtain. </seg>
<seg id="4">Islam, easy to accept this was chasing with great difficulty. </seg>
<seg id="5">All this, we have the courage and Ata. </seg>
<seg id="6">Amen. </seg>
<seg id="7">Urdu write law, was never. </seg>
<seg id="8">So this Bait - ul - write write. </seg>
<seg id="9">A little. </seg>
<seg id="10">Allah Hafiz. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Amir Timor in his book, will be selected in published in his life in that it is that if any army commander in chief, has never, they will be in the army failed. </seg>
<seg id="2">But on the other hand, and are </seg>
<seg id="3">It is our for people, we were martyred, for </seg>
<seg id="4">People in my murder, </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">,, while </seg>
<seg id="2">Today, after Isha prayers at night in the shop of a man who in a car has its attention. </seg>
<seg id="3">In this way the man forget has stopped in the car in the entire family was sitting. </seg>
<seg id="4">He carry dam. No canal in Arabic good by that not in said that the issue? </seg>
<seg id="5">It has to carry dam. No canal in Riaz here in Madina but no one has cut my pocket is any help you Please forgive said that to acquire brother, as a good situated in my first that the Muslims as Riyals that this petrol full to a, but it has started the work. </seg>
<seg id="6">I a anger the threat of a tangle. </seg>
<seg id="7">The condition of the Muslims is we deliver to the family of vehicles are we at least two or three. </seg>
<seg id="8">While clear - Prophet (peace be upon him) under from down to deliver. </seg>
<seg id="9">May Allah we should we made (Amen) Amen </seg>
<seg id="10">Grant </seg>
<seg id="11"> </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Singer Adnan Sami on the wife of violence to accused of Mumbai police station, while a have reached </seg>
<seg id="2">Police Station, the court has instructed to. </seg>
<seg id="3">The wife of the Adnan Sami falling his husband of application against Adnan Sami that these are continuously on violence </seg>
<seg id="4">And inhuman treatment instead of are, </seg>
<seg id="5">Now, it has to bear out of these, therefore, Adnan Sami of a case against </seg>
<seg id="6">Police has registered a case, instead of the court that the matter is in police is not done. </seg>
<seg id="7">You think Adnan Sami on his wife of is correct? </seg>
<seg id="8">If this allegation Adnan Sami to malign Indian, not to? </seg>
<seg id="9">From their opinion in this connection. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Sanghar, Mehr. </seg>
<seg id="2">As far as the allegations is concerned, any people can give other </seg>
<seg id="3">To honor of any thing is not </seg>
<seg id="4">The present his wife and Adnan Sami of some will also Adnan Sami their honor life left money was included in India, and now, the same for this the survivals is </seg>
<seg id="5">This is their actions regard. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> </seg>
<seg id="2">Higher American officials say that the President of the Afghan President Hamid Karzai on a hard stance will </seg>
<seg id="3">In Afghanistan, the US new strategy instead of Jang development in the more importance. </seg>
<seg id="4">Officials say that Hamid Zai in Afghanistan and the US targets to in is being considered as the government, because of corruption in the narcotics trade has increased and the strength of the Taliban again is being collected. </seg>
<seg id="5">American officials said that the US Administration in the people Hamid Karzai has more to these are in the Vice President of Pakistan and Afghanistan, and President of representative Richard hall. </seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the strategy of President Bush, who is after every two weeks after Hamid and Zai with a video conference and Afghanistan on these institutions and the citizens of this role in the reconstruction of the US stressed on. </seg>
<seg id="7">Officials say that the administration of the central government as an alternate of provincial leaders will work with. </seg>
<seg id="8">Authorities say that he Hamid Zai and corruption from the war against more on will urge. </seg>
<seg id="9">Hamid Karzai this year new elections is facing and it is not clear that the president and his colleagues, for his will support or not. </seg>
<seg id="10">The US officials, Afghanistan, the statement of the US policy in the change of, not? </seg>
<seg id="11">What Hamid Karzai, the end of the? </seg>
<seg id="12">In this connection, what are you? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Sri between Pakistan and one - day series of three matches, Sri Lanka to Pakistan, 1 - 2. </seg>
<seg id="2">The first one day match in Pakistan has defeated Sri Lanka with, however, within the next two Sri Lanka has won the election. </seg>
<seg id="3">The third one day match in National cricket team, the performance of the poor are national team, Sri Lanka, in response to the 309 runs in 23 overs only 75 runs on a lesson nose and it had to face defeat. </seg>
<seg id="4">The series, as a result of this proves that the performance of the national cricket team in is not. </seg>
<seg id="5">Home - ground and all claims in spite of the national team, was facing defeat in what are the reasons? </seg>
<seg id="6">The authorities of which fields attention on the need to? </seg>
<seg id="7">You are not satisfied with the election of the team? </seg>
<seg id="8">You defeat the responsibility of the sector on how will, fielding, batting and bowling? </seg>
<seg id="9">From their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Malik Babar Hussain, Jeddah, very sad fact is that the modern period of this kind of the Pakistani these cultures are Jagir, a landlord their sovereignty cruel from the innocent people are targeting He will say? </seg>
<seg id="2">Any Sardar correspondents The on time, the government can action against them why does not? </seg>
<seg id="3">When the Court Justice work </seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-, London, like the statement of these correspondents are also, prefer to our desire that some correspondents also true written to the statement on him not because of the ruler has a right order is chance of jihad and this is the only to change in the statement by reports are trying to </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Yousuf, - country. </seg>
<seg id="2">The same is the same people of Kashmir last 22 years of are fighting the war. </seg>
<seg id="3">Not a did not asked the terrorism and now the services of the war against terrorism, the Russian have been started talking </seg>
<seg id="4">The first Muslims massacred what now leave people are in </seg>
<seg id="5">However, Pakistan will have to understand the dual policy, </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Asad London - Khan, </seg>
<seg id="2">India, the situation is that the attention of the world be removed from the Kashmir </seg>
<seg id="3">India, but Pakistan has always face of the world is </seg>
<seg id="4">Now the British government also This is the same as for the name of terrorism from Pakistan to and from the Kashmir are </seg>
<seg id="5">With Pakistan and on this issue investing their </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The British Foreign Minister David received the band, has said that the resolution of the Kashmir issue will finish extremism, the Pakistan government on the border give birth to deal with will be effective manner. </seg>
<seg id="2">It should be remembered that prior to this, the newly elected President also on the Kashmir issue, the same ideas expressed. </seg>
<seg id="3">The British Foreign Minister in Mumbai, to the media in an article written that the war against terrorism is wrong of impending dangers to the people and to the murder of President Bush was the policy. </seg>
<seg id="4">David received the band, has said that Pakistan extremist groups for any of the demonstration. </seg>
<seg id="5">The major powers to solve the Kashmir dispute, stressed upon the need to India due to the tension in the region the attention, not? </seg>
<seg id="6">In Mumbai terrorism part of this strategy, not? </seg>
<seg id="7">India terrorism and on the basis of composite dialogue process to escape? </seg>
<seg id="8">Their claim. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Usman -. </seg>
<seg id="2">In my opinion, big powers are complete loss to Pakistan are not </seg>
<seg id="3">But it control measures for some of them are thinking that Pakistan is a nuclear power, </seg>
<seg id="4">Here a case of want to create </seg>
<seg id="5">The foreign countries are thinking that Pakistan to corner geographical as some political problems can help Pakistan to also want to meet their purpose and also want to </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- a city, U. S. A.. </seg>
<seg id="2">Hindu has always been tradition that path in with a knife by mouth strongly Ram </seg>
<seg id="3">I think that the bus would occasionally with abdominal pain in Kohistan and Pakistan is threatening to </seg>
<seg id="4">We are ready to India chief of their otherwise silence we continue to to know </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Faheem Siddiquee. </seg>
<seg id="2">The United States, told the minister from the statements of the brain is being the United States, India is only, but now the situation is also attacked, who will be seen reality know how much water is in </seg>
<seg id="3">Hamas Israel has any in shame, but that it should also Israel, India also provided India wants to the same </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Prime Minister Syed Yusuf Gilani has said that the US, the newly elected vice President Musharraf, the former president of the uniform and restore democracy Wali played an important role in this, the government of Pakistan to the Sitara - I - Imtiaz importance. The. </seg>
<seg id="2">The uniform and the restoration of democracy in any political party should not go to the credit, parliament is not a rubber stumps, </seg>
<seg id="3">All the decision will be taken in the parliament. </seg>
<seg id="4">The Prime Minister said that Dr Abdul Qadeer the chapter of the. </seg>
<seg id="5">You think to enter the protest against the public does not have any significance? </seg>
<seg id="6">What Lawyers Movement has not play any role? </seg>
<seg id="7">The Prime Minister on the statement of what you want. </seg>
<seg id="8">From their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">U. S. President George W. Bush has at a press conference in the newly elected President Barak advise has said that he has his post in many mistakes and the right to take Barak, he </seg>
<seg id="2">In the situation as president According to the US and under the law and the constitution, the US interests steps to its popularity given priority </seg>
<seg id="3">He said, even today, the US enemies of the US attack on planning, are Barak for these attacks to stop the biggest challenge, </seg>
<seg id="4">He said that from Iraq on a large scale Weapons of Mass Destruction [WMD] not to get my is the biggest disappointment in Iraq and to complete the mission of my biggest was a mistake. </seg>
<seg id="5">The White House in their last while addressing a press conference, the US President has said that it is my last press conference and participate in the conference, journalists, and other friends and I thank participate in it. </seg>
<seg id="6">Do you think that they will not repeat the mistakes the Bush has did? </seg>
<seg id="7">The mistakes of has not delay in? </seg>
<seg id="8">Bush will advise on? </seg>
<seg id="9">From their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The US Vice President Dick Cheney, says that Usama Bin Ladin, dead or alive, I want to watch. </seg>
<seg id="2">He said that Usama Bin Ladin is hidden in a hard and tough areas and their organization for effective has, If Usama Bin Ladin is arrested, dead or alive, then this also this it. </seg>
<seg id="3">America for the arrest of Usama Bin Ladin on and Osama bin Laden is determined for one. </seg>
<seg id="4">The arrest of Usama Dick Cheney will position would be? </seg>
<seg id="5">Their claim. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">All rounder Shahid Afridi as Qaid - i - Azam Trophy Cricket player in PIA and Habib Bank on the first day of the match after the end of the game of a clash with the spectators. </seg>
<seg id="2">The UBL on the ground, Shahid Afridi, play the match after drawing room, a large number of spectators, he has collected </seg>
<seg id="3">On one occasion the spectators a hand with him and his picture of Shahid Afridi, on which it has said the picture tomorrow, however, take the spectators on Afridi has spoken in it and before talks are in several people present there has Pakistani address provincial concerns. </seg>
<seg id="4">After that, Shahid Afridi said that it is being made an issue of prayer at this time, I was quickly, </seg>
<seg id="5">However, in the spectators will, from </seg>
<seg id="6">This attitude on Shahid Afridi will ask you. </seg>
<seg id="7">We inform their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has once again that Pakistan is accused of the environment of the war of is </seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan state terrorism and the policy of use. </seg>
<seg id="3">In New Delhi, Chief Ministers while addressing the conference, Manmohan Singh said that the neighboring Muslim countries, particularly Pakistan is backed </seg>
<seg id="4">Attacks and Mumbai terrorists of the navy and adopt a safe from the Indian Coast Guard. </seg>
<seg id="5">The Indian Prime Minister said that the attack on 22th November in Mumbai Lashkar - e - Taiyba has. </seg>
<seg id="6">He further said that terrorists new techniques and modern transportation system, we are using on the Line of Control, from where, we will also strictly infiltration is He said that any terrorism will not be tolerated, and it is our policy. </seg>
<seg id="7">The Indian Prime Minister to this allegation of how you are? </seg>
<seg id="8">The internal squabbles movements like Indian anxiety Mazhar? </seg>
<seg id="9">How India at the whims of the threatening attitude numerous? </seg>
<seg id="10">From their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Zubair - Khan, Karachi. </seg>
<seg id="2">This is a very tragedy so that the Israeli massacre of Palestinians are the same situation is also but Kashmir as the head of the Council is not new. </seg>
<seg id="3">All organizations, which are present in Kashmir and Palestine that they should continue to its war and while every kind of aggression continue a one day of his martyrdom color will </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Israeli air attack on Gaza, are continuing till now, hundreds of Palestinian men, women and children have been martyred. </seg>
<seg id="2">Hamas important political, including the wife and children have been martyred. </seg>
<seg id="3">On the other hand, the security council meeting ended without any decision. </seg>
<seg id="4">In the meeting, against Israel Libya and other Arab countries presented by the resolutions passed by the opposition. </seg>
<seg id="5">Palestinian civilian population many the bombardment of the Israeli planes. </seg>
<seg id="6">Mumbai on the incidents of the entire world was crying, but the blaze Israeli attacks on the, including America, Britain, this not? </seg>
<seg id="7">The countries are silent important Why? </seg>
<seg id="8">The world of double standards on what you want. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Saeed, New York. </seg>
<seg id="2">In my opinion, it is the most that our nation read them know that not only where their money is being tax by the government to fulfil its responsibilities in interest is such gas and electricity crisis. </seg>
<seg id="3">Because people who have the role of the elected from all know, </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan and breadth of gas and electricity crisis situation is </seg>
<seg id="2">On the other hand, from January 2st in the prices of gas 8 was while some cities of the country in the non - availability of severe problems for the people is. </seg>
<seg id="3">Pakistan, industrial and business circles, in the absence of gas and electricity crisis on such, rioting and demonstrations are going on violence, </seg>
<seg id="4">The industrialists factories ultimatum to stop. </seg>
<seg id="5">On the other hand, 2 to 22 hours in Karachi in the load shedding of the people. </seg>
<seg id="6">About life industrial crippled. </seg>
<seg id="7">In this regard, the government institutions at a allegations and his. </seg>
<seg id="8">The prices of gas and electricity talking to the nation that is not? </seg>
<seg id="9">The resolution of the issues of why not attention is being given? </seg>
<seg id="10">The government of the wheel jam that is not? </seg>
<seg id="11">This crisis control you for immediate steps proposal will be? </seg>
<seg id="12">From their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Imran, in Madina Munawara, I want to say that the people in the ruling. </seg>
<seg id="2">It is surprising that I public government the slogan of the people to people giving </seg>
<seg id="3">Gas to the wrath of petrol is not a </seg>
<seg id="4">The government institutions is not give any control </seg>
<seg id="5">Law and the situation is deteriorating day by day, this country mercy Allah give their </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Of the New Year. </seg>
<seg id="2">Last year, rioting and political and downs of the year, with regard to terrorism, it will be remembered. </seg>
<seg id="3">President Musharraf power of separation from President Bush and eight - year - old Bush, the end of a shoe rain and democratic government in Pakistan, the establishment of unexpected disaster, earthquake in Balochistan, all over the world, recession financial crisis. </seg>
<seg id="4">Now the arrival of the new year is coming years you how to see? </seg>
<seg id="5">You near the geographical color or political situation What will the strategy of what would be? </seg>
<seg id="6">What elimination of terrorism in any progress is hopeful? </seg>
<seg id="7">Pakistan will be in a crisis? </seg>
<seg id="8">What towards the relations between Pakistan and India will adopt? </seg>
<seg id="9">Surgical full or war, there is a possibility of? </seg>
<seg id="10">The new year expectations from you? </seg>
<seg id="11">From their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">President 8 years America on to the government after the White House with the President camp office Camp David to the White House, so that the new president Barak According to the wishes of the affairs and ready, </seg>
<seg id="2">Bush eight - year - old during in America in the attack on the World Trade Center and historic destruction, and then Pentagon attack on the global war against terrorism in Afghanistan and the military operation in Iraq while the forces of various countries in this war, and in this war, the American resources the use of Bush were memorable examples. </seg>
<seg id="3">This war, the US from the date of the worst economic and had to face financial crisis. </seg>
<seg id="4">In this war, the world damage and uncertain? </seg>
<seg id="5">What President Bush policies succeed? </seg>
<seg id="6">President Bush, during the era of you of opinion? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Indian government has the Indian cricket team visiting Pakistan stopped. </seg>
<seg id="2">The Indian cricket team visiting Pakistan in three tests and five one - day matches, a 20 - 20 play the match. </seg>
<seg id="3">The Vice President of the Indian Cricket Board, Rajeev Shukla, told GEO News, while talking to the board has said that the government of Pakistan to visit was asked for between the two countries, however, the present situation of Azad Kashmir is not possible due to the visit. </seg>
<seg id="4">What the current political situation of the Indian government to visit and cricket team has the right to cancel, playing politics from the should not to? </seg>
<seg id="5">The decision of the Indian government cricket for not harmful? </seg>
<seg id="6">In India, the security situation deteriorating of cricket team tour continue, the Indian team visiting Pakistan can not Why? </seg>
<seg id="7">You of opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Salman, Karachi. </seg>
<seg id="2">People who are proud to India </seg>
<seg id="3">And the video of his used or there are now be open India that how many people do respect correspondents </seg>
<seg id="4">I Adnan Sami of or ICNA, remember, in which he said that in the Pakistani citizenship is not my British </seg>
<seg id="5">The Adnan Sami that for the first time in Pakistan because there also did not become respect, </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Farid Ahmad. </seg>
<seg id="2">Karachi. </seg>
<seg id="3">After the attack Mumbai attitude changed is </seg>
<seg id="4">Singh has, or reaction in this situation is that Pakistan and Pakistani hate </seg>
<seg id="5">To know that Adnan Sami got with the song are now where cow and where with India, Adnan Sami to live in the upcoming should not need is here </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Mohammad Alam, Shamshad - </seg>
<seg id="2">Karachi, Singh on the statement of only write so that they will also like Pakistan. vajpayee's optimism color is </seg>
<seg id="3">The opportunity to all Pakistanis has said that in India is so how much you understand the mentality of. </seg>
<seg id="4">Mumbai after the incident of these statements have been increased hatred is now the famous Sami against poison. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Foreign news agency, according to Iraq at visiting U. S. President George W. Bush Prime Minister Noor Malikey along with his office situated in Baghdad in a press conference at this time, the situation has ridiculous when a journalist Iraqi President Bush said, while addressing the dog at. </seg>
<seg id="2">After this, the journalist a of Bush, President Bush has thrown expertise from a before his head and their you him. </seg>
<seg id="3">The second to US flag. </seg>
<seg id="4">The security personnel journalist, to the. </seg>
<seg id="5">On this occasion, President Bush has said that I know it has not why do, 10 I was not there a problem. </seg>
<seg id="6">You think of the Iraqi people by President Bush expressed was not angry? </seg>
<seg id="7">This incident, what would you? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In Mumbai terrorist after the incidents of the relations between India and Pakistan in the tension serious situation readily at this time, when the Indian Air Force planes sectors in Lahore and Kashmir of the Pakistan Air violation of the area. </seg>
<seg id="2">Pak Air Force of counter action due to the Indian plane to return to forced the. </seg>
<seg id="3">According to the sources, both the Indian plane arms and ammunition and bombs will experience. </seg>
<seg id="4">In the present situation as tense following the first incident. </seg>
<seg id="5">Pak Air Force has said that the air defense of the country to fully prepared. </seg>
<seg id="6">The information minister Sherry Rehman has said that the Indian officials has accepted that violation of the air space, however, it was a mistake. </seg>
<seg id="7">Pakistan military sources of this incident, the as serious. </seg>
<seg id="8">You think really in India and Pakistan air attack on plans? </seg>
<seg id="9">India is correct that stand against this mistake or from the purpose of the Pak Air Force? </seg>
<seg id="10">This incident between the two countries in the cause of tension will not? </seg>
<seg id="11">From their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Mrs. Benazir Bhutto Shaheed after the death of human rights at international award was his son and Peoples Party, the chairman of Bilawal Bhutto Zardari has received. </seg>
<seg id="2">The President of the UN General Assembly in office, during the meeting of Pakistan in a ceremony of former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto to human rights for his services in this award to Nawaz. </seg>
<seg id="3">On behalf of the UN resolution of human rights despite the birthday was celebrated on December 22. </seg>
<seg id="4">On this occasion, for the human rights to work in the personalities and institutions are being given awards in America of Benazir Bhutto as well as the former Attorney General and Clark up throughout the world human rights organization to work for the International Human Rights Watch are included. </seg>
<seg id="5">On this occasion, Pakistan Ambassador Abdullah Haroon Hussain and other Pakistani diplomatic senior officials were also present. </seg>
<seg id="6">Former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto Shaheed this award will ask you. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- are. </seg>
<seg id="2">. </seg>
<seg id="3">It is true that he was but we also remember that he has many innocent people in Karachi blood shed worldwide, on which they were proud that this Naseerullah Babar, has done a good job, </seg>
<seg id="4">After were completely in </seg>
<seg id="5">But it is true that he has his own party of senior people Nazar way and his son to a representative of the Peoples Party Channa, this is democracy,? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Jimmi daughter - Noor, Karachi, this news of this is called has proved that called of with. </seg>
<seg id="2">But, until the iron axe similar actives. group not axe on the can not cut </seg>
<seg id="3">The way our rulers is in its secret are due to the same new country. </seg>
<seg id="4">Our rulers, instructed the. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The UN Security Council panel has Hafiz Mohammad Saeed, including three Pakistani citizens and Jamaat - ud - Dawa, including five organizations in the name of included in the list of terrorists. </seg>
<seg id="2">The security council of the Taliban and Al - Qaida Pakistanis in the name of the committee, which included in the list of terrorists to approved in the JuD Mohammad Saeed, banned organization Lashkar - e - Taiyba operations Chief Zaki Rehman, leader of the treasury department, Haji Muhammad Ashraf. </seg>
<seg id="3">In addition to this, a Saudi citizens even the name of terrorists in the list of. </seg>
<seg id="4">These organizations in Kashmir, Pasban Jamaat ul Dawa, Al - Rasheed Trust International trust. </seg>
<seg id="5">Member countries and organizations immediately eye on every source personalities of all frozen assets and travel ban would strongly and they will be arrested. </seg>
<seg id="6">They would face cases. </seg>
<seg id="7">This Indian under the influence of sanctions propaganda, not? </seg>
<seg id="8">India without any evidence of Mumbai their imposed on organizations Why? </seg>
<seg id="9">India terrorist organizations present not? </seg>
<seg id="10">In India, the minorities tyranny international institutions not know? </seg>
<seg id="11">We inform their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Eid and spokesman of followers and on Eid [a cow] following the on the practice of Qurbani animals. </seg>
<seg id="2">On this licking its peak in a period when the price hike on political as I, and the poor their According to the preparation of Eid and different ways to their relatives of Eid. </seg>
<seg id="3">We also a blog, you are providing occasion that their loved ones messages short in the form of Eid appreciation. </seg>
<seg id="4">You Eid to verses through can also congratulated. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Jilani, </seg>
<seg id="2">Karachi, our rulers, it should understand that they are raids into western Iraq against Pakistan, which is the same kind of oppression, but the parties are love Pakistan are </seg>
<seg id="3">If the war, Pakistan will shoulder </seg>
<seg id="4">When their love would realize, only a protest will not get some from politics, I think the war between the two of decisive, there is a possibility of so that. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>
