<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" sysid="site13_single_constrained" trglang="English">
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Support Proposal of France </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The committee meeting on Friday in the Parliament House on Monday, the Chairman of the Committee, Mushahid Hussein Syed was held under the chairmanship of the Government has been suggested that all the political parties in the relief goods sent a parliamentary committee of the representatives of the Palestine. </seg>
<seg id="3"> After the meeting, while talking to the representatives of the media committee Syed Mushahid Hussein said that France has given by the proposal is welcomed in which it has been said that Israel should immediately ceasefire in the Gaza Strip and allow the relief works for the affected people. </seg>
<seg id="4"> He said the Fsltenaon by Israel against humanity as crime and said that all the countries should condemned these attacks. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Mr. Moshahid Hussaid double standards of the countries of the world criticized the target of making said that those who are talking against terrorism, but now it from Israel are silent on the attacks on the Palestinians. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The External Affairs Fslten, the chairman of the Senate Standing Committee on the "of the leaders of Muslim Mslh on Srdmhr control [LoC] also made the target of criticism. </seg>
<seg id="7"> He said that the United States has expressed the hope that the newly elected President Barak Abamh during the last 100 days of his government will address the Muslims so that the created between the United States and Muslim Ummah due to be finished. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Mushahid Hussein Syed said that the Muslim created between Islam and the West of relating to space for not only emergency steps to resolve issues like Palestine and Kashmir should be resolved. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Malik Imadud Khan, Minister of State for External Affairs Committee told that the meeting of the foreign ministers of the Organization of Islamic Countries for the participation in Saudi Arabia. </seg>
<seg id="10"> It is an emergency meeting of the attacks on Fslten by Israel has been called as a result. He said that "from the Palestinian informed and in this connection, the Government is in touch with the leaders of other countries. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Minister of State for External Affairs said that the Mslh of Palestine should be resolved according to UN resolutions. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Two reporters belonging to the Arab countries, also attended the meeting and the meeting, he said about the present situation of Palestine in. </seg>
<seg id="13"> On the other hand, the International in Islamabad University students held a protest demonstration against the Israeli attacks on the Palestine. </seg>
<seg id="14"> The protesters held up banners and Ktbe were also raised on which the slogans against Israel. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> to Avoid Flu Daetng to Avoid </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The American scientists were on this information Chohon has come forth. After experiences </seg>
<seg id="3"> The experiences show that the food at least Kylwryz has been kept on Chohon flue virus in the ability to deal with less. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The old research proved to be baseless that there would face starvation in fever, is to be better. </seg>
<seg id="5"> According to the scientists eat well. During the fever </seg>
<seg id="6"> Mshagn state of the investigation of the university has said that in the recent to Chohon infection of the ability to fight with less likely to die of was found and also increased and food it to the security force against flu virus in the Chohon was more. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Professor Alzbth Gardnr according to the people who Daetng flu, not only will soon be affected but he was recovering will also take a long time. </seg>
<seg id="8"> He also said that those people who flu has the vaccine. He also Daetng during the last few months the winter season should avoid. </seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Listen to 2008 Madona for Best. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> This shows the Madona Albm &apos; signs Kenda &apos; was given a made the basis and the Ukraine will be Jpsy or civil Bdw$ band and including two songs with the Jstn Tmbrlen. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In an old Rysng was on staging a car. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Salaen Daonz listen to two of the profit of eight thousand was most successful show in which Taes million Chhiasth get million dollars. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Canadian show &apos; Takng Chansz &apos; visited 24 countries, while Madona only in 17 countries who were in the past eight years. The international visit. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The Director of the Glokaron show Jymy was called King, who didn&apos;t see &apos; Spaes his&apos;, &apos; the Union of also visit arrangements. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The Madona to set up in the two thousand six its has broken the record. </seg>
<seg id="8"> He said, Knfashn listen to two thousand six Knsrts&apos; Anees million in Syntys Kmaee million dollars. </seg>
<seg id="9"> The Polstr marrow by the third which has declared the most successful singer 17 million Kmaee 60 million dollars. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Brws Sprngsten 16 million, 60 million dollars are on the fourth and the fifth position for and 12 million in their of six million dollars. </seg>
<seg id="11"> According to this "two thousand to eight people in North America in the Knsrt and to participate in the programs and the only why people participated in Prgramon, which was ready to buy tickets at expensive prices. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The United States views in a Madona and 8% increase in the price of the tickets for the show by it, three hundred Dalrka tickets were sold. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Polstr is editor of "become Bwngywny said that the international economic Ksad Ke Bhao in light of two thousand to for the glue proved to be a good eight years. </seg>
<seg id="14"> He said to the two thousand 9 for two and Sprngsten that this year, the Albm have released a year forecast to be predictions. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Coalition Taliban: Ban on Education. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> At the President of North Waziristan Miran Shah and other local Hafiz Gul Bahadur group in the Tehsils the Taliban government and other government has distributed relief Pamphleteer in which these institutions have been made to in which the boys and girls&apos; education is being paid. Mixed </seg>
<seg id="3"> Five Pamphleteer has said that if the coalition educational institutions were not stop, started action will be taken against them. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Pamphleteer in stating that the government for the aid and other educational matters of the women Bnoane identity cards and restrictions on women in every district has forbade from the offices of NADRA. </seg>
<seg id="5"> On behalf of the local Taliban ban on women Bnoane identity card was announced at a time when there is Nzerankm in North Waziristan support program for the offices of Nadrh, nearly two hundred and women have collected for the identity card Bnoane form. </seg>
<seg id="6"> According to the local people Pamphleteer issued by Taliban in all mosques of North Waziristan on Laoudspakr was read and. </seg>
<seg id="7"> However, it has not been mentioned in the letter that the ban on different educational institutions will or not. </seg>
<seg id="8"> According to the Pamphleteer after this announcement for the education or identity cards to make any woman was under the office, or the school to catch the woman and in the case of the family members of the divine will be punished. </seg>
<seg id="9"> In addition to this, in the district of Bannu police say that on Sunday, the robbers Miranshah on the road of a land mine explosion as a result of which is a pedestrain was killed and another injured. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The wounded have been admitted in civil hospital. Bannu </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> &apos; Stop Targeted Experiences More Dead Bodies Have been Recovered. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> According to the police, the president on Sunday morning at Myngwrh areas and green Sohrab Khan Chowk, two dead bodies were found who were self departing to the head. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Those killed Y belonged to the Frontier Corps and is being. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Witnesses say that a letter from near the dead bodies were also received a in which had been warned that the day before 11 a.m. on these were also raised his death will be responsible for themselves. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The local people has said that the dead bodies remained lying in the market by 11 a.m. after security officials, however the dead bodies were taken Hpstal to. </seg>
<seg id="6"> President at Myngwrh in and around during the past few weeks there is dangerous extent in the target King incidents in to increase. </seg>
<seg id="7"> There is in which the civilians including women and security personnel have been killed. </seg>
<seg id="8"> According to local media until now this type of incidents in more than 30 people have been killed. </seg>
<seg id="9"> So far no group has accepted the responsibility of the killings their. </seg>
<seg id="10"> local Taliban spokesman on Saturday in Swat Muslim Khan told BBC that were received on Friday in three bodies of their companions were in which the Taliban commander of Daolea Rafi were among the dead body of Allah. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Muslim Khan said that the Rafi, security forces were in custody for the last one and a half months. </seg>
<seg id="12"> He said that when the local Taliban were killed, before the issuance of a notice to while on the other hand, Myngwrh on these incidents of common citizens are very anxious. In </seg>
<seg id="13"> The local people has said that in Myngwrh security forces have deployed heavy contingent of but in spite of the fact that people in attacks are increasing. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Benazir Bhutto in Bkhtaor Gaeaka Tributes. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The voice of Bkhtaor was recorded a Rep in a new musical sang (and) and the post on the Taob has been. </seg>
<seg id="3"> five minutes on the Ngme pictures of Benazir Bhutto and her Klps have been given. </seg>
<seg id="4"> 18 year old Bkhtaor Edinburgh University student. </seg>
<seg id="5"> He felt about the poetry and Gaeaka is equally. </seg>
<seg id="6"> It is being said that he has apparently encourage your mother Shoqah after the Ngme started to sing. </seg>
<seg id="7"> While presenting the tributes to his mother he has said that he is intelligent and had a &apos; you, you have all work in a way. </seg>
<seg id="8"> about the incident of December 27, he said that you to his Keqrab Mari, was shot at the age of 54 years we have Sealg, three children family includes his. </seg>
<seg id="9"> The entire nation Kebger you or hope and all of them are present in the heart of Dhrknon. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Bkhtaor Benazir Bhutto, 20 year old, children of Belwell Bhutto is at No. 2. After </seg>
<seg id="11"> They are interested to start the music. </seg>
<seg id="12"> He said that it is being before his mother on the return of the US Grymy through a journalist friend in award developed and interests and Rypr PF anybody was expressed the desire to meet with, but it could not meet. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Some of the Bkhtaor poetry Sindhi newspapers, is also was published, but the voice of the first time the Taob being heard. Through the </seg>
<seg id="14"> Some workers of Benazir Bhutto and with the land of Bkhtaor Rep sang CDs of Bnoana started. </seg>
<seg id="15"> On the other hand, the spokesman of the Pakistan Peoples Party Farhatullah Babar has confirmed that the present at the Taob Ngme poetry and Bkhtaor. </seg>
<seg id="16"> He said that it is a sad on phone from Islamabad daughter of their courage to mother is paid tribute to the government of Pakistan has been issued on the TV network. </seg>
<seg id="17"> a PPP spokesman in Islamabad, Farhatullah Babar, has said that the Bkhtaor CDs of Ngme, to distribute the retain their program is not. </seg>
<seg id="18"> He said that in a few months ago book on the Web site of his party Joan year comity Belwell Bhutto was a fake account of Zardari or who have been finished. After </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Ajmal Butchers, Pakistan Is: Information Minister. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The Federal Minister for Information and Broadcasting, Sherry Rehman has sent the BBC Urdu service in a message S M S Ajmal butchers, while confirming the leadership of, is much more investigations are underway. said that </seg>
<seg id="3"> Before this, advisor to the prime minister of the country Rahman refused to Pakistani citizenship. The </seg>
<seg id="4"> He said that the record of the people, Nadrh from Ajmal was found no record of them. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The latest could not know about the announcement that the government of Pakistan has now changed its stand on what basis, Ajmal confirmed the leadership of the butcher. </seg>
<seg id="6"> However, according to the spokesman of the Foreign Ministry of Ajmal butcher Interior Ministry has confirmed the leadership. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Prior to this, the BBC Urdu service and a few other newspapers and TV channels had Ajmal butcher belong to Punjab from Okara, Fareed Kot of district town of it. </seg>
<seg id="8"> However, the Government had been refused to. </seg>
<seg id="9"> However, it is not clear that this Ajmal is related to this, Fareed Kot or any other area. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Rockets Fired from Lebanon, - Bombing. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The Israeli army and the television broadcast told the representatives of the media that Lebanon in the region, the Israeli four rockets were bombarded, out of which one on the soil of northern town Nharia down in which two people were injured. losing </seg>
<seg id="3"> rockets launched from Lebanon in reply to the Israeli TWP the bombing of Lebanon. </seg>
<seg id="4"> It is not clear that the attack, or the Hezbollah in Lebanon behind the scene of the Palestinian groups. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The Lebanese government has said that it is trying to find out about that who is behind the rocket attacks. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The BBC correspondent in the current crisis in the region has declared a very dangerous turn. For </seg>
<seg id="7"> The BBC Jyrymy is editor of the Middle East boen according to the rocket attacks by the risk to spread the war has increased. </seg>
<seg id="8"> For the last few days that it was feared that the operation in the Gaza Strip and Lebanon in the north along the border with Israel not to be there. </seg>
<seg id="9"> On the other hand, on Wednesday, on the night between Israeli air force 60 air attacks on the Gaza Strip. </seg>
<seg id="10"> According to the Israeli army in these attacks offices of the police of Hamas, explosions, on the weapons, in the rocket fire and weapons of Hamas workers were targeted. closed </seg>
<seg id="11"> in addition to the Israeli army and air attacks on Gaza with the navy TWP continued bombing throughout the night. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The Palestinian sources said that the air attacks in Gaza City in a mosque destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="13"> According to unconfirmed reports of the Israeli army tanks, who was by helicopter air help Khan Yunis progress towards the region. </seg>
<seg id="14"> This battle continued for the last 12 days in seven hundred Palestinian which include a large number of women and children have been killed. </seg>
<seg id="15"> while on the other hand, the Israeli army 11 soldiers were also killed. </seg>
<seg id="16"> Israel&apos;s security forces have confirmed that a top military personnel Amos Galad ceasefire Cairo are being taken to resolve the conditions. </seg>
<seg id="17"> A delegation of Hamas also parallel for talks with the ambassadors of Egypt Cairo is going to. </seg>
<seg id="18"> In addition to this, the leader of the Palestinian Authority, Mahmood Abbas are reaching Cairo on Friday. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> My Heart Broken, I Have Returned To. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Dr. Richard Batsta said that he has eight years ago to save the lives of his wife, Danl its them as they had been given. </seg>
<seg id="3"> According to the news agency, AFP, Dr. Batsta says that his wife have donated their kidneys to change the SLH that these fraud and to re-establish its relations with an and now the approach to divorce. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Dr. Batsta, a local newspaper, in an interview with the daily Jang, said that the alleged Meashqe my heart hole in and who is so far. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Dr. Richard Batsta&apos;s lawyer, though, according to the Bastsa their demand the withdrawal of them are but in the kidneys to those subsidies. worth of </seg>
<seg id="6"> According to his wife, their stand in the next few days will be presented in front of a judge. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> 140 Kilo 9 Years Old, Labstr Free. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Today, joint Labstr &apos; the two weeks ago, a had been caught from the sea. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The company of the city of food and 100 dollars there. In </seg>
<seg id="4"> and as soon as possible. Labstr pictures of the was started to use for the advertisement. </seg>
<seg id="5"> However, for the protection of the animals, make a working group, has demanded to leave the Labstr as a result of which it will be left to the sea. In </seg>
<seg id="6"> The US in Canada had been caught from the sea after which the city Kryb and the seafood company will pass 10 days. In </seg>
<seg id="7"> The age of Labstr can be assessed from the people. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The number of manager Kath Oalnta intention to say that these Labstr to any harm to do not and it will continue in the objective of the goods to provide the interests of the consumers. </seg>
<seg id="9"> The protection of the animals, belonging to make Angrd decision has said that the number of Nywkrk is appreciable and is an example for those who are in the famous animals, tank or want to keep them alive by abal want to. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> With Help of Mobile for Child. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> When the Ntala officials about the Maltaes shows, MASA Chaosts athol of the city police officer and AGR I came into play the forces. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The mobile of baby GP, with the help of the present in the right places know of the accused. </seg>
<seg id="4"> However, Gwkl Street organization with the help of the discovered that the daughter is in a hotel. </seg>
<seg id="5"> one week earlier Ntala grandmother, the Maltaes Ntala the legal the supervision of parents were taken. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The police chief of athol Tamotha Andrsn told BBC, he said that he is the Ntala of will never back and then he went to leave the state. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Police has contacted Mrs. Mltaes but when he did not Ntala back according to promise, the police have Ntala through mobile phone. decided to find it </seg>
<seg id="8"> two thousand five in the United States or law is that the companies of 100 meters to provide mobile service Dwry the 67 percent and three of 100 meters of 95% of Kalrz Dwry provide Lokashn. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Hamid Karzai on Tour of India. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Hamid Karzai Kagzshth five months in the second Indian tour. </seg>
<seg id="3"> It is being hoped that the Prime Minister Manmohan during his meeting with extremists in Mumbai, after the attack will talk about the situation. </seg>
<seg id="4"> During the visit he Mumbai attacks on Afghanistan and the sentiments of the people and expressed their solidarity with India wants to. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Karzai during the visit of extremism apart from the mutual trade will be discussed. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Islamic extremism with Nmtneke for mutual cooperation between the two countries will be discussed. </seg>
<seg id="7"> President Hamid Karzai during my last tour of India has said that according to the relations between India and Afghanistan will not be let. "between </seg>
<seg id="8"> He also said that both India and Afghanistan the terrorism and the body is facing a challenge and life activities. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Both countries and the entire region Dniaman peace and stability is beneficial for all. </seg>
<seg id="10"> &apos; We his defeat believe that both countries and the entire world is united and can face the menace of terrorism. </seg>
<seg id="11"> It should be remembered that last year, in the attack on the Indian embassy in Kabul Karzai for the secret agencies of Pakistan was held responsible for the ISI. </seg>
<seg id="12"> A high in this attack FSA including four Indian were killed. </seg>
<seg id="13"> after the attack on the consulate Karzai during his visit to India, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has said that the attack was attacked, India and Afghanistan&apos;s friendship, we agreed to the fact that we are under the relations between the would not allow. " </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The Special Judge for Attack, Shnoaea Mumbai. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The Mumbai Police Commissioner Hasan Ghafoor said that the extremists in Mumbai during the attacks were arrested for only Ajmal Amir butchers, who has registered a case against the accused of the Shnoaea the lea will be under the supervision of Thliana. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Before this, in this regard Ajol Nkm has been appointed lawyer. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Ajmal butchers, currently in police custody and police is being hoped that January 24th before the charge will destroy vested entered against them. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Ajmal butchers have no lawyers to defend himself. </seg>
<seg id="6"> in a letter addressed to the butchers has appealed to the legal aid. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Pakistan, India has joined the Pakistani extremists in the Mumbai blasts of evidence given delegated. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Pakistan has accepted that Ajmal butcher Pakistani citizens. </seg>
<seg id="9"> According to the case, the police Ajmal and his companion Abu Ismail (. The Chief Hymnt Krkre, additional Commissioner Ashok police Kamte, including the police inspector expert of Ankaountr Vijay Salskr after the killing of 6 police officials were they ran away after snatching a Skod who later, by Marg Grgam Chopata caught from his possession. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The police action in the death of Ismail Khan had been and police arrested Ajmal to live. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The case was represented by Ajmal for so far has not named any lawyer. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The lawyer of the legal aid cell was nominated to the Danish Mota on moral grounds, he had refused to the case. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Two the lawyers of a political party and opposition protests after the taken back their names. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Constitutional Amendment: &apos; Committee will be Formed. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> on Tuesday in a conference on environmental changes in Islamabad after the address while talking to the representatives of the media, he said that in this regard will be called the session of parliamentary party in the formation of such a committee will be. </seg>
<seg id="3"> He said that the Muttahida Qaumi Movement (MQM) has so far from the 17th amendment for the eradication of constitutional amendment bill was presented in the National Assembly and other political parties also in this regard constitutional amendment Bill will be presented in the parliament. </seg>
<seg id="4"> He said that the 17th amendment has also for the eradication of Pakistan People&apos;s Party has also sent a draft all the political parties and the Committee will also examined the constitution. </seg>
<seg id="5"> In response to a question, he said that the balance of power between the president and the prime minister will be decided in parliament. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The prime minister said that all empowered to make decisions in parliament. </seg>
<seg id="7"> In response to another question, he said that the ex-President General Pervez Musharraf (from the post of army chief with reference to leave the role of political parties and ex-Prime Minister of Pakistan Peoples Party chairperson Benazir Bhutto has also played an important role, who has urged the international community that the former President General Pervez Musharraf emphasize to take off his uniform. </seg>
<seg id="8"> He said that the elected vice president, which are in favor of democracy and the Pakistan Baeadn and the services of the parliament, President of Pakistan had the honor of being the Pakistan Red. </seg>
<seg id="9"> After the incident the Mumbai from the Indian government every kind of relationship with Pakistan to cut in response to a question about the threat of Yusuf Raza Geelani said that at this time the Indian rulers of the people are under extreme pressure, as a result of which they are such statements. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Journalists Protest against Dismissal of </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The journalists in Islamabad on Tuesday Tnzm &apos; R was under the auspices of the BJP, journalists in front of the press club in Islamabad from the TV channels and newspapers and the workers of a large number of employees Brtrfaon on the owners of media and shouted slogans against the government and. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Addressing the protestors took the biggest organization of Pakistan Federal Union of Journalists senior member of Mkrf Shamsi said that till yesterday, who were jurists do our protest on the streets with politics today, it is a ruler and are present in the house, but the owners of due to the fear of a certain groups are not do anything for the rights of the journalists </seg>
<seg id="4"> He said that the newspaper owners have to talk of human rights in the secret agencies and bagar is the camp where billions of rupees in spite of his additional activists have very little help and Senktron dismissed and they are being killed economically. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The example of Lahore a private television channel five before us, which is a member of the suicide, not getting to pay four months, and even today, many other victims Brtrfaon and months due to non-payment of salaries are spending their lives of the problem. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He said that the newspaper and TV journalists should direct action against owners and a permanent protest in front of the parliament for the rights of the camp. need </seg>
<seg id="7"> Mkrf Shamsi to the governor of Punjab, Salman Tather, they said that the target of criticism of the Urdu daily &apos; today the employees&apos; is being without any notice by Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The daily Jinnah, Daily News, five business, plus TV channel and TV has also dozens of workers have been dismissed </seg>
<seg id="9"> The Secretary General of the PTCL (Jui addressing the protestors, Mazhar Abbas said that in the country today press and journalists are the workers of the black day against Brtrfaon are celebrating for getting their rights and journalist tied black bandanas around Bazon in the parliament session will be. </seg>
<seg id="10"> According to the Mazhar Abbas Pchasa percent of Pakistan in the newspapers and television channels workers and journalists are being exploited where they are working without any of the agreement. </seg>
<seg id="11"> He said that till now more than 200 journalists and workers from the newspapers and TV channels are being carried out, and it is feared that during the current year more than hundreds of workers said that the economic crisis and owners will destroy dismissed. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The Nekha Mazhar Abbas will continue until the movement of the media persons on Kaegee employees suspended until now is, the workers of wages to determine the seventh implementation of the wage board award, newspapers and TV channels of the employees of the several months have not been stopped from payment of salaries. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> 11-member Cabinet Has Taken Oath. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> In the new cabinet Ateeq Ahmad Khan, former prime minister of anti-Muslim Conference Group 6, two of Pakistan People&apos;s Party, two of the Pakistan Muslim League and a minister of the Muttahida Qaumi Movement (MQM). </seg>
<seg id="3"> A woman in 11-member cabinet minister is also and they belong to Ateeq group. anti-Muslim conference </seg>
<seg id="4"> The ruling alliance has said that in the next week will be extended and it is expected that more than a dozen cabinet minister should be included in it may be recalled that at the beginning of this month, the opponents of Ateeq Khan have through the confidence motion was removed from the post of Qadri and the new Prime Minister Sardar Yaqoob Khan were elected. </seg>
<seg id="5"> These ministers of departments will be announced later. </seg>
<seg id="6"> On the occasion of the oath taking ceremony of the Pakistan Peoples&apos; Party activists have raised slogans in favor of former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The Virus from Five Lakh Consumers Affected. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> first identified in the 8 October 2000 to the virus Kwnfykr, down and up and Kado is like names. </seg>
<seg id="3"> are using Microsoft for dealing with the virus traced was issued, but in spite of the fact that one around five hundred and a Mymwry Astk have been affected by this. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The experts have said that the number of computers affect a more time. </seg>
<seg id="5"> This to deal with the government are using Microsoft &apos; of M S zero 8 zero people Sywn &apos; there is a need to use pass. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Lakhs of computers are using Microsoft, has said that the establishment of the virus -- mine was file &apos; services Dat-a search of Kesc, and it is included in the code. </seg>
<seg id="7"> After the system of this virus -- mine was Foldr, in the the kind of away. </seg>
<seg id="8"> This virus file laws, even the name. </seg>
<seg id="9"> then -- mine was Registry of changing the details of the sympathies. </seg>
<seg id="10"> After this virus was active in an issue that produces a &apos; NHS TT PIA has become as Sarwar, and the Rastor point of changing the sympathies. </seg>
<seg id="11"> After that, the Hykrz from the web site of the as download files. </seg>
<seg id="12"> are using Microsoft has said that this virus in various countries of the world has been affected. The computers </seg>
<seg id="13"> These countries, Brazil, China, Russia, India, the United States and Britain are included. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Indian Information on Jldrport Demanding Installations. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Home Ministry on Saturday in a meeting of the representatives of the media persons after talking to India, he said that by the </seg>
<seg id="3"> Information in this matter will help to investigate. </seg>
<seg id="4"> He said that India and Pakistan is an independent country on the information received from their investigation in any country from </seg>
<seg id="5"> We will not accept Republic. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He said that India&apos;s information, in addition to other information received from are also akhta. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Home Minister said that the law enforcing agencies 124 members of a banned organization under the apprehension disorder was taken into custody. </seg>
<seg id="8"> and if there is any proof against some of people get action will be taken against them, while the innocent people should be released. </seg>
<seg id="9"> In response to a question, he said that the arrested a man will not be handed over to India and the people of Pakistan action will be taken. According to the laws against </seg>
<seg id="10"> He said that the people of the action against the FIA is under the law. </seg>
<seg id="11"> In response to a question, he said that the law enforcing agencies in connection with the people involved in Mumbai incident in 42 days are akhta information that he is hopeful that the international community, including India Meloma on the investigation for some time to Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="12"> He said that the government has repeated the same that the Mumbai investigating the incident a Tffasha team should be formed. For </seg>
<seg id="13"> It should be remembered that under the leadership of additional director general FIA has constituted a three-member team Tfasha that India Mumbai attacks on behalf of the </seg>
<seg id="14"> on the information given to Pakistan in connection with the investigation has been. </seg>
<seg id="15"> In India, the Pakistani High Commissioner, Malik Shahid has met with the President Asif Ali Zardari in which the Pakistani president has clarified that if any individual or group was found involved in Mumbai, the laws and action will be taken against India will not be handed over to any while the Indian leadership India for the handing over of people involved in this incident is pressurizing continuously on the Pakistan. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> "Anything Possible in United States. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Mr. Obamh on 20 January will take oath as Choalasoan, President of the United States. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The 16th Ibrahim Lankan President of the United States in Washington in the memory of building construction of music and stand on you addressed a Knsrt </seg>
<seg id="4"> Mr. Obamh, Nekha that, the United States is facing the most serious Cynlnjz many generations and overcome these difficulties he is confident that the United States will pale. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Ibrahim Lanka in the United States had finished the tradition of slavery. </seg>
<seg id="6"> But Mr. Obamh with said that time in solving the problems faced by the country Lgega and open areas. </seg>
<seg id="7"> But, in spite of the fact that I hope that this country in the dream of Banaon will remain alive. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Besides the demonstrated in Afghanistan and Iraq, the United States is Jojh from an acute financial crisis. </seg>
<seg id="9"> swearing-in ceremony for the extraordinary steps are being. </seg>
<seg id="10"> It is believed that the organizers will be 20 million people participated in this function. </seg>
<seg id="11"> On Monday, the United States is a national holiday because the same day of human rights in the Alm carrier and Lothr Martin called King was killed. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Lothr called King black. Martin </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Lothr Martin Paid Tribute to Country, Determined to Work. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Dr. Martin Lothr to be called King snh hundred nineteen was killed in Arsth. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Barak Obama Dr. has paid homage to be called King and said that the Americans to fulfill the promises made by the nation should work together. </seg>
<seg id="4"> On the other hand, in Washington on Tuesday on the occasion of the new oath ceremony was presided over by the President of people were forums be that preparations are starting for a gathering. </seg>
<seg id="5"> It is expected that the President of the historic was presided over by the oath to see 20 million people will be collected in Washington. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Barak Obama on Monday, the start of the northern by a in the medical center in Washington visit where he met with the U.S. soldiers injured after this he has been set up in a shelter for the houses and a color. On the </seg>
<seg id="7"> Talking to reporters, Barak Obama said: &apos; The present crisis and that we are facing difficulties in which many people have been Ghre after we can only dismissed. </seg>
<seg id="8"> He said that the Lothr Martin called King in more than to serve the people also. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Barak Obama said that today, when we honoring the memory of these are not, this day and that we should be stayed with. This day is that we should obey. " </seg>
<seg id="10"> He said that this ceremony of many thousand persons Lothr Martin on the way which will be called King of &apos; I have a dream for the hearing, snh hundred nineteen were gathered in Trasth. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Lothr Martin called King said in his speech that the day will come when people, they came to see his would not be allowed. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The BBC Mathew Price says that premium bonds ask that day in the history Lothr Martin 24 hours before the day came when the black chapter of history will take oath of his office. </seg>
<seg id="13"> For many people in the southern state of the United States Barak Obama was presided over by Dr. Lothr, will be called King that the dream of. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Additional Political Agent. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> additional ten days ago political agent from South Waziristan unknown masked Poshon Neagoa Krliatha. </seg>
<seg id="3"> According to sources, the local officials received the Nazir group was kidnapped by Taliban. </seg>
<seg id="4"> According to the local administration on Tuesday evening at 4 o&apos;clock in the neighboring South Waziristan additional political agent Aamir Lateef has achieved a tribal jirga Skaouts to the camp. </seg>
<seg id="5"> However, he has not revealed that the additional political agent who had been kidnapped. </seg>
<seg id="6"> However, the local people has said that the political agent of a Nazir local was kidnapped by Taliban. </seg>
<seg id="7"> At this time, was kidnapped on Aamir Lateef when he was going from Wana Taank. </seg>
<seg id="8"> two thousand 9 11 January the tribal region of South Waziristan in Karknrh seven armed masked Poshon additional political agent Aamir Lateef, including the driver prophethood. kidnapping </seg>
<seg id="9"> According to the official and kidnapping have already present in a car was an armed guards and after that the additional political agent impression in a vehicle and there were taken. </seg>
<seg id="10"> According to the local administration was political agent of South Waziristan, security forces after the kidnapping of all the check posts in the tribal areas and other was sealed and of those coming to search for the last one week and was being officials also has imposed a ban on the Wana economic was imposed. </seg>
<seg id="11"> two thousand people on December 8 assistant political agent of northern Waziristan Asmat Ullah at this time, when he was kidnapped the Merela to celebrate Eid holidays was going to Bannu, and the Thsaldar Aman-ullah in North Waziristan after a few days of two people, including the unknown masked Poshon was killed by. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The British Hykr Victory in Court of </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Forty-two year old British citizens has admitted that he had HYK the American Army website. </seg>
<seg id="3"> become Asperger Sndrom patient. It is to be noted that Asperger Sndrom of the patient of a single type of work children. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The lawyer said that if they were handed over to the United States, it is feared that he will try to commit suicide. </seg>
<seg id="5"> However, the Government has said that the lawyers of become health is very low. apprehensions with reference to </seg>
<seg id="6"> The Lord Justice Mwrs and Mr. Justice Simon following the decision has said that they are allowed to become British court can apply for review. </seg>
<seg id="7"> become the lawyers, the court had adopted the stance that if the become away from his house and family was committed suicide if they can. </seg>
<seg id="8"> He further said that it is necessary for the Home Secretary did not consider. </seg>
<seg id="9"> But the government lawyer has said that the Home Secretary used their powers. </seg>
<seg id="10"> never become the American army has denied to HYK website. </seg>
<seg id="11"> snh become two thousand 1 and 2 American computer system in the HYK was due to the U.S. government was a loss of 8 lakh dollars. </seg>
<seg id="12"> American marines and NASA become the computer system and 97 HYK. </seg>
<seg id="13"> However, become has said that he has no courage to have not been HYK, but it&apos;s natural able to was looking for information about his opinion, the U.S. government was kept secret. </seg>
<seg id="14"> The mother of become Janice sharp said that they are happy with the decision. </seg>
<seg id="15"> become lawyer said, it is correct decision. </seg>
<seg id="16"> This case is continuing since two thousand two and eventually has a right decision. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Kashmir: Commander Killed. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The spokesman of the eastern command of Indian army deployed in Jammu Laftnt Colonel Acharah told BBC: &apos; 24 Rashtriya Rifles, and the men of Jammu and Kashmir police Msdqh on receiving reports of Doda district in Gndwh Tehsil 56 jungle in has has surrounded the place where armed was sitting on the extremists hiding. </seg>
<seg id="3"> He said the firing on the army and retaliatory action in two armed extremist were killed. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The spokesman said that two extremists killed in twelve years of prohibited district of Hizbul Mujahideen active in District Commander Zahoor-Khande is also who was an expert in landmine explosions. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The identity of Sajjad Hussein, which has been according to the army was linked with the extremists of last year. </seg>
<seg id="6"> According to the Acharah the growing is still continuing operation because according to him in the area of the more likely to the presence of extremists has said that the army operation in the first phase of two with rifles were also recovered. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Yesterday, the head of the province the Kaldip Kumar Khda has Delhi eight this year while the facts and figures of up to now declared the most peaceful years. </seg>
<seg id="8"> In November and December is worth mentioning that even in the assembly elections within seven stages was no violence. </seg>
<seg id="9"> In these elections, 13 more than 600 candidates took part. </seg>
<seg id="10"> It should be remembered that last 18 years, Hizbul Mujahideen active in Jammu and Kashmir. from </seg>
<seg id="11"> The first in Delhi July was announced a one-sided Faerbnda after which the Government talks between India and the commanders. </seg>
<seg id="12"> However, the only within 15 days of the ceasefire have finished. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Later, the number of Hizbul Mujahideen senior commanders were killed in various operations. </seg>
<seg id="14"> The daily, the news of Pakistan on Thursday, set up under the auspices of Pakistan about the extremist groups in Kashmir wrote that Hazbul Mujahideen, Lashkar-e-Taiyibah, and it has been decided consider Kashmir policy. </seg>
<seg id="15"> It should be noted that so far, this was the policy of the two organizations that the Kashmir issue can be resolved through armed resistance. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Dera Bgty: Gas Pipe Line on Explosion. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> According to police sources from the Loti gas field on the Pirkoh 18-inch pipe line of Qatar the explosion was to make. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The pipeline from plants are the direction. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Meanwhile, the extremist group of Baloch Republican Army spokesman expressed the Srbaz Baloch, a person named by telephone Prapna group has accepted the responsibility of this attack. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The fourth gas pipeline in Charroz was to make the explosion. </seg>
<seg id="6"> On Friday, in Dera Allah Yar, a 18-inch pipe line was destroyed the Qatar which was issued for the repair work on Sunday morning. </seg>
<seg id="7"> in Quetta, general manager of Sui southern gas company Mushtaq Siddiqui has said that the supply of gas pipeline from will be started. After afternoon </seg>
<seg id="8"> and Quetta, Sibbi our through the pipeline. </seg>
<seg id="9"> in Quetta and other areas Msafata visit the scarcity of gas from three days there is one of the snow is continuing, and remained below 0oC, last fell down and on the other hand, with cool ones. stoves and </seg>
<seg id="10"> In addition to this, in Dera Bugti in a motorcycle in the market in explosion, but according to the police, the explosion has not been any loss. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The Commander of Jamatul Dawa for Administrator. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Hadakoatr center of Jamaat Aldeo-e-Taiyibah, about 25 kilometers away from Lahore in Murid. </seg>
<seg id="3"> hospitals, schools and the center hostels of students are included. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The law minister of Punjab, Rana Sanaullah Khan has said that the commander of Jamatul Dawa center in a made so that in the process of working for the welfare organizations present there may not be affected. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The commander of Jamatul Dawa, Hafiz Mohammad Saeed&apos;s son-in-law Khalid Walid according to the center located in hospitals, schools and other welfare organizations for the supervision of a high official Khaqan Babar officer has been appointed as the administrative center while according to him in the number of police has also been increased. In </seg>
<seg id="6"> The UN Security Council has imposed ban on Jamaat Aldeo. After that, the federal government of Pakistan has Jmaetaldeo throughout the country and to take action against the Emir of the Jamaat Hafiz Saeed, and the other leaders have been in the-e-Tayyaba center on behalf of the Punjab government. Admnstr appointed by the federal government to the proceedings against Aldeoh is the continuation of. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Khaqan Babar, the group, the district management.&apos;s </seg>
<seg id="8"> Walid Khalid said that Commissioner division Khustoo Pervez Khan Lahore on Sunday, along with the police and civil administration in the center Tbah and Khalid Walid was inspecting different parts of the center. The commander of Jamatul Dawa, on behalf of the government has condemned the administrators appointed in the center and said that the government is due to the activities of patients in the hospital and school located in the center has been a reduction in the number of children. </seg>
<seg id="9"> On the other hand, according to a press release of Jamaat Aldeo Emir of the Jamaat Hafiz Saeed, Secretary General of the United Nations Ban Aun and committee of the Taliban in which has written a letter to the name of the UN Security Council by a ban imposed on party has appealed to. </seg>
<seg id="10"> He was told that in a letter to the UN Security Council on behalf of the Jamaat Aldeo one-sided decision of injustice and the ban on the Aldeo no connection with terrorism but it is involved in the welfare works. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Edhi Relief Mission in Gaza. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Gaza entering the required to obtain till now after the passage of the many stages of Egypt from New York may be able to reach. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Talking to BBC Urdu service in Cairo, he said that he is still could not reach because Egypt, Israel and Gaza too have put obstacles. </seg>
<seg id="4"> He said, "I am here are eight days have been and still no permission to the Gaza Strip. </seg>
<seg id="5"> At this time, and it is hoped that will be able to get permission to the Gaza Strip. </seg>
<seg id="6"> While giving details, he said: &apos; I only for the first Gaza was given a visa for seven days and later on my knowledge of the Pakistani authorities have help me and it Brhoa by one month of it, but this will only once I Gaza on condition that single-entry -. </seg>
<seg id="7"> He said that along with his son and daughters and they want to the relief operation in Gaza. </seg>
<seg id="8"> &apos; I came with some money. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Egypt&apos;s Red Cross has given a check of one million dollars so they are also given ten thousand dollars in cash and relief goods sent in Gaza. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Four More in Cabinet Ministers, Trasth. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Four new federal ministers, two the Muttahida Qaumi Movement (MQM) and two members of the Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam Fazal Al-Rahman group are included. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The new ministers to President Asif Ali Zardari, administered the oath. </seg>
<seg id="4"> swearing-in ceremony of the Prime Minister, Yusuf Raza Geelani, members of the Federal Cabinet also present </seg>
<seg id="5"> The new ministers of four with the participation in the federal cabinet and Federal Minister, Minister of State advisers number of Trasth has been. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The two ministers of the MQM and Farooq Sattar, Babar Ghauri, while in Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam Prime Swati, Maulana Fazal Al-Rahman group include Ataur Rehman. </seg>
<seg id="7"> So these ministers of departments have been announced. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The convener of the M.Q.M. Farooq Sattar, while of MQM, Babar Ghauri, senator and the period is ending March 10. </seg>
<seg id="9"> General Sawati Senator were elected in a free and their is the richest senator. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Maulana Ataur Rehman, a member of the National Assembly, Maulana Fazal Al-Rahman&apos;s younger brother. </seg>
<seg id="11"> It should be kept in mind that history important posts are not four secretaries of the members of the National Assembly. </seg>
<seg id="12"> It is to be noted that eight in the cabinet on 22 November 3 two thousand were included new ministers, state ministers and 18 at this time, it was said that the members of the MQM will also be included, but due to differences in the distribution of ministries among the MQM has not. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Balochistan, Given Pipeline. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> According to the police, the 18-inch pipe line of Qatar, which is on the Pirkoh of various fields in Sui gas plants are the and blew up the early morning, unknown persons killed. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Apart from this, the well was discovered number three in Sui have been completely destroyed by the explosion and Dera Allah Yar, a gas pipeline near the blast has been harmed. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The responsibility of these explosions banned organization Baloch Republican Army spokesman Srbaz Baloch, on behalf of the Organization. </seg>
<seg id="5"> two thousand years in Balochistan nine beginning is increasing incidents of violence. </seg>
<seg id="6"> till now this month of gas pipelines was to make the bombings and rail cars and attacks on the people belonging to the province of Punjab has increased. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The chief minister of Balochistan Nawab Aslam Reasana has expressed concern over the these incidents and the police intelligence agencies have been issued the orders of the exchange of information with the but so far to prevent these incidents. could not be possible </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> 819 Billion Dollars of Economic Approved. of Reconstruction and Rehabilitation Package </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The president Obama of this project in favor of any Rpblkn party belonging to any member of the vote. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Rpblkn members was of the view that this plan is very expensive &apos;, economic and will not be work. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The representatives of this package in favor of two hundred Choalas and 100 Athasa votes went in its opposition. </seg>
<seg id="5"> economic revival of this project next week to be presented in the Senate is where the power to Democratic Party is a very simple majority. </seg>
<seg id="6"> It is feared that that Rpblkn due to strong opposition from the party, the approval of the Senate will not be easy. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The representatives of economic plan for the rehabilitation Barak after the approval of the Obama urge Members has said that the important political differences did not allow obstacles in the path of this project. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The president said that this will project in which he has expressed his hope that the next month will shape and the supremacy of law in the country will prove helpful in a-environment in which would promote trade in US. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Under this plan for the common men and traders community, two hundred and seventy five billion dollars of loans and Miss in 540 million people of ten thousand roads, bridges, schools, and unemployment Alaoens new will be given for investigation capability. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The BBC correspondent Richard Lstr in Washington has said that Barak Obama PS PST through the political differences, a new political culture lauded the determination to economic package was, but this discussion has once again on political grounds in Tlxy has been created. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The representatives of members of the Rpblkn on behalf of the government has declared the Bill proposed by a waste of money and said that the quantum of reserves would not get any help in creating Moaqee. </seg>
<seg id="12"> On behalf of the Party, he stressed on the bill proposed by Tkson in which has been attention Miss. </seg>
<seg id="13"> He said that the package much less by the investment in very can create more Moaqee of employment. </seg>
<seg id="14"> He said that the construction of project in taxes, Miss than the immediate employment to create more Moaqee very can </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The President, Tlxy in Turkish Prime Minister </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> About Chakhte Rajub Tayyab Argan, the president said that the blood was shed many people in the Gaza Strip and they are looking sorry that the people by the Israeli forces on the justification of sincerity can also rang. With </seg>
<seg id="3"> Mr. Argan said: &apos; "I think you may change their crime are using the words for eliminating and they raise voice but you have the people were killed and I am remembering their children who were killed near the beach. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The tragedy of Shamon Peres has said that Gaza is not Hamas, which has set up a dangerous repercussions dictator has. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Davies from one of the BBC correspondent says that the World Economic Forum in the never in the scene to came. </seg>
<seg id="6"> However, after Erdgan made in respect of the President said that he Asraala are and they are also not yell due to which they but they were saying that Koson far from the truth. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Turkey chose the sugarcane from Muslim countries in which the diplomatic relations with Israel, but for the last few years is found. Tension in the </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> &apos; Plan were Not in Pakistan. Attack </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> An Indian TV channel, the TV, &apos; talking to Wajid Shams Hasan said that the Mumbai blasts of Pakistan&apos;s investigation report will be released very soon. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In the past the attacks in Mumbai on more than one hundred and seventy people were killed. </seg>
<seg id="4"> India has said that the responsibility of the attack on the extremist organization Lashkar-e-Tayyaba. </seg>
<seg id="5"> India has also said that in Mumbai, state of Pakistan elements were involved &apos;. </seg>
<seg id="6"> After the Mumbai attacks have been affected by the relations between the two countries. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The High Commissioner Wajid Shams-al-Hasan has made the statement about Pakistan studies that this impression is available to investigate what is expected in the report. </seg>
<seg id="8"> wajid Shams-al-Hassan said: &apos; As far as in their investigations have arrived on the spot, Pakistan has not been used. of the land </seg>
<seg id="9"> This could be in place and there is no, Britain, No. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The two some (Pakistan) and Britain were I was worried about the. </seg>
<seg id="11"> India and the international community to take action against responsible for the Mumbai blasts for a lot of pressure on Pakistan. Pakistan&apos;s statement is that attacks in Mumbai, allegedly involved in action against groups of people into custody. </seg>
<seg id="12"> On this Wajid Shams-al-Hassan said: "We are not tried to give. </seg>
<seg id="13"> We believe in to action on the facts. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Our investigation Manzoor come to the world. </seg>
<seg id="15"> We (investigation) satisfied with the results will try to. </seg>
<seg id="16"> He said the delay in Pakistan&apos;s defense, said that this kind of material to the understand, and it&apos;s time to seriously examined. </seg>
<seg id="17"> The High Commissioner Wajid Shams Hasan said that India was to be presented to the Dosaer in high 45 days. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The Leader of Rypyblykn Black Elected. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The Republican Party elections in the sixth Michael stal during the has won by a Soarsth votes in Akanoe to get the votes. </seg>
<seg id="3"> in the elections for the post of the party in stal Kemdmqabl candidate Katn Daousn Sttr votes while the ex-Chairman Duncan competition in the second stage of Dstrbrdar were injured. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Reports say that the chairman of the ruling party in five of the candidates were in the most moderate Michael stal leaders are acceptance. </seg>
<seg id="5"> After the victory in his address Michael stal said, "We a with their friends and opponents with us, but you are saying that this between the people who want to put away from they will be prepared for the. Michael stal belonged to my land where they have also served as the deputy governor. </seg>
<seg id="6"> When he got fame at the time in two thousand six for a seat of the Senate were standing in the elections. </seg>
<seg id="7"> But he lost in the election of Senate after a political party Knzroatao were given the Chairman of the Committee. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Now, after being elected as the chairman of the party Iowa Republican party of the country-wide the efforts of the campaign will be in his head. Their </seg>
<seg id="9"> He said the election Lrahe on this promise that he will give a new agenda through the party and Sacramento-based lobbying supporters from the party will use of new technical for the damaged. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Lashkar-e-Tayyaba and Jaish-e-Mohammad in Jammu Presence of Indian Claim. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The Jammu Poonch districts of the militants in the present information. </seg>
<seg id="3"> According to the official there army and on receiving secret information the police surrounded the area and start out. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Meanwhile, clashes started in which four militants killed, two soldiers and one police officer. </seg>
<seg id="5"> There clashes. according to the information received were underway in the area and Jaish-e-Mohammad and Lashkar militants linked to the are present more resupplied after days of the army sent there to fight has been. </seg>
<seg id="6"> In the meantime, chairman on behalf of the Government as the Chief Minister of Omar Abdullah meeting with Negornr and his party&apos;s national conference on behalf of the leader of the Assembly formally informed about the US. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Congress has also allied party of the national conference on the from the support of Omar Abdullah. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Omar Abdullah the oath as the Chief Minister of State assured will be. </seg>
<seg id="9"> It should be remembered that in the recent elections state&apos;s national conference for 28 seats in the House of Stasa members and became the biggest party have come forth. It is to be noted that the Pshnd parties of the elections Baekat. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Congress, which were 17 seats, with the national conference coalition government has agreed to make. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Today Srinagar on the arrival of the Party of the Rknon Omar Abdullah warm welcome. With Joshi </seg>
<seg id="12"> On this occasion Omar Abdullah has said that the talks between the Indian government and the separatism will be possible role for the preparation of the elections and the new government in India, but it will not be possible for coming into power. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Peace in Middle East for Role of European Union. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The Government should be seen in the war in the Middle East for the reconciliation efforts to stop the role of the European Union is a decisive. </seg>
<seg id="3"> According to the Brslzkesrkara stand Shoarzn, or the efforts of the Sarkoza hands are Btane in this work. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The European Commission spokesman Amade Altafaj said that an attempt is commendable that the joint statement of the European Union by the war may help to convey the parties. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The statement of the extent, seems to be all right. </seg>
<seg id="6"> But in fact the European Union slowly behind the scene of Tana is a sad is expected to the picture. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The president of the Union Ketor check on the role of Republic is weak. </seg>
<seg id="8"> on top of all other him helpless. </seg>
<seg id="9"> On the other hand, the French president Sarkoza attitude, as he is still under the chairmanship of are performing the duty of the European Union. </seg>
<seg id="10"> However, France has complete its term of six months. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Sarkoza and they want to Qiadta role and can also, but he is not allowed to. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The situation might seem ridiculous to face the French Foreign Minister Bernard Kchner. </seg>
<seg id="13"> They are included in the delegation led by check Republic of Foreign Minister are Schwarzenberg. </seg>
<seg id="14"> On this occasion Mstzad that war in the Middle East, both foreign ministers are giving statements. Different </seg>
<seg id="15"> Schwarzenberg says that Israel to have the right to defend the Kchner near the defense of this war does not come under his. Meanwhile, Germany has also sent a special representative Middle East. until the European Union based on the same stance on the diplomatic, we did not express solidarity it could not succeed. </seg>
<seg id="16"> . The attitude of Israel, which is proof of this Europe do not command respect to any reconciliation efforts. </seg>
<seg id="17"> at this time for some of the European Union and the golden opportunity to because due to the policies of the United States, George W Bush has failed in the Middle East. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Financial Crisis: Billion Leaf German Industrialists Committed Suicide. of </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> South Soabah in Germany Adolf living in the area of Merkle his, a big business group has left behind. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But some time ago by General German citizens were don&apos;t know most about them. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Then, when their industrial group to give loans to the 30 banks have talks with several weeks, the president also become the subject of the headlines Geeaor them Merkle group with life in future as well. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The German Merkle group Fwlks Karsaz, after the purchase of shares of Oagn due to financial crisis also had to bear a loss of several hundred million euros. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The financial institutions must take this group 1 billion and 700 million euros between the worth of new declined to give loans, Merkle came under extreme pressure. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Some time ago the bank loans Merkle group on an emergency basis, but Adolf were ready to give Merkle that a small industrialists arrived at this that the industrial group was an annual income nearly 30 billion euros, its necessary investment could not bear the deprivation by force. </seg>
<seg id="8"> adolf Merkle after the death of his father when his family business over Twjdyd were set up on the lines that very soon. also more development </seg>
<seg id="9"> He said his company name Ratpharm today that the big extremely successful and medicine manufacturers company of Germany. </seg>
<seg id="10"> A short time ago by the drug, the business was worth between 5 and 6 billion euros annual-and still is the income of 8 billion euros. Merkle after the victory of Rasao form a group, in which the construction equipment to buy organization, several large manufacturing hydel, Byrg from cement Krkhas, vehicles of producing Kssbhrer includes a company. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The number of employees in the world Merkle group is close to one lakh and properties in this Rasao to form a drug manufacturing company has always get special importance. </seg>
<seg id="12"> adolf Merkle said many times in his life was: "We Doasaza, four Nslan have been. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Now, it is my children have the and I hope that this organization only a few hundred years of me family in Anttam. </seg>
<seg id="14"> adolf of Merkle committed suicide after the banks of the group of 400 million euro for the Vem interim has given its approval of loans, but it is a requirement that Vem Korasao form to you will be long term basis so that the group&apos;s financial position on can be improved. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Therefore, Adolf Merkle after the death of Merkle group was they who will not as well. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Germany Crime Rate in Foreign Countries People in </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The latest statistic according to 2004 to between 2007 addition crime rate of foreigners. </seg>
<seg id="3"> nine per cent and 21. from </seg>
<seg id="4"> It has been come up to 4 percent. </seg>
<seg id="5"> In Baoeria Interior Minister of Jachm appearance according to the herrmann, it is a positive change. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He said: " it should be kept in mind that is necessary to the number of foreigners to get the German citizenship is increasing. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Therefore, it is also in statistic should be told that the German committing an offence to the people, but the background of foreign. </seg>
<seg id="8"> herrmann said that the province would do to collect facts and figures about the time it will keep in mind the. </seg>
<seg id="9"> In addition to Baoeria in the province Hmbrg is being thought on the same lines. </seg>
<seg id="10"> CD belonging to the Interior Affairs Senator Christoph Ahlhas said: " scientific and when it is investigating the person is already cannot results of its own choice but it will depend on the FBI statistics which have come after investigation is on. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Ahlhas a analysis of the provincial office crime prevention drew attention to the report which was ready in 2006, according to which Hmbrg parts of the city in Bergdrf it was discovered accused that the foreigners to participate in the crime is what percent. </seg>
<seg id="12"> shows that the foreigners results, </seg>
<seg id="13"> The crime rate in the province is very less in comparison to the crime. </seg>
<seg id="14"> In this when Berlin in 2006 during the crime rate in young people were reviewed, revealed that the foreign background the rate of young 44. </seg>
<seg id="15"> 7 percent. was </seg>
<seg id="16"> However, the other political parties of Germany; for example, SPD, environment of the Jamaat Grynz Orbaean-party Lnksparte against this proposal that time together with the facts and figures crime of collecting this information is also be background of the people who German foreign. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> As Soon as Army Withdrawal from Gaza: Olmert Want </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Ehud Olmert has stressed was full of forces from a permanent and lasting for the ceasefire agreement is necessary. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Hamas and Israel has announced ceasefire on Sunday. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Islamic militant organization Hamas has announced a ceasefire on Saturday while said that Israeli forces within a week to be completely out from Gaza Strip in the Gaza Strip and sealed should be abolished. </seg>
<seg id="5"> On the other hand, Hamas leader Ismail Hnah has said that the war in the Gaza Strip victory has been described by God. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He said that Gaza-Israel has been unable to its goals. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Before this, city Sharm el-Sheikh tourist resort of Egypt on Sunday in a meeting of the leaders of European and Arab countries was held in which with Israel was demanded immediate evacuation of forces from Gaza. </seg>
<seg id="8"> It was decided in the meeting that very soon the Gaza Strip for an international relief conference will be held. </seg>
<seg id="9"> in the meeting the German Chancellor angala Myrkl also participated. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Hamas and Israel Jngjoon Kemaben war continued for three weeks left at least 13 hundred ten persons including Palestine and killed 13 Israeli yesterday. </seg>
<seg id="11"> On the other hand, the Palestinian President Mmwd Abbas has stressed on making a national government in Palestinian areas. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The Name of Germany This Message of Al-Qaeda. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> 30 minutes of this, a person in the video of black and Pgra Tehran, mouth Dhanpe guns in their hands and undergo a German is giving a message to the Government. </seg>
<seg id="3"> the person is conducting introduced by the name of Abu Talha themselves and German language is talking. In </seg>
<seg id="4"> This video the message of the Arabic Taetlz were also present. </seg>
<seg id="5"> on the screen of the series of al-Qaeda has been set Lwgw, and in this date of 2008. October </seg>
<seg id="6"> The German from the government, it has been said in the statement that such a large number of forces stationed in Afghanistan and the country that it has been expressed that it will not be attacked, and it is not Bhola, then? </seg>
<seg id="7"> The Abotlhh tell the person who has not given the threat of Germany hot attacks on. </seg>
<seg id="8"> At that time, the allied forces in Afghanistan, NATO German included in the number of troops for three and a half thousand. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Last October last year in parliament more than one thousand troops to Afghanistan has given approval of the law. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Germany was at the to meet the Al-Qaeda is the first message. </seg>
<seg id="11"> with terrorism related affairs and expert Makhaeal keep an eye on the Lders, with reference to say this message: "in Kabul recently appointed in the suicide bomb attack outside the embassy in all condition is proof of the fact that we should take it seriously. </seg>
<seg id="12"> For the last few years on the Internet video Al-Qaeda is continuing messages and some messages were also after the attack. </seg>
<seg id="13"> The German ambassador in Kabul on Saturday, the responsibility of the suicide bomb attack outside the military organization of the Taliban. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Most of the German newspaper and the analyst this attack on a Al-Qaeda and are looking. </seg>
<seg id="15"> "They are targeting Germany. </seg>
<seg id="16"> fundamentalist Muslims, Afghan policy of Germany from the negative Ortnqada see. </seg>
<seg id="17"> The German government not only Afghanistan but also in the Middle East Mtesbanh pursuing a policy of accusing. </seg>
<seg id="18"> and due to this they Germany to no more than its target are clear. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Meanwhile, the German government has said that the video of this common from coming on already knew about the German secret agencies. </seg>
<seg id="20"> A German Institute of federal anti-crime this video message is busy in the test. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Obamane Taken Post of US President. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> In this context, the US public, on the one hand, the world is different from Obama expect,. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Now Barak Obama to the President of the United States are being received messages of congratulations from all over the Prdnia, subject to their expectations are also come. </seg>
<seg id="4"> In this regard a German Chancellor angala Myrkl have expressed confidence in the new US president. </seg>
<seg id="5"> "I believe that the federal republic deep friendship between the United States and Germany and on the basis of a we can solve the problems. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin has said that Obama a serious and are to be an open owner and it is a good thing. Yqnyny, </seg>
<seg id="7"> In this way, the former U.S. President George W. Bush&apos;s policies is facing criticism. </seg>
<seg id="8"> However, the Administration to China on to the role at the international level for the movement has appreciated is while China about the new US President has said that he to strengthen military ties between the two countries will have to work. </seg>
<seg id="9"> The German city Bwxm active in the political expert Gosoee had say: </seg>
<seg id="10"> In this context, "I believe in the coming weeks and months Obama and economic team will look enormous pressure and the Beijing Government with a Lchkdar and for the currency market rate to the discussion will be compelled to take. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The former US administration has also made more relations with India. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Obama where can take these relations, the professor of American subjects in New Delhi in the Krstofr Raj says: "Now we have come closer to the strategic partnership, but Obama at night, could not bring any change. </seg>
<seg id="13"> He also Benadkt Obama message in the name of peace in the world and promote the atmosphere of cooperation has stressed on. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Provincial Elections in Iraq. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The year 2005 after the war-these are the first important elections in the country. </seg>
<seg id="3"> 440 seats in the elections for the 14,400 have landed in Amadoarmadan. More than </seg>
<seg id="4"> During the elections to maintain the law and order situation for eight thousand police and troops have been deployed in Iraq. </seg>
<seg id="5"> In view of this danger that these days a bomb attack or a great of terrorism and would not all Iraqi borders have been sealed on Friday, one day before had been. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Besides, the closure of airports have been restored and has been banned. Public transport </seg>
<seg id="7"> According to reports, the traffic on the streets of Baghdad, due to the ban on transport not seen coming and Iraqi children play football in on the roads. </seg>
<seg id="8"> However, on one hand to the security situation in the Iraqi elections will be realized that the year of the return of American forces from Iraq in 2011 after the local Sakaorata agencies of the country bag he would be Snhbal or not, on the other hand, political analyst it as a test targeted are taking an from which Jaskega that the Iraqi people in the country in a democratic manner changes to the extent to which we are ready to. </seg>
<seg id="9"> the United Nations to help Seeraq provincial elections are being held in almost eight hundred and international observers are reviewed the election process. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Eashor Day Today, Day in Iran Eashor Syyed Alshhda Hadrat Imam Hussein (not) Memory of Great Sacrifice Celebrated with Respect and Honor. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> According to a report of Mehr news agency, the capital of Iran Tehran in all small and big cities, including Syed Alshhda of Imam Hussein (not) Ezadara was celebrated with great fervour and honor on this occasion, the Moumnen majalis AZA and also participate in large number in and Mufti Mukarram (s) of the different (not) presented condolence to meet today the martyrdom of Iran, son of Mufti Mukarram (s) in the fields of Karbala Imam Hussein (not) in the memory of the great sacrifice magnificent Ezadar and is mourning Moumnen Nesad Alshhda of Karbala Imam Hussein (not) unique unity in the memory of the latest on a large scale and majalis and also participated in the Ezadara. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Israeli Forces from Gaza Ejlen Area of Rice//Palestinian Militants for Stability. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> According to the Urdu service of Mehr news agency the Obatl in Gaza aggressive of the 16th day also by Israeli bombing Prohshianh urban population, Gaza on the ground and air force, navy 880 people killed in attacks and 3700 Palestinians have been injured. </seg>
<seg id="3"> 275 at innocent are also included in the martyrs of the Arab leaders treachery and Mskrate on the so-called international human rights organizations, died in Sogee. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The shrouds, Brdw$ Gaza today the Mujahideen Ejen Israeli soldiers from the area and the enemy and the faith and the best in Paedara are and showed patience and Jewish are due to the-on the enemy. </seg>
<seg id="5"> If the Egyptian President Hosny Nambark treachery of Hamas bears and does not, who was defeated Israel since when four from it, but Israel has laid siege of Egypt, along with the Palestinian Muslims have cordoned off the history of the Arab country of the incident. </seg>
<seg id="6"> On the other hand governments of Saudi Arabia and Jordan also the political, economic and are providing help to be treachery with the unarmed Muslims of Gaza by giving along with Israel. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Barak Obamh Iran will Use New Strategy with United States. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> According to a report of Mehr news agency, the elected President Barak Obamh said while talking to ABC News channel has said that the new on the issue of Iran and adopt a new strategy. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Barak Obama said that Iran "US will be a very big challenges for the Government. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Barak Obamh said that Aseflstena Hamas and Islamic organization Hezbollah and support of the is worried about Iran&apos;s nuclear program of Afjodga. </seg>
<seg id="5"> But he about Iran&apos;s current U.S. President George W. Bush&apos;s policy relations with Iran and we will not issued in connection with the policies adopted by different. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Barak Obamh said that their real purpose to completely clear while mutual respect and will emphasize on the desire of talks. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Barak Obamh have also said that in the past in the wake of talks with Iran before not imposing any conditions attached to Chahaean. </seg>
<seg id="8"> He has expressed his hope that during an interview of the Administration on this new strategy regarding Iran&apos;s&apos; acting rapidly. </seg>
<seg id="9"> In the Middle East crisis Obamh said that he was formed a special team in this regard. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Jomshrq efforts for the establishment of peace in the Middle Krdega start work since January. 20 </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> President Bush Sdrjarj Unfit and Mnfwr US President Bush, in His Address Press Admitted of Orjraem Mistakes. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Mehr news agency has a in connection with the Associated Press that the U.S. President George W. Bush said during the last several their mistakes in a press conference and confess the crime. </seg>
<seg id="3"> While addressing a press conference at the White House, President Bush said that the newly elected President of Obamh than are sentiments of goodwill gesture, but the biggest Cylynj for Obamh it would be possible attacks on the United States to sacrifice. </seg>
<seg id="4"> He said that the completion of the mission in Iraq and social security reforms their mistakes. </seg>
<seg id="5"> President Bush has said that he has done anything for the protection of the United States. 100 </seg>
<seg id="6"> ask about the Israeli aggression in Gaza was in response to a number of questions, President Bush has said that Israel has a right to defend themselves to their Hamas does not have the right to defend himself and by the United States and Israel should not to hand over the world cruel people instead of the death of Dbana should </seg>
<seg id="7"> The United States Nalaeq unfit and said that President Mnfwr have also not supplying weapons to Hamas and Israel from all over the world, the United States is the most devastating and deadly weapons field Palestinians in the murder of Israel has learned of the US President Bush has also praised the pro-Israel Arabs and Anahn as friend of Israel. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Bush Goantanama and Abu Gharaib prison in the some expressed on the crime committed suicide. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Analysts say on the US war crimes of the organizations and should be set up in this case will perform the task of humanity at a very good deeds. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The Iranian President Ahmadi Nejad President Leaders of Arab Countries Have Expressed their Grief over Silence. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> According to a report of Mehr news agency has said that the president of Iran, Dr. Mehmood Ahmadi Nejad had started committing massive atrocities on Gaza, Israeli aggression, and the leaders of Prerb silence on shd YD criticized be fixed but has also expressed his grief. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Sdrahmd are on the Arab countries and the head of Brahon silent on the Israeli&apos;s brutal action on Gaza expressing surprised on Palestinian people Kaho has said that Israel is Lokast Palestinian children, women and common citizens have been a target of their violence and Arab Rhnmaoun did not even also issued a statement. </seg>
<seg id="4"> President Ahmadi Nejad Nekha that all against Israel to be United Arab countries and the oppressed Muslims of Gaza Shar of Israel and started committing massive atrocities in the country. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Ahmadi Nejad of Saudi Arabia, in Gaza Strip by Israeli Human Genocide about its Stand to It. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> According to a report of Mehr news agency the President Mahmood Ahmadi Nejad Malik Abdullah, monarch of Saudi Arabia, said in his message that Muslims of Saudi Arabia Badshah of human genocide in Gaza Gaza and Skwt on in silence massacre of innocent children and women Dshmnan has been a cause of Islam&apos;s encouraging. </seg>
<seg id="3"> President Ahmadinejad, said in a message that your right stand in the Gaza Strip and destroy the support of the people and it so that the enemies of Pakistan Seaslama differences in the efforts to be met with failure </seg>
<seg id="4"> In his message, President Ahmadi Nejad said that you know that 19 days from Israel straightforward on human genocide in Gaza is innocent massacre of innocent children is destroying houses, schools, mosques and [in hospitals are bombing in the Gaza Nhtemslmanon of Jewish government is badly murder in these circumstances you like to the leaders of Israel is being made. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The president Ahmadi Nejad Malik Abdullah has said that Onzoela and Bwlywy as non-Muslim countries have are solid steps against Israel, then you Bhtraqdamat of these countries are expected. </seg>
<seg id="6"> President Ahmadi Nejad Nekha that will step had won the Palestinians in Gaza. </seg>
<seg id="7"> and for the victory will be got on the support and God promised. </seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Osama Bin Laden Hmdan Resistance will Teach will Continue. In Palestine </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> According to a report of Mehr News Agency correspondent Hamas in Lebanon&apos;s hmdan while talking to the French news agency has said that the international a one-sided ceasefire by Israel is against the efforts of the ceasefire, he said, until Asragal will present in Gaza until the same will be meaningless. ceasefire on </seg>
<seg id="3"> He said that the main ceasefire by Israel to avoid has failed to defeat hmdan wanted peace Paedar that Israel has said that if it Mhasr to put an end to accept the conditions of Hamas Prega </seg>
<seg id="4"> Hamas leader in Lebanon in the Gaza Strip has made it clear that the Israeli forces are, if a one-sided ceasefire, Israel will continue. Resistance against the </seg>
<seg id="5"> Beirut people in the Gaza Strip with unity, while addressing the conference&apos;s hmdan cutting ties with Israel from the European countries Krlene demanding the installations. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The leader of Hammas has said that the martyrs and the number of injured by increasing the number of our courage and determination and will be made. </seg>
<seg id="7"> He said that he was on the Palestinian people to become the door so in the war against Prdte resistance. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Pakistan in North Waziristan Tribal Region of Taliban, Killing Six People. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Mehr news agency with reference to Reuter has announced that a copy of the North Waziristan tribal region in two Afghan nationals the Taliban and four Pakistanis accused of spying sounded in murder. </seg>
<seg id="3"> According to reports, the local people on Tuesday morning in the area of Merela four corpses were found in the district Chowk which was shot and killed. </seg>
<seg id="4"> while two bodies were received from Miranshah is the place in a market, the market was were thrown. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The dead bodies were written to the Urdu letters have also been found in which it was claimed that the shooting espionage. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The President of North Waziristan two weeks ago at Miranshah in two Afghan nationals was murdered in the accused of spying. </seg>
<seg id="7"> In the last twelve days in the 15 people accused of spying for the United States has been killed. </seg>
<seg id="8"> It should be remembered that Gzshh in North and South Waziristan during the six years, more than 100 people have been killed in the accused of spying on the Taliban Alzam is that they are involved in this type of murder cases. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Barak Obamh Goantana Mobe Notorious Jail for past Signed Expected. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Mehr news agency with reference to sources, it is that the US President Goantana today Mobe the notorious jail for the past the signed </seg>
<seg id="3"> The new president Barak Hussein Obamh level in promises of his election campaign has started. follow a </seg>
<seg id="4"> In this regard, the President Obamh plan for the return of American forces from Iraq and today the US President, has ordered to Goantana notorious jail when the Mobe ordered to seize signed. </seg>
<seg id="5"> It is being expected that the President Barak Obamh this order Prmmknh today as a sign are under which the Goantamo within one year of imprisonment and will be closed. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Apart from this, the suspected terrorists from the White House to review the investigations and prisoners from it also issued the orders of the ban on Klama is likely to be. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The president Barak Obamh has held on the first day of election to fulfill the promises and his government before the start of the process and steps to ensure transparency in the above. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Analysts say that the US president on the international level of the United States to improve its falling reputation efforts have started, but they get success in this it is very difficult because we Israel as long as the United States Government&apos;s support for their is and till then it can&apos;t expect any good work if the United States wants to save their reputation in the world, it should be pitched carrier from Israel&apos;s Hamat and should not be involved in this crime. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Tony Blair Became Islamic Organization Hamas Stressed upon Need to be Included in Negotiations. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Mehr news agency with reference to British newspaper The Times of the movement that British Prime Minister Tony Blair has Kesabq in the Middle East peace process has stressed upon the need to include the Hamas. </seg>
<seg id="3"> According to the newspaper Tony Blair said that it is important that one should find a way through which Hamas should be brought in the Middle East peace process Bler only on the Bush Anzamah Mahmoud Abbas to talk with Hamas and also criticized to ignore it is to be noted that the Western countries of the people of Hamas and Nizami Bhanp power and now it is to be included in the negotiations are, and prior to this it as a "terrorist" organization Hamas to do as a "terrorist" organization, which were for the defense of the country are free from their houses by others to suppress and is service to the house of a country like Israel and occupied the government is jma possession from 60 years. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The Murder of Traders of Balochistan in Karachi, Complete Strike in Quetta. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> in Karachi on Thursday to protest against the killing of four traders of Balochistan has complete strike in Quetta and some other areas. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In the meantime, all the business centers remained closed while the traffic also was less than usual. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The protest strike appealed to the anjuman cattle in Balochistan, the Pathans was received by Awami Party and Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam, who alleged that the traders Karachi police alleged that killed in firing in his car when he arrived Tariq offer their vehicles on the road. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The President of the anjuman cattle Abdulrahim Kakar has demanded that police personnel arrested involved in the in the action will be taken against them. </seg>
<seg id="6"> However, immediately about the incident has not stand in front of the Karachi police. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The killed was traders who belong to the frontier city streets. </seg>
<seg id="8"> On behalf of the government on the occasion of the strike on a large scale and security arrangements were made an official of the important places in the whole city police was deployed. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Israeli of Hamas Senior Commander Killed in Attack. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> A Fdaee Israel a senior commander of Hamas was killed in the attack. </seg>
<seg id="3"> This one week in the Gaza Strip in order to the death of the second important personality of Hamas. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The officials of the Hammas has said that Abu Urdu, Bahauddin Zakariya Aljmal situated in the east of Gaza City on Saturday Alshjaeah killed in a village. </seg>
<seg id="5"> On Thursday, in an attack of Fdaee Israel Hamas very weak Alam Raeian were killed. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Syria living in exile of Hamas leader, Khalid ideal vowed to take "is against the ground attack on Gaza and warned Israel. </seg>
<seg id="7"> on the border of Gaza Israel deployed thousands of troops and tanks, and they are waiting for the orders of the army and sincerity. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The United States has appealed for ceasefire. But, has said that Gaza on sincerity or not to the decision will depend on the Israel. </seg>
<seg id="9"> US President George W. Bush said in a speech at his weekly radio Hamas violence for Bhrkane anger Angaza accused of and its after rocket attacks on Israel declared as terrorists. </seg>
<seg id="10"> He said that the United States has been working for the ceasefire, but a unilateral agreement will not be acceptable. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Three Bodies were Recovered in North Waziristan Tribal Region. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Pakistani security officials said that in the North Waziristan tribal region of the three men dead bodies were found. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The suspect that they have also been killed in Taliban to death. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The dead bodies were found near Miran Shah, the main town in the North Waziristan tribal region are with them and get a Rqee, in which these men on has been accused of spying for the United States. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The officials have said that these is perhaps the dead body of a man who had been kidnapped last week. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He said that Chhlna with bullets the remaining two bodies of Afghan nationals. </seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> U.S. Vice President Joseph, Baeadn Arrived in Pakistan. Elected </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The external affairs minister elected US Vice President welcomed. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The United States elected Vice President Joseph, on a tour of Pakistan Baeadn along with her delegation has arrived in Islamabad on Friday. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Foreign Minister, Shah Mahmood Qureshi and high officials of the American embassy has welcomed him. </seg>
<seg id="5"> U.S. Senator Lndsy with the Baeadn Graham has also become clear after this visit. </seg>
<seg id="6"> press officer of the American embassy people Fntrne told Voice of America that during his tour, newly elected president on various regional issues with the Pakistani leadership will hold talks, but he has also from giving any more details. </seg>
<seg id="7"> According to the sources of the Foreign Office Joseph, Baeadn high government officials, the chief of Army General Pervez Ashfaq Keyani will also meet with. </seg>
<seg id="8"> It is expected that these meetings with important bilateral and international issues in the war against terrorism related issues will be discussed. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Pakistan Noaza Joseph, the Baeadn red. </seg>
<seg id="10"> After arriving in Islamabad Joseph, Baeadn met with the President of Asif Ali Zardari. </seg>
<seg id="11"> In the meeting, the president them to close relations between Pakistan and the United States in the moon on the role of the honor of Pakistan. awarded </seg>
<seg id="12"> It should be remembered that the Joseph, Baeadn last year, the Chairman of the Senate&apos;s Foreign Relations Committee of Senator with Rchrdlogr as a Bill was introduced in Pakistan for the during next five years America&apos;s military aid increase in three times and it has been recommended to 5 billion dollars. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Former President General Pervez Musharraf&apos;s Uniform, Jobaeadn Has Played Important Role in &apos; Snapshots, Prime Minister Geelani </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Yusuf Raza Geelani, and the Baeadn (file photo </seg>
<seg id="3"> The Prime Minister, Yusuf Raza Geelani, has said that the United States elected vice president of the Baeadn snapshots, former President Pervez Musharraf&apos;s uniform, leave the post of the chief of the army is an important role in the &apos; and also for democracy in Pakistan. Jobaeadn has a great help. </seg>
<seg id="4"> This statement, Yusuf Raza Geelani, in Karachi shipyard, while talking to the journalists. </seg>
<seg id="5"> He said that the Baeadn "PR-Pakstan" or supporter leaders of Pakistan and they have as the Chairman of the Senate&apos;s Foreign Affairs Committee of Pakistan for the aid of $15 billion to the Bill. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Pakistani territory in the missile attacks by American spy planes to condemn the Prime Minister of Pakistan has once again said such attacks to allow the yoke of any kind of an agreement with the US government is not and Bqw L Askurdo/Khtarzara dams for the independence of Pakistan is concerned it in the country within a can not be allowed to such attacks. </seg>
<seg id="7"> He has also expressed the hope that the new government in the United States after coming to power policy will also change in the United States. </seg>
<seg id="8"> (File Photo). </seg>
<seg id="9"> Yousuf Raza Gilani has said that the government has from a major success is separate from the common tribal terrorists but jaso is the missile strike in Pakistan are harmful for the Government&apos;s efforts and terrorists are available from the Phrmqama tribes. </seg>
<seg id="10"> He said that the international community agrees with the stand of Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The prime minister further said that if there is no reliable evidence given to Pakistan forces will take action in their own areas. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The attacks in Mumbai Prime Minister, Yusuf Raza Geelani, its stand Dohrate said that if India to provide evidence, will be investigated on the basis of this and give proof of their involvement in Agrksa, the country according to the law, action will be taken against them. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Rehman of the country&apos;s tour of Britain and met with Altaf Hussein, the leader of MQM in response to a question about the Prime Minister said Rahman London with the permission of their country. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Quetta, DSP, Four Police Personnel were Killed. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Photo away. </seg>
<seg id="3"> A national highway of Quetta on Saryab Road in firing by unknown persons including one DSP, deputy Sprentndnt police, four police officials were injured. </seg>
<seg id="4"> On Wednesday morning a jeep in two DSP, a sub-inspector of training center and two Police constables were going towards the degree college situated at Saryab Road near the unknown assailants riding on a motorcycle Blaashteal started firing on the jeep Police Constable Sibghatullah, which sub inspector, Mehdi and Ornsrallh were killed on the spot when that one DSP Hasan Ali, it Torgee after arriving in hospital. </seg>
<seg id="5"> According to the hospital sources that severely injured during the condition of other DSP Ghulam Mohammad is also serious and shot in head and we have started. </seg>
<seg id="6"> After the incident, the police surrounded the area has taken into the incident has not accepted the responsibility of the. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The United States and Software Engineer&apos;s Killing in </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The United States, Andhra Pradesh belonging to a Anjbaer and software the unknown assailants also shot and killed. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In the Skndrabad 26 year old Akshe Oishal Aorne attack in two days ago, the State Arkensa unknown gunmen shot. Oshal during the first aid at the hospital have died. </seg>
<seg id="4"> He was an employee of Stym computers, and the United States in Falkn jet was serving in Aeroaz. </seg>
<seg id="5"> In the last one year in Andhra Pradesh seven students belonging to the United States in the hands of non-social elements have been killed. </seg>
<seg id="6"> in America for higher education and employment to the students, for the purpose of the increasing number of deaths in the province has created concern in their thousands of families whose children are living in the United States. </seg>
<seg id="7"> It is to be noted that, for the better future of the Andhra Pradesh higher education in the United States are given priority. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Chennai according to facts and figures of the American consulate in southern India to us every year for a visa for one hundred Dokhoastan are most, 40 per cent in which are in Andhra Pradesh. </seg>
<seg id="9"> In the meantime, the provincial government has started the efforts of the dead body of the deceased to Hyderabad. are </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The United States Chokna against Enemy Attacks Are: Bush. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> President George Bush Radaopr in his speech last week, and has stressed on the United States that it Chokna against enemy attacks. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Mr. Bush said that till now for the Americans, the biggest threat and a terrorist attack. And he warned that the enemy of the country with patience and they are waiting for a again,. Under </seg>
<seg id="4"> held different port folios president said that the United States or should be never ignorant from their safety. </seg>
<seg id="5"> President Bush has next president Barak also expressed best dreams for the Obama on Tuesday, which will take Kahlf his post. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The newly elected President Barak Obama on behalf of the Democratic Party in his speech on Saturday, radio swearing-in ceremony of historical importance by. On </seg>
<seg id="7"> He said that it was a established, which is a leader of other leaders of the transfer of power to the peaceful US has never shirked its responsibility with a lot of greatness. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Mr. Obama has reminded that many people from all over the world could not even think that the leader of the blood residential or without my powers will be pitched carrier. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> In Raiwind Sharif Brothers and Meeting of Federal Interior Minister, Political and Security Exchange Views on Matters. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The opposition&apos;s biggest, and the ruling party in Punjab, the head of the Pakistan Muslim League-Nawaz Sharif and Federal Interior Minister Rehman raiwind on Sunday between the country in meeting, in which the Chief Minister of Punjab, Shahbaz Sharif were also present. </seg>
<seg id="3"> According to local media Rehman possible as the country under the leadership of Pakistan People&apos;s Party is important to take a message. </seg>
<seg id="4"> However, talking to the journalists after meeting in this regard Rehman country has not given any details regarding the political affairs said that just and the politics of consensus, he is, and attacks on the situation after the Mumbai P M N P.T.C.L. has given a briefing to the leadership of the party. </seg>
<seg id="5"> In his words: &apos; so far as action has been provided information about it. </seg>
<seg id="6"> not that big operation in the Punjab, and the government of Punjab has and is still in which the team has also set up the support of the Punjab government. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The media Rehman Malik said that every day, but the PIA, not to you in the leadership of the Party to exchange of daily Pagamon. Meanwhile, the spokesman of the Pakistan Muslim League (N, Pervez Rashid has also talked with regard to the political affairs in some points and made sure that the said that Rehman refrain from Mr. Malik said that he was telling you. </seg>
<seg id="8"> It should be noted that the leadership of Pakistan Muslim League (N with the advisor to the home is a time when the hot summer of the province in politics, p m against Punjab government will Q more than 20 Nazems belonging to the governor of Punjab, Salman Tatherke p m a press conference with the N administrators of the steps taken by the provincial government, rejecting the criticism of the Pakistan People&apos;s Party belonging to the governor of Punjab also objected on participation in this matter. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Obama Promising to Pakistan&apos;s Speech: President Zardari. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The Pakistani president Asif Ali Zardari, the new President of the United States Brak Obama of the welcome address, said that with the help of the Muslim world by their mutual interests and with respect to promote the talk to Pakistan and its people are praiseworthy. </seg>
<seg id="3"> On Wednesday, he said in a statement issued by the US President&apos;s traditions and norms determined of people from all over the world for a better future. </seg>
<seg id="4"> According to the statement, Ali, the president said that the United States along with the international community and the peace in Akasoan century, finding new avenues of progress and prosperity of the important responsibility for it. </seg>
<seg id="5"> It is to be noted that the President Obama after taking oath of his office on Tuesday in the opening address said that the United States wants a new progress with the Muslim world is based on mutual interests and mutual respect. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He assured the people of poor countries was that the United States should work together with them, so there reduction in poverty and social development. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The President Obama Pakistan and Afghanistan. Appointed Special Representative for </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Richard hall broke the United Nations for the Sferrchrd hall broke the for Pakistan and Afghanistan has been appointed as the special correspondent. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In the hall broke the Bosnian Hrzgoena play an important role in the peace agreement in. </seg>
<seg id="4"> hall broke on affairs of Pakistan and Afghanistan has said that he is ready to consultations with President Obama. </seg>
<seg id="5"> He said Adafh that it is not an easy task. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He said that the date of the two countries is very different. </seg>
<seg id="7"> George MCL for the Middle East has been elected as the Arab peace talks in Israel will try to life. </seg>
<seg id="8"> He said MCL former senator and to establish peace in Northern Ireland was role in. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Today in the State Department while talking MCL said that the situation in the Middle East, Napaeadar complex and is dangerous. </seg>
<seg id="10"> But, in spite of the fact that the United States and that they did not recede from the efforts of peace. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> Afghanistan: Voter. Endangered Registration </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The election commission of Afghanistan, has said that the security concerns about the voter in some areas of the south due to the delay in registration. </seg>
<seg id="3"> without question in southern Afghanistan near the voter for the presidential election was started this week. Registration </seg>
<seg id="4"> The Commission has said that until the security situation will not be better, in some areas of Halmand Province voter will not be able to get themselves registered. </seg>
<seg id="5"> In these areas of the south last year, there has been an increase in the violence, where Taliban rebels and Afghan forces have increased their attack on the international forces given. </seg>
<seg id="6"> In the meantime, the international forces and Afghan forces has said that he has on Wednesday and on Thursday night between the people of Afghanistan during clashes in this at least 28 militants were killed. </seg>
<seg id="7"> NATO has said that the army in the Eastern Province Khost near the border of Pakistan Fdaee 22 militants were killed in attacks and land. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The Afghan Defense Ministry has said that the Afghan forces in the province eight rebels were killed and two injured. </seg>
<seg id="9"> It is not clear that Afghan authorities have come to this incident. </seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> in North West Frontier Province [NWFP] Government Has Swat Rejected Demand for Ban on Girls&apos; Education </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Taliban warriors in NWFP authorities have Swat on behalf of the girls&apos; education to ban on the threat of is rejected by saying that the announcement, the law and is against Islam. </seg>
<seg id="3"> On Sunday, the education minister of the North West Frontier province, Sardar Hussein Babar such efforts to further said that the government will do not allow successful. </seg>
<seg id="4"> He said that extremists are trying to that our children should be deprived of education in the area. </seg>
<seg id="5"> In his words: &apos; The stolen hiding schools and their children Dhmkaneka try to the children. </seg>
<seg id="6"> fear and panic while talking about the situation, he said that the provincial government should know Heaor wishes to made it clear that no one Pkhtonon from the land could not stopped the promotion of education. </seg>
<seg id="7"> A day before Allah under the leadership of Maulana Fazal Taliban militants from 15 January the ban on the girls&apos; education in the educational institutions of Swat demanded an and threatened that to break Oaletelama institutions will be destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The on going military operation in Swat during the last one and a half years despite 150 around the militants in the educational institutions of explosives Seaorag fact were destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="9"> As a result of the &lt; N educational institutions to the thousands of boys and girls in Shwlyt have lost. of education </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> India Republic Day on Occasion of Security of Security Arrangements. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> Sathoan on Monday in India Republic Day is being observed all this occasion, very strict security arrangements and thousands of troops have been deployed in the country. </seg>
<seg id="3"> the Republic Day Prdarlhkomt during the parade military weapons in New Delhi, planes and other military equipment are in the exhibition. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Officials say that security arrangements under the anti-Topan and sharp Shotr "also have been appointed the parade police and keep an eye on Link Road, the US president Brak Obama, India has congratulated on this occasion. </seg>
<seg id="5"> and Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh&apos;s heart operation on Saturday. Thaan desire of the quick recovery of the message also Bhajahe. </seg>
<seg id="6"> It is to be noted that the police have taken the two suspected militants Pakistan yesterday, after fighting on the outskirts of the New Delhi was claimed killing. </seg>
<seg id="7"> According to the police, local officials from both these AK 47 rifles, a grenade and some have been recovered documents that show that both are Pakistani. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The police of this is also investigate what the both belong to the Pakistan of banned organization Lashkar-e-Tayyaba, which is last year was involved in Mumbai blasts in November. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The Tea: Breast Cancer Effective Treatment for </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> It has been revealed in a new research that three cup of tea daily. </seg>
<seg id="3"> in women under 50 years old and for breast cancer risk of less than a third. </seg>
<seg id="4"> U.S. state in Florida MOFT cancer in the research center has been told that 50 years of age such women in the breast cancer of Rswly </seg>
<seg id="5"> Kekhtre is being to 37 per cent reduction in Jorozanh you are at least three cup of tea. </seg>
<seg id="6"> research, it has also said that the three women aged or more Cup daily from drinking tea in this connection, a special is not benefit. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The experts think that because of tea in the presence of these stages of you who is more effective against those particular types of Rsolaon Hotehan are generally the target of 50 years of age women are becoming. </seg>
<seg id="8"> State MOFT cancer set up in Florida Tmpa city center of more than five thousand women in this information was made had for breast cancer treatment. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Emran was between 20 and 74 years. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The experts of the medical records of life style and compared with such women who were safe. from for breast cancer </seg>
<seg id="11"> It also shows that the experts on a particular type of cancer, Lwblr, tea, Athrdkhaia on the rise, and until 66 per cent reduction. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Breast cancer Dsoan almost all of the patient is suffering from this kind. </seg>
<seg id="13"> This type of is more dangerous than for you, because he is in depth and it is usually show at the time of has spread a lot when they have. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Experts says at least three day cup of tea regularly and women who are less than less important as the risk of your breast cancer in May. </seg>
<seg id="15"> He said that the tea in your daily routines of a number of everyday to participate in the body to a proper Medaft against you. </seg>
<seg id="16"> In Britain, though 40 thousand women in the breast cancer is against the. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> The War in Afghanistan, United States Faced Biggest Challenge Military: Gates. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> American Secretary of Defense Robert Gates war in Afghanistan, has said that the United States is the biggest challenge military faced. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Gates today the members of the Senate and the representatives of the Obama administration on Afghanistan and Iraq war strategy was giving a briefing about the. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Gates told the Armed Services Committee of the Senate that war is no solution to the issue of Afghanistan but only he further said that many areas to protect the number of soldiers are not enough for, which benefit of diverting Taliban action. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> With Help of Exercise Why? Reduction in </seg>
<seg id="2"> The New Research. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="3"> in every age for good health. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The heart is continuously energy, you Lata reduce cholesterol levels, weight Rkhneman is&apos; hello, to help to stop diabetes and Alzaemraena Nsian Keeml SST. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Unfortunately, many people are up with the reduction in the ability to exercise are. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Experts say that exercise with our mind body and force Rhtahe but can affect the age. </seg>
<seg id="7"> American exercise Medical Association says that are not to be presented many health problems. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The Sota Mayo Clinic of Dr. Ptrasha pay exercise increased laka says that in Semedhora and physical activity is a major cause. reduction in the </seg>
<seg id="9"> Dr. Ptrasha Mayo medicine at clinic. are </seg>
<seg id="10"> He said the age of heart disease and people in the ability to exercise the a study in connection with the leadership. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The performance of the team of doctors has heart to review the voice of the high Frykwnsy Lhran use. </seg>
<seg id="12"> in the heart pumps blood to Skraou, Ordl to rest of the process of studies. </seg>
<seg id="13"> The experts have their attention kept the left-focused on the part of the heart pumps blood to the central part. </seg>
<seg id="14"> They know that are up to rest with the heart of the defects in the process of increase. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Dr. Ptrashia says that in the process of heart to rest with Emrbrhne though partners, and are with the increase in the impact on the ability to exercise is increasing. </seg>
<seg id="16"> Dr. Garoen were included in this study. </seg>
<seg id="17"> They say that after the Krhert that is compulsory in effect of this exercise and it was clarified that the bad performance in the heart of how it is concerned with the process of rest. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Some workers blood pressure in the process of heart diseases of Ordl may become a cause of. </seg>
<seg id="19"> If the doctors and workers of heart work together with regard to the age, he can also get the benefits of exercise in spite of. </seg>
<seg id="20"> In this regard a detailed report "has been published in the American Medical Association. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1"> No Possibility of Immediate War with Pakistan: Indian Army Chief. </seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2"> The head of the Indian Army was Dypk Kpwr has said that Pakistan should not present the threat of war. However, defending the country and to protect the interests of the society to ensure that are ready for all the time. </seg>
<seg id="3"> General Kpwr alleged that that prejudice and as a result of attacks in Mumbai, in spite of the international pressure on Pakistan, in the words of the infrastructure of terrorism not only in Pakistan&apos;s soil, the situation is] active. </seg>
<seg id="4"> He said this during a conversation with reporters in Srinagar in the talks. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The head of the Indian army freed Kashmir under the administration of New Delhi&apos;s total security situation and armed forces on the borders to review the preparation for the one-day visit to Kashmir Valley. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He was asked a question that according to media reports about the Mumbai blasts of Pakistan by India has rejected the evidence is presented in this regard, he is comment. </seg>
<seg id="7"> General Kpwr said that the decision of the issues of peace or war is the political leadership. </seg>
<seg id="8"> alleged on Pakistani soil while mentioning the presence of the infrastructure of terrorism, he said that the Indian army will be dealt with such elements of the peace and Zahid Hussein are under. on India to weaken the </seg>
<seg id="9"> He said that the Indian Kashmir on the soil to seven eight hundred who are present in which is approximately 50 per cent to foreign countries. </seg>
<seg id="10"> General Dypk Kpwr said that the weather is with the improvement in Pakistan-administered Kashmir and borders with the efforts of the coming down in May, however, on the borders interaction from its employees, India has also increased. </seg>
<seg id="11"> He said in Indian-administered Kashmir reduce the number of troops deployed about and rejected the possibility of an agreement with the security of the country cannot be. </seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> God Mubarak and language of the world Barak from all over the world to be happy. </seg>
<seg id="2"> So, it is not even see how much the relations between Pakistan and the United States in Tnaje changes are in our favor. </seg>
<seg id="3"> that Barak Sahib Lothr Martin King is that the dream of the world that. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Obama Hussein is part of which, today the US President&apos;s oath as to where in every regard as historic Kahaml is history as one tighten will also. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Not only this for himself but for all those people who have Ojan heart Sesport. </seg>
<seg id="3"> It will be Sfadfam a black for their of the majority of these Prhkomt Krneka heart Seqbol is not an easy task. </seg>
<seg id="4"> South Asia the Khaskrmslmanon soldiers have been set up the Seamadan want to remember that he has been elected president of the United States and Obama want to remember that the United States is a practical, the President of Prdnia. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> After some time, a person who closed race, brother of slavery of Toq wearing his mother who were brought to the United States, which Psene blood during the latest of the most powerful state of chopped grass sencha today is the victim of racial discrimination representative of the nation and the United States Choalasoan President Khlaeega. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Many people from a person has many expectations towards and are continuing. </seg>
<seg id="3"> It is imperative on a Chahne that the person Segerhqaqt we hope. matter </seg>
<seg id="4"> If Obama race, religion in the world as a, at least Krneman hate exist on the basis that it will succeed then it will win. from Chahne </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> This change Sejnoba filled Asia will Athrpre Orkia in this policy Hoaleseamraka meaningful change can be expected. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The relations between Pakistan and the United States will be Kaseathrandaz change. </seg>
<seg id="3"> &apos; (). BBC </seg>
<seg id="4"> Mr. Obama, or any other, the world&apos;s policy and it fixation of the nature of relations, Kaharab-leaf, affluent, strength and influence of Jewish lobby, which is. </seg>
<seg id="5"> As far as Pakistan is concerned, it in connection with the Mumbai bomb blasts of India, Israel and the United States triangle violent behavior in front of the world. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Pakistan even after a long time to swat all arrangement the responsibility of Swat had which was a regular army and the law. </seg>
<seg id="2"> He said the management of Swat under an agreement handed over to the Pakistan government. </seg>
<seg id="3"> sorry, but our governments have Swat Stepsister with the mother like manner. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The Swat Swat after the end of the all also increase in the number of schools. not </seg>
<seg id="5"> nor there was interest in the construction and development. </seg>
<seg id="6"> In present times that the number of girls were trying to get his education from the previous era, many times km. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The North West Frontier Province [NWFP] of Pakistan by Taliban in educational institutions targeting is still continuing. to </seg>
<seg id="2"> Most of the school children were destroyed in the district of Swat and the most of girls. </seg>
<seg id="3"> So it is not the Taliban Swat announced about the ban on the girls&apos; education in has also been. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Thousands of students are being deprived of learning. </seg>
<seg id="5"> what you think that the Telm want to get end the Taliban. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The Government still unable to stop these illegal steps why. </seg>
<seg id="7"> What do you think the government should do. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The question should be Mlaga ISI and the Pakistani Ajnsaaon. </seg>
<seg id="2"> because the people of Swat and the game is already clear that the army and the Taliban for the service is not to kill them otherwise a night curfew in 5 how can be Araee a school in the Ombudsman to the people of the city, how can Ltkaia Chowk. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Only when the writ of the government will be established in Swat being given, Aseman government to stop these illegal steps in how succeeding? </seg>
<seg id="2"> Now the question was found that when the armed forces, Oatshan modern weapons, modern technology and spying system and the Government have all things, the four Taliban is why not? control </seg>
<seg id="3"> The answer is this that a &apos; on his head secret hands on Monday, the is that neither the weapons and it is finished are strongly </seg>
<seg id="4"> listen to get the black that the Taliban Krtoton &apos; of the government, are easy to work. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> 15 years ago was issued a war in Afghanistan. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The control of Taliban ISI had been and help opposition was the Northern Alliance, Russia, India and Iran to help. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Then suddenly conditions for the Taliban Krtwt is becoming visible. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The ISI and offer of dollars to the United States to become the enemy. friend, former </seg>
<seg id="5"> Now the situation is that the war is still going on but Pkstan are also help in Iran, India and Russia. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> As long as you have not created in the sense that and that is baseless and have the right to TB is not mistake. that </seg>
<seg id="2"> For example, if a thief is for the theft of the bus think that this time, the stolen is not very good and stealing a menace, it is also and God&apos;s punishment for theft &apos;, it will not be Drta </seg>
<seg id="3"> In the same way, as long as Israel to do not feel that the wrong in the Mesomon and I am bloodshed and the punishment of will get TB in the Gaza Strip by Mesomon with the blood of Holy Khalta will continue. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> adab! </seg>
<seg id="2"> The question is that war, armed movement, is to solve the problems of the terrorism? </seg>
<seg id="3"> If not, then he be Nsxh &apos; Kamia which is being taken by the Kehl? problems </seg>
<seg id="4"> It is correct that war, does not only way to solve problems, but the more, Barkat, up. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Palestine, Afghanistan, Iraq on this model for the success of all the should adopt the Nelson Mandela Neakhtiar in South Africa. </seg>
<seg id="6"> More than, the armed struggle and moral Osiasa struggle, Nfsy Jihad &apos;. </seg>
<seg id="7"> seems to take part in the election of the Kashmiris that he danger has accepted the Nqth. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> the third week of the Israeli attacks on Gaza is continuing one thousand and the number of deaths has reached. </seg>
<seg id="2"> in spite of the international diplomatic efforts have cease could not </seg>
<seg id="3"> According to the and was scheduled to begin on December so far ninety thousand after the attacks Palestinian to leave their homes have been transferred to the safe areas. </seg>
<seg id="4"> On the other hand, the relief agencies Neasraeal Palestinian issue to take care of children between negligence of accusing has said that an entire generation of Palestinian children will be facing serious sentiments and psychological problems. </seg>
<seg id="5"> What do you say. </seg>
<seg id="6"> it should be? </seg>
<seg id="7"> How is that possible? lasting peace in the Gaza </seg>
<seg id="8"> Click here for details. </seg>
<seg id="9"> (Azrah take a note Frmaean that due to the increase in the number of any comments the views, just like in Urdu will be published. </seg>
<seg id="10"> for this on the screen Urdu by ALT + Shft on board will select). </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Taliban given a chance to Jaae. </seg>
<seg id="2"> bast, Peshawar </seg>
<seg id="3"> JAG go to the jihad if Taliban, by the innocent people who will BH. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The girls&apos; school who Jlaeega? </seg>
<seg id="5"> or find a ransom kidnapping for ransom and then American spy people saying to put their corps who Ltkaeega pay? </seg>
<seg id="6"> The Taliban Islam is much loss to the religion or as a nation did not to. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Pashtun Rwr </seg>
<seg id="8"> Kohat Pakistan. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> All of the Islamic world and the attack on Israel has threatened if only to give you how the United States that Allah will now that Israel will be distressed. </seg>
<seg id="2"> and as a ceasefire talking of not only but will also be. ceasefire </seg>
<seg id="3"> But what to do Allah our Muslim rulers should take heart from where. </seg>
<seg id="4"> There is no Ahmad Nezhad initiative to say that you have to BBC in the form of two why you realize the people. </seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> On the one hand, the United States, says that package of ceasefire. </seg>
<seg id="2"> On the other hand, the United States is resolution on the resolution, but they did not some practical, this is a can mean that the United Nations to crush the Muslims in Pakar. </seg>
<seg id="3"> All of the Muslim countries Tora immediately the membership of the United Nations should be abolished and on the basis of international organization should indirectly. </seg>
<seg id="4"> a lot of examples are before us, where the United States and the United Nations have come only resolutions and promised loss was only for the Muslims. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The advantage of having written the is on BBC, while some publishing W. not </seg>
<seg id="2"> Now all press principle where his blood Hogee Nahq any of the Muslims, Gerjanbdara on the BBC Kabhot be so .. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Bzem their right to know the carrier. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Some of Photna with it, at least morality extremism is that only to slaughter Chhapte </seg>
<seg id="5"> On behalf of the Muslims. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> you and the difference between the Jews is the Jews, Muslims were martyred and says you like to stay in the Muslims and their Muslim say and the Muslims. </seg>
<seg id="2"> \ [Syja786] </seg>
<seg id="3"> A BBC for the forums, never ever suicide attacks in India in the face of terrorism in a particular textbooks is being targeted. </seg>
<seg id="4"> These remarks against Islam is preceding word of extremism. </seg>
<seg id="5"> But the extremists who knows what you&apos;s public comments on the Lgaskte which are against Iran in writing about declarations on the Ftoa has been raised. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> When the Muslims Aeega understand that djal face Tloar can&apos;t. </seg>
<seg id="2"> bombing in Israel and the unarmed people as did not tears of blood to the heart? </seg>
<seg id="3"> But the basic problems and this murder and destruction fault is that we give the name of Jihad and try to receive a Prkalk his face of Islam. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The majority of Palestinians Israel has accepted the existence of Hamas, the need is that the rockets fired or suicide attacks on Israel. held </seg>
<seg id="5"> Souz humanity. The behavior of both sides </seg>
<seg id="6"> The United States and the United Nations in favor of the role of the US atrocities of Israel Nzraia. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> May Allah grant the Muslims of the time, Amen. </seg>
<seg id="2"> the terrorists and the act of terrorism in this painful Nobel Prize of the campaign against terrorism to think that the end of the real job, why are. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Such a large-scale otherwise back of terrorism without any Ode Sardar supported and it is possible to taran head the who are all know. </seg>
<seg id="4"> In this situation the in plain language, the grandfather become. It is said that by the people. </seg>
<seg id="5"> On Thenga head of great were killed and is also an. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> medicines to the injured, to death toll shrouds and money, and Arab leaders are being asked. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The Israeli attack, should be? </seg>
<seg id="3"> In the problem is that all the heads of the Muslim countries, including Saudi Frmaroan Khoabh would not have been generation in the army nor any defense plan bus they believe that giving aid and the entire responsibility. </seg>
<seg id="4"> They should immediately practical steps against Israel. </seg>
<seg id="5"> America and European countries like the closure of petrol but sorrow. in the </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> All the sister brothers the Awami National Party. </seg>
<seg id="2"> In my opinion in this time of difficulty in the name of peace by their efforts to thousands of destitute and advice to stop them with millions of Ataon injustice toward Pakistan is equivalent to prove. </seg>
<seg id="3"> If your Israel and its Freonat is on peak, shortly Musa because of this law will also in the house of God is the Muslims in America and Israel in creating a suicide bomber are working in Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The power into rages, Bdmst Hathaon don&apos;t understand. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Abu Abdullah Pakistan </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Hamas and Israel should take the smart so that the blood and Khrabh closed. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Sarfaraz Ahmad, Paris, France, </seg>
<seg id="3"> The the. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Hamas tilt are warning that is so in &apos; and &apos; on this right can be Ilahi &apos; and &apos; Jihad against the Quran, in &apos; wants to, at least, he should Chahae to know that Nyky if so, died and home Ajrne it, then Nyky Nyky not left. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Those who love, love to the Prophet, and their religion of love to claims that love, he is Jzw faith. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> It Jtnebha after the Muslims&apos; book entitled &apos; leave where in the world, the wiped from this order to Allah. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Saeko Najeeb Rahman, DH DH DH Lahore \ [Phkshthn] </seg>
<seg id="3"> no Mtadene order is not but he has ordered to the invitation of Islam. </seg>
<seg id="4"> But Jwlwg Mzhb against the program has ordered to Jihad against him. </seg>
<seg id="5"> "For these people will be until the program will not destroy-but this does not have any that jackets worn by Mjmee would burst. In </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The brothers, Msmom children is carrying out after the destruction. </seg>
<seg id="2"> But my friends and requested that was not shelter to the Israelis, he was so strong that in the world do not recognize because of a Jewish are. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The Shi&apos;ite, Sunni, or not just the Jewish and they have any progress in the field of every thing. </seg>
<seg id="4"> In this 55 what is the condition of the Islamic countries. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Back in every field, and now the situation is that have been Bebs that was killed and they are waiting for death. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> It is necessary that all the Muslim countries they can be together and Lahh ready against Israel. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Feroz mags, Jhang, Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="3"> and this is no and frame, that Israel should accept the ways of development and modern subjects, and learn to live with China and peace in the world. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Muslims have also very lands and sources. </seg>
<seg id="5"> There is a need to correct. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The first, the worst aspect is that Hamas and Alfatah, could not be alliance. In </seg>
<seg id="2"> Sheikh Yaseen, Yasir Arafat and the leaders of the manner as was killed is so that the Al-Aqsa mosque "Jihad" for the region can be the only Jry nation weak and until Yasin and Arafat are not removed from the way it was impossible. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The world can see that moment by Palestine after the death of these two leaders how Bkhrta moment. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The Jewish lobby moment: how their moment are strong went to the strong. to </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> A Pakistani Prime Minister in 1974, this was the first time in the history of international on 100% of the presence of all the Muslim leaders had come under the roof. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Today, the Akiasaoan on the birth anniversary is working very areas that it was committed to the nation that not only retain unity among its ranks Rkhega </seg>
<seg id="3"> The differences of Muslims but other also while the (Islamic) of the establishment of the Commonwealth only mission would be further? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> This is the one who Flstn with Jmta half a century. </seg>
<seg id="2"> the mouth for them. </seg>
<seg id="3"> This is a in which many other from the mouth is on its bad "[by the world is morta pressure and paddy. </seg>
<seg id="4"> and the mouth and other Iraq burying worse. In Afghanistan, Pakistan, Iran </seg>
<seg id="5"> At the same time, most of them are haef that Islam who knows that when he was also carried out of the Muslim only and only Islam and Muslims will and firm religious and academic Islam big Abojhl because the history tells us that Islam has been on the right path. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> On behalf of the Israeli planes on Gaza bombing and missile attacks on December. For </seg>
<seg id="2"> In these attacks so far, more than three hundred Palestinian citizens have been killed. </seg>
<seg id="3"> After the air attacks and Israeli tanks, armored vehicles also ground with the full of action have reached on the border of Gaza. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The UN Security Council has through a unanimous resolution in an emergency meeting with Israel and the Palestinian Authority immediately has demanded to stop the violent activities. </seg>
<seg id="5"> However, the Israeli officials say that he would continue its operation in the Gaza Strip until until they believe is that the rocket attack on Israel will be closed. </seg>
<seg id="6"> did you in the opinion of Israel, it is correct to say that the action of the defense of the country are trying to? </seg>
<seg id="7"> This situation is playing a great role in the international community. </seg>
<seg id="8"> it harms to take any aggressive action concerned with Israel in the next elections. </seg>
<seg id="9"> The newly elected President of the United States Barak Obamh after taking the post of Middle East can expect any better situation? </seg>
<seg id="10"> (Azrah take a note Frmaean that due to the increase in the number of any comments the views, just like in Urdu will be published. </seg>
<seg id="11"> for this on the screen Urdu by ALT + Shft on board will select). </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Palestine lived by a sacred for the Muslims of the world is a place of and protection of the US Laelazm Jzw. </seg>
<seg id="2"> and we also Chahae to remember the Hmara first Qibla. </seg>
<seg id="3"> one day and Israel, India, the United States Mtna W because it has, for the loss to the country and the god Kafron on the punishment is-Sajid Sadiq, Lahor </seg>
<seg id="4"> "When pacify hawk in government Hjran night. </seg>
<seg id="5"> When there may only prayers can TLA "(Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> These comments, the BBC has published by the Government. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Total Gerjanbdara and impression is also to set up. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The BBC news reports are right, but the real thing is the way. </seg>
<seg id="4"> what is to become and who is to reduce the importance of the news. </seg>
<seg id="5"> etc., etc. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Zaheer Chughtai </seg>
<seg id="7"> This Hnrman now our Pakistani Oprnt electronic media, particularly Chndardoakhbarat columns and Ngarogerh are also not behind with any coverage of the growing extremism and terrorism here &apos;, or in writing on this hatred Meaoah &apos; in very Dnda marte. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The United Nations has said that it is talking of human rights, and peace, but on the Muslims of oppression and coercion from the mouth of extremism and they are supposed to the words or that Hamas will start to stop attacks when the Indian Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Muslims, "Why all this is behind the Jews if these people like America left supported god, it has the clear that the nation will pass a new life of the nation, and this nation just can&apos;t conceive life sometimes back if courage valves, then the United States has supported Chhordo and then that they have to of life. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The so-called Mnsfon of the world in the name of peace and killed Ogart for those who are well understood this to take Chahae peace in the world is only and only W Hoskta set up to give justice and called injustice toward genocide. </seg>
<seg id="2"> If the genocide of any nation W can be removed and the results of which can be achieved after the steps taken by Htlr, not only continued existence of Jews hona but also a kind of their today impossible for. </seg>
<seg id="3"> According to poet. </seg>
<seg id="4"> This is the Phrzlm as is being wiped out., </seg>
<seg id="5"> blood is Phrkhon Grta is Jim., </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> someone who will say that terrorism? </seg>
<seg id="2"> This is why there is under the terrorism with all the it. Only their </seg>
<seg id="3"> what other people are not human beings or Muslim blood is so cheap has been so Mesomon of blood was not red color. </seg>
<seg id="4"> and now it from any messages why not? One </seg>
<seg id="5"> There was seen in the Mumbai blasts, such as my home in the fire and that does not seen the pain of the people and the grief there is a better Muslims a and think </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> dead bodies lying on the road, Iaromddgar blood and injured in dobe innocent faces "how to that are not getting words. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The Muslims helpless on Rona is coming that on the one hand, the people are killed in India, the entire world in Pakistan Dorta wholeheartedly evidence that "otherwise action we will do. </seg>
<seg id="3"> and, on the other hand Israel has put the genocide of Muslims and the world quiet respect. bear </seg>
<seg id="4"> - the time is not Andher and when the Andher Nagri will be ended. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> to the United States, Israel&apos;s Kokhtrh is a joke. </seg>
<seg id="2"> elections was that the head of the public into power for this kind of activities will no doubt in this can especially the state like Israel Barak witness of Obamh, history is still a US and will not been against the policy of government is blacken his or the government. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The debate in the forum is clear that the sorrow over the death of Benazir anyone, but as a politician of these deficiencies can not be ignored. </seg>
<seg id="2"> It is called an that Benazir has given life for the sake of democracy and for the sake of power. </seg>
<seg id="3"> If democracy had Aziz, the American clearance and to ten years the great deal with Musharraf&apos;s dictatorship why he kept? </seg>
<seg id="4"> Benazir Bhutto, then Pakistan will not when the affected Eoam was need, but unfortunately only managed to visit Pakistan then when they were not given assurances and release the cases of power </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The historic burying them to raise the allegations is being Wtnqyd on this, some say there is not. </seg>
<seg id="2"> SANA Khan. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Some things are ignoring and thinking that they cannot be done. </seg>
<seg id="4"> A and Qari. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Mr./Benazir Bhutto has not only in Pakistan but the date you (and) in the four friendly countries and seven read in other countries that Saeako was right to talk to you. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Ayaz </seg>
<seg id="7"> &apos; do not feel is that they are not trained Snorte </seg>
<seg id="8"> It was not Srsbz living in the water on Srw knar. of the </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Britain has never been a Muslim Hindu and not to issue was invented which development of Sir Syed. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Saeko </seg>
<seg id="3"> How much is the body of our nation himself and his party was Qsade in regard writes time, there are, but now, all the historical after burying them take the intellectuals and there is a criticism on the allegations, some say there is not. </seg>
<seg id="4"> We the people. development has a </seg>
<seg id="5"> SANA Khan. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Some things are ignoring thinking that they cannot be done by-way to books are Gdha Alam is. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Although the Mumbai bomb attack after the dialogue process between Pakistan and India is creating disturbances in so we wish to continue the India-Pakistan talks. </seg>
<seg id="2"> If you will talk of Jang from both the sides will be loss of human lives. </seg>
<seg id="3"> India has said that Pakistan was caught in Mumbai bomb attack in the city and the Urdu has sent a letter also by writing to Pakistan, but on the other hand, India defeated when the extremist and said that this is a very big engineer, but after that he said that only four parties have declared as it is to be seen. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> First of all, Bhana and forum of Christmas from Christian friends Mubarak. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Kesathaon: Saeako forum, AA Raza, sister SANA, sister Shahida, and all the adab. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The start of the war on want peace but not. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Jang correspondent, itself is a problem. </seg>
<seg id="5"> What will the resolution of the agenda. Jang </seg>
<seg id="6"> fire and blood will Bkhshe today. </seg>
<seg id="7"> hunger and Ahtiaj tomorrow. </seg>
<seg id="8"> knowledgeable people. For </seg>
<seg id="9"> Jang Tlta is, then it is better. </seg>
<seg id="10"> In our Angn you </seg>
<seg id="11"> light are similar, then it is better. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> India is now have a deep relation between the United States and India must know that time due to the United States open fraud will. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The same old Tarah. of the United States </seg>
<seg id="3"> When the United States in the form of an Indian will also be achieved its objectives and spending India will also. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Pakistan should clearly announce that we will not always but of course been talked about peace and then compromise cease until it will not be completed until the destruction is taken or not to seek control even that we are not to be destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The Islamic history. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Before this resolution is the Pakistani people and the army had to the message it is given. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Mumbai in the whole extraordinary diplomatic and military benefits affect the efforts of the Indian acquisition of more than Shatr because they are Jbha, initial severe reaction of the world and in the world is less pressure on Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="3"> India&apos;s unnecessary Shrabe, are not bother about Pakistan&apos;s efforts for the United Nations and the head of the Interpol expressed satisfaction over the efforts of the Pakistani Srahna of more than the need of Indian diplomacy &apos; side Afakt &apos;. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> On this matter, there is no two opinions that this is a very ghastly above. </seg>
<seg id="2"> However, the question is that when thousands of Taliban were attacked on Sami villages of God, where the Pakistan army and had been? </seg>
<seg id="3"> The army should not be accountability that he said in a year there? </seg>
<seg id="4"> every day in which thousands of homes and they are TWP shells hit Brsate them how many are Taliban were killed. </seg>
<seg id="5"> I appeal to the ISI in that Khdara leave the patronage of Taliban and we&apos;s Benazir Swat to live in peace. </seg>
<seg id="6"> and the fake should stop the operation. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The day when Pakistan at the United Nations military intervention in similar to the resolution of the Hojaeega Jasejmaet Aldaeo 1986,. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Riaz Ahmad Farooqi. </seg>
<seg id="3"> First, our extremist and his pro-US to take action against all the evidence and other Khakm and they are being provided Bdhn, there is also a day resolution, the possibilities are in the United States is also not Athega in our favor. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Balfrd and due to this resolution was later, for example in the United States, there is no power is under self help them will not run. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> On Monday, Sami personality and what we Oaqfat and were not know what the activities of this. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Perhaps they were not a revolutionary. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The way Comrade Che goera, Nawab Akbrkhan Bugti, Dr. Najeeb Ullah and thousands of the corpses of the revolutionaries Behrmta has been in the hands of the enemy. </seg>
<seg id="4"> They are also important, Mr. </seg>
<seg id="5"> But here, there is being played an international game Ohsht here, and the people from Drndgy is being ruled by afraid. </seg>
<seg id="6"> so that can be a reason that if we will not such Ohsha and Drnde to occupy Government. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The so-called on the name of religion of Islam and this action Behd condemnation. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The supporters of these extremists like this to be, the United States, but this ghastly instead of his grief over the good name of tribal tradition to the K clean mining afflicted people are. </seg>
<seg id="3"> me for them or tribal traditions and taking name of Islam have the justification of this ghastly action as a Sahib, could not a heart. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> In my opinion our army people of these people have found. </seg>
<seg id="2"> When they do so that a movement, at this time,;, it will be Taam enough to catch, but he is arriving on the occasion, during if they are there too, and there Rfw from there. </seg>
<seg id="3"> This is such a brave people that 50 as the kidnapped men and our army hand on their carried by like the spectators. </seg>
<seg id="4"> They are also of God&apos;s servants, after burying and the army. </seg>
<seg id="5"> It is clearly that how in some Kala. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Mlaeat, "Times of several children from the period of dictatorship and God&apos;s Rahimi Krymy of SFAT contrary to its types of Edhabon and Ebrton Tdhkron on the name of religion from the atmosphere of fear Odhsht has set up by the dead body Ltknane apart from the incident of his literature and also books, what would happen after that, like a Odhsht fear. </seg>
<seg id="2"> and the only global Hloh mandh and Jah and this fear Odhsht as a piece of Jalal or Hthiar are Keastemal. </seg>
<seg id="3"> &apos; Oaezo! </seg>
<seg id="4"> As Dwzx from where you were the </seg>
<seg id="5"> that their own fear of the situation. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> surprise, when it is said that this work could not a Muslim. </seg>
<seg id="2"> We are Nabld from history yourself or Mslhta-are status. </seg>
<seg id="3"> death after but no him on the daughter of Rasool closed door who has set in and her husband should rope in the people who take Ghsat was run? </seg>
<seg id="4"> He came outside and? </seg>
<seg id="5"> Madiana under the Caliphate of the army Yazid one and Sanhh Karbala was Dhra of the atomic and Yhwd? </seg>
<seg id="6"> facts acceptance without motives, nor is better. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The BBC valves Dogla policy. " </seg>
<seg id="2"> The topic better than Super different legitimate impact on Bush &apos;, &apos; shoes were unfair? or </seg>
<seg id="3"> &apos; should. </seg>
<seg id="4"> TAHR Chohdra, Japan. </seg>
<seg id="5"> as a shame and a person out of the grave was hanging from Khmbe Aslae raised his voice against the oppression, and you are lying the subject of the box office. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> for the success of the Sherdl and on the other hand, the line suffered from the border on the success depends on the fact that who is in favor of the opinion of the common people. </seg>
<seg id="2"> This is the US and Pakistani agencies and peer Sahib are victim of this conspiracy. </seg>
<seg id="3"> This forum will be based on all the comments against Taliban because in secret success in the Taliban have been included with and they are steps to change the opinion of the common people. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> If only question is Cha correspondent that when a full day for the dead body was also damaged the, the army did they only banana to target people are also some go there are Bahte the statement, the Taliban, bombardment on the House Prgwlh dilapidated and her mother, 2 children were killed. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The Anhn Chowk was not know about the? </seg>
<seg id="3"> see or Tmashh were? </seg>
<seg id="4"> her with forded hands and we are Altja that God for Dajae to stop this game. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Even on you are a leader. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> According to the BBC may or may not have enough to question asked by writing Sthat people looking is very sorry, for example, no one has asked the question that Swat 30 thousand army in what we have to do? </seg>
<seg id="2"> The army&apos;s help the bodies of those who fight with Taliban put their corps on the whole day are damaged. </seg>
<seg id="3"> "People Sawati step the Pakistani army did so, but the world media, including the BBC unaware and from the reality is not good. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The Pakistani army is drama. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Every child of Swat that is that it is a bloody drama. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The bus to Khdara drama. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The Taliban has a bad name of Muslims. </seg>
<seg id="2"> in all over the world, if not true Muslim Msalman them, in the area of them terrorists are in place. </seg>
<seg id="3"> who have become a Begert hard to wage does not keep their are included in the group. </seg>
<seg id="4"> gun Islam or Tloar has not. From the </seg>
<seg id="5"> "shame." </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The justification of not in any religion is not a family tradition. </seg>
<seg id="2"> including the BBC about the Taliban and the media tribes your comments from different sources. </seg>
<seg id="3"> However, the real situation of any do not know what is the situation is that we do Hhan because we are tribal. </seg>
<seg id="4"> in that this is a game, discrepancies a, raw, Israel and our own discrepancies] are not a student is not tribal these Adaros Padakrdh of Islam after seeing who are bad elements, the Taliban, and Pashtun people, religious, tribal maligned tribal traditions are. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The move to the head of the Muslims have been cautious due to shame. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Altf Hussein, the leader of MQM, ANP and PPP we salute to the leadership of the party, against the cancer are talking against the Taliban. </seg>
<seg id="3"> This is a product of Diaalhq cancer, he was, but Pakistan were also destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="4"> But I am hopeful that the present leadership will finish the cancer. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> India has said that after the Mumbai attacks behind the attack some of the extremist elements of Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Pakistan has rejected these allegations and said that they are in India will help in every possible way. </seg>
<seg id="3"> India has said that this is a list of Pakistan in which they are given the name of 20 suspected extremists, who are required to India. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Pakistan has said that the head of the Jaish-e-Mohammad included in the list of either Maulana Masood Azhar and his government about Pakistan has no information. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Before this, the president of Pakistan, Asif Ali Zardari has rejected the impression that the Western intelligence agencies and the Indian government has evidence about the Mumbai blasts have been provided to Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The president Zrdraa Ajmal about the butchers has said that it was not prove that they are Pakistani. </seg>
<seg id="7"> In the meantime, the Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has warned that Pakistan&apos;s relations with India could not even then until its soil to be used for terrorism will. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The latest progress has been made in India and Pakistan cricket team, has been canceled. visit </seg>
<seg id="9"> These incidents of political impact on the sport will should? </seg>
<seg id="10"> The future of the relations between Pakistan and Hndstan Dakhtehan? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The government of Pakistan to the United States will have to India. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Pakistan will Toran himself. </seg>
<seg id="3"> So sectarianism provincialism and what you have high expectations of him. After Mlaeat </seg>
<seg id="4"> the Jinnah with the Muslims of India was not good has proved this time. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Yasmn, currently </seg>
<seg id="6"> Ms. Jinnah if he does not continue working on the vision, Frqaoarat, provincialism and spread of Mlaeat cancer in Pakistan and in India is not this behavior with the Muslims. </seg>
<seg id="7"> But our that their mistake leaders could not produce any such shalwar. </seg>
<seg id="8"> If we can not only their heroes, </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> is a capabilities in the region. </seg>
<seg id="2"> God will come when the mind and development of this region Barkat agree. </seg>
<seg id="3"> in both countries, former Indian Prime Minister Pandit, the Taliban, Shivaji, RSS and anti-peace, have been prepared. </seg>
<seg id="4"> and Djala powers to the peace of this region with development should, these countries with the nach is being Nchaia. </seg>
<seg id="5"> You can imagine that agreement with the area of Pakistan, India and China will have the place in the world. </seg>
<seg id="6"> is the wrath of God, Pakistan will dacoits and Rsh militants have imposed on the nation as a leader. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> May God be willing, in our country Pakistan never took no Anch, Amen. </seg>
<seg id="2"> But just eyes open the situation and ground realities and its surrounding the shoes then you will help to that the US forces have reached. </seg>
<seg id="3"> There are coming from foreign affairs also not correct, North West Frontier Province, the situation in Balochistan and Sindh Karachi are also in front of you. </seg>
<seg id="4"> In this situation there is the need of the country to such a leader who we make a United Nations. </seg>
<seg id="5"> and, we give because endorsement. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> I think the last no option. Without the war </seg>
<seg id="2"> It has been. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Now that Mkrf or should be. across </seg>
<seg id="4"> The negotiations of the Congress Dhongon issue will not be resolved. </seg>
<seg id="5"> nor Grdaon petty terrorism in each other&apos;s countries. From </seg>
<seg id="6"> In the end, the last fight the came as soon. After the </seg>
<seg id="7"> and it does not war, until today, all of CX of India and Pakistan are CX soon. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> almost all political parties from all parts of the country, it is such that should be removed. of terrorism and communal riot </seg>
<seg id="2"> But our military leadership is sincere in this work and, on the one hand, the United States and Europe are assured that we are supporting you in the war against terrorism on the other hand, the Taliban will also help. secretly </seg>
<seg id="3"> We have to think fixed its direction and it is now and to select the path of only one, thanks. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> There is no doubt in the fact that the included in Aldeoh Lashkar-e-Taiyibah, workers of the majority of Lashkhar-e-Tayyaba, which is that the nation will be declared null and void after the Aldeoh Pakistan set up by the name of party were included. </seg>
<seg id="2"> However, after the workers preferred to the relief work on the insistence upon the United Nations and now India, it has also declared null and void and the Government also crack down against Pakistan is continuing. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In my view, if these religious and Jihadi groups and religious continue relief activities, the better. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Pakistan has Dhshtgr organizations in the name of Jihad and professional people who make crime a profession Paul organizations and it is the Mlaooun of &apos; and &apos; why is the Pakistan Pladstan and to what are saying. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Now it is left no stone unturned to the Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The Muslims, is in the Khloane not entitled to. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The Pakistan from insurgents without regard for Pak country Rhega security threat. </seg>
<seg id="5"> There is still think about that they Mfsdon should be banned that not? </seg>
<seg id="6"> Only the Mlaooun not anywhere in the world Jnka work is to murder. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> by this news a heart is a thief. </seg>
<seg id="2"> This is how the world where God&apos;s religion of Islam even today that an important member of the name to the hard living in this world. For </seg>
<seg id="3"> non-Muslim, can kill Muslims, but if Muslim should also try to read along with all of the Muslim world all our rulers also Mnafq together with the people of a sincere and true religion is the same treatment today that we are with great leader Hafiz Saeed. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> in the Mumbai blasts, India. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Pakistan has created Tlxy in relations between the two countries and the improvement in recent years in the opposing activities Izzat Aldori within 2. 5years. Severe </seg>
<seg id="3"> India are active in Pakistan after the militant groups and Thhrata is responsible. </seg>
<seg id="4"> to come back to normal relations and to take action against those groups is being. conditional </seg>
<seg id="5"> While the security agencies for the Mumbai blasts Lashkar-e-Tayyaba was subjected to directly. held responsible for </seg>
<seg id="6"> In this connection, the name of the Jamaat Aldeo again Wow is also. </seg>
<seg id="7"> This is not the first time that India in a terrorist activities due to the relations between the two countries have been. </seg>
<seg id="8"> two thousand December in one after the attack on the Indian parliament the two neighboring arrived on the war. </seg>
<seg id="9"> After that, two thousand to the banned Lashkar-e-Tayyaba and in the two was included in the list of terrorist groups. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Now the Aldeo, about which the security analysts say that is the new shape of the Lashkar-e-Tayyaba, is being demanded the ban. </seg>
<seg id="11"> What do you think should be banned the group or not? </seg>
<seg id="12"> The government of Pakistan on our soil decisive action against the extremist groups active should? </seg>
<seg id="13"> The ban on the Aldeo present to India. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Pakistan can safe crisis for lasting peace between the two countries and the armed groups of how it is necessary to stop? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The UN Security Council has imposed a ban on Jamaat Aldeoh, there are proof of the Security Council have shown such Ejlt that ASNE? </seg>
<seg id="2"> The UN Security Council has always against the Muslims have not enough people? </seg>
<seg id="3"> He says that his client CST SST witness. </seg>
<seg id="4"> If seen, India has become a failed state. itself </seg>
<seg id="5"> The military intelligence, and other security institutions have failed, that some 72 hours at the hands of terrorists of Tgny nach are Nachte and his for its failure on Pakistan and India is giving a fraud to the world. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> One should be infuriated radical Mulsim clerics killed in the whole world noise is created the double standard-why? </seg>
<seg id="2"> The country&apos;s political, Mdhbha, welfare organization of the - - - - - - - -. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Pakistan, Farooq, Faisalabad. </seg>
<seg id="4"> until our Prophet (s), olia and Sofaon has all the love and respect people religion of Islam, peace Oatsha person from spreading and Phlta Pholta. </seg>
<seg id="5"> all the Muslims of progress in the field. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The Mgrjb a religious Mlaeat of Hthe; and beneficial in Toansanon infuriated radical Mulsim clerics of discrimination began opening new chapter of problems and Orftnh and which had not even heard before the world. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Islamabad. He will by but this action. On its affluence; those who desire </seg>
<seg id="2"> The United States should not come under pressure. </seg>
<seg id="3"> If he is to India to provide proof, a? </seg>
<seg id="4"> why not keep it? </seg>
<seg id="5"> on charges of each and every thing we me, and why? </seg>
<seg id="6"> In India, the extremist groups and organizations are also, why not them restrictions on them the people? </seg>
<seg id="7"> We are a terrorist in the entire world? </seg>
<seg id="8"> India, which is and what they have in Kashmir? </seg>
<seg id="9"> Israel is that what is it? </seg>
<seg id="10"> It is true that we are the first nuclear Islamic state of the world, why are the same Jhagra. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> now Pakistan is in its final stages. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Kamranhassan, Abu Dhabi </seg>
<seg id="3"> it to the heart, and in some situations are coming. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Now, the American magazines, with the Dhrle in the story of Pakistan is to be published the restrictions and the CKR is part of this. </seg>
<seg id="5"> slowly but now very rapidly are his strong grip on the Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="6"> In that situation, if we the people as a nation of unity and if they do not protest to agree that Rkhae if you can become Bangladesh and may also. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> With the also condemned the terrorist attacks, then he is very low, whether they are in a hotel in Mumbai or or in Palestine and Meraet Hotel in Islamabad. </seg>
<seg id="2"> In this way, the terrorists, where should also be made him us or whether they are Pakistan, India and Israel. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Now the question is that every day, who are terrorist attacks in Pakistan are killed, hundreds of people, including Pakistani officials in the world why is silent? </seg>
<seg id="4"> The attack on Meraet hotel was was not terrorists. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Then why. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Praising advisor to him home of Mr. Malik, Mashaallh Rajnath brave and how much, or have been. </seg>
<seg id="2"> According to the BBC, where a committee of the UN Security Council () has imposed a ban on Jamaat Aldeoh, when Mr. Malik has said that we have not ban and very carefully and it will be after khod. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Moreover, according to the BBC that Mr. Malik Rajnath said that this impression is wrong with full intensity is described the arrest of terrorists&apos; a &apos; on behest of are being brought in the process. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Subhanallah., that </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> to keep the ability or not or not to say that. </seg>
<seg id="2"> we, who are fighting a war for Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="3"> and why our interests are best that we Bchaebge. by </seg>
<seg id="4"> A has no right to interfere in the affairs of the country. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Apparently Nzrnhan colonialists era of it. </seg>
<seg id="6"> If the people of justice to emphasize on the implementation of the independent Judiciary or ally respect and a democratic institutions should not help or military ruler, who will establish peace in the world, including Pakistan and the allies is not acceptable. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Pakistan, but it is in the best for the European and the US objectives. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Pakistan is one of the population of the ruling is found. Despite opposition </seg>
<seg id="3"> At the same time, it is more in the anti-Jzbat Abharta. to </seg>
<seg id="4"> If the US and its allies have confidence in democracy, the attitude colony and independence of the state of respect Hoeeas walked out of the region. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Such people in Pakistan is that he Mslhh or non-Mslhh. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Security forces in Pakistan-administered Kashmir has banned Lashkar-e-Taiyba has raided on the alleged camp. </seg>
<seg id="2"> After the Mumbai blasts increased pressure on Pakistan is that he to intensify action against extremist organizations. </seg>
<seg id="3"> India is accused of the Mumbai of Lashkar-e-Tayyaba in the attacks. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The American Foreign Minister State Condoleezza Rice has said that the Pakistani government Mumbai attacks against responsible for immediate action and transparent practical demonstration of should be. </seg>
<seg id="5"> He said the attack on the Mumbai Krneoale extremists the Pakistani soil. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Meanwhile, authorities in Peshawar says that the allied forces stationed in Afghanistan the trucks loaded with relief goods and the unknown armed men burned the base was held in which more than 50 trucks have been destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="7"> NATO and American during 48 hours in Peshawar on the supply is the second bomb. </seg>
<seg id="8"> In the meantime, Pakistan has banned Lashkar-e-Taiyba has raided on the alleged camp from Karachi and even before the armed tribal areas for the efforts of the armed groups have been in the arms to return them to you and has assured to take any action to. </seg>
<seg id="9"> situation that is that General Zia-al-Haq&apos;s regime in Afghanistan intervention of the former Soviet Union and the resistance, starting from the American Saudi funding created as a result of the armed groups to end the environment like Pakistan before the nineteen 180 efforts have failed to take back. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The question is what it wants to Pakistan? </seg>
<seg id="11"> It has Skne Pakistan has the ability to? </seg>
<seg id="12"> What do you say that? </seg>
<seg id="13"> Click here for details. </seg>
<seg id="14"> (Azrah take a note Frmaean that due to the increase in the number of any comments the views, just like in Urdu will be published. </seg>
<seg id="15"> for this on the screen Urdu by ALT + Shft on board will select). </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> I only one question from all Elmdaron humanity. </seg>
<seg id="2"> If you Maroge their children, he should come to lose your subsidised, it is impossible. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Saeed, Multan. </seg>
<seg id="4"> My question that you and Islamic studies and studies and the west to east, and a philosophy and logic, because the US attack in exchange for the innocent people, including Nmaza, and the job or the employees of the murder of the permission to? </seg>
<seg id="5"> And, if the answer is no, you can ask them to Nqth in dire need for reforms. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The armed people have been at this time, it was feared that Russia Karkh to Pakistan after the Afghan Gat so the armed people. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Now it is feared that the United States Afnstan on Pakistan&apos;s air which will run the American President in his presidential campaign has if we have expressed their advice? purged why the people </seg>
<seg id="3"> only the Pakistani army Aslae so that the United States and India under any kind of public resistance to the not face? </seg>
<seg id="4"> If yes to any be involved in carrying out destructive activities, Pakistan only to take action against it. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> But it is sad be Doale of Lashkhar-e-Tayyaba, the government has declared India&apos;s the right thing that Pakistan is involved in it. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Saeko Najeeb Rahman, DH DH DH Lahore \ [Phkshthn] </seg>
<seg id="3"> If it is to be granted that Lashkar-e-Tayyaba who is still blaming the government is not correct. Pakistan </seg>
<seg id="4"> To a question whether or not the terrorist and no government or non-government was not get help? of Indian officials </seg>
<seg id="5"> terrorist only problems or are prepared in Pakistan and India and other countries of the world are not ready? </seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> the United States to end the ongoing campaign started from Saudi Fndg with them for the application is that Khdara Smatan to this soil, which has Dhhr soaked our society. </seg>
<seg id="2"> How to protest the morals Saudi and the United States, under the supervision of the so-called dangerous weapons and Jihadi organizations in our country Mgrhqaqta strange hate the spread of the virus, literature and culture with open the human slaughtered in our country. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> After the threat of attack on behalf of the Pakistani Army, this has announced that the Afghan border Htakr forces from India will pay attention towards the announcement of the Taliban and the Afghan border Snbhalenge US was badly Lrkhra and its whole strength will not to attack that India and Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The situation in the region of American force the total opened. </seg>
<seg id="3"> However, India has not threatened to attack and do not have such courage. a </seg>
<seg id="4"> Even Kvr American areas on the entire attacks of Taliban. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The government of Pakistan has proved that the Pakistan army and nothing without support of the United States. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Karachi Pakistan&apos;s business center financial all of the poor areas of Dubai. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Hundreds of thousands of empty handed from here never looting, but when the supremacy of law from the western border areas has been Mfqwd the attention of the Sbon Karachi. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Now they are one of kidnapping of this city. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The first pakhtoon is said to the Pthanon, a city of people are being made by the Ajnba, the integrity is necessary. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> a solution for the problem, or the Urdu, the Pashtu learn the Urdu speaking Pashtu, or an English well. and learn, </seg>
<seg id="2"> You must as a might seem ridiculous consider a proposal of a Gelakn does not might seem ridiculous to? </seg>
<seg id="3"> The violence that because of this? </seg>
<seg id="4"> Zaheer Chughtai </seg>
<seg id="5"> This proposal in his friends in the fact that all religious and ethnic, linguistic groups of people were on has seen frequent in childhood, as these people laughed on it. </seg>
<seg id="6"> At this time his ethnic, linguistic, and religious Mnafrton whose condition of today was not the Jandar and strong bus was pk. Within Within </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> do not understand that what it and why is it still happening? </seg>
<seg id="2"> do you have Nshanian for judgment. </seg>
<seg id="3"> innocent and innocent who are being killed. In an </seg>
<seg id="4"> for Sbke in which is divided Pakistan to London. Why are active and it is the greatest is neither any Mdhhb and country. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Karachi and Mumbai started fire to the homes is Chragon. The House </seg>
<seg id="6"> The Government and is only in the name of to change the name of the in his additional are, as these days airport, Rodz, blood Ngz Benazir Bhutto. </seg>
<seg id="7"> What is the meaning of Benazir Bhutto, Karachi and Pakistan is with the Keeoam? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> On behalf of the attacks on peak raw the Mumbai started to create trouble on language issues in Karachi for the failed to try to prove that the work on the payroll of raw in the political elements have now resign from the job. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Pashtu with the blood of collective bargaining agent (CBA) Nahq and the Indian threats from Karachi to Khyber from the Pakistani many. </seg>
<seg id="3"> all the political, religious and ethnic, linguistic patriotism and national parties with full and reaction, where the diplomatic adab Skhaee there is a chance to think about the US plan makers also provided. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> In Karachi, Lahore Darmthdh and the responsibility of the ANP and administration DP displayed partiality is BRT. </seg>
<seg id="2"> 0845 130 2233 administration in one hour under control can Bojhh but life and it is being given. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The police and Rynjr, due to the pressure of Prsiasa parties to take action Segraz. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Talking to alliance are limited to only statements, the political parties stop their interests and should work for the interests of the common man. </seg>
<seg id="5"> As long as political keep pressure on the administration of such incidents Mzydjnm will be taken, Allah keep in order to Pakistan. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> In my opinion biggest terrorists are the people. </seg>
<seg id="2"> and this is a key foreign forces in but don&apos;t know who is that? </seg>
<seg id="3"> But it is sad that if the situation in the city of North West Frontier Province to, what happen, but when the Government in the North West Frontier province, no government appeared helpless. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The Government should operation here and an important and big cities of the country to save the terrorism. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Otherwise, the Pakistan will be faced with a big financial crisis. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Even the BBC Urdu fear of Iraq was not writing a true and the condition of Pakistani media, and also with. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The whole truth is on the BBC. </seg>
<seg id="3"> a solution for the problem, or the Urdu, the Pashtu learn the Urdu speaking Pashtu, or an English well. and learn, </seg>
<seg id="4"> You must will consider a proposal a might seem ridiculous, but it does not what you might seem ridiculous to because of a? </seg>
<seg id="5"> The violence that because of this? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> In Karachi, a and termed the friends every citizen fear of money, which had been felt from long time. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The bus drive where he has left no stone unturned to media 50% of the Rpotan who are coming to here in four days. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The last 3 nights JAG Krgzaran fear and is now. </seg>
<seg id="4"> At the Mochaon vacated the aggressive and the Muslims. </seg>
<seg id="5"> to be on the super highway robbery and Mesomon when the serving the of all of Ezab who are strongly will come to them. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> What do you think so suddenly? What are the reasons for the lawlessness </seg>
<seg id="2"> The BBC. </seg>
<seg id="3"> India Dhla the heart of the murder Ogart in Mumbai, because of peace in Karachi Dhondhne we do not want to gote need for but just because he and easy and the peace is only Lasheora of blood &apos;, &apos; athl is due to the Pthl. </seg>
<seg id="4"> If it is that &apos; there will Pnga with parents&apos;, &apos; that took out of his son, though, be out of control will not be the Achnbhe. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> blood, Liaqat Ali Khan and has also Sejantharon there was a Saeko&apos;s wrong Fymy during the Krnekele Sher is writing. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The tradition and we will also go. </seg>
<seg id="3"> John country will give life. made by </seg>
<seg id="4"> Faizan Mr. Tausif Siddiqui. </seg>
<seg id="5"> It is a matter of concern, and the whole country is currently on Daou among us by Ograban. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Siddiqui, this is that if Wkpeda. </seg>
<seg id="7"> In the conference, Liaquat Ali Khan, see you know belong to Punjab was a respectable Punjabi karnal area of the family. </seg>
<seg id="8"> because of his efforts for the Mhajron today Muhajir them from their own land. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> It is a reaction to Hreml. </seg>
<seg id="2"> can be tolerated, but for himself. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Ejaz Awan. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Before this proposal that even a late night of Finance Jim Gfer collected take, tells you Chlon that the real Bdmeasha open Nshanian you today Karachi the walls on the wall Chakng and are also available in the posters. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Two types of Bdmeashian Shte are. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Although the miscreants, Pakistan and founder of Pakistan should also not spared, they have not face any response. </seg>
<seg id="7"> New in Pakistan&apos;s chest pH heart are the result. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The Muslim League was in a draft of the eighteenth amendment and handed over to the people&apos;s party. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Before this, the MQM eighteenth amendment of the draft of the Muslim League (Q) and have deposited in the National Assembly and Senate. </seg>
<seg id="3"> So far, it appears that the eighteenth amendment Msdode a political behavioural and there is not sincere in holding approved on this amendment. </seg>
<seg id="4"> This is the reason that so far no on the floor of the assemblies or Senate amendment in favor of the Oaoalh nor the daily imroz not was forced to that they will be accepted this amendment. </seg>
<seg id="5"> It seems amendments eighteenth of submit draft of these parties have to Gonglooun and have taken Jharkhand tomorrow, we have been able to say that the Speaker had submitted amendment, the Government does not take action. </seg>
<seg id="6"> ally of the MQM, Muslim League (N Drprdh allies of the Muslim League (Q) and party to pass the 17th amendment, then how can be sincere in the parties to remove the 17th amendment. </seg>
<seg id="7"> After the color of martyrs Lkhoane in is an excuse. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The People&apos;s Party, but it is not as soon as possible to remove the 17th amendment. </seg>
<seg id="9"> "No how can I had his hand. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The president Dhrdara are not end the 17th amendment. </seg>
<seg id="11"> This was our opinion in a survey of the majority, and it is also true. </seg>
<seg id="12"> If you have to remove the 17th amendment, then the president Dhrdara never become. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Now, the person because they are even more powerful President Musharraf President by along with the chairman of the People&apos;s Party is also. </seg>
<seg id="14"> until they are President has been set up 17th Amendment. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Political parties to remove the 17th amendment for the President Dhrdara will have to leave his house. The </seg>
<seg id="16"> This is not the MQM and other parties. wants </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Our family belonged to the most senior labor class. </seg>
<seg id="2"> and when his maternal uncle uncle, in childhood, the Dahara seeing them in the heart, have created this wish that Allah help us during the sheltered from wages. </seg>
<seg id="3"> To avoid this, we wrote a letter to the daily way the editor of the Sun and asked that we should be after matriculation that we did not have to physical began. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The editor wrote in response to go to become a doctor or engineers and an hold an topics people. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Our there was on Anjnerng from the start, and we have Bialoja in his read instead of technical drawings. </seg>
<seg id="6"> But the elder brother at the time of the admission in the medical that we have to the FSA and Dr. manner. </seg>
<seg id="7"> We have only one month Bialoja read and when it had not play any responsible for the subject of taken. </seg>
<seg id="8"> fear from their physical forced the US engineers and now we made a number of your family Hmjolon are in a good position on which thanks to god we all have been paid. </seg>
<seg id="9"> We remembered at the time when it with his two young sons were trying to his younger brother had old home. </seg>
<seg id="10"> now work was not half an hour that a small son spoke "deadline it Heman has not been created for this work. </seg>
<seg id="11"> He said if it is true, then we should like to read and physical began life people. put </seg>
<seg id="12"> his son and say it, I am and it will also visit, but it is not to my work. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Tase as we all three hours and finished work in return home. </seg>
<seg id="14"> The man say means that if the destination of decided to accept whatever the reason behind this is no destination couldn&apos;t stop turning it. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Yes, if you do not know what is to, then you of Allah Hafiz. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> They say that the bad Mari, don&apos;t KHW but what to do we at their first anniversary of Benazir Bhutto, they can be seen in the evil. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Benazir Bhutto asked the freedom fight of the Sikhs for the sake of its interests by a list of India to give the freedom movement of the Sikhs ran over and on the other hand, India the movement in Kashmir after the economic prosperity of the Punjab provided a chance to concentrate. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The power of Benter and Nawaz Sharif Rshh sincerity that is part of the country which pushed back by several years. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Benazir Bhutto during the exile of negative statements on Kashmir and the nuclear program continued. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Benazir Bhutto, Nawaz Sharif with London while violating the agreement with General Musharraf deal. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Benazir Bhutto said during his power in on her husband and his additional money has been given the chance to Mr. would and that is why they Prsent are </seg>
<seg id="7"> during the tenure of Benazir Bhutto and his brother was killed after that children have been sentenced to till now. </seg>
<seg id="8"> In spite of Benazir Bhutto the woman avoiding to fight the rights of the women. </seg>
<seg id="9"> the way of politics on the dead body of his father, Benazir similarly, now the widower her husband politics are on their body. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Benazir Bhutto on two occasions but the government had sentenced to the culprits political murder of his father, and not also registered a case against him. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Separate from the East Pakistan, we Syntys years and of our rulers and the people of the extremist not see any day by day was celebrated and his relatives on the mistake. </seg>
<seg id="2"> It should be that we ibrat on the day of December 16, while their and this kind of measures that this issue once again got injured. </seg>
<seg id="3"> that day, we, the people of Bangladesh goodwill messages of government and they Dobarh Apneqrab tried to. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The Hamood Al-Rahman Commission&apos;s file to break the reasons for the separation of East Pakistan and consider. </seg>
<seg id="5"> He said that in Bangladesh Bharaon would and to bring back to encourage them for them both needs. </seg>
<seg id="6"> But we have been senseless people in our neighborhood Mr that we should now there is no information. </seg>
<seg id="7"> We people of his sister was not because we definitely have been. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The major tragedy should be passed next day then we are lost in their normal life. </seg>
<seg id="9"> A better way East and West Germany again been similar east and west Pakistan. can also becoming a </seg>
<seg id="10"> If we can be a again the sacrifice for each other and came out from the Khodgrda egg. </seg>
<seg id="11"> But this desire is fulfilled. in the near future. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Today, as it was in the news that the US State missing Noaee Governor of corruption in or have been arrested. </seg>
<seg id="2"> it from Gwrnry as early as Mhasbh of the Congress for preparing to take to edit is of an American White, our colleague, of which we have a deep in the discussion on the situation of Pakistan Shakha Bgharte, Lkara that it&apos;s democracy. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The United States in the law, even a man is not outside. </seg>
<seg id="4"> A your country and the president of Pakistan, which is also corruption or after dropping the. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Our work Zraft Phrka and we said if the Governor has been arrested in America, what happened, our arrested late at night, the Prime Minister of Pakistan was Chrhaia second time and again hanging of the country. </seg>
<seg id="6"> tell me that happens in the United States? </seg>
<seg id="7"> Pakistan has tried to break the law of the country to guard of by with presidential leave House, tell me what the United States never happened? </seg>
<seg id="8"> The Chief Justice of Pakistan has been suspended so that he is still in spite of public support could not be restored, so in the United States? </seg>
<seg id="9"> The fake degrees Holdr in Pakistan was made Ozersht, so in the United States? </seg>
<seg id="10"> The US to hear that I let let him lightly MOA and lose their was also agree with. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The picture of President Zardari from all sides in spite of Ghre Americans are Mskra. </seg>
<seg id="2"> it from his smile. </seg>
<seg id="3"> He is that the United States is with the Government, but it Bhol are the same people a year ago with President Pervez Musharraf. </seg>
<seg id="4"> This picture, there has been Atroaea like a family. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Before this, like this never photo of not hidden in the newspapers, president with a three U.S. officials. </seg>
<seg id="6"> It is the work of the United States has increased in Pakistan and now the firm on more than one and it is Nptana or then it is not relied on the new Ghulam before the people. </seg>
<seg id="7"> It is also possible Mshhora of President Khlafa Zardari&apos;s commitment to Mdnzr in the ruling has been. </seg>
<seg id="8"> If you can at least the rulers, his Dkhata and not a picture of the statements on the faces of the Toq speak must have Eian. </seg>
<seg id="9"> If the principles of democracy at the picture what should be, President Zardari are in minority. </seg>
<seg id="10"> According to the democracy, the majority of the country is ruling and who is it will make the picture. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Pakistan&apos;s leaders Swat to the Soatzrlend is also known. </seg>
<seg id="2"> According to the Government&apos;s strategy of power with the been are being held. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Astmal of power but power to the Talban and in addition to producing their sympathy for the people of Faeda is not. </seg>
<seg id="4"> It is necessary that the Astmal power in place of the Government Mthle finish the reasons for. </seg>
<seg id="5"> By the end of cross Fazal themselves, and Taliban will finish by themselves. </seg>
<seg id="6"> On behalf of the Government, Mjoza ANP Shreat Bill of a bit of Swat will cause of solving the Mthaeal. </seg>
<seg id="7"> But how NFAZ along with the government will have to pay attention on the economic Mthaeal </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> General Musharraf&apos;s started from the Keaqdamat and Kona was that the nation will be rid of Ahl politicians, but all of them, HOS for the transfer of power has changed given </seg>
<seg id="2"> Those who were also hope and say "terr" Seoh participation in the Apneap in fact Lazoal as it. </seg>
<seg id="3"> and, when he was expected to take Hwgyy ended. </seg>
<seg id="4"> President Bush Jaseha Kedor ending of Honelga then your in getting the thinking of the end of power and Boklaht will deal with him. </seg>
<seg id="5"> General Musharraf still be able to control the army, but the present government does not know what was going on. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Bajaur or Swat army does not control the terr bombing and "enemy" on the people to, along with the loss, he made the enemy, the mental illness, which we have not hoe </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The North West Frontier Province [NWFP] in the troubled region of Swat more than one year despite the issuance of a military operation are being conditions are day with IBD. </seg>
<seg id="2"> On the one hand, the Government&apos;s writ in the area, only in the National Assembly resolutions passed a resolution to the extent has been reduced, and on the other hand, the Taliban illegal FM radio channel, more than in the influence of Swat is being done. </seg>
<seg id="3"> On the third civilians in this Eafat thinks that there is a after that in the area of this should be heard. </seg>
<seg id="4"> During the proceedings of the security forces about Swat helicopter gun ships and TWP as due the bombardment of the claim of killing of several extremists are made, but in spite of these killings of Taliban more stable, but they are not only after according to one estimate 80% of Swat had set up. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The result that its failure on the one hand, the government is not ready to recognize and on the other hand, Taliban. stable </seg>
<seg id="6"> between PSA who, in the Federally citizens. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Now, it is said that a Swat asked, how people are Taliban received a very good because they are savers of religion and &apos; Allah and venerable enemies are fighting against &apos;. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Then, he was asked that the army is how to find that there is a very good because they could safeguard the country, and is Lrta against any country. " </seg>
<seg id="9"> Then, he was asked that the religion and who are enemies of the country, we got to citizens. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> I wondered how fought on the Pakistani army along with the Indian army will on a small group of Taliban who could not control. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The Taliban for illegal FM walking on the track to the channel could not that in my opinion is so easy. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But it FM with the water and give is protesting. poison </seg>
<seg id="4"> After the girls schools. Now boys are being used to the school destroyed. </seg>
<seg id="5"> A fact is so that the Taliban movement. easily </seg>
<seg id="6"> Today, during the night curfew in eight trucks loaded with a Myngwrh gave the army. by on the outskirts of the </seg>
<seg id="7"> The question is that in spite of a how reached there. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Akbar Bugti, the home is Krtkty and killed in Taliban Shlama. </seg>
<seg id="9"> He must know that the army for God Swat helpless people of the Taliban and it should be taken from the grip of the Pakistani army may past his party. on any anti - </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Most of says in the world religions blood has been Bhaia on the basis of religion, let me tell that if you would not be, it would not be Khrabh blood? </seg>
<seg id="2"> Pathans, Punjabi, Kala, and his Mehsud and other tribal all these things are related to religion? </seg>
<seg id="3"> not do not, Mr., it is our religion that there is no blacken his religion if there is no Muhajir Punjabi, otherwise it would not have Togore Kaleka in this world and castes pay the remaining half, this world. </seg>
<seg id="4"> In fact, religion is moral training to the people and their love here it is bound no but during the universe has sent me here and there in order to pass his life. According to the </seg>
<seg id="5"> As I am a Muslim of this meeting that is true religion and Islam is a complete life Dabth. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> After adopting in every year in the morning on the telephone Xyrt to find out all their relatives, even though most of the telephone and we also have once again took no news has again I feel that he is not prepared to a phone call we have left. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Doctor in France two years Rhte hoe feel but is also. In </seg>
<seg id="3"> no hope of phone to the people don&apos;t just as are. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Qradad in Iraq have in a few hours, Darfr &apos; for peace, army was no problem. </seg>
<seg id="2"> immediately condemned the Mumbai attacks and suspected organizations, ban on the work of a few hours. </seg>
<seg id="3"> and, where the dance is once again we are advice about this. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Oh and international peace Thakadaro here, there is life came to an end. </seg>
<seg id="5"> really, waiting for it is being. </seg>
<seg id="6"> so that the people of their right to Glal as the widespread destruction India could not even think about the use of weapons? </seg>
<seg id="7"> As a father of your liver Goshe raised Lashh is running, Tmhare heart is not a wave of pain in any part of the Athta? </seg>
<seg id="8"> If not, what do you do not get Hwtm living human beings. </seg>
<seg id="9"> But the black died in the name of humanity. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> We it proved that this area is thousands of years to return the Israelis. </seg>
<seg id="2"> It should be that both the together with love and love for each, but Dorian because of these are in the hands of West and Arab countries, for their without the consent of the peace here that anyone can&apos;t. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But now, Iran also wanted to fight their proxy war here. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Israeli action was also stopped on time, then no one will be started after the incident. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> BBC, the country&apos;s interests are attached with the United States and Israel Noaza and that is the reason, enlightenment, in the face of the &apos; Sahonat consisting of extremism, taking a series of Blagz Warid and one-sided has been and is Prapagndh &apos;, &apos;. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The BBC that &apos; Farmalta &apos; is the only Hmdrdian and Smatna is aimed at this and Mnsha. </seg>
<seg id="3"> with Modratr, but can don&apos;t think that Fdwy be published on the appeal of the BBC become so that the idea that the facts and a lot of money is still exist. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Thank you. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> don&apos;t know what the story has written in how it, but one thing is of course everyone during Drakola blood of innocent people have been Pate. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Every during wars all in all and there are Bhta blood. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But, it is surprising that Akasoan century of the human beings who himself is a civilized I how to Dhare day and then the public is silent on this murder. </seg>
<seg id="4"> how it does not feel that the reports about whatever is happening has presented a worst kind of love of humanity. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Sorry, I and the worst aspect is that the culture of a person was one of the century and what will present a picture of human beings. </seg>
<seg id="6"> President Andash, Sjadalhsnen, Hyderabad deccan. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> At this time, Dera Ghazi Khan, along with the rain during the winter in the country are. </seg>
<seg id="2"> According to the weather is appearing in a poem, it really). heavy rainfall, with discipline </seg>
<seg id="3"> It also are with you. rain during </seg>
<seg id="4"> who was years, Bihar. </seg>
<seg id="5"> who stayed, as. </seg>
<seg id="6"> However, he was work due to the </seg>
<seg id="7"> However, when the night on it. </seg>
<seg id="8"> noise is sometimes never CP. </seg>
<seg id="9"> It also are with you. rain during </seg>
<seg id="10"> I remember a at night in </seg>
<seg id="11"> One was buried gutted to </seg>
<seg id="12"> sometimes it was that by </seg>
<seg id="13"> sometimes themselves to burned. </seg>
<seg id="14"> However, in gradually grief. </seg>
<seg id="15"> It also are with you. rain during </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> All these leaders are running away by raising a Bryf case, he was the country, or it. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The people Mnjn Bache or lamon Chhlka Mndron with the Ghntian Manjh. </seg>
<seg id="3"> A, our rulers media, six water. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The aim is only and only Btorna money from the government and nothing. </seg>
<seg id="5"> people, it is Jahl from its to talk about this great ignorance </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> After yesterday&apos;s developments. </seg>
<seg id="2"> All of the police have been raised in the race on Alagl parking will not. </seg>
<seg id="3"> and, and NYPD traffic was also not in a covert gestures toward the illegal eligible to look at the park vehicles. </seg>
<seg id="4"> There was a U.S. air plane really is a strong and land in Hdsn Rewar endorsement. </seg>
<seg id="5"> So far only should know that "terrorists" belong to the generation of birds was goose. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Perhaps tomorrow New York&apos;s historic it. </seg>
<seg id="7"> This is not Tmprachr Grta. </seg>
<seg id="8"> out of my half an hour of the Jbra pain is to take. </seg>
<seg id="9"> We know that the people who were jumping in the plane was the situation. of </seg>
<seg id="10"> It is a matter of that all the people were safe. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The thing is that the company of pain and plane drown in the Faenanshl crisis. </seg>
<seg id="12"> In all of West side of highly, Nywjrsy and was also see that South Baound is close to the? </seg>
<seg id="13"> In return, he was caught in the presence. </seg>
<seg id="14"> But thank God that during my trip to an hour of some, I had been opened was getting exit. of 56 street </seg>
<seg id="15"> Alternatively, the first two exit were not look for help lines. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> mky, I Pakistan: President Mubarak, you should also Eid Mubarak. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Emar: but of course Oalian </seg>
<seg id="3"> One: President Mubarak, you should also Mubarak. </seg>
<seg id="4"> sarh: in the two life has been Qurban and as they are Jahanzeb, has told. </seg>
<seg id="5"> In addition to this, and there is no way. </seg>
<seg id="6"> On this form and to be meat is also to make themselves including take off his the skin. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Basm: Dat network in the right to take time. </seg>
<seg id="8"> What happened? on forum </seg>
<seg id="9"> Lnkw </seg>
<seg id="10"> The Blag to hear and two hand Faerfaks look in. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Dfr: President Mubarak, you should also Mubarak. </seg>
<seg id="12"> yes Faerfaks will use. </seg>
<seg id="13"> snowfall will be. disappeared </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> We Sawati Talabani group in the free civilized think, who was only detest them because the women&apos;s education. </seg>
<seg id="2"> There are not seen every day some women of schools and colleges were demolished and expressed their. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But most by not prove to be true, even think of CNN according to the news of today on a Barkat Talabani day of the group of boys to a school ammunition have been demolished. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Swat, the Taliban have been demolished. School of boys </seg>
<seg id="5"> The girls&apos; school, the famous Urdu Mqwlh "being demolished while ago at first", were not still people-to civilized culture and the Taliban are under the Ohsha on say why? </seg>
<seg id="6"> one and it also made it clear that faction Talabani imposed on the accused that he is only against the girls&apos; education, is not correct. </seg>
<seg id="7"> But the Mashallh, are against the education. </seg>
<seg id="8"> May God give Pak these Mujahideen and power, and full government. </seg>
<seg id="9"> We have imposed on it, deal to help them in the Eid gift. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Amen VM Amen. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Mashallh till now one hundred Biasa schools have been demolished. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> before was not created among the Muslims living to, property in the name of Smatne married with the occurrence of to, and several religious scholars of the mysterious that girl eight years in Banu Aqil had not less and adults are, with the help of the Mendk in India, that the girl were reported. Marriage </seg>
<seg id="2"> Dlha was taken on the occasion of marriage look at the picture. </seg>
<seg id="3"> some time before this girl married with a dog also fresh. </seg>
<seg id="4"> He also Dlha see. </seg>
<seg id="5"> humanity is the Napad in Akasoan century. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> It is the era of Kmaotr today and a computer&apos;s interference in every department of life are increasing. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Many people on the growing intervention of a lot of Tkhfzat are such that financial matters. </seg>
<seg id="3"> use a credit card to you can get these from your personal life, then it is also improving the grip of the law enforcing agencies. </seg>
<seg id="4"> that only financial matters such as using a credit card to the record of your address can be judged. </seg>
<seg id="5"> and in the future, when the subsidy to use will be very little about this and will be increased. </seg>
<seg id="6"> In the same way, the crime in the World Bank instead of taking the risk of looting of credit cards are resource information. </seg>
<seg id="7"> In the same way, now be able to friendship Kmpaotra sources have already become a </seg>
<seg id="8"> social network, working websites fees, such as Arkt book and Mai spys popularity in come in the first class. </seg>
<seg id="9"> But you should not think that we mentally as they are being social net works are Mtae, which is likely to the people are taken away. </seg>
<seg id="10"> In the same way, the web site of the match Mykng, where do you like to other people and with which suits you are given after the list of the people. </seg>
<seg id="11"> do you just as soon as their life to another person can live? </seg>
<seg id="12"> I can&apos;t conceive for this, Jeevan half the members are also say. </seg>
<seg id="13"> He that "I&apos;m flaws they should be. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> I was perhaps some part in mind]. </seg>
<seg id="2"> A big in childhood, which also say there is true for me. </seg>
<seg id="3"> As I was sure Abajan to answer to every question know of the world. </seg>
<seg id="4"> I also Arta a joke. On </seg>
<seg id="5"> But it is true that the Hoskta even possible. </seg>
<seg id="6"> There is a fairly that false-was needed. of </seg>
<seg id="7"> In this age also raised this loss. </seg>
<seg id="8"> That is why I try is false at least bolon. </seg>
<seg id="9"> A false Lara don&apos;t Lgaoun after and they along with the name of Allah. </seg>
<seg id="10"> and Allah and when I pray to Allah that after the work. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The rest of the Naton situation, then only Allah knows better. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> It is a matter Ghnaouna which has created as a result of Dwry religion. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Hmara religion and two innocent children according to the law of Pakistan should have a mother. </seg>
<seg id="3"> He spent his father is responsible for parents and children can get. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Then, when children, adults Bakhar to be, as a result of which have to live. </seg>
<seg id="5"> You have the right Lkha that the real problem teach relatives and friends who served bandanas around. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Jagirdar past his party on all our deeds. Thinking </seg>
<seg id="2"> It is also working thinking that his father&apos;s property in new will become a part of the opposition and it is to be otherwise this process of his father, is commendable and they. </seg>
<seg id="3"> These with reference to our relations with Jkr and have created a social evil. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Mtlqh, and the widow of the concept of marriage Napad is being done. </seg>
<seg id="5"> in the same way faith and wrongful traditions are due to the family is facing a chaotic system. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> If a Pcbn 50 year old person in our society of any of his husband or wife if process where should be sent to make sure and other marriage, it does not seen? In view </seg>
<seg id="2"> We are a Pakistani Ankl near, his wife ten or twelve years ago were passed away after the marriages of all children, and he has made a widow married with a woman, if your child has been against them. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In my view, this is the divine what you say that? </seg>
<seg id="4"> We have no take place of our mother, we cannot tolerate the thinking what kind of thinking? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> In my opinion this is the children of all children should think that if he said after married the widowed women from, what went wrong? made a </seg>
<seg id="2"> In this way, the widow woman and they also found in Ankl was able to take the House No. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Because of their children, Yqnn their world has been busy me will be and they don&apos;t time will. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> It is Jahlat. Because of </seg>
<seg id="2"> If the their wives has refused to serve the old, then they will do? </seg>
<seg id="3"> This is a result of the pressure of society. </seg>
<seg id="4"> When the people go for any action plan of a family blowing atom on the other children, parents are married to. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Even though they should fight the circumstances and should say that their father had according to the process of Islam. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> In our society this is a menace during the last 40-50 years, if we have been fully in. </seg>
<seg id="2"> That is one granted to his wife, the Mian six Topian does Phre but some other used to not married. </seg>
<seg id="3"> If the bus, even after your death to it. </seg>
<seg id="4"> along with the Mian and is also destroyed by the hereafter spread in society. Also a big cause of </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Islam as its integral part of Islam have nothing to not we really like that we are living. and established </seg>
<seg id="2"> For example, many, investment, like to this from the girls&apos; education and DZ on the marriage. </seg>
<seg id="3"> If you have a question and the widow&apos;s home to go to the met any other widow who its own house instead of Oarthen, from the top Shoro on the Goga Cup and with them (the widow of the Oarthen in his stomach and Mror Athta). </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Pakistan and India in the subcontinent we have accepted centuries ago Islam, but the Jahlanh thinking to pursue till now could not released and established and living in the world to go to Muzaffarabad. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The man on the marriage Oahiat clinic taka, the divorce, a woman to divorce Achhot on the marriage of like dignity and a man of his marriage older women from the result of the woman&apos;s Mkara understand this thinking. is due to </seg>
<seg id="3"> and, and a copy of the Western nations Prhazgara and curtains Dqianosa. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Islam, it was to accept this thinking to pursue Chhrana very difficult. </seg>
<seg id="5"> May God as the courage to the courage and this Frmae. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Amen. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Urdu was never areas, then too much. write </seg>
<seg id="8"> Sdian by a writes writes for that. </seg>
<seg id="9"> A few Janae. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Allah Hafiz. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Amir Timor in his book, "I&apos;m Timor," I believe that it was found in his life in the army that if any SPH Salar line Awwal will be held in the army, Nhanhoga failed. </seg>
<seg id="2"> However, the conditions are and. </seg>
<seg id="3"> These people are saying, to death for us, we will Mran, were martyred. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The people have died in a murder </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> matters Assalamoalaikum Orhm Obrkath. </seg>
<seg id="2"> tonight after the prayer of Isha prayers on Oaps shop in Arhathakh one man, in a car Bathahoathaas have focused on Athaiaaormjhe their hands. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In the Sochakh Shaadke the way forget it Iakchh Pochhnachahtahe Giatoaska stopped in his entire family was batha in a car. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The Apnamdeabian Kiakh in Arabic by a Sktahon understand that no has said that there is no issue in heap Btaoukh Kiabat? </seg>
<seg id="5"> The Khnashroe Kiakh in Riyadh Aiahon from here in Madina, but no one has pledged me please send in any help you have taken by said that her brother forgive me as a Asaha, in the first Hochkahe that with the person Kwbys to added that the petrol full Krriad to go, but he said that Saage Jakrphroha started. </seg>
<seg id="6"> I am very angry Aiaman on the very Bolaaorspaha threat of any Nodogiarh. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Toab condition is that we are for the Muslims of the Prsoarhokrsath family come with the Ordn&apos;s at least Dwtyn Hzarka dhara them. </seg>
<seg id="8"> (Holy Hadith and clear why can Allah Oalh)) under the US from the Oproalahath Oalahath down getting better for Oalaaoraoproalahath to Oalahe. </seg>
<seg id="9"> We should Prapnakrm Orhm God made Koschamslman (Amen VM Amen). </seg>
<seg id="10"> ; </seg>
<seg id="11"> Jaoadaqbal </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> famous singer Adnan on Sami, his wife, accused of violence while the Mumbai police have reached. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The police station, he has instructed to go to court. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Adnan Sami&apos;s wife SBA Gladara application against her husband has that are continuously acted upon them. Adnan Sami </seg>
<seg id="4"> human and non-violent behavior have been kept. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Now it has been taken out of these so be registered a case against the Adnan Sami. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The police have registered a case, instead of them by saying that the issue of instructed to go to court to a system is not the police. </seg>
<seg id="7"> What do you think Adnan on Sami, his wife is correct. blames </seg>
<seg id="8"> This allegation Adnan Sami, not trying to defame to the Indian? </seg>
<seg id="9"> about their opinion about it. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Adam sanghar,. Mehr, </seg>
<seg id="2"> As far as the allegations is concerned, no one other pH and May. </seg>
<seg id="3"> respect is nothing else. increased with </seg>
<seg id="4"> Some are also present with his wife and Adnan Sami Adnan Sami their honor life was his additional money to leave India, and the leadership of the people Prgea. </seg>
<seg id="5"> This is Khmiazh of their good. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Washington ... </seg>
<seg id="2"> Senior officials say that the US President Obama about the Afghan President Hamid Karzai will adopt a tough stand. </seg>
<seg id="3"> America&apos;s new strategy of Afghanistan, instead of progress in the war has been given much importance. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The authorities have said that Hamid and zai hindrance in the US targets in Afghanistan is being considered as because of corruption in the government, drug dealers have been increased, and the strength of the Taliban are being collected. Again </seg>
<seg id="5"> American officials say that the US administration in some more on the Hamid Karzai from the people who are pressurizing for the vice president in the Baeadn and the president of Pakistan and Afghanistan Obama representative Richard hall broke. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He said that the strategy to President Bush, has revealed that after every two weeks after a video conference with zai. "and" on Afghanistan and the civic institutions were urge U.S. role in the reconstruction of. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Authorities say that Obama administration as an alternate of the central government will work with the provincial leaders. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Authorities say that the war against corruption from zai further by Hamid the will emphasize on. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Hamid Karzai is facing a fresh election of this year, it is not clear that Obama and his colleague for President will support or not. Their </seg>
<seg id="10"> This statement of the US authorities of Afghanistan, the indication of changes in the U.S. policy regarding not? </seg>
<seg id="11"> The end of the Hamid Karzai is going to happen? </seg>
<seg id="12"> In this regard opinion you? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Pakistan and Sri Lnkake in this series of three one-day matches between Sri Lanka has defeated Pakistan 1-2. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The first one-day matches in Pakistan has also Sri Lanka defeated, but the next two Machzman Sri Lanka has won. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In the third one-day match was extremely poor performance of the national cricket team, 309 runs in response to Sri Lanka for the national team only 23 over 75 runs in ibrat what the Dherhogea and it had to face defeat. </seg>
<seg id="4"> This proves that as a result of the national cricket team&apos;s performance is not continuously. In </seg>
<seg id="5"> Home-ground and all regardless of national team from defeat was not, what do you think of the reasons are? </seg>
<seg id="6"> The authorities Kokhal fields more there is a need to pay attention on? </seg>
<seg id="7"> If you are not satisfied with the selection of the team. </seg>
<seg id="8"> you can defeat the responsibility will lie on how to, for batting and bowling., </seg>
<seg id="9"> about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Jeddah, Malik Babar Hussein, it is a matter of concern that today&apos;s era, also this kind of Jahlanh cultures are Osara issued the Jager landlord, local tenant with its sovereignty cruel are targeting innocent people who Mslamn they will say? </seg>
<seg id="2"> However, there is no Sardar Khodapne Dkhlaee on these Koelon you do, the Government does not take action against them? </seg>
<seg id="3"> When the court justice work ga </seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Glfam, London, the statement of your choice Chhapte are you prefer the same it is their wish that you should write truth even some Parnab, in a statement on backed will not right to treat objecting because it is an order to say and what is equivalent to the Jihad Parnab according to change the statement. trying to stay in the news </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Yousuf, Dubai. - country </seg>
<seg id="2"> all of these people are Dhra Kashmiris are fighting a war for freedom for the last sixty years. </seg>
<seg id="3"> No one has not asked why now have been caught in the war of extremism and terrorism, have started talking of compromise cleanliness. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Before the Muslims massacred now to resolve issues in. </seg>
<seg id="5"> However, Pakistan will have to understand the Indian Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru for them. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> London-Asad Khan. </seg>
<seg id="2"> India and this kind of situation is that Kashmir be removed from the attention of the world. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But Pakistan has always, India&apos;s maintaining are Dkhladia of the world. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Now the British Government is that Indian state terrorism in the name of Pakistan to defame and are stealing from occupied Kashmir. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Talking on this issue with Pakistan and are unwilling. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> British Foreign Secretary, David received band has said that to solve the Kashmir problem on the border will finish extremism, the government of Pakistan to give birth to would be an effective way to deal with the dangers. </seg>
<seg id="2"> It should be remembered that, before this, the newly elected president Obamh also on the Kashmir issue have expressed their way. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Talking to media persons in Mumbai the British Foreign Secretary and an article written that in view of the war against terrorism is wrong said that the dangers faced by themselves and President Bush&apos;s policy to kill people. </seg>
<seg id="4"> David extremist groups had band, has said that Pakistan should not show any flexibility for. </seg>
<seg id="5"> On behalf of the large powers of the resolution of the Kashmir issue stressed upon the need to India due to the tension in the region Padakrke tried to divert attention from this issue is not?, </seg>
<seg id="6"> terrorism in Mumbai, not part of this strategy. </seg>
<seg id="7"> India based on the terrorism and the process of composite dialog wants to adopt? escape from </seg>
<seg id="8"> do about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Usman Aftab. </seg>
<seg id="2"> In my opinion, big powers are not damage to the Pakistan Chahtan. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But some steps to control it in are thinking of they know that Pakistan is a nuclear power. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Here, there is no want to create the revolution. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The foreign countries are thinking that Pakistan to corner geographical, some political problems could also want to help Pakistan and also want to meet its objective. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> A citizen, USA. - </seg>
<seg id="2"> always Hindu in this is that a knife mouth Ram pH </seg>
<seg id="3"> I think that the bus a shortly causes pain in his stomach and he is to threats to Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="4"> We all kinds are ready to keep its close to the Indian army chief and the mouth. We know. Answer </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Fahim Siddiqui. </seg>
<seg id="2"> ras Alkhamh, the United States Shrart Yhs from the United States is being sold of statement, it is bad, but now it&apos;s the same situation with India, out by making attack will know the reality, which is how much water </seg>
<seg id="3"> Hamas on Israel is attacked, but in a in Nhynn that it should also of Israel, India was seen India wants to do the same. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The Prime Minister, Syed Yousuf RDA Gilani has said that the newly elected vice president Jobaeadn former U.S. President Musharraf&apos;s military uniform and Lwly snapshots Lngra can play an important role to restore democracy in Pakistan, the government has touched them was awarded. </seg>
<seg id="2"> However snapshots any political parties and restore democracy in the credit should not be, parliament is not a rubber Astmp. </seg>
<seg id="3"> All the decision will be taken in the parliament. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The Prime Minister said that the chapter of Dr Qadeer has been closed. </seg>
<seg id="5"> What do you think free of public protests against Mryt had no importance? </seg>
<seg id="6"> lawyers movement did not play any role? </seg>
<seg id="7"> The Prime Minister of what you would like to say on this statement. </seg>
<seg id="8"> about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> US President George W. Bush said his farewell newly elected President Barak in a press conference here, said that he has the Obama have held several mistakes and his post Barak Obama the right and he Krdale. </seg>
<seg id="2"> According to the situation as president and the US steps under the law and the constitution, preferred over its popularity in the US interests. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Even today, he said that America&apos;s anti-America is planning to attack, Barak Obama for these attacks will stop the biggest challenge. </seg>
<seg id="4"> He said that the large mass destruction of weapons does not meet me to is the biggest desperate to admit to complete the mission in Iraq and I was the biggest mistake. </seg>
<seg id="5"> the White House in the last while addressing a press conference, the president said that it is my last press conference and journalists attending this conference and other relatives who I thank to participate in it. has </seg>
<seg id="6"> What do you think that they Obama and will not go mistakes, which Bush? </seg>
<seg id="7"> The Kiabsh to admit the mistakes and no delay in? </seg>
<seg id="8"> here Obama Bush will following? </seg>
<seg id="9"> about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Vice President Dick Cheney has said that Osama Bin Laden in I want to see the dead or alive. </seg>
<seg id="2"> He said that Osama bin Laden is a difficult amendments in the area and for his organization has been ineffective, also be arrested if Osama Bin Ladin dead or alive, it&apos;s the organization should be abolished. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The United States to arrest Osama&apos;s determination and should have issued for the garb of nabbing bin Ladin. </seg>
<seg id="4"> to arrest Osama Bin Laden&apos;s wish of Dick Cheney will be? </seg>
<seg id="5"> do about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The all rounder Shahid Afridi as cricketer PIA in the Quaid-e-Azam trophy habib bank and the first day of the match after the end of the clash with a spectators. </seg>
<seg id="2"> In the UBL on the ground to play Shahid Afridi as came out of drawing room, after the large number of people were collected around them. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The spectators on one occasion with him and his with picture on the request of Khnchoane Shahid Afridi said in a change in the picture tomorrow to take the spectators insisted on Afridi has, however, Ty$ Thpr it in a market before that, in Gthm Gtha there are people that concerns Dfe by. </seg>
<seg id="4"> After that, Shahid Afridi said that it is being made made issue without cause at this time, I was as soon as possible. Prayers </seg>
<seg id="5"> However, in the spectators will Krlon apologize. </seg>
<seg id="6"> This attitude of Shahid Afridi will ask what you. On </seg>
<seg id="7"> US about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has once again alleged that Pakistan is. environment of the war </seg>
<seg id="2"> Pakistan and the state terrorism used as a policy. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Addressing the chief ministers&apos; conference in New Delhi, Manmohan Singh said that terrorists Grdenasrka neighboring countries, especially when Pakistan can be supported. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The terrorist attacks and Mumbai Pakistani and Indian coast guards, but also adopt the way remained safe from. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The Indian Prime Minister said that the Mumbai bomb attack in November Lashkar-e-Taiyba has. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He further said that terrorists are using new techniques and modern satellite system, we will have to order on line of control from where they have said that infiltration and terrorism will not tolerate any circumstance that it is our policy. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The Indian prime minister to this allegation of how you see? </seg>
<seg id="8"> Kiabhart&apos;s internal squabbles Orelahdga extremist demands sacrifices of Indian found Mazhar Tonhan? </seg>
<seg id="9"> What is being made on the attitude adopted,? </seg>
<seg id="10"> about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Zubair Khan, Karachi. - </seg>
<seg id="2"> This is a very painful incident that the murders of Israeli Palestinians are the same situation is also in Kashmir, but Salmta Council on the head is not Rygty. to </seg>
<seg id="3"> All organizations, which are present in Palestine and Kashmir that they should continue his war for freedom Rkhen, and a Athad continue to face of every type of aggression on the death of a one day they not will bring Allah. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Israeli air strike on Gaza is still continued till now, hundreds of Palestinian men, women and children have been martyred. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The important political Rhnmanzarian of Hamas his wife and children have been martyred. </seg>
<seg id="3"> On the other hand, the meeting of the UN Security Council has ended without any decision. </seg>
<seg id="4"> In the meeting, Libya against Israel and other Arab countries presented by the resolutions is facing a resolution opposing the US. </seg>
<seg id="5"> the Palestinian civilian population Prgzshth many Rozse bombing by the Israeli planes is continuing. </seg>
<seg id="6"> on the incidents of the entire world Mumbai screaming was broken, but the Israeli attacks on a, including America, Britain have not been in the murder. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Why is moot important country of the Muslim Ummah? </seg>
<seg id="8"> the world what you would like to say on this double standards. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Saeed, New York. </seg>
<seg id="2"> In my opinion, it is true that most of our nation has read them that they do not know where the money is being taxes to the government to fulfill its responsibilities is interested in crisis of electricity and gas will work. </seg>
<seg id="3"> because the people who have been elected from all is well aware of their role. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Pakistan throughout the length and breadth of gas and electricity crisis Sngan shape Krgia. </seg>
<seg id="2"> On the other hand, in the prices of gas from January 1st on 8 has increased and non-availability of petrol in several cities of the country have been the cause of severe problems for the people. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Pakistan&apos;s industrial and business circles as well as long as of electricity and gas in severe reaction on the issue of the violence and disturbances, are underway. </seg>
<seg id="4"> industrialists to stop the factories ultimatum to release. </seg>
<seg id="5"> On the other hand, in Karachi, 8 to 10 hours to load shedding of citizens is feeling uneasiness. </seg>
<seg id="6"> industrial life has been reduced. Nearly paralyzed </seg>
<seg id="7"> The Government, in this regard, a second accusations on its stand by setting up a statement. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Talking of increasing prices of gas and electricity is not a joke with the nation? </seg>
<seg id="9"> to solve the problems is being given attention to why not? </seg>
<seg id="10"> The government of Amlky development wheel jam is not happy? </seg>
<seg id="11"> did you to control the crisis, suggested actions will? </seg>
<seg id="12"> about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Imran Khokr-in Madina Munawara, the people like I want to say that he is ruling. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I wonder if the slogan of the Lgana distressing to the people is giving Heb </seg>
<seg id="3"> The petrol secretly gas not receive has been a punishment and torment. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The government institutions have no control Ph. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The law and order situation in the day is will of God, this country on their body loss. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Agazhogiahe of the new year. </seg>
<seg id="2"> last year, and Khazaon and political year of "and" was also with reference to terrorism, it will be remembered. </seg>
<seg id="3"> President Bush and President Musharraf&apos;s from the power of eight-year period of the world, Bush shoes on rain and the establishment of democratic government in Pakistan, natural calamities, earthquake in Balochistan, financial crisis in all over the world, Ksad Ke Bhao ". </seg>
<seg id="4"> The arrival of the new year, you see how the coming year? </seg>
<seg id="5"> What do you near political or its geographical location and it will Obamh strategy will be? </seg>
<seg id="6"> The eradication of terrorism in any progress made it? </seg>
<seg id="7"> Court crisis in Pakistan will be finished. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The relations between Pakistan and India will take?% </seg>
<seg id="9"> surgical Astraek or there is a possibility of war? fully </seg>
<seg id="10"> What you can expect from the new year? </seg>
<seg id="11"> about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> US President George W. Bush, 8 year on the government to leave after the White House and has been transferred to the Camp David presidential camp office White House so that the new president Barak Obamh according to the wishes of the people should be prepared and can be. </seg>
<seg id="2"> During his term of eight-year old historic attack on the World Trade Center in America and destruction, Pnta Gwn attack on the pretext of the global war against terrorism and the military action in Iraq and Afghanistan, the troops of various countries in this war Ghsatne and full use of American resources in this war during President Bush&apos;s memory of A. </seg>
<seg id="3"> This war to the US that had to face the worst economic and financial crisis. </seg>
<seg id="4"> What do you think of this war in the world freedom and found? </seg>
<seg id="5"> President Bush&apos;s policies remained successful? </seg>
<seg id="6"> The era of US President George W. Bush on you? On </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The Indian cricket team, the Indian government has stopped from visiting Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The Indian cricket team visiting Pakistan in three tests and five one-day matches, was a 20-20 matches. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The vice president of the Indian Cricket Board has Shukla said while talking to Geo News permission for the Pakistan tour of the Board was between the two countries but due to describe the situation of this visit is not possible. </seg>
<seg id="4"> said that the present political situation of the Indian government and cricket team&apos;s tour is a right to cancel step, should not be separate from politics. Game </seg>
<seg id="5"> The Indian government decided not harmful for Pakistan? </seg>
<seg id="6"> The security situation in India Baojodanglsh cricket team will continue, why can&apos;t, the Indian team visiting Pakistan? </seg>
<seg id="7"> opinion you are in this connection. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Salman, Karachi. </seg>
<seg id="2"> People who are proud to India. </seg>
<seg id="3"> or your video film and now there are on their birth record to their eyes open Chahaean how you that the people of India. The dignity of </seg>
<seg id="4"> I Adnan Sami recall an interview in which he said that Pakistan is not my citizenship, the British. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Adnan Sami should help Pakistan in the first Roti, because there did not become Tjhe dignity made. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Farid Ahmed. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Karachi. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The Indian attitude changed after the attack Mumbai. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Jgjyt Singh, the reaction Zhahr in this case is that they hate Pakistan and Pakistan </seg>
<seg id="5"> It should be Chhaaee that Asha Adnan Sami sing songs with Bhonsle from where they are the tip there, Adnan Sami should be in India is not required to come here. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Shamshad Alam. Mohammad </seg>
<seg id="2"> In Karachi, Jgjyt Singh&apos;s statement on will I just like that they Grgt and minds. </seg>
<seg id="3"> who is flying to the Pakistanis are in India, Kholo that how much you are expected Kndw of cars to understand. </seg>
<seg id="4"> After the incident, the Mumbai they hate flying strange statement is now is against the famous Glokarednan Sami poison are protesting. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> According to a foreign news agency farewell visiting U.S. President George W. Bush said of Iraq Baghdad along with the Prime Minister Noor Malikey during the press conference in his office situated in the present situation might seem ridiculous injured when a journalist Iraqi addressed to President Bush said "this is a farewell Bwsh dogs. </seg>
<seg id="2"> After the a journalist Jota down, brought by President Bush, the US President George W. Bush to end Jota by their heads before and Jhka guarded. On its </seg>
<seg id="3"> The second Jota and the US flag. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The security officials, the journalist Ghsatte took place. </seg>
<seg id="5"> On this occasion, President Bush has said that I don&apos;t know why do you have, Jota 10 no, I had no problem. </seg>
<seg id="6"> What do you think Kiashafa this process of the Iraqi people by President Bush against the did not express their outrage? </seg>
<seg id="7"> This incident occurred on will ask what you? </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> After the incidents of terrorism in Mumbai the relations between India and Pakistan in the tension created at this time, the situation has Krgea when the Indian air force planes, Lahore and Kashmir sectors in violation of the limits of the Pakistan Air Force. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The Pakistan air retaliated to the Indian plane were forced to go back. </seg>
<seg id="3"> According to the sources, the Indian plane USS Nimitz would with arms and ammunition. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The present complications, this is the first incident of its kind. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Pak air force has said that it is fully prepared to defend the country. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The information minister Sherry Rehman said that the Indian government has admitted that violation of the air limits, but it by mistake. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Military sources said Pakistan has declared the serious this incident. </seg>
<seg id="8"> What do you think it really is planning to conduct air attacks on India and Pakistan? </seg>
<seg id="9"> It is true that the stance of India, by mistake or violating the purpose of the Pakistan Air Force have ability to Lganatha? </seg>
<seg id="10"> It was due to further increase the tension between the two countries will not? </seg>
<seg id="11"> about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Mrs. Benazir Bhtoko after at mrg human rights in the world award was that his son and Zardari Belwell Bhutto, chairman of the People&apos;s Party has received. </seg>
<seg id="2"> in the office of the UN general assembly meeting of Pakistan in a ceremony in the Shhadbe of former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto the approval of their services for their human rights in this award was Nawaz. </seg>
<seg id="3"> On behalf of the UN resolution of human rights of the Sathoan birthday was celebrated on December 10. </seg>
<seg id="4"> On this occasion, working for the human rights in the approval of the personalities and institutions are being given this honor of Benazir Bhutto, former US Attorney General Loeas Rmze Clark and all over the world in the international human rights organization working for the Human Rights Watch. </seg>
<seg id="5"> This occasion Praqoam ambassador of Pakistan in the Abdullah Hussein Haroon and other senior officials were also present at the occasion. diplomatic </seg>
<seg id="6"> The former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto will ask what you received this award. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Sameer. </seg>
<seg id="2"> currently. </seg>
<seg id="3"> It is true that he was shad but he said we also remember that how the blood of innocent people in Karachi, in which they were out of the Nasirullah Babar have done a good job. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Later, the Lkyn were completely in exchange. </seg>
<seg id="5"> However, it is also true that he did his party&apos;s senior people on the way to his son and another correspondent of the People&apos;s Party, the number of democracy,?. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Karachi-jimmi Noor, the statement of the Holy Quran by this news has proved that infuriated radical Mulsim clerics will only infuriated radical Mulsim clerics with the. </seg>
<seg id="2"> But until these including the axe by the on it not met axe. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The way our rulers that he is a secret in their are due to this country is very much in sync Aftan. </seg>
<seg id="4"> May God give instructed to our rulers. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> The UN Security Council panel, Hafiz Mohammad Saeed, including three Pakistani citizens and Jamaat Al-Dawa and the name of five organizations are included in the list of terrorists. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The Committee Senkshnz Taliban and al-Qaeda members of the Security Council that included in the list of names of terrorists to Pakistan has approved of the Jamaat Al-Dawa in Amerhafz Mohammad Saeed, chief of banned organization Lashkar-e-Tayyaba operations Zaki Rehman, head of the Treasury Department Lkhoa, Haji Mohammad Ashraf. </seg>
<seg id="3"> In addition to this, a Saudi citizens Mahmood Ahmad Bazak name is also included in the list of terrorists. </seg>
<seg id="4"> These organizations in the Jud, Al-Rashid Trust Oralakhtr pasban, Kashmir Trust International. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The member countries, major will destroy frozen assets belonging to all of the people and organizations and will be on travel restrictions and they will be arrested. </seg>
<seg id="6"> They will face cases. </seg>
<seg id="7"> The sanctions under the influence of Indian propaganda, not? </seg>
<seg id="8"> India without any evidence of Mumbai attacks on the charges of these organizations are imposed? </seg>
<seg id="9"> terrorist organizations are not present in India? </seg>
<seg id="10"> In India, the atrocities on Muslims from the international organizations are not? </seg>
<seg id="11"> US about their opinion. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> Thoarkhoshaon of Eid and the spokesman of Msrton and one man on Eid Abrahama Sunni Qurbani animals while the process. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The weak policies on time when price hikes on their political situation in the Dgrgon, according to their Asttaet poor and Baojodamer all of the preparation of Eid and his relatives in different ways to calls for Eid. </seg>
<seg id="3"> We will give you a chance Blag are that their loved ones in the case of a short messages of Eid June. </seg>
<seg id="4"> you through verses from the Eid can also calls. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1"> - Murtaza Jilani. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Karachi, our rulers should understand that they are an operation against the Pakistan Qdrdan why are the every kind of this Shh but love Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="3"> If not, then why should fight shoulder to shoulder with Pakistan. </seg>
<seg id="4"> when they will be feeling of love, will not only get a protest politics, I think, there is a possibility of war between the two decisive so that Bhras out. </seg>
</p>
</doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>
