<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="site07_single_unconstrained">
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Support for the Proposal of France</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The meeting of the committee was headed by the Chairman of the Committee Syed Mushahid Hussain in Parliament House in which he suggested that the government had sent a delegation of the Palestinian parliament as well as representatives of all political parties.</seg>
<seg id="3">Syed Mushahid Hussain while talking to the media after the meeting said that the committee welcomed by France to suggest that there is an immediate cease-fire and said that Israel would allow the relief works for the affected people in the Gaza Strip.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that as a crime against humanity by the fsltinion attack on Israel that it should condemn the attacks of the entire world</seg>
<seg id="5">Mushahid Hussain said double standards in criticising the countries of the world that those who speak against terrorism but why are silent on Palestinian attacks on Israel.</seg>
<seg id="6">The chairman of the Senate Standing Committee on Foreign Affairs srdmhr you on the issue of community leaders also criticized the issue of fsltin.</seg>
<seg id="7">He said that the Committee has expressed the hope that the newly elected president aubamh bark from the United States will address the Muslim community in the first 100 days of his government lifted so that they can be created the gulf between the United States and the Muslim community.</seg>
<seg id="8">Mushahid Hussain Syed said that the gap created between the West and the Muslim community to fill will not only be an emergency measure but a longstanding issues like Palestine and Kashmir should be resolved.</seg>
<seg id="9">Minister of State for External Affairs Ammad Malik Khan told the committee that they are going to Saudi Arabia to attend the meeting of foreign ministers of the Organization of the Islamic world.</seg>
<seg id="10">It calls for an emergency meeting of fsltin attacks on Israel.  He said that he was informed by the Palestine issue and the government is in touch with the leaders of other countries.</seg>
<seg id="11">State Minister of Foreign Affairs said that the Palestinian issue should be resolved in accordance with the UN resolutions.</seg>
<seg id="12">Two journalists from the Arab countries also attended the meeting and they talked about the latest situation in Palestine.</seg>
<seg id="13">The students of the University staged a protest against Israeli attacks on Palestine.</seg>
<seg id="14">The protesters had banners and also an inscription on the burden on which the slogans were registered against Israel.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Prevention of Dieting to Avoid Flu</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The research by American scientists have come to the fore after tests on mice.</seg>
<seg id="3">It has been proved by experience that fewer calories of food on the ability to deal with the flu virus in mice relatively.</seg>
<seg id="4">Research has proved wrong the old proverb that &quot; it would be better to starve a fever.</seg>
<seg id="5">Ate drank it very well in the heat according to the scientists.</seg>
<seg id="6">Michigan State University investigation of cars say that the fighting capability of more than da-eit infection was found in mice with little chance of dying and also increased their immunity against the virus while taking a dose of flu in mice were normal.</seg>
<seg id="7">According to the People do dieting. Elizabeth financial will be not only quick suffering from flu but it will take time in recovering.</seg>
<seg id="8">He also said that the flu vaccine that has assumed even they want to avoid dieting few months during the winter season.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Best Madonna for 2008 Year</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The exhibition was organized on the basis of &quot; hard candy for Madonna album &quot;and was also to sing gipsy with one or two nomad band and Justin tmbrlin of Ukraine.</seg>
<seg id="3">An old racing cars were also put on stage.</seg>
<seg id="4">The profits of the 2008 sila-endionz was the most successful show in which 236.6 million have been achieved.</seg>
<seg id="5">&quot; Chances of Canadian tikng clock visited the exhibition to countries while Madonna seventeen countries that was only a first world tour in the past eight years.</seg>
<seg id="6">The director of the two singers Jaime King, who was the &quot; spa-es Girl &quot;and a &quot; union of his visit was made.</seg>
<seg id="7">Madonna has beaten by her on the record.</seg>
<seg id="8">In 2006 had earned 193.7 million dollars in &quot;knfishn &quot; concerts.</seg>
<seg id="9">Polster described as the most successful singer at Bonn to find out who earned 176 million dollars.</seg>
<seg id="10">Bruce sprngstin fourth after earning 166 million dollars and stayed in fifth place and the police came to 120.6 million shares.</seg>
<seg id="11">Much less people in North America in 2008 according to the journal attended the concert programs and song in these prgramon and only those expensive tickets were willing to buy.</seg>
<seg id="12">Eight percent averagely one ticket prices have increased in the United States and the most expensive tickets were sold in the Madonna of 350 dollars.</seg>
<seg id="13">Gerry bongioni editor of the journal polster glue said that in the context of the global economic slump has been a good year for 2008.</seg>
<seg id="14">The two 2009 and you are released album of the year for which sprngstin has predicted after a year.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Ban on Co-education: The Taliban</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Capital Miran Shah in North Waziristan and the local Taliban in Group Hafiz Bahadur in other districts of Gul has distributed a pamphlet in which the semi-government government and educational institutions have been threatened with boys and girls are being co-education.</seg>
<seg id="3">The pamphlet and if the educational institutions were closed until January 5 no action against them if it is said that would be started.</seg>
<seg id="4">Identity cards for the women said that the government and other educational pamphlet advisors will be having a ban on women and made at the offices of NADRA in all districts have also been refused.</seg>
<seg id="5">Identity cards of women from the local Taliban on the spot when there is a ban on having made the announcement when nearly 200 women in the offices of Nadira Benazir Bhutto for Income Support Program in North Waziristan have collected the forms needed to have identity cards.</seg>
<seg id="6">After reading on loud speakers of the mosques in northern Waziristan pamphlet issued from the Taliban was reported by the local people</seg>
<seg id="7">But in a statement that there is no mention at different educational institutions of the girls also will be banned.</seg>
<seg id="8">Education following an announcement by the pamphlet or went to the office of the school or any woman NADRA identity cards to make it in the case of a legitimate and their families will be punished.</seg>
<seg id="9">In addition in the Bannu district police said on Sunday that he would have been an explosion of the mine on a road in Miran Shah and a passerby was injured in the explosion.</seg>
<seg id="10">&quot; I will become the wounded have been admitted in the Civil Hospital.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">&quot; Target Killings, and More Dead Bodies Recovered</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Green Sohrab Khan and Chowk area of the Mingora capital Sunday morning by the police have recovered the bodies of two people who were removed from Chowk head of the body.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Frontier Corps and of those killed was told by the police.</seg>
<seg id="4">According to eye-witnesses a letter from the near dead bodies were found in which he warned that those who 11:00 the day before being raised to these bodies will be held personally responsible for his death.</seg>
<seg id="5">Corpses to say that the people in the local market was 11:00 but rose later two security officers dead bodies were transferred to the hospital.</seg>
<seg id="6">Mingora capital and in the near past incidents of target killings in a few weeks to an alarming level seen;</seg>
<seg id="7">It has come in which civilians including women and security personnel were killed.</seg>
<seg id="8">According to local sources over 30 people in such incidents have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="9">So far no group has claimed responsibility for the killings claimed.</seg>
<seg id="10">The Khan spokesman on Saturday by the local Taliban in Swat had told the BBC that the three dead bodies on Friday was also received by his colleagues in the diol-ei Taliban commander was among the dead body of Rafi Ullah.</seg>
<seg id="11">The Rafi Ullah Khan said that security forces had been in custody for the past one and a half months.</seg>
<seg id="12">He said that when the local Taliban kills prior to any notice issued to the serious concern at the continuing attacks on civilians in Mingora is found.</seg>
<seg id="13">According to the local people a heavy contingent of security forces are deployed in Mingora but still it is increasing attacks on civilians.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Revenue in the Singing of Bakhtawar Benazir Bhutto</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Recorded raped a modern style of acting (a) of the sound of music on YouTube Bakhtawar positions as well.</seg>
<seg id="3">Pictures and video clips of Benazir Bhutto on the song of five minutes.</seg>
<seg id="4">Eighteen years old are Bakhtawar Edinburgh University student.</seg>
<seg id="5">They have a deep attachment of poetry and singing.</seg>
<seg id="6">It is being said that after he apparently encourage their mother lovingly and sing songs had started.</seg>
<seg id="7">He said while presenting his mother revenue that he was &quot; bright and beautiful, you have a job in every way.</seg>
<seg id="8">He said about the incident of 27 December that you were fired near the temple to us, at the age of 50 years, and their four children left in three separate left over.</seg>
<seg id="9">The entire nation is not disappointed with you and you are in the hearbeats.</seg>
<seg id="10">Twenty years old in Bakhtawar children of Benazir Bhutto on second place after Bilawal Bhutto.</seg>
<seg id="11">He has been taking interest in the music.</seg>
<seg id="12">It has expressed a desire to meet through grimi award winner and music producer Puff wrapper daddy of a journalist friend in the United States before the return of his mother.  But it has not been able to meet.</seg>
<seg id="13">Some of the Sindhi newspapers also published poetry translation of Bakhtawar but his voice was heard for the first time on YouTube.</seg>
<seg id="14">Some workers and devotion of Benazir Bhutto has made the CDs of rape Bakhtawar to follow.</seg>
<seg id="15">On the other hand Farhatullah Babar of People&apos;s Party spokesman has confirmed that the voice of the present Bakhtawar poetry and song on YouTube.</seg>
<seg id="16">He said on the phone from Islamabad that their courage to mourners a daughter and shut the revenue is that the mother of the TV network has been issued.</seg>
<seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar said the CDs of songs of Bakhtawar and his party to distribute program has not made at present.</seg>
<seg id="18">He said that before you book a fake accounts of youthful Bilawal Zardari Bhutto chairman of his party on the website or a few months had been destroyed after that.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Ajmal Kasab Are: Information Minister</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Federal Minister for Information and Broadcasting Sherry Rehman said only so much while confirming the nationality of the SMS Ajmal Kasab sent a message to the BBC Urdu service that further investigation is underway.</seg>
<seg id="3">Earlier Rehman Malik Home Advisor to the Prime Minister had refused to Pakistani citizenship.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that they are keeping a record number of Nadira citizens had not received any record of Ajmal.</seg>
<seg id="5">Talking about the latest announcement may not know the basis on which the government changes its position and now has confirmed the nationality of Ajmal Kasab.</seg>
<seg id="6">But the interior ministry of nationality verification of Ajmal Kasab according to the spokesman of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.</seg>
<seg id="7">Earlier the BBC Urdu service and a few other TV channels and newspapers had reported Farid Kot town of Okara district in the province of Punjab Ajmal Kasab ties.</seg>
<seg id="8">The government was refusing to do so.</seg>
<seg id="9">Now it is clear that there is no connection with this Farid Kot Ajmal of this or any other areas.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">In Response, Lebanon and Rocket Fire Bombing</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The officials of the Israeli army and police have told the media that four rockets on Israeli soil was thrown from the Lebanese territories of this nharia town in northern Israel as a result of an ordinary people have been injured down.</seg>
<seg id="3">Israeli artillery in response to rockets from Lebanon has bombed the area of Lebanon.</seg>
<seg id="4">It is not clear that this is not a Hezbollah attack of active behind the Palestinian groups in Lebanon.</seg>
<seg id="5">The Lebanese government said it is trying to trace who was behind the rocket attacks.</seg>
<seg id="6">The BBC correspondent in a very dangerous twist it for the current crisis in the region as it.</seg>
<seg id="7">The editor of BBC has increased the risk of the spread of the rocket attacks in the Middle East Jeremy bo-en.</seg>
<seg id="8">The last few days have expressed fear that the operation in Gaza would not spread out from the Israeli border with Lebanon in the north.</seg>
<seg id="9">On Wednesday night between Israeli Air Force carried out air strikes and sixty Thursday in Gaza.</seg>
<seg id="10">Offices of the police, the attacks by Hamas in the tunnels, the Israeli army stocks of weapons, were targeted members of Hamas armed places and firing rockets.</seg>
<seg id="11">The Israeli army artillery and the navy and air strikes as well as the throughout bombing in Gaza.</seg>
<seg id="12">Palestinian sources in Gaza said that air strike destroyed a mosque in the city.</seg>
<seg id="13">Tanks of the Israeli army according to the unauthenticated information obtained by air to help helicopters have advanced to the area of Khan Younis.</seg>
<seg id="14">Palestinian close to 700 in the fighting for the last 12 days in which include a large number of women and children were killed</seg>
<seg id="15">On the other side of the Israeli army for 11 soldiers have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="16">Israeli security forces have confirmed that a top defense officials of a amosgilad war is going to Cairo to resolve.</seg>
<seg id="17">A Hamas delegation is visiting Cairo for parallel talks with the ambassadors of Egypt.</seg>
<seg id="18">The leader of the Palestinian Authority Mahmud Abbas is reaching Cairo on Friday.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">&quot; My Heart Is Broken, My Return Kidney</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Dr. Richard Batista.  He said that eight years ago as he donated his kidney to save the lives of his wife danl.</seg>
<seg id="3">[batsta. According to the AFP news agency has said that his wife gave the donation of recompense in exchange for her kidney to cheat by somer and other ties have been strengthened and be consulted for divorce.</seg>
<seg id="4">The. Batista said in an interview with a local newspaper Daily News alleged that the boreed issue in my mind that is so far.</seg>
<seg id="5">The lawyer of Dr Richard Batista.  like bastsa are demanding the return of his kidney but they actually want subsidies equal to the cost of kidney.</seg>
<seg id="6">According to his wife its stand in the next few days will be presented before a judge.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">140 Kg, Nine Years of Free Labstr</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">&quot; George was caught out by a sea of labstr closed for two weeks.</seg>
<seg id="3">The company of sea food in the city of a hundred dollars it had purchased</seg>
<seg id="4">It should be publicly exposed to take pictures of the labstr had begun to use.</seg>
<seg id="5">While working for the protection of animals beat a group called &quot; labstr &quot;to leave as a result of which it will now be released back into the sea.</seg>
<seg id="6">Caught in Canada in which he and George beguiled in the next 10 days of Kareeb tanks and sea food company.</seg>
<seg id="7">The labstr age can carry out his weight.</seg>
<seg id="8">kithoalnti manager of the restaurant has said that it had no intention to harm to any of the labstr and was to provide food for the purpose of the tank.</seg>
<seg id="9">angrdniokrk peta relating to the protection of animals has said that the decision of the restaurants are praiseworthy and this is an example for those who want to keep either tank in such rare animals or do they want to eat ebullition alive.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Search for Children with the Help of Mobile</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The authorities when they found out about ntalimalta-es police officer of the athol city of misachiosts and agr forces extinguish came into action.</seg>
<seg id="3">The traced its right place with the help of the GPS automobile at present.</seg>
<seg id="4">But when gokl found out that with the help of the view that it is in a hotel.</seg>
<seg id="5">A week before the ntali grandmother was taken by the Legal Daily malta-esntali her parents.</seg>
<seg id="6">The police chief timothiandrsn athol told the BBC that&quot; the ntali said that he will never come back now and then a left to the state.</seg>
<seg id="7">The police have established links with the mlta-es. ntali but when he did not say if police were searching for him to return to the ntali mobile phone.</seg>
<seg id="8">The United States is a law that by 2005 or distance 67 percent of the mobile phone service providers and one hundred meters companies will provide the location of shaking 95% of distance of 300 meters.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on His Visit to India</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In the past five months and Hamid Karzai is to visit India.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is hoped that he would talk about the situation after the extremist attacks in Mumbai during a meeting with Prime Minister Man Mohan.</seg>
<seg id="4">He in the Mumbai attacks on Afghanistan and wants to show their solidarity with the sentiments of the people and India.</seg>
<seg id="5">There will be bilateral talks on trade and terrorism during a visit by Karzai.</seg>
<seg id="6">nmtneke Have from extremism is expected to hold talks on bilateral cooperation between the two countries.</seg>
<seg id="7">President Hamid Karzai during his last visit of terrorism has said that relations between India and Afghanistan will not be allowed to come in between.</seg>
<seg id="8">He also said that India and Afghanistan face the challenge of terrorism and merciless deadly activities and the two.</seg>
<seg id="9">Peace and stability in the region and the world is beneficial for all.</seg>
<seg id="10">&quot; We believe that the ownership rights to the two countries and the whole world is united to fight the menace of terrorism can.</seg>
<seg id="11">Karzai for an attack on the Indian embassy in Kabul in July this should be remembered that last year put the blame on the Pakistani ISI intelligence agencies.</seg>
<seg id="12">The Indians including a senior official in the IF was killed in the attack.</seg>
<seg id="13">Prime Minister Man Mohan Singh during his visit to India after the attack on the embassy of Karzai said that the attack was &quot; an attack on a friendship with India and Afghanistan, and we agree with the fact that the relations between us and we will not be allowed to return.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Special Judge, Mumbai for Hearing</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Mumbai police commissioner Ghafoor Hassan has said that he was arrested alive in the Mumbai attacks on suspected extremists who have registered a case against the butcher Amir Ajmal will only be under the supervision of the thliani L and M.</seg>
<seg id="3">ajolnkm on this issue before it was appointed state lawyer.</seg>
<seg id="4">Ajmal Kasab is now in police custody and it is hoped that the charge sheet against him before January 24 admitted to police.</seg>
<seg id="5">Ajmal Kasab does not have a lawyer to defend themselves.</seg>
<seg id="6">Butcher wrote in a letter to the Pakistani government had appealed for legal aid.</seg>
<seg id="7">India has given Pakistan evidence of being involved in the Mumbai attacks by extremists.</seg>
<seg id="8">Pakistan has claimed that a Pakistani citizen is Ajmal Kasab.</seg>
<seg id="9">According to the police Ajmal case and his colleagues ATM Ismail Abu Hemant, chief of the brittle erased Additional Commissioner of Police Ashok, killing six policemen including a professional police Inspector Vijay salskr encounter of the car and ran away after snatching skod De marggrgam B which was later caught by chopati.</seg>
<seg id="10">The police were killed in the operation and Ismail Khan police arrested Ajmal alive.</seg>
<seg id="11">The case was represented by Ajmal of no one has been nominated lawmaker.</seg>
<seg id="12">The lawyer who nominated fat cells legal aid to the Danish government has refused to accept the case on moral grounds.</seg>
<seg id="13">Two lawyers have withdrawn their names after protests and opposition to the people of a political party.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Constitutional Amendment: &quot; The Committee Will Be Formed &quot;</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">On Tuesday while talking to the media after his address to a seminar on environmental changes in Islamabad said that the meeting of the parliamentary party will seek the formation of the committee.</seg>
<seg id="3">He said that the people in the national assembly amended the constitutional amendment bill to remove the seventeenth from the Muttahida Qaumi Movement and other political parties will also be presented to the parliament on a constitutional amendment.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the Pakistan Peoples Party to end the seventeenth has also sent a draft amendment to the political parties and the committee will also review of the constitution.</seg>
<seg id="5">In response to a question he said that the decision of the balance of power between the president and prime minister.</seg>
<seg id="6">The Prime Minister said that the Parliament is empowered to take all.</seg>
<seg id="7">In response to another question said that former Prime Minister of Pakistan Peoples Party and the role of political parties as well as with regard to the post of army chief and the retired former President General Pervez Musharraf is also the chairperson Ms. Benazir Bhutto stressed the important role that have urged the international community to take off his uniform by President Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
<seg id="8">He said that the elected deputy president of Pakistan is that Biden and democracy and the President of Pakistan has given a reward for his Hilal of Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="9">The Pakistan by the Indian government after the Mumbai disconnecting the threat of any kind of relations in response to a question Yousaf Raza Gilani said that the Indian government is due to intense pressure from the people whom they make such a statement.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Protest Against the Dismissal of Journalists</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">On Tuesday the media of the &quot; tnzm &quot;I J R U of journalists and media workers in front of the Press Club in Islamabad protested against the owners of the media and government dismissals of a large number of employees from television channels and newspapers and chanted slogans.</seg>
<seg id="3">Senior ANC member of the Federal Union of Journalists Shamsi Pakistan&apos;s largest organization of journalists at the demonstrators protested against the politicians said that till tomorrow on strkon with us today are sitting in the house at the paper is doing nothing but for the rights of journalists because of the threat of a certain group of owners</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the newspaper owners talking about human rights have given rise to torture and forced labor camps box where their bodies and dismiss billion rupees to sinktron and a low wages to workers in spite of the economic and earnings are killed annually.</seg>
<seg id="5">A private channels of the Lahore in front of us is a member of the Channel 5 that committed suicide by hanging herself for not being given four months &quot; salary to the life of the issue will not be forced dismissals and salary workers still has several months.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the newspaper and TV should be a good step against owners and there is a need of installing a permanent protest camp in front of the parliament for the rights of journalists.</seg>
<seg id="7">R C Shamsi said while criticizing the governor of Punjab Salman Taseer Urdu newspaper that he&quot; has been dismissed by these days without any notice to employees.</seg>
<seg id="8">The Jinnah, daily newspaper report, the daily Business Plus TV Channel 5, AAJ and a dozen employees also dismisses TV</seg>
<seg id="9">Secretary-General Mazhar Abbas U P J F said while addressing the demonstrators across the country today that journalists and media organizations to press is a black day against the dismissals of workers and black stripes hawks at the session of parliament to the journalists after their rights to tie.</seg>
<seg id="10">Eighty five percent of the Pakistani newspapers and Mazhar Abbas are exploited workers and journalists in TV channels where they are working without a contract.</seg>
<seg id="11">He said that the newspapers journalists and more than 200 workers are still hiding from TV channels and while it is feared that this year caused by the economic crisis owners will dismiss hundreds of workers.</seg>
<seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas will continue until the movement of the journalists said as long as the employees were dismissed has not been restored, and television channels, the seventh of the Wage Board Award; the daily wages of workers have not been paid salaries for several months in the newspapers.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Eleven Members of the Cabinet Took Oath</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Ateeq against former Prime Minister Sardar Ahmad Khan in the new cabinet meeting of the Group six, two of the Pakistan Peoples Party, two of the Muslim League and People&apos;s is a part of the United National Movement.</seg>
<seg id="3">A woman in the cabinet minister for 11 members and is associated with the opposition is Ateeq fearlessly Muslim Conference.</seg>
<seg id="4">The ruling alliance has said that the cabinet would be extended next week and will be included in it is expected that the dozens of other cabinet ministers should be remembered that this month to his opponents Ateeq Sardar Khan was removed from the post of a&apos;zmai with distrust and the new Prime Minister Sardar Yaqub Khan was elected.</seg>
<seg id="5">The minister of these will be announced later.</seg>
<seg id="6">The People&apos;s Party on the eve of the swearing-in chanted slogans in support of former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto of Pakistan.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Outbreak of 3.5 Million Customers</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">October 2008 for the first time identified the virus going down and konfikr, and is known by names such as kido.</seg>
<seg id="3">Microsoft issued a Peach to combat the virus but nearly 3.5 million computers and memory stick to have been affected by this.</seg>
<seg id="4">The number of computers that were infected by the experts could be enough Zeyad.</seg>
<seg id="5">The Microsoft consumers to deal with it &quot; MS sewings &quot;zero to six zeros eight of Peach use.</seg>
<seg id="6">Microsoft has said that the windows to file the virus affecting hundreds of thousands of computers and searches &quot; E S A and E dot service is included in the code.</seg>
<seg id="7">The virus is L L D type of file folder in the system of windows.</seg>
<seg id="8">The names of the virus, also created the files</seg>
<seg id="9">The details of the windows had been registered.</seg>
<seg id="10">The virus created a problem that had been operating train ticket examiner H P Sarwar is restored &quot;as well as the machine.</seg>
<seg id="11">The files on the website of the hackers also downloaded.</seg>
<seg id="12">Microsoft said that this virus affects computers in various countries in the world.</seg>
<seg id="13">China in these countries, Brazil, India, Russia, the United States and Britain.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">&quot; Demand for Jldrport The Data on Indian</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">While talking to the media after a meeting at the Interior Ministry said on Saturday that going by India</seg>
<seg id="3">It will also help in the investigation into the matter of m&apos;lomat.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that Pakistan is an independent country and one of the country in an investigation going on these data from India</seg>
<seg id="5">Dictation will not be accepted.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that more information and data from India are also doing together.</seg>
<seg id="7">Home Advisor said that the law enforcing agencies have been arrested under the threat to breach the law to 124 members of a banned organization</seg>
<seg id="8">It is available and if any evidence against some of these people will take action against them while innocent people will be released</seg>
<seg id="9">In response to a question he said that the person who was arrested in India would not be handed over and under the law against those who will be there.</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that action against those who have suffered under the law of the FIA.</seg>
<seg id="11">In response to a question he said that the Indian law enforcing agencies have collected information in 42 days in connection with the people involved in Mumbai and so is the hope that it will give some time to Pakistan to investigate m&apos;lomat on the international community including India.</seg>
<seg id="12">He again repeated the offer of the Government will form a joint tffishi Mumbai team to investigate the incident.</seg>
<seg id="13">Headed by it should be noted that additional director general of the FIA has been one of the three tfishi member squad of Mumbai that the attacks by India</seg>
<seg id="14">It is investigating the information given to Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="15">The meeting with President Shahid Malik Asif Ali Zardari Pakistan&apos;s High Commissioner to India in which the president has made it clear that if they are found involved in the Mumbai attacks any individual or group would then it will be taken against him under the national laws and to India would not be handed over to the Indian leadership and Pakistan handed over to the people involved in this incident is mount pressure on Pakistan.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">&quot; Anything Is Possible in America &quot;</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Mr. Obama will take oath for the post of 44th President of the United States on the basis of January.</seg>
<seg id="3">After standing on the stairs of the building in the memory of the sixteenth President Abraham Lincoln in Washington at a music concert</seg>
<seg id="4">Mr. Obama faces the most serious chinlnjz by several generations of the kh&apos;amrikh and said he is hopeful that America would foster control over these difficulties.</seg>
<seg id="5">Abraham Lincoln has ended the tradition of slavery in America.</seg>
<seg id="6">But at the same time Mr. Obama said that it will take time to resolve the problems faced by the country and would be difficult.</seg>
<seg id="7">&quot; But I am still hopeful that the dream of the founders of the country would remain alive.</seg>
<seg id="8">Iraq and the United States has been a fight with a severe financial crisis as well as the wars in Afghanistan.</seg>
<seg id="9">The unusual steps are being taken for the swearing-in ceremony.</seg>
<seg id="10">The organizers believe that 2 million people will take part in the ceremony.</seg>
<seg id="11">On Monday there is a national holiday in the United States as a great pains and Martin Luther official for human rights were killed the same day King.</seg>
<seg id="12">Martin Luther King was black.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Martin Luther Tribute, Vowed to Work</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Martin Luther King and was murdered in 1968.</seg>
<seg id="3">Barack Obama taxes paid tribute to the King.  He said that the Americans to abide by promises of this nation will work.</seg>
<seg id="4">On the oath taking ceremony held in Washington on Tuesday for a new president is prepared for a public gathering on the occasion of the presidency.</seg>
<seg id="5">It is expected that he will gather in Washington close to two million people to see the historic ceremony presided over by the president.</seg>
<seg id="6">Barack Obama on Monday during a visit to the medical center in Washington earlier in the day where the injured US soldiers after they went into a safe haven for the houses without and painted on a wall.</seg>
<seg id="7">Barack Obama said while talking to reporters: &quot; The present crisis and we have had to face many difficulties that we can not be sitting in their spare.</seg>
<seg id="8">He said that Martin Luther King crossed over to the people.</seg>
<seg id="9">Barack Obama said that &quot; today we are respecting the memory when it is not a day that we will remain as well.  This is a day that we will act.</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the meeting will be held on Tuesday at the way in which several thousand people of Martin Luther King &quot; was one of my dreams are gathered to hear in 1963.</seg>
<seg id="11">Martin Luther King said in his speech that the day will come when people see the color would not distinguish.</seg>
<seg id="12">Mathew Price of BBC has said that although tormenter said that Martin Luther day in history has come back for more than 24 hours a day when the first black president in American history will take oath his duties.</seg>
<seg id="13">A, Barack Obama for many people in the southern states of the United States will be the dream of Dr. Luther King.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Additional Political Agent Was</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The folders veil from South Waziristan 10 days before the additional political agent had kidnapped.</seg>
<seg id="3">Sources say that the local Taliban Mullah Nazir group of the workers were abducted.</seg>
<seg id="4">According to local administration at a tribal assembly and Aamir Lateef additional political agent of South Waziristan near Wana conveyed to 4:00 p.m. Scout camp.</seg>
<seg id="5">However he did not say that the additional political agent who was kidnapped.</seg>
<seg id="6">The local Taliban Mullah Nazir Group of political agent although according to the local people were kidnapped.</seg>
<seg id="7">Aamir Lateef were kidnapped when they were given to stitch in Wana.</seg>
<seg id="8">Seven armed folders karknrh veils in the tribal region of South Waziristan to 11 January 2009 was kidnapped along with the driver additional political agent Aamir Lateef.</seg>
<seg id="9">Kidnapping vehicles under the present government employees were unarmed guards at first and then seating with a car in the additional political agent was taken from there.</seg>
<seg id="10">Security forces after the kidnapping of an additional political agent under the local administration and South Waziristan had surrounded the check post in semi-tribal area and it is hard to find and the last one week and authorities had imposed a ban on Wana.</seg>
<seg id="11">asstint The Asmat Ullah political agent of northern Waziristan have been 2000 to December 8 were kidnapped when they were made by the Mir Ali in order to celebrate the Eid holidays.  And the veil of two unidentified persons including Amanullah folders collector in north Waziristan were killed in a few days later.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Victory in the Case of British Hacker</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The British citizens forty-two years has admitted that he had made to the US military hack website.</seg>
<seg id="3">Gerry aisprjr of sndrom is ill.  It is exciting to work for a range of the patients should be kept in mind that the aisprjrsndrom.</seg>
<seg id="4">His lawyers say that if they were handed over to the United States that it will try to suicide.</seg>
<seg id="5">The prosecutor said that the government fears about the health of Gerry is very low.</seg>
<seg id="6">The Lord Justice Morse and Mr. Justice. Simon said while announcing the decision to allow Gerry is being revised to apply for a British court.</seg>
<seg id="7">Lawyers for Gerry had adopted at the point of view was that if the court Gerry away from his family home and they can commit suicide</seg>
<seg id="8">He further said that the Home Secretary on this issue should not be considered.</seg>
<seg id="9">A government prosecutor has said that his forces had used the Home Secretary.</seg>
<seg id="10">Gerry hack out of the US military has never denied the website.</seg>
<seg id="11">Gerry made hack into the computer system of another two 2000 losses 800,000 dollars to the US Administration.</seg>
<seg id="12">Gerry hack was 97 computers with the US Navy and NASA system.</seg>
<seg id="13">But Gerry said that they did not have any intention to hack it wrong information on heavenly creature was finding that they think that the US government kept secret.</seg>
<seg id="14">Mother of Gerry Janice Sharp has said that he is happy with the decision.</seg>
<seg id="15">The lawyer of Gerry said &quot; it is the right decision.</seg>
<seg id="16">The case has been issued by the end of 2002 and it has been decided.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Kashmir: The Two Sides Commander Killed</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The spokesman Lieutenant Colonel Acharia of the Northern Command of the Indian Army deployed in Jammu told the BBC: &quot; The clock Rashtriya Rifles Officer of Jammu and Kashmir police has besieged in a jungle hideout in has distributed gndoh Tehsil of Doda district received reliable information on where the armed extremist chuhpe was made.</seg>
<seg id="3">He opened fire on a military response and killed two armed extremists.</seg>
<seg id="4">The spokesman said that you will also have been killed in the district commander Zahoor Uddin sword since the outlawed Hizbul Mujahideen in the district for 12 years in the extremists who was an expert in explosives were.</seg>
<seg id="5">The following are identified as hasin Sajjad was related to the extremists to force the last year.</seg>
<seg id="6">In the wild area under the Acharia operation is still going on according to them because of the presence of the army as much as two Kalashnikov assault rifles in the first phase of the operation also recovered.</seg>
<seg id="7">The police chief kuldip khuda Kumar of the province in the year of 2008 which he described as the most peaceful so far this year.</seg>
<seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that the assembly will be held within seven stages in November and December elections there was no violence.</seg>
<seg id="9">Candidates of more than 1350 took part in the elections.</seg>
<seg id="10">It may be recalled that in Jammu Kashmir Hizbul Mujahideen is active for the past eighteen years.</seg>
<seg id="11">Hizb for the first time had declared a unilateral ceasefire in 2000 and July after talks between the government and party commanders.</seg>
<seg id="12">However the cease fire only destroyed within 15 days.</seg>
<seg id="13">The most senior commanders of Hizbul Mujahideen were killed in various operations.</seg>
<seg id="14">On Thursday known as &quot; the daily news &quot;under the auspices of Pakistan had written about the extremist groups in Kashmir and Lashkar-e-Tayiba Kashmir Hizbul Mujahideen has decided to review the policy.</seg>
<seg id="15">It should be noted that the two organizations so far this policy was that it could be solved through armed resistance to the Kashmir issue.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Dera Bugti: Explosion on a Gas Pipeline</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The eighteen inches in diameter pipeline running from the gas field in the Pirkoh according to police officers have been destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="3">The pipeline is the direction of the Sui plant.</seg>
<seg id="4">Meanwhile a man named srbaz Baloch showed Republican Army spokesman of the banned organization Baloch has claimed responsibility for the attack on the telephone with his organization.</seg>
<seg id="5">The fourth gas pipeline in charroz has been destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="6">In a Friday in Dera Allah Yar eighteen inches in diameter pipeline were released on Sunday morning for repairs.</seg>
<seg id="7">General manager Mushtaq Siddiqui of Sui Southern Gas Company in Quetta has stated that the supply of gas from the pipeline will be started in the afternoon.</seg>
<seg id="8">The Sibi of the pipeline comes to Quetta.</seg>
<seg id="9">Quetta Ziarat and is a severe shortage of gas in three days in other areas where the msafati is still continuing snow and temperatures fell below freezing point and on the other hand heater and stoves have been cold.</seg>
<seg id="10">The Dera Bugti has been an explosion in a motorcycle in the property market in the city but there has been no casualties from the blasts according to the police.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Nazim Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah for</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">I followers of nearly twenty five kilometers away from Lahore Hanif hidakoatr center of Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah.</seg>
<seg id="3">In the center of the hostel, hospital and school students.</seg>
<seg id="4">Punjab Law Minister Rana Sanaullah Khan said that the appointment of a guardian of the Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah and carries out so that the work of charities there is not affected.</seg>
<seg id="5">These centers in the son-in-law of Waleed Khalid Amir Hafiz Saeed Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah, a senior government official Khaqan Babar to monitor school and other charities has been appointed as the secretary of the police force them to increase it.</seg>
<seg id="6">Puts a ban on the Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah Security Council and the federal government from all over the country took action against jma&apos;tald&apos;ot and other leaders including the Emir of the Jamaat Hafiz Saeed detainees are being carried out.  The center of the Punjab government is a continuation of Jamat ud Dawa action against the Federal Government and the aidmnstr are to be fixed.</seg>
<seg id="7">Khaqan M D G Baber in connection with the management of the group.</seg>
<seg id="8">Hafiz Waleed Khalid said that the division of the Lahore Commissioner Khosrau Pervez Khan on Sunday came in police and civil administration and the tbih center in different parts of the center.  Waleed Khalid has condemned as the administrator of the Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah government and said that there is already a decrease in the number of patients in hospitals and schools situated in the center of government actions.</seg>
<seg id="9">The Emir of the Jamaat Hafiz Saeed according to a press release of the Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah has wrote a letter to the Taliban Ban Ki-moon Committee and the General Secretary of the United Nations in which he was party to the Security Council on the appeal of the ban.</seg>
<seg id="10">The statement said that the unilateral decision by the injustice of the Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah Security Council and is connected with the Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah but also are engaged in the relief work.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Relief Operations in the Gaza Strip Edhi</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">After passing through several steps needed to get permission to enter the Gaza Strip have so far been successful in getting insists from New York.</seg>
<seg id="3">Speaking to the BBC Urdu service in Cairo said that they still do not arrive in Gaza since Israel and Egypt have raised a number of obstacles.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said he came here eight days and was still going from Gaza is not an.</seg>
<seg id="5">&quot; I am currently in Cairo tomorrow and it is hoped that they would have gotten permission to go to Gaza.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said while giving details: &quot; I have already made a visa for only seven days to go to Gaza and Pakistani officials later on I helped my insistence and conducted a brhoa of creating a month but on the condition that he would be available only to the Gaza Strip is that a single entry.</seg>
<seg id="7">He said his sons and daughters are with them and I want to do relief work in the Gaza Strip.</seg>
<seg id="8">&quot; I have come up with some money.</seg>
<seg id="9">Cheque of 100,000 dollars to the Egyptian Red Cross has donated 10,000 dollars and also give cash to send relief goods in Gaza.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Four Cabinet Ministers, Last Sixty Three More</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Muttahida Qaumi Movement in four new federal ministers and two members of the Jamiat Ulma-e-Islam Fazal-ur-Rehman Group.</seg>
<seg id="3">The new Ministers of Asif Ali Zardari took oath.</seg>
<seg id="4">The swearing-in ceremony Prime Minister Yousaf Raza Gilani, also present members of the federal cabinet</seg>
<seg id="5">The federal minister, with the participation in the federal cabinet ministers of the four new sixty three increased the total number of ministers and advisers.</seg>
<seg id="6">Babar Ghori Farooq Sattar and the ministers of the two clerics of MQM are jamiat and Maulana Azam Sawati Ataur Rahman Fazal-ur-Rehman Group of Islam.</seg>
<seg id="7">So far the minister does not announce them.</seg>
<seg id="8">Farooq Sattar is convener of MQM and the MQM Senator Babar Ghauri was and is ending on March 10 this time.</seg>
<seg id="9">Sawati Azam was elected senator in the status of a free and it is counted as the richest among senators.</seg>
<seg id="10">Maulana Ataur Rahman is a member of the National Assembly and the younger brother of Maulana Fazlur Rahman.</seg>
<seg id="11">Appointed four advisors on important positions that are not members of the national assembly.</seg>
<seg id="12">It should be noted that the 3rd November twenty two new ministers in the cabinet ministers including 2008 and eighteen state then it is considered that the members of the MQM will also be included in the cabinet while but due to the differences in the distribution of ministries was not included.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Balochistan Province Blew Up, Pipeline</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The police is under eighteen inches diameter pipeline of the wells of various Monday on the gas plant at Sui and some unidentified persons on the dawn blew up.</seg>
<seg id="3">In addition to this good number three in Sui were completely destroyed by the blast yesterday and a gas pipeline near Dera Allah Yar damages in the explosion.</seg>
<seg id="4">srbaz spokesman for the Baloch people Republican Army banned organization claimed responsibility for the blasts have taken from his organization.</seg>
<seg id="5">2009 in southwestern Balochistan province has increased incidents of violence as soon as they start.</seg>
<seg id="6">This month the dozens of gas pipelines have been destroyed and trains have increased attacks and the people of Punjab province.</seg>
<seg id="7">Nawab Aslam Raisani although the chief minister of Baluchistan has expressed concern over the incidents and has issued orders for the exchange of information with intelligence agencies but the police could not yet be able to prevent such incidents.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Admired a Package of Economic Recovery of 819 Billion US Dollars</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">A member of the Republican Party in favour of the plan of President Obama did not vote.</seg>
<seg id="3">Republican members said that the economic plan is a &quot; high &quot;and that it would not prove effective.</seg>
<seg id="4">244 in favour of this package in the parliament and the oppositions 188 votes.</seg>
<seg id="5">The plan for economic recovery has been presented in the Senate next week where the ruling party Democratic Party enjoys a very simple majority.</seg>
<seg id="6">It is feared that the approval of the Senate due to strong opposition from the Republican Party would not be easy.</seg>
<seg id="7">Barack Obama after the approval of the plan for economic recovery in the parliament members said while pressing for them in the way of this important project to political dissensions should not let go.</seg>
<seg id="8">The president said that the situation in which he expressed his hope that the law would be taken next month adopts a manufacturing environment in the country would be helpful in making a business in which the U.S. will make it.</seg>
<seg id="9">It has released a loan of 200 billion dollars seventy fives for the common man and the business community in accordance with the plan and 540 billion roads, bridges, schools, will be given 10,000 decoration for research and technology of alao-ens new jobs.</seg>
<seg id="10">The BBC correspondent Richard Joseph Lister in Washington have said that Barack Obama has thus turned down the political dissensions a new political culture but was determined to hold confessor discussions on the financial package has once again created bitterness on political grounds.</seg>
<seg id="11">The members of the Republican Party in the parliament and said the government planned to pay a bill proposed by the government in creating moaq&apos;e new jobs and will not help.</seg>
<seg id="12">He stressed on the bill proposed by his party and pay more attention to remain in the tkson.</seg>
<seg id="13">They may be created moaq&apos;e more jobs for more investment in some of the package.</seg>
<seg id="14">He said that more than the construction of the project had been released in taxes can be immediately created moaq&apos;e job</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Israeli President, Bitterness in the Turkish Prime Minister</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Tayeb argan Rajab told the Israeli president and screaming about it sheds blood that many people in the Gaza Strip and unfortunately we have to see that the reason for the attack on the Israeli people can be applauded.</seg>
<seg id="3">Mr. argan said: &quot; I feel that you could sense his crime is using such words to erase and loud but also to the people and I am remembering those children who were killed near the coast.</seg>
<seg id="4">shimon Perez said that Israel, the Gaza Strip that Hamas would not have made it dangerous dictatorship.</seg>
<seg id="5">Before it according to a representative of the World Economic Forum in a BBC Davis had never seen such a scenario.</seg>
<seg id="6">But Ardgan later said he respected the president of the old asraili and as a result of which they screamed at them but not exactly what he was saying was far away from it.</seg>
<seg id="7">Turkey has been reduced from those countries that have diplomatic ties with Israel but the tension in the last few years is found.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">&quot; It Is Not a Plan of Attack in Pakistan</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">&quot; The Indian channel Wajid Shams ul Hassan and D while talking to the TV report said that the investigation of the Mumbai attacks will be issued soon.</seg>
<seg id="3">More than 170 in attacks in Mumbai last November.</seg>
<seg id="4">The responsibility for the attacks on Indian troops are extremist group.</seg>
<seg id="5">India has also stated that the Mumbai attacks &quot; some elements &quot;were involved.</seg>
<seg id="6">Mumbai is affected relations between the two countries after the attacks.</seg>
<seg id="7">The High Commissioner Wajid Shams ul Hassan has made a statement attributed to the Pakistani investigation which receives view of the fact that it is in the report of the investigation.</seg>
<seg id="8">Wajid Shams ul Hassan said: &quot; As far as the investigation into the car has reached its conclusion, there has not been used.</seg>
<seg id="9">Some other this can be achieved, there is no way.</seg>
<seg id="10">The two places (Britain) and that he was worried about.</seg>
<seg id="11">India and the international community has made a lot of pressure on Pakistan to take action against those responsible for the Mumbai attacks.  Pakistan said it has arrested dozens of people allegedly involved in the action against the groups in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
<seg id="12">Wajid Shams ul Hassan said: &quot; We are not to conceal it.</seg>
<seg id="13">&quot; We believe in taking action on the facts.</seg>
<seg id="14">&quot; I will be granted to our investigation.</seg>
<seg id="15">&quot; We (the investigation) will try to be satisfied with the results.</seg>
<seg id="16">He said while defending a delay in the investigation of such material to collect, understand and it takes time to test.</seg>
<seg id="17">The High Commissioner Wajid Shams ul Hassan said that India had presented its dosi-er forty five days.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Ripiblikn Also Elected Black</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Michael steel in the sixth round of the presidential elections in which Republican Party wins by making a soarsth was won by one vote ninety votes.</seg>
<seg id="3">Opponent kitndaausn candidate for the post of steel in the election of the chairman of the party got seventy seven votes while former chairman Duncan dstrbrdar was to compete in the second round.</seg>
<seg id="4">There are five candidates for the presidency of the Republican Party Correspondent Michael Steel acknowledges the most moderate leader.</seg>
<seg id="5">Michael steel in his address said after winning the&quot; of his opponents with his friends and we are going to say that you come with us but those who want to hinder it would be willing to take away from us.  Michael is related to the land where they have also been Steel vice governor.</seg>
<seg id="6">He got fame in 2006 at a time when he stood for a seat in the election of Senate.</seg>
<seg id="7">But after losing the election of Senate made chairman of a committee of the knzroitio political party.</seg>
<seg id="8">The chairman of the party will be under the patronage of a nationwide campaign of Republican Party after being elected.</seg>
<seg id="9">lrahe The election promise that he would give a new direction to the party and will use a new technical to join with the reactionary forces to party supporters.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Claims About the Presence of Ti^bh Troops in Jm^on and Jaish Mhm^d</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">jm^on of Poonch is reported to be present in the districts of militants.</seg>
<seg id="3">The army and police on receiving secret information according to official sources surrounded the area and started searches.</seg>
<seg id="4">During the fighting started in which four militants, two soldiers and a policeman were killed.</seg>
<seg id="5">According to sources Fights released a report by the ti^bh and the army in the area and Jaish militants linked to mhm^d is that the army to fight the further reinforcement sent there.</seg>
<seg id="6">In the incoming Chief Minister Omar Abdullah on behalf of the coalition government met with the governor and formally informed them about being chosen by their party leader of the National Assembly.</seg>
<seg id="7">The National Conference of the Congress party also informed the support of the Governor Omar Abdullah.</seg>
<seg id="8">Omar Abdullah will be provided to the oath for the post of Chief Minister.</seg>
<seg id="9">National Conference in recent state elections that have emerged as the largest party twenty eight seats in the House of eighty seven members.  It should be noted that the pshnd separation parties had boycotted the elections.</seg>
<seg id="10">Congress, which seventeen seats were won a coalition government with the National Conference, agreed to form.</seg>
<seg id="11">The members of the party on the arrival of Omar Abdullah ardently welcomed.</seg>
<seg id="12">On this occasion Omar Abdullah has said that he will play its role to make the dialogue between the government and separatist but holding of elections in India and there will not be able to take over the new government.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The European Union&apos;s Role for Peace in the Middle East</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">It should be seen in the reconciliation if the government to stop the war in the Middle East is a decisive role in the European Union&apos;s.</seg>
<seg id="3">shoarzn Leaf or delegation under the brslzkesrkari point of view is tantamount to help the work of Sarkozi.</seg>
<seg id="4">European Commission spokesman Amadeu Altafaj said that it is a commendable effort through which the joint statement of the European Union can help the parties to the war.</seg>
<seg id="5">An official statement to the extent that it is all right.</seg>
<seg id="6">But actually within the European Union has struggled household is presenting a sad picture.</seg>
<seg id="7">The role of the Czech Republic on the basis of the president of the union is already weak.</seg>
<seg id="8">&quot; from internal differences are helpless.</seg>
<seg id="9">On the other hand the attitude of the French President Sarkozi such as if he is still performing the duty presidency of the European Union.</seg>
<seg id="10">The presidential term of six months have been French.</seg>
<seg id="11">Sarkozi qiadti wants to play a role and they can do but they are not allowed.</seg>
<seg id="12">Facing the most ridiculous situation of the French Foreign Minister Bernard Kouchner.</seg>
<seg id="13">He is a part of the delegation that the Schwarzenberg foreign minister is leading the Czech Republic.</seg>
<seg id="14">The additional to the Middle East is giving statements have both foreign ministers about the war.</seg>
<seg id="15">The Schwarzenberg said that Israel has the right to defend its Kouchnerke war and it does not come close to the defense.  The German is also a special envoy to the Middle East.  The consensus on the point of view that the EU would not show up on the diplomatic front, could not be achieved success</seg>
<seg id="16">This attitude is proof that the reconciliation efforts of Europe does not give any importance.</seg>
<seg id="17">The European Union is a golden opportunity for serving as the United States has had some success in the Middle East because of the policies of George W. Bush.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Financial Crisis: Suicide of German Billionaire Industrialist</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">adolfmirkle residents of the area of soabih in southern Germany you have left behind a large business groups.</seg>
<seg id="3">But until recently before the German common citizen does not know more about them.</seg>
<seg id="4">And when the banks to give loans to 30 of its industrial group several weeks he had to negotiate as long as it has become the subject of headlines and they started the black and the future of the mirkle group.</seg>
<seg id="5">Loss of a 100 million euro due to the financial crisis after the purchase of shares worth folks German Institute and the mirkle group also burned.</seg>
<seg id="6">The financial institutions to the obligatorily group refused to give new loans worth between 700 million and one billion euro needed and mirkle when they came under pressure.</seg>
<seg id="7">Some time ago the mirkle bank group on an emergency basis for providing loans are you willing but adolfmirkle who had arrived at the site of a small industrialist whose annual income of the industrial group has become almost 30 billion euro, capitalistic to his deprivation of power could not be tolerated.</seg>
<seg id="8">adolfmirkle after the death of his father when he took over the family business as soon as he stressed on the tojdid developed regions.</seg>
<seg id="9">He put his name to the Ratiopharm company which is very successful and very pharmacist Company of Germany.</seg>
<seg id="10">Until recently been trading value of the pharmaceutical institutions was between five and six billion euro and it still makes an annual income of 1 billion euro.  The great success of the mirkle and rasio forms have purchased large institution has taken a number of construction equipment like krkhas took out a Kssbohrer named birg hydel cement manufacturing company cars.</seg>
<seg id="11">The mirkle groups all over the world number of employees is close to 100,000 rasio and their assets to form a pharmacist named company has been making special significance.</seg>
<seg id="12">adolfmirkle said it had several times in his life: &quot;We have been doing pharmacology and four generations.</seg>
<seg id="13">The management of this organization is with my children and I hope that this organization for just a few hundred years I will remain in the anttam family.</seg>
<seg id="14">Banks adolfmirkle of suicide after you have approved the provisional loans worth 400 million euro for the VEM group but the situation is that we will have to sell korasio VEM to form a long-term economic condition of the group could be improved on the basis.</seg>
<seg id="15">The mirkle group after the death of adolfmirkle will not be the same as that never was.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">According to People with Crimes in Germany</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">22 percent of crimes by foreigners between 2004 and 2007 according to the latest statistics.</seg>
<seg id="3">21 after decreasing by 9 percent.</seg>
<seg id="4">It was up to 4 percent.</seg>
<seg id="5">In an apparent positive change is only the dakhlhJoachim Herrmann according to the minister of Bavaria.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said: &quot; &quot; It is increasing the number of foreigners who is that keeping in mind the German citizenship.</seg>
<seg id="7">It should also said that although the figures in committing the crime is a German citizen but his background is foreign.</seg>
<seg id="8">Herrmann said that the number of criminals by 2010 at the time of his province also collects and they should keep in mind.</seg>
<seg id="9">In Bavaria and Hamburg also considers in those regions.</seg>
<seg id="10">Senator Christoph Ahlhaus belonging to the CDU points of entry said: &quot; The Scientifically &quot; when it is already investigating the humanitarian consequences of their choice but it can not be will depend on these figures that emerged after the research.</seg>
<seg id="11">Ahlhaus drew attention towards an analytical report by the provincial office of preventing crimes that 2006 was produced in 2006 and the Hamburg found in the Bergdorf part of the city that how many percent participation in the crime of foreigners who are here.</seg>
<seg id="12">It found out that the results of the foreigners here</seg>
<seg id="13">According to the crime rate is less than the crimes in the province.</seg>
<seg id="14">Contrary to this when the crime rate among young people in 2006 in Berlin when it was confirmed that 44 percent of young people with foreign background.</seg>
<seg id="15">It was 7 percent.</seg>
<seg id="16">The other political parties of the SPD environment, such as Germany are against the Green Party and the leftist Linkspartei party figures related to crimes that this information is collected at the time of who is also will collect the German foreign nationals.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Army Withdrawal from the Gaza Strip Soon To: Olmart</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Ehud Olmart stressed that a stable and permanent ceasefire agreement for the complete withdrawal of troops is necessary.</seg>
<seg id="3">Hamas and Israel announced a ceasefire on Sunday.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Islamic militant group Hamas to declare a ceasefire said Saturday that Israeli forces within a week to go out completely from the Gaza strip and barricade in the Gaza strip should be abolished.</seg>
<seg id="5">On the other hand the leader of the hm^as hnih Ismail said that a victory by God to Israel in the ghz^h war has had the luck.</seg>
<seg id="6">Israel in the ghz^h war has failed in achieving its goals.</seg>
<seg id="7">Earlier the city of Egypt was held a meeting of leaders of European and Arab countries on Sunday in Sharm El-Sheikh bombings in which he has demanded an immediate withdrawal of Israeli forces from the ghz^h.</seg>
<seg id="8">It was decided that an international donor conference to be held in ghz^h.</seg>
<seg id="9">German Chancellor angilamirkl also participated in the meeting.</seg>
<seg id="10">Israel and the Palestinian Hamas at least 1300 to continue the war of resistance among for three weeks and killed ten Israelis soldiers including Teerah yesterday.</seg>
<seg id="11">On the other hand the Palestinian President mmod Abbas has called for a national government in the Palestinian territories.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Video of the Message of Germany</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">A man in the video, thirty minutes to wear a turban of black color, and face concealed gun in hand is a message to the German government has held.</seg>
<seg id="3">The person is introducing in the name of Abu Talha and talking to himself in the German language.</seg>
<seg id="4">The video message on the Arabic ta-etlz all were also present.</seg>
<seg id="5">Everyone has been linked to the side of the screen, video was filed in October as the date of 2008.</seg>
<seg id="6">The German government in a statement has said that such a large number of Afghanistan and I am expressing belief that the fixing of the army that it wouldn&apos;t be attacked if they forgot the pin, and they are?</seg>
<seg id="7">The person telling the abotlhh although indirectly on Germany did not threaten the attacks.</seg>
<seg id="8">The number of German soldiers involved in the NATO allied forces in Afghanistan is around 3,500.</seg>
<seg id="9">Another thousand soldiers German parliament in October last year has been given to send the bill of Afghanistan.</seg>
<seg id="10">This is the first message received by the Al - Germany.</seg>
<seg id="11">Prominent expert mikha-eil LDERS, keeping an eye on matters relating to the state terrorism in connection with the message: &quot; The Kabul recently&quot; suicide attack outside the German embassy is proof of the fact that we have taken it seriously at any cost.</seg>
<seg id="12">Al - for the last few years is to issue a video message on the Internet and there is a message after the attack.</seg>
<seg id="13">On Saturday, the military organization Taliban claimed responsibility for a suicide attack outside the German embassy in Kabul.</seg>
<seg id="14">The German newspapers and analysts are looking after joining the message to the Al-Qa&apos;ida attacks.</seg>
<seg id="15">&quot; We are &quot; targeting Germany.</seg>
<seg id="16">Fundamentalist Muslims, and the victim of a negative view of the Afghan policy of Germany.</seg>
<seg id="17">The German government has not only accusations being prejudiced adopting policies in Afghanistan and the Middle East.</seg>
<seg id="18">And because they have lived up to Germany as its target.</seg>
<seg id="19">The German government has said that the public before the video of the German intelligence agencies were aware of it.</seg>
<seg id="20">German is engaged in a video message to stop all the crime.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Obama Has Taken Charge American Presidency.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">US citizens in this context, the world has the Associated different expectations than Obama.</seg>
<seg id="3">The President of the United States that Barack Obama has received messages of congratulations from all over the prdunia if it hopes to have decided to come forward.</seg>
<seg id="4">In this regard the German Chancellor angilamirkl has expressed confidence in the new &quot;.</seg>
<seg id="5">&quot;I am confident that we have a deep friendship and partnership between the United States of America and German Federal Republic can solve this problem.</seg>
<seg id="6">Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin said that the owner of a sincere and open mind Obama is seen as well as for the iqnini Sounds good.</seg>
<seg id="7">Facing criticism of the policies of the former US President George W. Bush.</seg>
<seg id="8">It is to give the movement to play a more constructive role on the international level to China while China and his new administration of President Bush has said that he would have to work for a strong military ties between the two countries.</seg>
<seg id="9">Active Chinese political scientist guosuo-eeouo bokhum City in German:</seg>
<seg id="10">&quot;Obama in the weeks and months and I am sure that in this context and his economic team will influence for the Chinese currency and a flexible exchange rate and the Beijing government coinciding with to market forces to adopt.</seg>
<seg id="11">The US administration has made by India and Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="12">The Obama can be taken to these relations, Prof Christopher.  Raj of education in the United States about what New Delhi says: &quot;We have come very close to the strategic partnership with Obama during the night but they can not bring any change.</seg>
<seg id="13">Pope Benedict has stressed on the promotion of peace and cooperation in the world in the name of Obama message.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Provincial Elections in Iraq</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The important elections in the country after the war-stricken of the year.</seg>
<seg id="3">14 400se, candidate for over 440 seats in provincial elections have landed in the field.</seg>
<seg id="4">800,000 troops and police to maintain law and order situation during the elections have been deployed in Iraq.</seg>
<seg id="5">In view of the risk that such an important day is not a terrorist attack or any other attack should be a day earlier that all Iraqi borders have been sealed on Friday.</seg>
<seg id="6">The airport was closed and restricts on public transport.</seg>
<seg id="7">According to reports, traffic on the bghdadki road due to the ban on the transport and there is no Iraqi children play football is clearly visible on the streets.</seg>
<seg id="8">During the current security situation for the Iraqi elections will be held on one hand it over to the local security agencies from Iraq after the withdrawal of US troops in 2011 halter snhbal will be the year of the country and on the other hand they are also taking political analysts as an experiment in which jaskega estimated that the people of Iraq are democratically agreed to what extent to bring a change in the country.</seg>
<seg id="9">The provincial elections in Iraq with the help of the United Nations is going to hold and nearly 800 international observers are the election process.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">For the First 10 Days of Al-Shuhda and Syed Muharram Day &quot; in the First 10 Days of Muharram Day of Hazrat Imam Husain (&apos;) Today Was Celebrated with Great Respect and Honor the Memory of Animal</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Syed-us-Shuhada in all small and big cities of the Iranian capital Tehran according to a report of the Mehr news agency (&apos;) of Hazrat Imam Husain observed with great zeal mourning on the occasion of the maumnin was attended by a large number of Majlis Aza protests and Nabi Mukarram Sad (and) and his followers (&apos;) ratio in front of their condolences to all the evidence of Iran Mukarram Nabi son of Hazrat Imam Husain (Sad) (&apos;) is a mourner and mourning in memory of the great sacrifices in the field of Karbala of Hazrat Imam Syed Husain maumnin Al-Shuhda (&apos;) made a fresh memory of incomparable sacrifice in the field of Karbala and widespread protests and they attended the assembly of mourning.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Incomparable Determination of Soviet Troops from Palestinian Gaza Strip with Israeli Soldiers in the &apos;jlin Area</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr sixteenth day of fighting for the truth and falsehood in Gaza to serve the Urdu news agency prohshianh continued for the civilian population, air bombardment by Israel, the Gaza Strip on the ground and naval attacks so far 880 people and injuring 3700 Palestinians martyred</seg>
<seg id="3">275 innocent martyrs are included in the smile on his so-called mutiny of organizations and international human rights of the Arab leaders who are sog-ee in the embrace of death.</seg>
<seg id="4">The brdosh shrouds soldiers from the Gaza Strip to the Israeli army retreated to &apos;jin with the help of a pa-edari zone and the power of faith and determination and they are evidence showing rhyme and Israel is the teasing Hayat</seg>
<seg id="5">If there is no mutiny unfortunate of Egyptian President Hasni and then Mujahid Ghayyur Bahadur Israel and Egypt along with four Hamas has erupted when an Israeli siege but put away from defeat is besieging Palestinian Arab Muslims who is the most tragic accident of history</seg>
<seg id="6">The government of Saudi Arabia and Jordan and Israel are providing political, financial and aid from the revolting unarmed Muslims are Israelis support the Gaza</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The New Strategy Adopted By the United States to Barack Obama Iran</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Barack Obama elected President of the United States according to a report of the Mehr news agency has said in an interview with ABC News Channel that he should adopt a new and modern strategy on the issue of Iran.</seg>
<seg id="3">Barack Obama said that Iran &quot;will be a big challenge for the US government&quot;.</seg>
<seg id="4">Barack Obama said that the aseflstini Islamic group are concerned about the nuclear programs of Iran and afzhodgi Iranian support for Hezbollah and Hamas.</seg>
<seg id="5">But the policy of President Bush on Iran would continue and would not take part in various policy relations with Iran.</seg>
<seg id="6">Barack Obama said that their real reason to completely clarify that he will emphasize on the desire of mutual respect and dialogue.</seg>
<seg id="7">Barack Obama has also said that in the past as part of negotiations with Iran previously did not impose any conditions to go.</seg>
<seg id="8">In an interview he hoped to follow the new pr&apos;tizise strategy with regard to Iran in his administration.</seg>
<seg id="9">Obama said about the Middle East crisis that he is the only form a special team</seg>
<seg id="10">The krdegi beginning January 20 and for efforts to establish peace in the Middle jomshrqi.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Incapable Mnfor and Sdrjarj U.S. President George W Bush Had Confessed His Crimes in the Past Mistakes and Addressing Press</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Mehr News Agency has reported in reference to the Associated Press that U.S. President George Bush had confessed his crimes and several mistakes in the last press conference of his time.</seg>
<seg id="3">While addressing a press conference at the White House said that President Bush put sentiments of goodwill in relation to the newly elected president, but the biggest challenge for Obama Obama will be possible to stop attacks on the United States.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that the social security reform and complete the mission in Iraq was a mistake.</seg>
<seg id="5">The president said that he had made for the protection of the United States.</seg>
<seg id="6">In response to the asked many questions about the ongoing Israeli aggression in the Gaza Strip President Bush said that Israel has the right to defend its right to say that Hamas is not defending his career on the Hamas and Israel did not want to raise a hand to strangle oppressed and the oppressor instead of the world like America</seg>
<seg id="7">Unworthy mnfor incompetent and President of the United States said that the Hamas weapons also did not want to give the United States and Israel are providing the most deadly and deadly weapons in the world can take advantage of US weapons in Israel for the massacre of Palestinian President Bush and his Israeli Arabs also praised anihn as a friend of Israel.</seg>
<seg id="8">Bush expressed shame over certain crimes at Abu Ghraib and goantanama prisons.</seg>
<seg id="9">Analysts say the case for war crimes on Bush should be established and that the organization will perform this work will be great interest on the humanity.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Iranian President Ahmadinejad Has Expressed Sorrow Over the Silence of the Arab Countries</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Mehr said according to a report by the News Agency.  that President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad of Iran and the Israeli aggression on the Gaza Strip and hand over the te crisis criticizes the silence of oppression and tyranny pr&apos;rb leaders have expressed their grief.</seg>
<seg id="3">sdrahmdi Origin has said Arab countries and wondering silence on the Israeli brutal action on Gaza roads by the head of lokast lettuce Palestinians that Israel is targeting Palestinian children, women and civilians their barbarism and rhnmaaun still has not issued a statement.</seg>
<seg id="4">President Ahmadi Nejad said that all Arab countries should unite against Israel and satanic oppressed Muslims of Israel and the Gaza Strip to protect them from the oppression and tyranny.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Human Genocide By Israel in the Gaza Strip King of Saudi Arabia Will Clarify Ahmadinejad in Connection with My Point of View</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Iranian President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad according to a report of the Mehr news agency has said in his message to the rulers of Saudi Arabia Abdullah Malik that Saudi Arabia has become the cause of the enemies of Islam silence over the massacre of innocent children and women in the Gaza Strip and silence on human king of genocide in Gaza</seg>
<seg id="3">President Ahmadi Nejad said in a statement made it clear that the support from the right point of view on the Gaza Strip and oppressed so that the efforts to keep the differences in front of the Islami enemies have failed to be</seg>
<seg id="4">President Ahmadi Nejad said in his message that you know that Israel is fried for 19 days on human genocide in Gaza is innocent of killing innocent children homes, mosques, schools and hospitals in the brutal bombing of the Zionist government nhtemslmanon in Gaza has badly in these circumstances is ascending the courage to silence by Israeli leaders like you</seg>
<seg id="5"> President Ahmadi Nejad said that Abdullah Malik onzo-ela such as bolioi and un-Islamic countries should take concrete actions against Israel from if you are the steps taken by the expectation of a better world</seg>
<seg id="6">President Ahmadi Nejad said that success in the Gaza Strip will pay tribute to the Palestinians.</seg>
<seg id="7">Victory over the oppressor and oppressed people will need luck and there is a commitment to the Almighty God.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Osama Hmdan Will Continue Its Resistance in Palestine</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Osama hmdan Hamas representative in Lebanon according to a report of the Mehr news agency said in a conversation with French news agency that the unilateral cease-fire with Israel is against the international efforts for a comprehensive ceasefire said they would remain there until a asraghil cease-fire in the Gaza side by that time will become meaningless</seg>
<seg id="3">The failed Israeli attempt to avoid further said that a ceasefire side defeated hmdan said that if Israel wants that lasting peace will have to accept the terms of the Hamas besieging</seg>
<seg id="4">The leader of Hamas in the Gaza strip Lebanon made it clear that he was of the Israeli army of a unilateral cease-fire with Israel if it will continue its resistance against it.</seg>
<seg id="5">Disconnected lizard ties with Israel on behalf of the European countries that hmdan while addressing a conference of solidarity with the people in Gaza to Beirut.</seg>
<seg id="6">The leader of Hamas said that the injured were martyred and increasing the number of our determination and courage and I will ascend.</seg>
<seg id="7">He asked the Palestinian people to resistance was a prdte rock in the war against the enemy.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Taliban in the North Waziristan Tribal Region of Pakistan Has Killed Six People</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Mehr News Agency has reported in reference to Reuters that two Afghans in the North Waziristan tribal region of Pakistan and the Taliban have killed four people on charges of spying.</seg>
<seg id="3">The district in Mir Ali district Tuesday morning to the local people are reported to have received four bodies at Chowk which was shot dead.</seg>
<seg id="4">The two bodies Miran Shah who have received capital threw a market in the market.</seg>
<seg id="5">Letters written in Urdu near bodies have been found in which he claimed that he spied died on the spot.</seg>
<seg id="6">Two weeks ago two Afghans in Miran Shah in North Waziristan capital were murdered on charges of spying.</seg>
<seg id="7">Fifteen people have been killed in the last 12 days on charges of spying for the United States.</seg>
<seg id="8">More than 100 during the six years that South and North Waziristan in the past has been accused of spying on the Taliban alzam is that they are involved in the murder case of this type.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Expecting Signed a Closing of the Notorious Jail of Barack Obama Goantanamobe</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Mehr News Agency has reported in reference to sources that President Bush would sign a closing of the notorious jail of goantanamobe today</seg>
<seg id="3">The new US Barack Obama Hussain has begun implementing pledges at the level of his election campaign.</seg>
<seg id="4">The President Obama has instructed the planning for the withdrawal of US forces from Iraq, and he will sign a closing of the notorious jail of &quot; goantanamobe.</seg>
<seg id="5">It is expected that the order of President Barack Obama prmmknh today the signing of the Guantanamo Bay prison to be closed within one year.</seg>
<seg id="6">In addition to this view on other ways of investigation of suspected terrorists and the White House to talk to the poor prisoners are also likely to be released.</seg>
<seg id="7">Mr. Barack Obama began work for fulfilling the promises of the election on the first day of his presidency and first of all he has taken a transparent process and the action of the government.</seg>
<seg id="8">Analysts say that President Bush has begun efforts at the international level of savings falling reputation of the United States but it is very difficult to get in there as long as the United States is girded up in support of the ferocious Israeli government until it a good job but it should not be expected to be able to save its credibility if the United States in the world if it wanted to become a hamit meeting with the Israeli side and the crimes they did not want to participate.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Forces on the Need for Dialogue Between the Islamic Group Hamas Tony Blair</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Mehr News Agency has given the British newspaper the Times reported that former Prime Minister Tony Blair of Britain has stressed the need for Hamas and the peace process in the Middle East.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to the newspaper Tony Blair said that it is important to find a way through which will be brought to the Middle East peace process of the Hamas Blair on anzamih Bush only to talk with Mahmoud Abbas and Hamas for ignoring the public of the Hamas and it should be noted that the Western countries &quot; criticism after guessing the right now is talking about Nizami during talks with him before it and take it as a terrorist group E with the defending the home countries that Hamas is a terrorist organization is making an effort to liberating people from their homes as a usurper Israel at home and country The sixty years have been taken into custody.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Businessmen of Karachi, Killing a Complete Strike Was Observed in Quetta</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The death of the four businessmen in Karachi on Thursday went on a strike and completed in some other areas.</seg>
<seg id="3">In the meantime the business centers remained closed and traffic was less than usual.</seg>
<seg id="4">A protest strike appealed traders, Balochistan Association - Pashtoonkhwa Milli Awami Party and Jamiat Ulma-e-Islam, who was alleged that the Karachi police have killed by firing at the showroom of their vehicles had arrived in his vehicle at Tariq Road.</seg>
<seg id="5">President Abdur Rahim Kakar businessmen of Al - union demanded that the personnel involved in an accident police action will be taken against those arrested.</seg>
<seg id="6">But immediately after the incident of the Karachi police did not come to the fore.</seg>
<seg id="7">The border cities of the four businessmen who died were from Chaman.</seg>
<seg id="8">The government on the eve of the strike on a large scale and the security arrangements and the police personnel were deployed at key locations throughout the city.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Senior Hamas Commander Was Killed in an Israeli Attack</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">A senior commander of Hamas in an Israeli air strike.</seg>
<seg id="3">In the ongoing attacks by Hamas in a week by Israel in Gaza is the death of the important personalities.</seg>
<seg id="4">Officials of Hamas said that Abu Zikarya was killed in aljmal on Saturday in the alshja&apos;ih neighborhood east of Gaza City.</seg>
<seg id="5">In another air strike by Israel on Thursday when they were slim Alam ra&apos;i^an of Hamas.</seg>
<seg id="6">Exiled Hamas leader Khaled torch residing in Syria shows vowed to take revenge attacks against Israel and the Gaza Strip on the ground has been warned.</seg>
<seg id="7">Thousands of Israeli tanks and troops are deployed on the border of the Gaza Strip and are waiting to attack it.</seg>
<seg id="8">The United States has appealed for ceasefire.  But it said that the attack on the Gaza Strip and the decision of not dependent on Israel.</seg>
<seg id="9">US President George Bush in his weekly radio alleged provocation to inflame violence Hamas and Israel in a speech on terrorism he declared that the rocket attacks.</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the United States is working for a partial ceasefire agreement, but it will not be acceptable.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Three Bodies Were Recovered in North Waziristan</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Pakistani security officials said the bodies of three people in the North Waziristan tribal region have received.</seg>
<seg id="3">The suspect that Taliban kills him to death.</seg>
<seg id="4">The dead bodies were found near the central town of Miran Shah in North Waziristan and ruq&apos;e that he has been given to them in which he has been spying for the United States.</seg>
<seg id="5">According to the officials of the body of a local person who did this probably kidnapped last week.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the crib with bullets remaining Afghans are two bodies.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Elected Deputy President Joseph Biden Arrived in Pakistan</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Foreign Minister was elected deputy president</seg>
<seg id="3">In his delegation on a visit to Pakistan was elected Vice President Joseph Biden of the United States has arrived in Islamabad on Friday.</seg>
<seg id="4">Foreign Minister Shah Mahmood Qureshi and high officials of the US embassy welcomed him.</seg>
<seg id="5">He is visiting the United States with Biden in sinitrLindsy Grahambhi.</seg>
<seg id="6">Press Officer of the American Embassy told you fntrne Voice of America that the newly elected president will hold talks on various regional issues with the Pakistani leadership during his visit but he avoided to give more details.</seg>
<seg id="7">Joseph Biden according to the sources of the Foreign Office with General Parvez Ashfaq Kayani as well as the army chief will also meet senior government officials.</seg>
<seg id="8">It is expected that the matters related to the war against terrorism as well as major international issues and bilateral meetings as well as the exchange of ideas.</seg>
<seg id="9">Joseph Hilal-i-Pakistan Biden was given</seg>
<seg id="10">Joseph Biden reached Islamabad after meeting with President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
<seg id="11">The meeting held in the honor bestowed by the Hilal-i-Pakistan for his role in establishing close relations between Pakistan and the United States.</seg>
<seg id="12">It should be remembered that Joseph Biden introduced a bill with Senator rchrdlogr as chairman of the foreign relations committee of the US Senate last year in which 7 out of three times a demilitarized increase in aid from the United States during the next five years. It recommends that 5 billion dollars.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Joba-eidn &quot; Autroane &quot;in the Uniform of President Pervez Musharraf Has Played an Important Role, Gilani Prime Minister</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Yousaf Raza Gilani and that Biden (file photo</seg>
<seg id="3">The Prime Minister Yousaf Raza Gilani has said that the elected Vice-President of the United States that Biden autroane uniform of President Pervez Musharraf &quot; has played an important role in &quot;to give up the post of army chief and for democracy in Pakistan also helped a joba-eidn</seg>
<seg id="4">Yousaf Raza Gilani has held talks with newsmen at the Karachi shipyard.</seg>
<seg id="5">He said that &quot;Pakistan&quot; Pro Biden - or supporter leaders of Pakistan and he presented the bill for the help of 15 billion dollars for the Pakistani Foreign amuor Committee Chairman of the US Senate.</seg>
<seg id="6">The missile strikes by US spy planes in Pakistani borders Prime Minister of Pakistan once again condemned the attacks of letting things said about me with the US government does not have any kind of compromise and bqol because it is a matter of sovereignty of Pakistan so they can provide a basis of such attacks in the national boundaries</seg>
<seg id="7">He also expressed the hope that the policy of the United States and the ruling of the new government will bring a change in the United States.</seg>
<seg id="8">The (photo)</seg>
<seg id="9">Yousaf Raza Gilani said that separates the common tribal terrorists but the huge success of the jasos missile strike aircraft prove harmful for the government and the phrmqami tribes not terrorists.</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the international community agrees with this position.</seg>
<seg id="11">The Prime Minister further said that if no reliable bear witness to Pakistan if military action should be taken in their areas.</seg>
<seg id="12">The Prime Minister Yousaf Raza Gilani said in Bombay repeat attacks on their positions if India to provide evidence that it will investigate it and on the basis of the evidence of the involvement of agrksi was found will act in accordance with the law against it.</seg>
<seg id="13">The visiting British Rehman Malik and asked about the MQM leader Altaf Hussain for the prime minister in response to a question has gone to London with the consent of the Rehman Malik said.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Quetta, Killing Four Policemen and DSP</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The photo</seg>
<seg id="3">The DSP in firing by unknown people on a highway on Saryab Road &quot; was four police officials including Deputy sprintndnt of Police.</seg>
<seg id="4">The two on Wednesday morning in a jeep DSP, a sub-inspector and two police constables were going to training centers that unknown attackers riding on a motorcycle near degree college situated at Saryab Road started unprovoked firing on a jeep in which the police inspector and a constable Mehdi Sibghat Ullah Nasrullah and died on the spot while torg-ee moments after reaching a DSP Ali Hassan.</seg>
<seg id="5">Hospital sources say another severely injured is critical condition and DSP Ghulam mhmdki have been shot in the head and neck.</seg>
<seg id="6">The police have surrounded the area and that no one has claimed responsibility for the incident so far not accepted.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Death of Other Indian Software Engineers in America</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Unknown attackers to another anjbi-er software belong to Andhra Pradesh shot dead in the United States.</seg>
<seg id="3">Two days after the 26 year old Akshay Vishal The living in an unknown attacker before the arkinsa state.  Vishal during the first aid to the hospital.</seg>
<seg id="4">He was an employee of the stim jet Shaheen and computers in the United States was working in the ai-eroiz.</seg>
<seg id="5">Seven students belong to Andhra Pradesh in the past year have been killed in the hands of anti-social elements in the United States.</seg>
<seg id="6">Increasing deaths of students heading for the acquisition of higher education and employment in the United States has created anxiety among the thousands of families in the province that the child is living in the United States.</seg>
<seg id="7">It should be noted that the United States in Andhra Pradesh for higher education and a better future is preferred.</seg>
<seg id="8">They have received a 100,000 dokhoastin each year for US visas for South India according to the US consulate in Chennai in which 40 percent is the highest in Andhra Pradesh.</seg>
<seg id="9">The state government has launched efforts to bring the dead body of Hyderabad.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Chokn^a Attacks Against the United States Was the Enemy: Bush</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">US President George ridiopr Bush has called on his last weekly &quot; in the United States that it was an attack against the chokn^a of the enemy.</seg>
<seg id="3">Mr. Bush has said that the biggest threat to Americans there is a possibility of another attack by terrorists.  And he warned that the enemies of the country are waiting with patience and they are on a tule again.</seg>
<seg id="4">The accusations being subk to US efforts to protect its stated definitely does not want to distract.</seg>
<seg id="5">President Bush also expressed his best tmnaaun Barack Obama, for the next president Tuesday that it will take oath of his office.</seg>
<seg id="6">the newly elected Barack Obama keep the light on the historical significance of the oath taking ceremony held at the weekend radio address at the Democratic Party.</seg>
<seg id="7">He said that this meeting is a constitution is a very strong relationship with U.S. peace with dignity of transfer of power from one leader to another leader.</seg>
<seg id="8">Mr. Obama reminded that most people in the world can not do as well as the ts^or massacre or its leaders should be given up without the power struggle.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Federal Interior Minister Brothers Sharif and Met in Raiwind, Exchange of Views on Political and Security Affairs</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The opposition and the ruling party in Punjab, Pakistan met in Raiwind on Sunday between Nawaz Sharif Rehman Malik Federal Interior Minister and head of the ruling Pakistan Muslim League (N) in which the Punjab Chief Minister Shahbaz Sharif was also present.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to local media Rehman Malik possibly came after an important message to the leadership of Pakistan Peoples Party.</seg>
<seg id="4">However, in a conversation with journalists after a meeting with the Rehman Malik did not reveal any details and only said that he has talked about the political affairs of the politics of consensus and Mumbai, the PML leadership has briefed on the situation after the attacks.</seg>
<seg id="5">In the words of them: &quot;So far as much information about this operation have been provided.</seg>
<seg id="6">He did not forget that has become a major operation in Punjab and the Punjab government and is now that he has formed a team of Punjab also need support from the government.</seg>
<seg id="7">The daily said that Rahman told the media are not the PML, but with the leadership of the day is an exchange of messages.  There, the Pakistan Muslim League (N) spokesman, General Rashid also avoided to say something about the political affairs and mhz said in a conversation that Rehman.  was that the country has said.</seg>
<seg id="8">It should be noted that the meeting of the Home Advisor to the leadership of Pakistan Muslim League (N) has been a period of 20 more seats while the government of Punjab and hot rival PML Q in politics and the governor of Punjab province with Salman tasirke told the press conference, the PML reject criticism of the steps taken by the provincial government Nazems belonging to the governor of Punjab People&apos;s Party joining the objects as well.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Obama Nejad&apos;s of Pakistan Is Promising To: Mr. Zardari</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Pakistani President Asif Ali Zardari has said in his welcoming speech at the opening of the new president of the United States Obama rock belongs to the fact that the process of mutual interests and respect for the Muslim world by promising to Pakistan and its people.</seg>
<seg id="3">On Wednesday he said in a statement issued by the reiteratation ideas and values highly the determination of President Bush is expected to a better future for the people around the world.</seg>
<seg id="4">The statement said that Zardari in accordance with the international community in the United States in the 21st century, peace is the main responsibility for finding new ways of development and prosperity.</seg>
<seg id="5">It should be noted that President Obama had on Tuesday said in his inaugural speech after taking oath as the United States wants the Muslim world and the latest developments that are based on mutual interests and respect.</seg>
<seg id="6">They had assured the people of the country that the United States will work together with them so that there is a social development and the alleviation of poverty.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Obama President Has Appointed a Special Representative to Afghanistan and Pakistan</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">by Richard Hall put it has been appointed as a special representative to Afghanistan and Pakistan to prevent it from a former ambassador to the United Nations Richard Hall.</seg>
<seg id="3">Hall had played an important role in the peace process in Bosnia to prevent hrzgoina from it.</seg>
<seg id="4">Hall said the checking and that they are ready for consultations with President Obama on matters from Afghanistan and Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="5">The azafh has said that this is not an easy task.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the two countries is very different.</seg>
<seg id="7">President for the Middle East was to insist that the Arabs and Israel to try to animate the peace talks.</seg>
<seg id="8">The former senator and insist that they had played an important role in arranging the ortho peace in Northern Ireland.</seg>
<seg id="9">The said they would insist that the State Department while talking in a very unstable situation in the Middle East, is a complex and dangerous.</seg>
<seg id="10">But despite the efforts of the United States will not establish peace.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Afghanistan: Voter Registration Is in Danger G-ei</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Election Commission of Afghanistan has said that it is delaying the voter registration in some areas of the south due to concerns about security.</seg>
<seg id="3">Voter registration for the presidential election which was near &apos;n in southern Afghanistan had earlier this week.</seg>
<seg id="4">But the commission said that until the security situation will be better in some areas, voter in Helmand province will not be able to register.</seg>
<seg id="5">There has been an increase in violence since last year in the areas of the south, where Taliban rebels increased their attacks against Afghan forces and international forces.</seg>
<seg id="6">Meanwhile, Afghan army and international forces have said that they killed at least 28 militants during clashes in Afghanistan over the night between Wednesday and Thursday.</seg>
<seg id="7">NATO has said that its forces killed 22 insurgents in air and ground assault in eastern Khost province near the Pakistani border.</seg>
<seg id="8">The Afghan Defense Ministry had said earlier that the Afghan forces in the province and killed eight insurgents and wounding two.</seg>
<seg id="9">It is not clear whether the Afghan authorities have given a reference to an accident.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">NWFP Government Rejected the Demand for the Education of Girls in Swat</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">NWFP authorities have rejected by saying the threat of a ban on education for girls to Taliban warriors in Swat that &quot;this is against the law and Islam.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Northwest Frontier province on Sunday, the education minister Sardar Hussain Babar said that governments at all such efforts will not be allowed to succeed.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that it was an attempt by extremists in this area that children were deprived of education.</seg>
<seg id="5">In the words of them: &quot;These people secretly schools and children try to fly dhmkaneki.</seg>
<seg id="6">In the atmosphere of fear and panic, he said that the provincial government is well aware of this and want to clarify that no power to the promotion of education stops the country can not of Pakhtoons.</seg>
<seg id="7">A day earlier under the leadership of Maulana Fazal Ullah Taliban warriors demanded banning education for girls in the educational institutions of Swat from January 15 and threatened that they violate the oalet&apos;limi will be destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="8">The 150 during the past one and a half years in spite of the military operation in the educational institutions around the main Suwat seaorag explosive material has been made.</seg>
<seg id="9">As a result of destroying ain boys and girls educational institutions have lost their number in the thousands of sholit from the education.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Hard for Security Arrangements on the Occasion of the Indian Republic Day</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The sixtieth Indian Republic Day is celebrated on Monday, the very strict security measures all across the country and has deployed thousands of troops.</seg>
<seg id="3">The prdarlhkomt of the Republic Day military parade in New Delhi are exhibiting the planes, weapons and other military equipment.</seg>
<seg id="4">The officials say that the anti-aircraft guns in accordance with the security arrangements and Sharp shotr&quot; and &quot;were also deployed along the routes of the parade police under the rock Obama &quot; while keeping an eye on the occasion of his India</seg>
<seg id="5">And that of Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh on Saturday was a heart operation of the thaaun bhijahe as well as the message of the recovery.</seg>
<seg id="6">In keeping in mind the other day that Indian police had claimed killing after fighting on the outskirts of New Delhi to the two suspected militants.</seg>
<seg id="7">According to the local police officials from both of these men AK 47 rifles, grenades and recovered some documents that show that this is the Pakistani.</seg>
<seg id="8">The police also are investigating whether the Lashkar-e-Tayiba is a banned organization affiliated to them that the Mumbai in November last year was involved in the attacks.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Tea: The Breast Cancer Treatment</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In a new research said that three cups of tea a day</seg>
<seg id="3">Age less than 50 years to drink a few more than a third of the risk of breast cancer in women.</seg>
<seg id="4">Tumor breast cancer in women under the age of 50 years and it is said that the moft in cancer research center of the US state of Florida</seg>
<seg id="5">Loss of up to 37 percent of the risk of drinks are at least three cups of tea Zana wife.</seg>
<seg id="6">The research also shows the three women are said to get a tea cup or more per day to drink it does not have any special favor.</seg>
<seg id="7">Analysts think that this is the presence of those ingredients in tea due to that of the hotehin more effective against tumors that this particular type of cancer in women under age are usually less than 50 years.</seg>
<seg id="8">The researched the women on more than 5,000 moft cancer center located in tmpa City in the Florida who was treated for breast cancer.</seg>
<seg id="9">Only 20 and 74 years between the ages.</seg>
<seg id="10">Experts have women in comparison to their medical records and to save the life of breast cancer.</seg>
<seg id="11">Experts also discovered that a certain types of cancer, loblr, asrdkhaia prominently on their tea and decreased to 66 percent.</seg>
<seg id="12">The breast cancer patients suffer in almost every tenth.</seg>
<seg id="13">This type of cancer are more dangerous because it is in the depth and generally indicate at a time when they have enough.</seg>
<seg id="14">According to the experts regularly at risk of breast cancer in women under the age of daily drinking at least three cups of tea may have been a few</seg>
<seg id="15">He said that it is an everyday to drink tea and there will be a m&apos;daft day against cancer in the body in a routine.</seg>
<seg id="16">In Britain every year there is a diagnosis of breast cancer in the nearly 40,000 women.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The Battle in Afghanistan Is the Biggest Challenge Faced By the US Military: Gates</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">American Secretary of Defense Robert Gates has said that the war in Afghanistan is the biggest challenge faced by the US military.</seg>
<seg id="3">Iraq and Afghanistan to the members of the US Senate and Assembly Gates was briefing journalists about Obama administration on the war.</seg>
<seg id="4">Gates told the Senate Armed Services Committee of the war that the only solution to the problem of Afghanistan but he added that a number of troops to secure the area do not take the Taliban, to take action.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Why the Exercise with Age?</seg>
<seg id="2">New Research</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="3">Exercise is good for the health of all ages.</seg>
<seg id="4">It is your heart, a reduction in the level of Assistant cholestrol weight, it brings in some help to prove, diabetes and Alzheimer is that slows down the process of oblivion.</seg>
<seg id="5">Unfortunately it is decreasing in the capability of doing exercises with the increasing number of older people.</seg>
<seg id="6">According to the experts to exercise our body and mind are cautious but may affect the age.</seg>
<seg id="7">The American Association of Health said that many problems to do exercises may not happen.</seg>
<seg id="8">Mayo Clinic.  Patrisha lika Monday said that the increase in the age of Minnesota is a major cause of disability and lack of physical exercise and performance.</seg>
<seg id="9">Medicine in Patrisha teaches at Mayo Clinic.</seg>
<seg id="10">He presided over by a study in connection with the ability to do exercises and human heart disease in older age.</seg>
<seg id="11">The team of doctors used frikonsi high waves of sound to review the performance of the heart.</seg>
<seg id="12">Among the heart pumps blood to go through the process of taking a rest, shrinkage of his heart.</seg>
<seg id="13">Experts have agreed on the part of his left hand on heart pumps blood that is part of the central.</seg>
<seg id="14">He added that the problems in the process of moving from the rest of my age.</seg>
<seg id="15">Dr. Patrisha said that the problems in the process of taking the &apos;mrbrhne with a clear mind and its impact on the ability to exercise with an increase in the age increases.</seg>
<seg id="16">Dr. Garvin may have been involved in this study.</seg>
<seg id="17">He said that they were watching the krhirt that has the effect of the important thing and it was explained how to do with the rest of the poor performance of the exercise.</seg>
<seg id="18">We can make blood pressure and heart problems of diseases of the heart.</seg>
<seg id="19">If doctors and patients for heart problems then they will work in spite of growing old may also get benefits of exercise.</seg>
<seg id="20">In this regard a detailed report has been published in the journal American Medical Association.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">There Is No Possibility of War with Pakistan: The Indian Army Chief of Staff</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The head of the Indian Army General Deepak Kapoor said that the possibility of war with Pakistan, but the national defense and to sacrifice in order to ensure the protection of the interests of all the time is ready.</seg>
<seg id="3">General Kapoor made assurances that in spite of international pressure on Pakistan as a result of the Mumbai attacks and, in the words of the infrastructure of terrorism, not only in Pakistan but there are also active.</seg>
<seg id="4">He was talking to reporters in the Sri Nagar.</seg>
<seg id="5">The head of the New Delhi under army administration was on a one-day visit to Kashmir Valley to review preparations for the armed forces on its borders and the security situation in Kashmir.</seg>
<seg id="6">When asked about the Mumbai attacks that Pakistan has denied media reports say the evidence presented by India, it is.</seg>
<seg id="7">General Kapoor political leaders said that the issue of war or peace.</seg>
<seg id="8">Allegedly he mentioned the infrastructure of terrorism in Pakistan, he said that it will compete with those elements of Indian forces to tule and that he is upset for the weak.</seg>
<seg id="9">He said that the militants of up to 800 from seven countries of the Indian Kashmir is nearly fifty percent of whom are foreigners.</seg>
<seg id="10">General Deepak Kapoor said that with the improvement in the weather and under his administration could be in the azafh infiltration in Kashmir, India has increased caution on the borders.</seg>
<seg id="11">He rejected the possibility of relief by calling corner in the number of troops deployed in Indian administered Kashmir that the security of the country can not compromise.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">God will be auspicious language in the world and prove auspicious for the world, &quot; Barack</seg>
<seg id="2">Although aum^id is still not see the t&apos;luqat of Pakistan and the United States to what extent it is our right in a change in the tnije</seg>
<seg id="3">Mr. Barack.  That is what the dreams of Martin luothr explained that the king in the world.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Obama who is also the name of Hussain, to take oath today as &quot; where there is a historic event in all aspects of it is also a crucial moment in history</seg>
<seg id="2">Not only does for their own people but also for all those who supported the heart and life.</seg>
<seg id="3">The test will not be easy to accept the heart of the prhkomt out of a black for them as well as the majority of the sfidfam.</seg>
<seg id="4">On his expectations from the khaskrmslmanon South Asia have been setup should remember that they have been elected president of the United States and you have to remember that the US President Mr. Obama is the basis of practical prdnia.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">And from now on a person after a while wearing a badge of slavery brethren were brought out of the country and the United States with his mother of blood and sweat which has irrigated the roots of the most powerful country in the modern era; khla-eega The forty four representatives of the United States of the victim of racial discrimination the nation.</seg>
<seg id="2">Most people expect a lot from a man who had been associating,</seg>
<seg id="3">It is imperative that the seghirhqiqt lovers on expectations were not likeliness.</seg>
<seg id="4">The global race, Obama laid the foundations on the basis of religious hatred a reduction in the lovers will be able to attain through his massive victory.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The asrpre will be on the South Asia and how it can expect significant changes to the hoaleseamriki policy.</seg>
<seg id="2">The kiseasrandaz will be a change in the relations between Pakistan and the United States.</seg>
<seg id="3">&quot;(BBC)</seg>
<seg id="4">My dear sir, Obama is setting, or any other kind of policy on puori relations and the world is one hundred billion petals!, influential and powerful Jewish lobby in the approach.</seg>
<seg id="5">And as far as Pakistan is concerned about the recent in Mumbai, India, Israel and the United States is the world triangle of aggressive behavior.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The management of Swat until after a long period of Swat that Pakistan was a responsibility of the army and the law.</seg>
<seg id="2">The government of Pakistan over the management of Swat in accordance with an agreement</seg>
<seg id="3">But unfortunately that our governments treated as stepmother to Swat.</seg>
<seg id="4">The number of schools by the end of Swat in Swat exactly as it did not rise</seg>
<seg id="5">Nor has taken an interest in the development and prosperity.</seg>
<seg id="6">The girls who were present in the number of times past is very low.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Educational institutions from the local Taliban in the Northwest Frontier Province of Pakistan is continuing were targeted.</seg>
<seg id="2">The school district of Swat had destroyed most of whom are girls.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Taliban had no ban on education for girls in Swat also announces.</seg>
<seg id="4">Thousands of students are being deprived of the acquisition of knowledge.</seg>
<seg id="5">What should be done to help you think of the Taliban and the girls.</seg>
<seg id="6">The government has yet to stop these illegal actions were unsuccessful.</seg>
<seg id="7">Do you think the government should do.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The question that should be made to the Pakistani ISI [mliga aijnsiion.</seg>
<seg id="2">The people of Swat had now realized this game that military service is there to hang about how the Taliban will fly to kill them or not a night curfew in five schools can at Chowk of the city after slaughtering the people under curfew.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">An official at the request of Swat aren&apos;t allowed to be established to check illegal actions if the government succeeds in how such?</seg>
<seg id="2">Now the question when it was discovered that the armed forces, sophisticated firearms and modern technology, and spying system is close to the government and all the four Taliban control then why not?</seg>
<seg id="3">The answer is that someone on his head of intelligence &quot; on Monday that neither the weapons nor are these ends</seg>
<seg id="4">Summary that the Taliban is simplifying the international imperialist &quot; black &quot;through his actions</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">From now on 15 years before the war in Afghanistan was issued</seg>
<seg id="2">The Taliban took control and that the ISI was cooperation with the opposition Northern Alliance which helped India, Russia and Iran.</seg>
<seg id="3">The situation changed suddenly started to come to the Taliban]</seg>
<seg id="4">The ISI has also offered US dollars from the previous close friend was done about it.</seg>
<seg id="5">Now the situation is that the war is still going on but also in the pkstan which is helping Iran, India and Russia</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">So the people in this connection and corrects wrong and that it does not make up a human being is wrong.</seg>
<seg id="2">For instance when a thief goes to steal if they thought it would be a good thing that &quot; to steal and not a curse, theft is punished by God and fears and then it will not steal human</seg>
<seg id="3">The Israel as long as it would not be felt that I was wrong and shedding innocent blood and his sentence would have to wait until it will thrust played with the blood of innocent in Gaza.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Manners!</seg>
<seg id="2">The question is that the war, armed struggle, is to solve the problems of terrorism?</seg>
<seg id="3">If the nskhh`chemistry again that there is no solution to the problem?</seg>
<seg id="4">The fighting hard to the right path, that does not solve problems but also in the &quot; blessing &quot;is.</seg>
<seg id="5">Palestine, Afghanistan, you should be adopted this model for the success of his movements to Nelson Mandela that Iraq had adopted in South Africa.</seg>
<seg id="6">This is the moral and political struggle over the armed struggle and self &quot; Jihad &quot;.</seg>
<seg id="7">It seems to be taking part in the election of the Kashmiris that they have accepted this point.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The third week of Israeli attacks on Gaza and the number of deaths has reached close to 1000.</seg>
<seg id="2">In spite of international diplomatic efforts could not be Truce</seg>
<seg id="3">And since the attacks began on December 27 according to an estimate by 90 thousand Palestinians have been shifted to safer areas after leaving his household.</seg>
<seg id="4">The relief agency said while accusing a reckless affair of the Palestinian children that an entire generation of Palestinian children will be a serious suffering from psychological and emotional problems.</seg>
<seg id="5">Do said.</seg>
<seg id="6">What should be?</seg>
<seg id="7">The lasting peace in the Gaza Strip is how?</seg>
<seg id="8">The description click here will be</seg>
<seg id="9">Please note the way (The said that due to the increasing number of reviews will only be published similar opinions in Urdu.</seg>
<seg id="10">Moment screen to select Urdu and pressing the alt+shift key board will be)</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Taliban will be given the opportunity</seg>
<seg id="2">basit Peshawar</seg>
<seg id="3">You will wake up if the Taliban began to take real Jihad who zbh the innocent people.</seg>
<seg id="4">The jla-eega schools for girls?</seg>
<seg id="5">It wasn&apos;t paid ransom kidnapping for ransom or who ltka-eega poles Monday by calling the American spy?</seg>
<seg id="6">The so much damage to the Taliban Islam as a religion or any nation did not benefit.</seg>
<seg id="7">ror Pashtun</seg>
<seg id="8">Kohat Pakistan</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The scholars were working together to attack Israel threatened only if you will see how much trouble her father of Israel and the United States</seg>
<seg id="2">It should be a real war is not only a ceasefire but also advisors will be.</seg>
<seg id="3">But what should have been a lot of heart and liver our Muslim rulers.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Ahmad said that the reason that you will begin conversion of your bravery in the forum are very talked about.</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">On the one hand the United States has said that it would try to &quot; Jang &quot;, a woman</seg>
<seg id="2">On the other hand on a UN resolution approving the resolution is not practical, but both the meanings, has come to the United Nations in a bid to crush the Muslims have been warring.</seg>
<seg id="3">Membership of the United Nations to all the Muslim countries should immediately end the Turi and they should start to his international organization.</seg>
<seg id="4">There are many examples in front of us, where the US and the UN resolutions were only about and there have been only loss of the Muslims.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It has benefited the delusions when something is not to print the BBC</seg>
<seg id="2">The entire journalistic principles which were buried unjustly blood flowed particularly the impartiality of the BBC Raho if it is to have ridden.</seg>
<seg id="3">In view of its standard bearer of one&apos;s right</seg>
<seg id="4">Some of the spread of the time, then it is the limit of meanness so that they do not print reviews</seg>
<seg id="5">The Muslims.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">He has so much difference between Jews and the Jewish state, killing Muslims and their release to the Muslims as you have asked the Muslims</seg>
<seg id="2">[syja 786]</seg>
<seg id="3">Sometimes suicide attacks in the forums for a long period of BBC a certain sect under the pretext of terrorism in India is often targeted</seg>
<seg id="4">This is the word of Islam and reviews</seg>
<seg id="5">But who is as well as the lgaskte review of the situation in which you to write about it fixes Against Iran ftoa of infidelity.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">When we think that the Muslims should not be Dajjal than the sword.</seg>
<seg id="2">Do not tears of blood to the heart by Israeli bombing of unarmed people but you do?</seg>
<seg id="3">But the murder and ravage the fault is a basic and which we give the name of jihad and beautiful prkalk face of Islam tries to get.</seg>
<seg id="4">The majority of Palestinians acknowledged the existence of Israel if the need that Hamas fired rockets on Israel or suicide attacks.</seg>
<seg id="5">Behavior inhuman from both sides.</seg>
<seg id="6">[UN&apos;s nzraia supporting characters and then the Israeli atrocities.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">God has a capacity of aum^h Muslims, amen,</seg>
<seg id="2">And the Nobel Prize in this painful to the muhim terror acts of terrorism as well as the real terrorists that eventually the ouhi work.</seg>
<seg id="3">If there was widespread terrorism without any mumkin and is pusht to save the day chief and who knows all the strings are shaking.</seg>
<seg id="4">The grand father Gerry in such circumstances is the only language they have been told that they have to do that.</seg>
<seg id="5">Thumb of the great leader fluttered and also does not have to pay.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The injured people die to give shrouds, medicine and money are living with you and Arab leaders.</seg>
<seg id="2">The Israeli attack, should be made?</seg>
<seg id="3">The fact is that all the Muslim countries including Saudi Arabia and slept in frmaroankhoabh against his army is not being nor any defense plans to understand the responsibility to help it has been completed.</seg>
<seg id="4">You should immediately practical steps against Israel.</seg>
<seg id="5">It means that the stoppage of petrol but unfortunately the United States and European countries.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Salutation to all the siblings!</seg>
<seg id="2">Injustice with thousands of widows and hundreds of thousands of ition to give advice to abandoning their struggle in the name of the Hamas at this time of difficulty in my opinion and is tantamount to proving a failure.</seg>
<seg id="3">Israel and its supporters are at the top of its arrogance then Musa will soon be created in their houses because the law is the nature of the United States and Israel are working in a suicide bomber in fertilizers.</seg>
<seg id="4">The intoxicated elephants in the intoxication of power does not understand.</seg>
<seg id="5">Pakistan Abu Abdullah</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Now they must take to reconcile the Hamas and Israel in order to stop the blood and turbulence.</seg>
<seg id="2">PARIS, France, Mohammad Sarfaraz</seg>
<seg id="3">Exactly sounded said.</seg>
<seg id="4">The supposed to make sure that Hamas is in fact a true and accurate percentages of &quot; jihad &quot;against the &quot; tyranny &quot;in the divine after a &quot; successful &quot;if it wants to be at least a lot of course if they want to know what had been agreed for goodness house began to be destroyed if there is no other goodness goodness.</seg>
<seg id="5">People who love of God, his Prophet, and they claim their love their religion, faith commitment to human being is part!</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It means that &quot;People of the Book&quot; jtnebhi deal after the Muslims in the world, it is trying to obliterate the God</seg>
<seg id="2">Advice Najeeb Al Rahman sa-eko lahor*, [P@KI$T@N]</seg>
<seg id="3">there is not the mtadine but they are also trying to preaching Islam</seg>
<seg id="4">It is a plot against mzhb people who are trying to wage jihad against them</seg>
<seg id="5">Will it be fought with them until the conspiracies and eliminate - but this did not mean that they are not wearing a jacket and they will be detonated gathering in</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Brothers, the msmom killer of children is destruction.</seg>
<seg id="2">But there is a request from my friends yesterday that he was not in place of finding a safe haven to the Israelis, he was so strong that they did not accept the Jews as one of the world.</seg>
<seg id="3">Neither Shiite, did not listen to the country, and they are all Jews and everything they made progress in every field.</seg>
<seg id="4">The 55 of the Islamic world is against this situation?</seg>
<seg id="5">Rear in every field and now the situation is that they were showing so that the enemy is killing them and they are waiting for death.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is necessary that all the Muslim countries should unite and work together to make lah-e action against Israel.</seg>
<seg id="2">magsi Feroz Jhang Pakistan</seg>
<seg id="3">And another good from the program, which will not recognize Israel, to let him stay with modern training and learning from China to the world and the way of development.</seg>
<seg id="4">Lands and Muslims is very close to the sources.</seg>
<seg id="5">Needs using it.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The most tragic aspect is that if the alliance in Alfatah Hamas and could not be.</seg>
<seg id="2">Great leaders like Yasser Arafat and Sheikh Yasin organizedly was killed so that &quot; jihad &quot;for the al-Aqsa Mosque to only those with weak nations of the region and that it was impossible as long as there is a way out of the Yasin and Arafat.</seg>
<seg id="3">The world is watching how are scattering Palestine after the death of these two leaders every minute</seg>
<seg id="4">And how Jewish lobby every minute a stronger and stronger stock went.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Pakistani prime minister in 1974 was the owner of the international confidence in history that all the Muslim heads with 100 percent attendance has for the first time to came under a roof.</seg>
<seg id="2">Today is being carried out in a very arduous task eighty birth anniversary is that our nation will not only help to maintain unity in their ranks to</seg>
<seg id="3">The Muslims of other conflicts as well as the establishment of the (Islamic) Commonwealth during an incomplete mission will move out?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is a jmta that is the past 50 years to flstn</seg>
<seg id="2">Those who dare to several</seg>
<seg id="3">Several times that their forgot to suffer from a bad kih and twists and pressure from the international rice</seg>
<seg id="4">And those who are taking the men in Iraq and Afghanistan and Pakistan face another Iran</seg>
<seg id="5">The ha-ef that Islam is the most because it knows that whenever he was removed only Kamil religion of Islam and Muslims and Islam will only be practical because history tells us that Islam is a father of ignorance on the straight path</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The missile and bombing strikes on the Gaza Strip by Israeli planes have been going on since December 27.</seg>
<seg id="2">These attacks more than 300 Palestinian civilians have been killed so far.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Israeli air strikes and tank after it cut off by vehicles also arrived at the Gaza border with full preparation for ground action.</seg>
<seg id="4">Violent acts by Israel and the Palestinian Authority through a unanimous resolution in an emergency meeting of the UN Security Council has demanded an immediate stop.</seg>
<seg id="5">But according to Israeli officials said they would continue their offensive in the Gaza Strip until they are not so sure that the rocket attacks on Israel must be stopped.</seg>
<seg id="6">What is your opinion of the correct to say that it is an attempt to defend the integrity of Pakistan?</seg>
<seg id="7">The international community is playing its role in this situation?</seg>
<seg id="8">Is this aggressive action is coming from the indirect elections in Israel do?</seg>
<seg id="9">What you can expect a better situation in the Middle East by taking charge of the newly elected President of the United States Barack Obama?</seg>
<seg id="10">Please note the way (The said that due to the increasing number of reviews will only be published similar opinions in Urdu.</seg>
<seg id="11">Moment screen to select Urdu and pressing the alt+shift key board will be)</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Palestine till the end of the world is the holiest site for Muslims and their safety is part of our lielazm</seg>
<seg id="2">We should also remember that it is our direction I</seg>
<seg id="3">&quot; Israel and the United States is one day due to erase the country in a bid to break the infidels and there is a problem, Lahore Sadiq Sajid</seg>
<seg id="4">&quot; When the tear are Kutty night separation;</seg>
<seg id="5">When there have been only without the&quot; Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan (prayers)</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The review publishes after searching for BBC.</seg>
<seg id="2">Secret an impression of impartiality and eventually have to keep.</seg>
<seg id="3">The BBC report is correct but it is the right way.</seg>
<seg id="4">In what is the best and the importance of the news which is to be reduced.</seg>
<seg id="5">Etc and others.</seg>
<seg id="6">Chughtai Zaheer</seg>
<seg id="7">In this skill now our Pakistani electronic and print media and columnists, especially chndardoakhbarat and there is no one left behind by the increase in the coverage of extremism and terrorism on the Muawiah ho-ee&apos;bghz or write to give weight to well short &quot;</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The United Nations said that apparently to discuss human rights and peace are Muslims but the extent of terror and compulsion and these words are available to listen to his face that Hamas to stop attacks when the coalition policy.</seg>
<seg id="2">Why so much on the Muslims are oppressed people had the support of the Jews in America would provide Almighty God leaves it clearly said that most of the nation should pass shameless nation and the people who can not life be right if the United States is encouraged and supported by the chhordo valve then to see if the life of his fortune</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This was the killings and plundering in the name of so-called judges and the peace of the world to clearly understand that peace in the world to provide justice can only be established by the barrier injustice and genocide.</seg>
<seg id="2">If the genocide there may be an end to the nation and the results of its own choice of Jews then can be obtained by Adolf Hitler of not only the continued existence but a kind of its height is impossible today.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to a poet</seg>
<seg id="4">Oppression phrzlm grows it is erases</seg>
<seg id="5">Blood phrkhon falls is it consolidates</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Who will tell them what is terrorism?</seg>
<seg id="2">What does not come to the zumre terror in all its kiuon just as they are linked to all</seg>
<seg id="3">The other people do not have enough human or at the muslmanon khuon khuon surkh did not have a lot of color m&apos;suomon</seg>
<seg id="4">And now not anywhere from a condolence message to kiuon?</seg>
<seg id="5">I have seen the Mumbai attacks such as this in my own house caught fire and sorrow that the people do not go and see what the sorrow that we do not see any such ideas with some muslman</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The road, showing the bodies and injured many innocent faces drowned in blood will condemn the words are not available</seg>
<seg id="2">It is coming to the helplessness of the Muslims that the people have been killed in India when they ascend the world runs on a proof that we do not take any action</seg>
<seg id="3">And on the other hand Israel is manslaughtering of the Muslim world is intolerable and quiet</seg>
<seg id="4">In a late - God tyranny and when it will end the lawlessness.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">A hazard to the integrity of the United States and Israel as a joke.</seg>
<seg id="2">As far as the election was taking action will be taken over power to a public acceptance of any suspicion is not particularly Barack Obama like the rest of the state of Israel is evident that did not go so far and there will be no government policy against American imperialism is black and Caucasian is imperialism.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is evident from the discussion at the forum that the pain of death of Benazir Bhutto is to everyone but it was not a mistake as politicians.</seg>
<seg id="2">The debate has demanded that she died due to the power or democracy.</seg>
<seg id="3">&quot; If you have a loved so as to why U.S. clearance and the deal could be left ten years of dictatorship in Pakistan?</seg>
<seg id="4">Be it did not come to Pakistan with the &apos;oam dictatorship when needed and unfortunately it came to Pakistan when he was in power and promised to acquit trials</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Risen rose to a man who criticized the accusations and they are just not saying anything else.</seg>
<seg id="2">Praise Khan</seg>
<seg id="3">Some of them are ignoring this thinking that it can not be him.</seg>
<seg id="4">Another reader</seg>
<seg id="5">Respectable history. You might not only in Pakistan but also (head) and about your four friendly countries have also read out in seven other countries might have been linked to the right of sa-eiko.</seg>
<seg id="6">Ayaz Tariq</seg>
<seg id="7">&quot;The Health of that there is no adorned with education</seg>
<seg id="8">It was not the rest of the green cypress tree in a way that the &quot;</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Britain never did not allow them to be invented a Hindu-Muslim dispute and Sir Sayyad development.</seg>
<seg id="2">sa-eko</seg>
<seg id="3">The merciless how our own nation and at the time of writing ode to his party is going blind but has now increased to a historic intellectuals and men have criticized the accusations that only if it is not saying anything else.</seg>
<seg id="4">The people we have made progress.</seg>
<seg id="5">Praise Khan</seg>
<seg id="6">Some of them are ignoring this thinking that they can not be - like the donkey books are not a burden Alam</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Although the Mumbai have disrupted in the ongoing negotiations between India and Pakistan after the attack but the India-Pakistan talks should continue.</seg>
<seg id="2">If they will talk about the human losses of lives from both sides.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to Indian city Mumbai Pakistan is caught in a letter to Urdu and it also has sent by writing to Pakistan but on the other hand when India first caught the extremist then said that this is a great engineer but afterwards they are looking at it as the only four parties.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">First of all you brandished auspicious Christmas to all Christians Sahib and friends of the forum.</seg>
<seg id="2">Companions of the Forum: sa-eiko.  Raza, a twin sister, praise, &quot; Shahida Akram manners and all.</seg>
<seg id="3">&quot; We want a peace but not the flame of war!</seg>
<seg id="4">The itself is a problem</seg>
<seg id="5">Wage War solution to the problem will be</seg>
<seg id="6">Fire and blood will today</seg>
<seg id="7">Appetite and need to be held tomorrow</seg>
<seg id="8">The intelligent people</seg>
<seg id="9">The then it is a better off</seg>
<seg id="10">Are you in our courtyard and</seg>
<seg id="11">Candle is burning then it is better</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">India relations between the United States has been very strong and we know that the United States in Pakistan&apos;s troubled times to defraud.</seg>
<seg id="2">It is also the tarih of the United States.</seg>
<seg id="3">The United States in case of an attack on its objectives will be achieved and the cost will be.</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that Pakistan should announce clear that we will not launch aggression but it could compromise peace and war will not come until the woman was destroyed completely by India or the reason for this is not occupied for this we ourselves will not be destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="5">This is an Islamic history.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistani people and army before the resolution was to ensure that the message has given.</seg>
<seg id="2">After being hit with a clever party Indian efforts to achieve this extraordinary diplomatic and military benefits at the cost of mmbi attacks against the very initial that&apos;s why international action is now reduced international pressure on Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="3">The riots in India is unnecessary and expressed satisfaction over the interview of Pakistan and the United Nations diplomacy with too much to praise the efforts of the Pakistani side of the pool &quot; affect &quot;.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">On this matter if there is no two opinions that this is a very brutal action.</seg>
<seg id="2">But the question is that when they were attacked the village of Samiullah Monday when thousands of Taliban where the Pakistan Army and did what they were doing?</seg>
<seg id="3">Do not military accountable for what they should be carried out within a year?</seg>
<seg id="4">Everyday people that the number of mortar and cannon bombard do many of them have been killed in Taliban?</seg>
<seg id="5">&quot; I appeal to the ISI for God&apos;s presence that after the Taliban left and we have given to live peacefully in Swat as an example.</seg>
<seg id="6">The operations were closed.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is not a UN resolution on the day when the military intervention would be in Pakistan when it was launched near jisejma&apos;talda&apos;ot.</seg>
<seg id="2">Riyaz Ahmed Farooqi</seg>
<seg id="3">I then our protector extremist and all the evidence and reason for the action against him are being continuously and God forbid, he also presented a resolution if there is any possibility that the voice of the United Nations will not increase our right,</seg>
<seg id="4">The deceased was supposedly being passed a resolution then in power in some other than the United States to help themselves ascend it will run.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The personality and the achievements of Samiullah Monday experience and knowledge that has not made its activities.</seg>
<seg id="2">It was not a revolutionary.</seg>
<seg id="3">The way comrade che Guerra, akbrkhan Nawab Bugti, Dr Najeeb Ullah.  have suffered at the hands of the desecration of the bodies of the enemies of the Revolutionaries.</seg>
<seg id="4">He died after you have made.</seg>
<seg id="5">But here, an international game to play here and frightening people in solitude and ferociousness have ruled.</seg>
<seg id="6">That is the reason that could be developed that we would not be a wild beast will occupy and by the government.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The so-called Muslim movement in the name of religion is highly condemnable.</seg>
<seg id="2">The cruelty of the supporters of these extremists have been shown to him but he instead of grieving over the brutal actions such as this would be the tribal traditions and it has been avoided.</seg>
<seg id="3">Gown aor and left-hander of tribal traditions are sometimes with no justification for such a brutal action by the name of Islam can not be.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In my opinion of our army has met with them.</seg>
<seg id="2">He said this when a copy moves you so much time, you have to be taim enough to catch him but he will have to arrive at the scene and if there is also the sneaks it away.</seg>
<seg id="3">Are these people are brave enough to do that seventy fifty people hostage and our forces supported the victim as spectators on hand.</seg>
<seg id="4">He is a man of God and the army.</seg>
<seg id="5">It is clear that it is a black lentils in.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Religious extremism dictator Ziaul Haq, at the time of the dictatorship really highlighting the qualities of mercifulness and krimi of Fiza that should be setup of fear and terror in the name of religion with reference to the troubles and &apos;brton looks like a dead body in its literature and to display the &quot; and will make books such as &quot;who died after being created fear and terror.</seg>
<seg id="2">And as a tool or the fear and terror in order to only halva worldly mandh grandeur and they are being used for weapons.</seg>
<seg id="3">&quot; oa&apos;zo!</seg>
<seg id="4">The fire to frighten the hell where you</seg>
<seg id="5">The situation of fear &quot;]</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">I am amazed when it was revealed that the work can be a Muslim.</seg>
<seg id="2">&quot; We ourselves are ignorant of the history or expediently they are forgiven.</seg>
<seg id="3">When they closed the doors of the Prophet daughter who made the refusal after a meeting of the fealty Nazar fire and rope put your complaint in her husband had to drag?</seg>
<seg id="4">How did it come from?</seg>
<seg id="5">The charges are and what was the Battle of Karbala of Yazid army Madina on the Jews and Hindus?</seg>
<seg id="6">Incentives without a recognised facts are not only be countered.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Close valve policy and BBC.</seg>
<seg id="2">It hit super title over the subject: &quot; He had to face the legitimate or illegitimate Bush?</seg>
<seg id="3">&quot;It should be</seg>
<seg id="4">Tahir of Japan,</seg>
<seg id="5">In some friends feel ashamed a man was hanged after the pole from the grave as he raised his voice against terror, and it is the subject of box office.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Operation for the success of shirdl and on the other side of the border is dependent on the success of the operation of the center line of the ordinary people who are in the right.</seg>
<seg id="2">The move is the US and Pakistani agencies and they have this conspiracy Peer Sahib.</seg>
<seg id="3">The forum is reviewing the Taliban will be based on the opposition because it has been successfully contained in a secret Taliban and that they are taking the public opinion could change.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">&quot; I just have to ask the cha nga when the body for an entire day hanged what forces were conducting a banana to target only public statement that there are too many places like I do on the bombing of the hin&apos;talban prgolhgrnese home, 2 children and their mother died on the spot. &quot;</seg>
<seg id="2">Does he not know about the Chowk?</seg>
<seg id="3">Or he was witnessing a show?</seg>
<seg id="4">The imploringly and requested that the game supplication to God is closed.</seg>
<seg id="5">Finally there is also a government on top of you.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The sthit is looking for whatever it is reasonable to question asked by the BBC, unfortunately not to ask any question whether the present 30,000 troops to Swat had gone to do?</seg>
<seg id="2">The bodies of those who fought all day with the help of the Taliban army is hanging on electric poles.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Pakistani military Swati Unlucky with people who sleeps did, but also the media including the BBC ignorant of the fact it after the world has not cured.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Pakistani military drama.</seg>
<seg id="5">A child of Swat that it is said that this is a bloody drama.</seg>
<seg id="6">For God&apos;s will end after drama.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The name of the Taliban.</seg>
<seg id="2">The entire world if they are not a true Muslim msalman said if the place is available to terrorists in the region.</seg>
<seg id="3">The dishonorable with a hard work that does not have the gun is among the group.</seg>
<seg id="4">Islamabad has not come up with a gun and the sword of force.</seg>
<seg id="5">Feel ashamed.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The reason for this is not in any religion in a family tradition.</seg>
<seg id="2">The media including the BBC about his comment from different tribes and Taliban sources</seg>
<seg id="3">But none of the actual situation is that he does not know the exact situation is what we know about hhin because we are the tribal people.</seg>
<seg id="4">mkhtsra That there is a game in which the CIA and Mossad, RAW, including our own ISI has no Talib pidakrdh are not the tribal miscreants elements of the Taliban, adaros Islam, as a nation, Pashtun tribes, and slandering the tribal traditions.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Nonsense shame for all Muslims from the leader of the movement has gone.</seg>
<seg id="2">I salutation in the leadership of the PPP and the altf of MQM leader Hussein against this cancer is to speak against the Taliban.</seg>
<seg id="3">This cancer is a product of Ziaul Haq to you, but Pakistan was also destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="4">But I am hopeful that the leadership would be taken to end the cancer.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">India said that after the Mumbai attacks at the hands of extremist elements behind the attacks.</seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan denied the allegations and said that the investigation would help in every way.</seg>
<seg id="3">India has said that he has given Pakistan a list contains the names of the suspected extremists, the foundation has given that he is willing to India.</seg>
<seg id="4">The president said that Maulana Masood Azhar and Jaish Muhammad included in this list is not detained and there is no information about the government of Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="5">President of Asif Ali Zardari earlier rejected the impression that Western intelligence agencies and the Indian government provided evidence relating to the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
<seg id="6">The zrdrai stated that the Kasab Ajmal now could not prove that they are Pakistanis.</seg>
<seg id="7">The Prime Minister Man Mohan Singh has warned that relations between Pakistan and India to it until it can not be better for the country will be used for terrorism.</seg>
<seg id="8">The latest developments in India and Pakistan cricket team has cancelled.</seg>
<seg id="9">The influence of these political events should be made?</seg>
<seg id="10">The future of dikhtehin relations between Pakistan and the hndstan?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The United States will not break Pakistan or India.</seg>
<seg id="2">The Pakistani team to Pakistan to break.</seg>
<seg id="3">Are you so much provincialism and communalism and religious extremism;.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Jinnah with Muslims of India did not have proved the treatment.</seg>
<seg id="5">Chicago yasmin</seg>
<seg id="6">Mohtarma had been working on it.  vision of Jinnah provincialism, not frqaoarit cancer spreads and religious extremism in Pakistan nor there are treated with Muslims in India.</seg>
<seg id="7">But it is a mistake by a leader like him can be created.</seg>
<seg id="8">&quot; We respect their heroes if you can not</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Competencies are mostly in the region.</seg>
<seg id="2">God knows when to be wise and with the blessing of the region will develop harmony.</seg>
<seg id="3">The two annexed pandit, Shiv Sena, the Taliban, the RSS, and others were being made against the law.</seg>
<seg id="4">The djali forces do not want peace in the region will develop these countries are so thin the dance.</seg>
<seg id="5">What you can imagine what the world in this area of Pakistan and India will be in harmony with China.</seg>
<seg id="6">&quot; The problem is that of robbers and thieves stole rope have imposed on the leader of the nation.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">May God grant that our country Pakistan has never at a loss, amen.</seg>
<seg id="2">But please.  situation and ground realities of opening his eyes look around and you will see that they reached the US forces.</seg>
<seg id="3">Important issues and it is not correct, NWFP, the situation in Balochistan and Sindh are with you.</seg>
<seg id="4">In this situation needs to be a leader in the country so that we can become a united nation.</seg>
<seg id="5">&quot; The O God! Rahmat said.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">There is no way out for the last one in my opinion.</seg>
<seg id="2">He was just too.</seg>
<seg id="3">Now the matter or to walk across.</seg>
<seg id="4">The insincere by deceit for these talks can not be resolved.</seg>
<seg id="5">Neither grdion terrorism in the country are from one another.</seg>
<seg id="6">The European countries have also set at rest after the last great battle.</seg>
<seg id="7">And the world is not a war even if all of them are still doing so that Pakistan and India.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It was agreed on almost all the political parties that he wanted to end terrorism and sectarianism in the country.</seg>
<seg id="2">But our sincere to the military leadership is not seen, the United States and Europe are being given assurances that on one hand we are with you in this war on terror on the other side of the Taliban as they secretly.</seg>
<seg id="3">We are still to think and to identify their direction and choose the path of only one thanks,</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">There is no doubt in the fact that the majority consists of Jamat ud Dawa are members of the Lashkar-e-Tayiba after being declared null and void the Lashkar-e-Tayiba joined the party in the name of Jamat ud Dawa, he was Pakistan</seg>
<seg id="2">But after that those who preferred to the relief work and now their insistence on the strength of India has also declared null and void and the government of Pakistan has also been a crackdown against them.</seg>
<seg id="3">In my opinion if they leave the militant religious extremism and religious groups and upheld it better.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The dhshtgr organizations in Pakistan who have professional criminals Paul people in the name of jihad and the mlaoaun of these people are &quot; very &quot;unclean what the station said that Pakistan is doing well.</seg>
<seg id="2">Such a Pakistan is not to destroy it.</seg>
<seg id="3">Convert actually is not entitled to you as a human being.</seg>
<seg id="4">National security is cleared by the rebels to Pakistan would be in danger.</seg>
<seg id="5">What is still to think that it will not restrict the disturbances that?</seg>
<seg id="6">In this world of strong mlaoaun position that it does not work to carry out the assassination.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Heart of this news is crumbled.</seg>
<seg id="2">What kind of a world where religion of Islam and an important member of that today it is difficult to live in the world for naming.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Muslims killed Muslims but it can also take revenge if Muslim rulers try hypocrite if all its along with the non-Muslim world together with having a true and sincere religious feelings that are treated with our great leader Hafiz Saeed.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">India for the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan has created bitterness in relations and severe blow to the improvement in relations between the two countries have in recent years.</seg>
<seg id="3">India and Pakistan army continuously active in the country is responsible for an armed groups</seg>
<seg id="4">And to come back on a normal relationship is being done to take action against these groups.</seg>
<seg id="5">The Indian security agencies to be directly responsible for the Mumbai attacks Lashkar-e-Tayiba</seg>
<seg id="6">The forum also repeatedly called Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah aha! &quot;.</seg>
<seg id="7">This is not the first time that a serious relationship between the two countries because of an act of terrorism in India.</seg>
<seg id="8">The two neighbors after the attack on the Indian Parliament on December in 2001 reached the edge of war.</seg>
<seg id="9">After that, the ban on Lashkar-e-Tayiba in 2002 were included in the list of terror groups.</seg>
<seg id="10">The Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah Security, on which analysts say that actually there is a new form of Lashkar-e-Tayiba, is requested restriction.</seg>
<seg id="11">In my opinion should be banned group you want it or not?</seg>
<seg id="12">What needs to take decisive action against extremist groups operating on its soil for Pakistan?</seg>
<seg id="13">Is the present ban has been imposed on Jama&apos;at-ud-Da&apos;wah.</seg>
<seg id="14">Clean crisis may put off and how it is necessary to stop armed groups for a permanent peace between the two countries?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It has banned Jamat ud Dawa what the Security Council, according to the UN Security Council evidence which shows he did so much haste?</seg>
<seg id="2">The Security Council is not always show readiness against Muslims?</seg>
<seg id="3">Say that was evident in slow!</seg>
<seg id="4">You will find themselves if India has become a failed state!</seg>
<seg id="5">The intelligence, the army and other security agencies have failed, Naach that the tripartite for 72 hours at the hands of the terrorists were dancing and benefit fraud is to keep Pakistan in the world after the failure of its own.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It will be an infidel] have been killed in the world is a repeat the standard?</seg>
<seg id="2">The country is non-political, mzbhi organization, the Khidmat-e-Khalq.</seg>
<seg id="3">Faisalabad, Furqan Farooq</seg>
<seg id="4">The Prophet (our) saints, Sad saints and gave the love and respect for all human beings, well over the religion of Islam and peace and fierier are flourishing.</seg>
<seg id="5">The Muslims also made in every field.</seg>
<seg id="6">It is a religion of religious extremism mgrjb ascended the gap began in toansanon and infidel believer and a new chapter of the Fitna contradiction and began to open the first was not aware of the world.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Salutation.  She will have to do.  practice but it will take action on their own strength.</seg>
<seg id="2">After coming under pressure from the United States.</seg>
<seg id="3">If there is a problem for India to provide evidence don&apos;t?</seg>
<seg id="4">Why does not give it?</seg>
<seg id="5">That is why put on all of us?</seg>
<seg id="6">&quot; The extremist organizations and groups have also setup, why don&apos;t the ban on the people?</seg>
<seg id="7">&quot; What we are a terrorist in the world?</seg>
<seg id="8">What is that India is doing in Kashmir?</seg>
<seg id="9">What Israel is doing that?</seg>
<seg id="10">The truth is that we are the first nuclear Islamic state, which is why it is a problem.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan is now in its final stages.</seg>
<seg id="2">kamranhassan ABU DHABI</seg>
<seg id="3">His statement and wants a similar situation is also evident</seg>
<seg id="4">The new map of Pakistan with the U.S. dhrle journals have now has begun the cycle and published in this series too strict restrictions are there.</seg>
<seg id="5">US slowly but as far as Pakistan is strengthening its grip on.</seg>
<seg id="6">In that case if the harmony and unity of the people as a nation we did not demonstrate remember if you can make Bangladesh and then it may be too much.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Terrorist attacks as much to condemn it was low, even if it is in the Marriott Hotel in Mumbai and hotel in Islamabad and or in Palestine.</seg>
<seg id="2">This is also the terrorists where you want to eliminate them whether they are Pakistan, India and the United States and Israel.</seg>
<seg id="3">Now the question arise daily that Pakistan is a terrorist attack, hundreds of people have been killed, why the world is silent with Pakistani officials on them?</seg>
<seg id="4">What went on the attack on the Marriott hotel wasn&apos;t terrorists?</seg>
<seg id="5">Then why.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">You sacrifice for the welfare of one&apos;s. Home Advisor mosuof Rahman Mashallah, Malik was and how those brave!</seg>
<seg id="2">According to the BBC &quot;(where) has a committee of the UN Security Council banned Jamat ud Dawa., Malik said that we have not been imposed and there will be a very close attention after</seg>
<seg id="3">The Malik.  According to the BBC has termed the impression being violently wrong that the arrest of terrorists to say &quot;no &quot; to be taken.</seg>
<seg id="4">Hey subhan, Allah!</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">To be or not to have to say this or that it does not like.</seg>
<seg id="2">The Pakistani team is that we are fighting.</seg>
<seg id="3">That is why our own bcha-ebge and after that we have made every effort.</seg>
<seg id="4">There is no power of interfering in domestic affairs.</seg>
<seg id="5">He apparently of settlements.</seg>
<seg id="6">This is expected to justice to the people and insisted on the implementation of the US independent judiciary should respect the democratic institutions and the military dictator or not to help the developing world and then peace will be established in Pakistan and that the coalition would not be accepted.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan has maintained the same obedience of European and American interests.</seg>
<seg id="2">This is in spite of opposition from the control of the population of the country.</seg>
<seg id="3">The rival jzbat raised more to it.</seg>
<seg id="4">If the United States and its allied democracy is confident it will be given to the settlement of ho-eeas respect for state sovereignty region except behaviour.</seg>
<seg id="5">There is so much ability in Pakistan itself as well as mslhh or mslhh.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Pakistani security forces in Kashmir has been under the administration of the camp raided an alleged Lashkar-e-Tayiba null and void.</seg>
<seg id="2">Mumbai is increasing pressure on Pakistan after the attacks to speed up action against extremist organizations.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is alleged that the Indian side of the Lashkar-e-Tayiba attacks in Mumbai.</seg>
<seg id="4">US Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice has said that the Pakistani leadership Mumbai should be a practical demonstration of transparency and immediate action against those responsible for the attacks.</seg>
<seg id="5">He said the attack on krneoale extremists used the Mumbai.</seg>
<seg id="6">The Peshawar armed persons of another truck had been carrying relief goods to the authorities say that the US troops deployed in Afghanistan is set on fire trucks were destroyed in which more than fifty.</seg>
<seg id="7">NATO during eight hours and forty in Peshawar is the second attack on a US supply.</seg>
<seg id="8">In the Pakistan has raided a camp of the outlawed Lashkar-e-Tayiba and armed groups in the tribal region Karachi even before it has tried many of them unarmed and compensation to those who return weapons and any action to do so.</seg>
<seg id="9">In Afghanistan say that the intervention of the former Soviet Union during the period of Gen Ziaul Haq and various armed groups of resistance begins with American and Saudi funding has come to an end to the efforts being taken back to 1980 environment has not been successful.</seg>
<seg id="10">The question is: does want to do so? &quot;</seg>
<seg id="11">What to do so that Pakistan has been able to do?</seg>
<seg id="12">What do you say?</seg>
<seg id="13">The description click here will be</seg>
<seg id="14">Please note the way (The said that due to the increasing number of reviews will only be published similar opinions in Urdu.</seg>
<seg id="15">Moment screen to select Urdu and pressing the alt+shift key board will be)</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">I am with the whole of mankind only one question:</seg>
<seg id="2">If your child killer then they will come after you have lost your channel with it, it is impossible</seg>
<seg id="3">Saeed Multan</seg>
<seg id="4">The question of whether you my knowledge to the east and west of Islamic teachings, or any logic, innocent people in the US attack argument and philosophy, including labor and devout person will be allowed to salaried employees of the poor?</seg>
<seg id="5">If the answer is not in dire need of reform if you have your view.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This was the time when it was feared that the people of Pakistan and Afghanistan will go bust and Russia were armed people.</seg>
<seg id="2">Now when it is feared that the United States and afnstan ascend to run the country and the current President Bush during his presidential campaign has publicly expressed then why should we be unarmed people?</seg>
<seg id="3">There is no way so that the Pakistan Army resistance after defeating the United States and India did not have to suffer?</seg>
<seg id="4">Yes No if it is involved in terrorism activities with Pakistan only if any action would be taken against him.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">But unfortunately it has the right to doale India to become a Lashkar-e-Tayiba of the government of Pakistan is involved in it.</seg>
<seg id="2">Advice Najeeb Al Rahman sa-eko lahor*, [P@KI$T@N]</seg>
<seg id="3">You will agree that the Lashkar-e-Tayiba is implicated Pakistan even if the government does not have the right to be charged.</seg>
<seg id="4">There is also a question whether any government or non-government aid of these terrorists received the official Indian wasn&apos;t?</seg>
<seg id="5">Is it a terrorist act was born in Pakistan or India and other countries in the world and they aren&apos;t ready?</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the United States to end the Saudi fndg campaign will start on that date for God&apos;s after he wrapped up to clean the polluted zhr that have made to our society.</seg>
<seg id="2">Ask him and he will demonstrate that the United States and Saudi ethics virus spread of dangerous weapons and so-called abominable mgrhqiqta jihadi literature and culture in our country, which are slaughtered human box in our country.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Pakistan army after the announcement of the danger of attack by India that it pull out forces from the Afghan border should pay attention to India and the announcement of the Taliban to the Afghan border and snbhalinge US was badly staggered all its forced that India would not attack on Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="2">All of the US forces in the region because it was exposed.</seg>
<seg id="3">Although neither India nor threatened to attack there is so much courage.</seg>
<seg id="4">Attacks by the Taliban left on over ksr US supply.</seg>
<seg id="5">Proved to Pakistan without support from the United States and Pakistan does not.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Business financial hub of Dubai is in poor areas.</seg>
<seg id="2">Empty handed out hundreds of thousands of the withdrawal, but it has been missing since the rule of law in Karachi on the western border region of sbon.</seg>
<seg id="3">They follow the kidnapping of the city.</seg>
<seg id="4">For the first time the Pakhtoon Pathans, has said that the people of the city have been fighting for a stranger, even though unity is needed.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The solution of the problem is that if either learned Urdu speaking Pashtu, Urdu and Pashto speaker or learned English and they are all good.</seg>
<seg id="2">Are you certainly aren&apos;t ridiculous in a collision with a suggestion as ridiculous gelikn?</seg>
<seg id="3">This is the reason why the language?</seg>
<seg id="4">Chughtai Zaheer</seg>
<seg id="5">I actually this proposal to my colleagues were among the people of all religious and linguistic groups, often in childhood people had laughed on these issues.</seg>
<seg id="6">At the same time that the religious and linguistic hatred today was not only a great and was being secretly PICIC.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Doesn&apos;t so as to why and what is it?</seg>
<seg id="2">Are these signs of disaster?</seg>
<seg id="3">In which case he is innocent and killing innocent?</seg>
<seg id="4">Reasons sbke are on the way to break into pieces to Pakistan and that they are doing all that neither his country nor is there any religion.</seg>
<seg id="5">The House in Karachi and Mumbai has caught fire lamps in the house.</seg>
<seg id="6">The government is set only after earning in the name of the name change, as the airport road, Benazir Bhutto, all ngz blood.</seg>
<seg id="7">What is the meaning of Karachi and she is being held by the people of Pakistan?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Mumbai fail to prove the best start of linguistic riots in Karachi at the RAW Ain Urooj attacks Monday that RAW in past ruin the political elements who has resigned from his job.</seg>
<seg id="2">Blood was speaking in Pashto hard work and Sui was unjustly Indian threats from Karachi to Khyber have wakened to Pakistanism.</seg>
<seg id="3">The full political, religious, linguistic and even the reaction of patriotism and national parties which has dried diplomatic norms to another round of musical instruments and the US plan also provides.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In darmthdh in Karachi and the responsibility of the administration and partiality is using.</seg>
<seg id="2">The management will be able to control the situation in 1 hour but John bojhh is doing it is aired</seg>
<seg id="3">Police prsiasi ranger and not to act because of pressure from the party.</seg>
<seg id="4">Matters of the alliance are limited only by their own statements, the political parties should work for the interests of the common man of abandoning.</seg>
<seg id="5">The political pressure on the administration will remain mzidjnm such incidents, &quot; God protected her.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Terrorist in my opinion this is the biggest.</seg>
<seg id="2">And of course there are no foreign forces operating there but not know who is that?</seg>
<seg id="3">But unfortunately this is that if there are any such situation in the border city of if but when the government is doing it otherwise in the NWFP government is helpless.</seg>
<seg id="4">The government here that the operation would be a big and important cities of the country and protect them from terrorism.</seg>
<seg id="5">If a major financial crisis in the country will face.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">BBC Urdu frightingly as it is not true and the Pakistani media and too thin.</seg>
<seg id="2">The BBC is true in English.</seg>
<seg id="3">The solution of the problem is that if either learned Urdu speaking Pashtu, Urdu and Pashto speaker or learned English and they are all good.</seg>
<seg id="4">How will surely you think a ridiculous proposal but what the cause of the accident is not ridiculous?</seg>
<seg id="5">This is the reason why the language?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In another story of savagery in Karachi had eventually been feeling was written by a long period of every citizen.</seg>
<seg id="2">It was right where he did not leave any stone fifty percent are rpotin the media here that has been in four days.</seg>
<seg id="3">Previous three nights you wake up and there are still krgzarin.</seg>
<seg id="4">Killing saddlers and peanuts vacating the hotel.</seg>
<seg id="5">Plundering on Super Highway and ears cut all the innocent is unaware of &apos;zab to God that it would ever come to it.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Do you think the reasons for the sudden peace is bad?</seg>
<seg id="2">(BBC)</seg>
<seg id="3">The reason to seek the disorder in Karachi and Mumbai ravage frighten was giving the diveeing for any of us do not need it very straight and easier but this is the reason that the disorder has been unknowingly only because of the &quot;authlputhl &quot; blood.</seg>
<seg id="4">Zahir said that if there is any problem with the &quot; father &quot;will try to get out of his son &quot;self &quot; out of control, it will not be a marvel of.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Blood Liaquat Ali Khan and is also the devotees of a lion wrote this is the wrong time of Mr. fimi krnekel-ee sa-eko.</seg>
<seg id="2">We will repeat the elderly of tradition</seg>
<seg id="3">Made to save the dying and later died.</seg>
<seg id="4">Beneficence Tausif Siddiqui</seg>
<seg id="5">Much behind all over the country, it is a fact that we have risked and the ogriban side.</seg>
<seg id="6">Siddiqui.  request is that if the wikipedia.</seg>
<seg id="7">What Liaquat Ali Khan to see if you know that were related to a respectable Punjabi family Karnal in the areas of Punjab.</seg>
<seg id="8">Because of the steps taken for the refugees to refugee their counts.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">There are a response to the hr&apos;ml.</seg>
<seg id="2">You can afford it but it does.</seg>
<seg id="3">Ijaz Awan</seg>
<seg id="4">before you also have been collected during the milling crowd of kndgan, the proposal said you go to the original roguery nshanian opened the wall chalking and on the walls of Karachi are also being provided in the form of posters.</seg>
<seg id="5">bdm&apos;ashian The bear is coming from both.</seg>
<seg id="6">However the rascals and the founder of Pakistan did not even Pir Bakhsh, they did not have any action.</seg>
<seg id="7">At the heart of Pakistan has been the opposite daal heart.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">As far as a Muslim League (N) he also handed over to the draft amendment at the eighteenth.</seg>
<seg id="2">Prior to the MQM and the Muslim League Q have deposited in the National Assembly and Senate amendment draft of the eighteenth.</seg>
<seg id="3">So far it seems that there is a political msdode and eighteenth the amendment is not sincere toward approving the amendment.</seg>
<seg id="4">This is the reason that so far no one has not excite oaoilh in favour of the amendment on the floor of the House and Senate or is forced to approve the amendment.</seg>
<seg id="5">It seems that has swept erased from gongloaun parties to submit the draft amendment of the eighteenth was able to say that this is the other day that the government has appointed the amendment process.</seg>
<seg id="6">It is an ally of the MQM, Muslim League (N) behind the curtain of the government and a close ally Pakistan Muslim League-Nawaz Group Q seventeenth amendments are sincere then I will be able to end the seventeenth amendment to the party.</seg>
<seg id="7">This has made the color is dictating the names of martyrs.</seg>
<seg id="8">If the amendment is not the same seventeenth fast.</seg>
<seg id="9">If you forget any thoughts of cutting his hand.</seg>
<seg id="10">The zrdari is the seventeenth president and there is no amendment.</seg>
<seg id="11">This was the opinion of the majority and is also true in a survey.</seg>
<seg id="12">If the amendment is seventeenth or zrdari if the president does not suffer.</seg>
<seg id="13">Now they are the most powerful man President Pervez Musharraf as he is also the chairman of the party as well as its president.</seg>
<seg id="14">As long as he is president of seventeenth amendments.</seg>
<seg id="15">Parliament President zrdari the first amendment to end the seventeenth political parties will be presided over by the see-off.</seg>
<seg id="16">It does not like other parties or the MQM.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The old man of our family has links with the working class</seg>
<seg id="2">And when we see our childhood, an uncle and maternal uncle and wages if it wishes in mind that they are to avoid any physical labor wages.</seg>
<seg id="3">To avoid this and asked written a letter to the editor of daily today what we will do after matriculation that we do not have to do physical labor.</seg>
<seg id="4">The editor writes in response to the doctors and engineers and you would like these subjects.</seg>
<seg id="5">The trend was started by the anjn-erng and we also read at the matriculation technical drying instead of bialoji.</seg>
<seg id="6">But the elder brother at the time of entry into the ANC has forced to S C and F in medical treatment.</seg>
<seg id="7">The bialoji study hardly a month and when it did not importune any article of calculation has taken his revenge.</seg>
<seg id="8">Engineer we fear that there is a physical labor and now we are in a good position in many of her friends and family always thank God for us.</seg>
<seg id="9">This was the time has come to us when we were trying to raise the old rug home with his two young sons.</seg>
<seg id="10">The work was not half-an-hour younger son said that &quot;this is linked to the death toll was not there.&quot;</seg>
<seg id="11">He said if it is really very well read it and we have run away from your physical labor.</seg>
<seg id="12">Began his son to read it and I have been or will be done but this is not the mine.</seg>
<seg id="13">What should we do it in all three hours and returned home.</seg>
<seg id="14">The saying is that if a person has to be destination whichever is the reason behind it since then we can not put an end to it.</seg>
<seg id="15">Yes if you do not know what to do if you are only Allah Hafiz.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">He said that he would not have turned out to be lost but what we do on the first anniversary of Benazir Bhutto as can be seen in the evil.</seg>
<seg id="2">Benazir and to provide a list of Indian Sikhs fighting the war of independence because its interests on one side crushed the freedom movement of the Sikhs and on the other hand the opportunity to pay attention to the pressing the movement to Punjab and Kashmir to India.</seg>
<seg id="3">rshh Killing of bintir of power and Nawaz Sharif is a part of history that pushed the country several years backwards.</seg>
<seg id="4">Be exile in Kashmir and continued negative statements on its nuclear program.</seg>
<seg id="5">Benazir has dealt with General Musharraf while violating the agreement with the London Nawaz Sharif.</seg>
<seg id="6">Benazir Bhutto and her husband were given a chance to the United States term earning money and for the happiness she was called prsint tin</seg>
<seg id="7">His brother at the time of Benazir was murdered and has so far been killer from punishment.</seg>
<seg id="8">Be confrontation avoided the women&apos;s rights in spite of being a woman.</seg>
<seg id="9">The way of politics on the body of Benazir Bhutto as his father is now doing politics on his body widower her husband.</seg>
<seg id="10">The Benazir government but he was twice given you a case against him as political criminals of the assassination of his father could not register.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">East Pakistan became separate from us thirty seven years and the people of our rulers apathy and that no one saw that day of mourning nor did not mourn over his mistakes.</seg>
<seg id="2">It should be an example to be observed as a day of December 16 and schemes that do not have such incidents occuring again.</seg>
<seg id="3">Messages of the people of Bangladesh to send us a day and try to bring apneqrib back.</seg>
<seg id="4">The rulers of the Hamood ur Rehman has been opened the commission and would consider the separation of East Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="5">The plan to bring back the brooms and become entangled in Bangladesh and encourage them to send gifts.</seg>
<seg id="6">But we have an impassive will die in our neighborhood and now we have no news.</seg>
<seg id="7">&quot; We are worried about our siblings because we have been selfish.</seg>
<seg id="8">The event will spend the next day we are lost in our normal life.</seg>
<seg id="9">The way the eastern and western and eastern Germany as one of West Pakistan was also one can be resumed.</seg>
<seg id="10">We can only be resumed if he sacrificed for each other and they came out of the selfishness of Shell.</seg>
<seg id="11">But the desire is fulfilled in the near future.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The report said that when the US state governor has been arrested on charges of corruption Nawa-e Ali</seg>
<seg id="2">The provincial congress and to remove the gubernatorial office as soon as possible and it is prepared to resume Edit for checking accounts and then keeping an eye on the situation in Pakistan when a fellow of the American lkara fair-skinned and boasting that said we see it. &quot;</seg>
<seg id="3">The United States is the largest as well as well as the person is not</seg>
<seg id="4">And if Pakistan is a country whose president has also had to drop corruption charges.</seg>
<seg id="5">Our vein wit fluttered and said that we have been arrested in mrikh if a governor in our country, they were arrested during the night Prime Minister gulped once exiled execution down and was the second time.</seg>
<seg id="6">You can tell there was ever in the United States?</seg>
<seg id="7">The see-off was from the presidential guard of honour with those who break the law of the country, there will be some time in the United States?</seg>
<seg id="8">Suspend such as the Chief Justice of Pakistan that was in the public support so far, it couldn&apos;t be restored if the United States?</seg>
<seg id="9">The fake degree holders in Pakistan ozirsht, was made in the United States?</seg>
<seg id="10">The hearing was killed by a laugh laughing pitiful American and also accepted its defeat.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Mr. Zardari in this picture of the smiling has been surrounded the Americans.</seg>
<seg id="2">There is linked with his smile</seg>
<seg id="3">The understanding was that the United States is with the government but they are the people forget that it was a year ago with President Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
<seg id="4">The picture then descend to such as a family is.</seg>
<seg id="5">Before it was never a photo published in newspapers with three US officials who is a president.</seg>
<seg id="6">It is up to the United States and Pakistan has increased to more than one agents now have to work together and they are confident that his new Ghulam who had earlier on.</seg>
<seg id="7">You can also be the credibility of disloyalty to President Zardari was organized by the mdnzr.</seg>
<seg id="8">If there is no any ruler or at least their teeth in the picture does not show the necklace of slavery and shame on the face of it becomes clear.</seg>
<seg id="9">If implemented the principles of democracy will be if the president of Zardari is in the minority.</seg>
<seg id="10">The majority leader is in accordance with the constitution of the country and who has been saying that the picture.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Heaven is also asked Switzerland to Swat.</seg>
<seg id="2">The talks with the power of the government are being carried out.</seg>
<seg id="3">But the use of force and talban force to increase their sympathies to the people is not only a few fa-eda.</seg>
<seg id="4">It is necessary that the government of the use of force to eliminate the causes of msle.</seg>
<seg id="5">The Taliban with the grace of God and the people will come to an end for their own good.</seg>
<seg id="6">ANP will cause of Swat until the resolution of the msa-eil mjoza of Islamic law as per the government bill.</seg>
<seg id="7">But the msa-eil government as well as the economic nfaz of Islamic law will have to concentrate</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It has been linked with the start of the steps taken by President Musharraf that the nation will get rid of the politicians corner of hos scientists but changed his intention all</seg>
<seg id="2">&quot;People who were expected to actually began to consider joining the eternal apneap ah sacrifice terror! &quot;</seg>
<seg id="3">It was expected that the actions of the hogii.</seg>
<seg id="4">honelga The jisehi of the time when Bush is worried about the end of his power and dealt with thieves in boklaht.</seg>
<seg id="5">General Musharraf has still managed to control the present military government only but he does not know what is going on.</seg>
<seg id="6">The Bajaur Swat and terrorism are not controlled by the army and the bombing as &quot;enemy &quot; has to go on public property loss &quot;and &quot;dshmn&apos;ko made a mental patient if we had no enemy</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">More than a year in the troubled region of Swat for a military operation is going worse conditions are worse despite being released.</seg>
<seg id="2">On the one hand in the area of the government to the condemnatory resolution approving only in the National Assembly, and on the other side of the illegal FM radio Taliban are going beyond the influence of Swat channel.</seg>
<seg id="3">The third quarter as the protection of civilians in the area who would listen to the practical action.</seg>
<seg id="4">During the proceedings of the security forces have claimed nearly Swat known as many of the death of more than gunship helicopters and artillery fire, but the Taliban in spite of these deaths were not only strong but it is also proceeding according to an estimate was based on the Swat percent.</seg>
<seg id="5">The result was that on one hand in its failure to accept the government and the Taliban.</seg>
<seg id="6">How to grind the Beach, fodder citizen.</seg>
<seg id="7">The Swat now it is said that some people have asked how the Taliban had received a very good because he is the custodian of religion &quot;and&quot; fight against the enemies of God and religion.</seg>
<seg id="8">When asked whether it is the army that they had received a very good because of the country and protect against the &quot;enemies&quot; in the country.</seg>
<seg id="9">When asked as to who are the enemies of religion and state then we received was a citizen.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">&quot; I am surprised how to fight with the Indian army troops to a small group of Taliban could not control.</seg>
<seg id="2">Track FM channels for illegally running the Taliban could not do that in my opinion is very easy.</seg>
<seg id="3">But it is still brightly all FM reproaching.</seg>
<seg id="4">Schools of children.  The school boys are now.</seg>
<seg id="5">The Taliban has imposed a curfew so that it can be easily.</seg>
<seg id="6">Today it into the outskirts of the Mingora curfew in eight trucks during the night curfew bunker.</seg>
<seg id="7">How to the questions arise in spite of the curfew.</seg>
<seg id="8">Army krtkti Akbar Bugti was killed in shlami and is home to the Taliban.</seg>
<seg id="9">No to God that he explained to the army withdrew from the grip of the Taliban and helpless people of Swat and this will prove that Pakistan can be overcome by any enemy.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Does gentleman said most of the world on the basis of blood flow religions, you should tell me that if there are no religion if not a bloody fight?</seg>
<seg id="2">What are the Pathan, Punjabi, black and Caucasian Mahsood, and the production of other tribes religion all this?</seg>
<seg id="3">However, no way.  religion does not educate, that there is a Caucasian Kala refugee or any Punjabi if there had been no fighting in the togorekaleki half of the world&apos;s enmity religion and caste system is sinking the rest of the world.</seg>
<seg id="4">In fact to provide moral and religious obligates that he did not come here with his creator but also sent him here and he is here to live life as ordered.</seg>
<seg id="5">As a Muslim I believe is the secretary zabth Islam is a complete life and it is true religion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The all his relatives on the telephone every morning before the year for me after taking up abode in London has never once known as though most of us do not question about when I felt that they are not too palatable to call us we left the ring.</seg>
<seg id="2">On the other hand I live in France for two years have also realized this.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is not just a stone people expect from us by phone.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Resolution on Iraq within a few hours, &quot; for the Darfur peace and there is no problem to send troops.</seg>
<seg id="2">The Mumbai attacks immediately ban on demonstrations and criminal organizations are working for a few hours.</seg>
<seg id="3">The dance where you live in connection with the death again we are conducting consultations.</seg>
<seg id="4">O thikidaro! &quot; is the world peace is the end of his life.</seg>
<seg id="5">Does it really does not have to wait.</seg>
<seg id="6">He believed that if the wider use of weapons of mass destruction to catapult its right to get any oppressed couldn&apos;t as well?</seg>
<seg id="7">When a father has raised is running if your child dead body of a wave of pain does not have any part of your heart?</seg>
<seg id="8">If the person is not entitled to be called hotm or not.</seg>
<seg id="9">But there is a black spot in the name of humanity.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Went it has proved that this area of Israelis for thousands of years is also in the country.</seg>
<seg id="2">It is the wish that the two nations together with each other with sincerity and dedication, but his laces are due in the West and the Arab countries, without his desire that peace can never be here.</seg>
<seg id="3">But as Iran still wants to fight with their proxy war here.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Israeli action was also went to temporarily stop you will be started after an accident.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Interests of the BBC has given the United States and Israel and that is why the zionism choice &quot; under the pretext of &quot; enlightenment &quot;has admitted by taking a series of blogs consisting of &quot;and &quot; propaganda &quot;one-sided and blind.</seg>
<seg id="2">&quot; The BBC is only and only farmilti are fulfilling their sympathies to wrap up their aim is and!</seg>
<seg id="3">In the petition. modritr said that this was the subject of the review would be published so that it can be estimated that some realism in a short statement to BBC is still remaining.</seg>
<seg id="4">Thank you.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">How did not know who wrote the story came into existence but of course it is a dracula every time to kill innocent people,</seg>
<seg id="2">He is going to war at any time and blood is flowing at any time.</seg>
<seg id="3">it&apos;s The strange how the lives of the 21st century accepted that much in broad daylight and civilized as silent on this massacre, are being openly</seg>
<seg id="4">If it does not have the feeling that what is going on is presenting the worst form of humanity.</seg>
<seg id="5">Regrettable and the tragic aspect is that in the coming century another person in this aspect of the civilized world picture.</seg>
<seg id="6">Well wisher, sjadalhsnin, Hyderabad Deccan</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">He has been raining in the winter season in the country and Dera Ghazi Khan.</seg>
<seg id="2">According to the weather presents a poem, you are faced with severe enjoy the discipline.</seg>
<seg id="3">The rains are with you</seg>
<seg id="4">It rained if there are Bihar</seg>
<seg id="5">It was then there are living</seg>
<seg id="6">Sometimes back without reason;</seg>
<seg id="7">Sometimes swarmed out of evening</seg>
<seg id="8">We have never made enough noise</seg>
<seg id="9">The rains are with you</seg>
<seg id="10">No one at night in a memorandum</seg>
<seg id="11">One more compressed to ashes</seg>
<seg id="12">Sometimes such that it was extinguished</seg>
<seg id="13">Sometimes they burned themselves from their</seg>
<seg id="14">Sometimes drop was in shock drop</seg>
<seg id="15">The rains are with you</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">All of them are running short a case, the rulers, he has served as the country or left.</seg>
<seg id="2">People have been sold toothpaste or spilled out of lemon has been the bells of temples.</seg>
<seg id="3">The first our media as well as corrupt politicians.</seg>
<seg id="4">Its purpose is just to deceive money from the government or not.</seg>
<seg id="5">As far as if it was public ignorance greater than what to talk about this fool</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Yesterday afternoon was a disaster.</seg>
<seg id="2">The police here and there he asked aligl to run the parking is running.</seg>
<seg id="3">The nypd as well as traffic was not in the mood to look for illegal car park.</seg>
<seg id="4">There was no such a plane that the aircraft was truly air and land in the Hudson said.</seg>
<seg id="5">So far only knows that the &quot;terrorists&quot; were from goose generation of birds.</seg>
<seg id="6">The other day was perhaps a cold in New York.</seg>
<seg id="7">It is so the temperature did not fall.</seg>
<seg id="8">Jaw to walk out of the half-an-hour has started to my pain.</seg>
<seg id="9">He estimated that these people had jumped into the river from the plane.</seg>
<seg id="10">It is a matter of pleasure that all people remained safe.</seg>
<seg id="11">And the pain of the matter is that the plane drowned in the fa-enanshl crisis.</seg>
<seg id="12">Do I go to New Jersey victim from the west side alas! &quot; all the way and was also looking after the South is still under close what I should do?</seg>
<seg id="13">G trapped in a rush to return.</seg>
<seg id="14">Are you some of my road trip during which he had opened one hour 56 exit from the streets.</seg>
<seg id="15">Otherwise he became the first two exit on this has not taken the lines.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Maize, my Pakistan: You can also anyways auspicious Eid Mubarak.</seg>
<seg id="2">Ammar: Of course in</seg>
<seg id="3">Blooming: Anyways, also auspicious Eid Mubarak.</seg>
<seg id="4">Sara: &quot; I have had two roosters and sacrificed as it is said to have Jahanzeb</seg>
<seg id="5">In addition to this and there is no way.</seg>
<seg id="6">The meat on this form and also have to be constructed with the skin.</seg>
<seg id="7">The name: It may take time off the .NET.</seg>
<seg id="8">The forum what happened?</seg>
<seg id="9">lnko</seg>
<seg id="10">Fire in order to cheat the two did you will hear blog, the fox.</seg>
<seg id="11">dfr: Anyways, also auspicious Eid Mubarak.</seg>
<seg id="12">Sir G fire fox crane used.</seg>
<seg id="13">Snow will have disappeared.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">&quot; We are free to understand the Taliban&apos;s uncivilized Sawati group, only that they had been harassed on education for women.</seg>
<seg id="2">Everyday the anger out of school and college women were expressed by demolishing.</seg>
<seg id="3">But like many of the ideas also did not prove to be true, according to the report of the Taliban&apos;s CNN today with the blessing of the group were demolished by a school for boys.</seg>
<seg id="4">Suwat, Taliban collapsed schools for boys</seg>
<seg id="5">The famous English to girls actually saying he was acting on &quot;ladies first&quot; in his first tule address, why is still not speak for the Taliban and uncivilized men wild free of civilization?</seg>
<seg id="6">There is also made it clear that the Taliban&apos;s group was the only that they are against the education of girls, is not correct.</seg>
<seg id="7">But they also oppose Mashallah of education.</seg>
<seg id="8">Pakistan and the mujahideen, and gives the government power and infernal</seg>
<seg id="9">This applies to us, it said the uprooting of.</seg>
<seg id="10">Amen sm amen.</seg>
<seg id="11">Mashallah 182 schools have so far been demolished.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In a statement confirming born before marrying the constitution, the Muslim holy Quran by wrapping up the implementation of the constitution, and the number of mysterious mftion Aqil in eight years that the girl has been attained maturity, and there were no reports of the girl, who married with frog was in India.</seg>
<seg id="2">He saw the pictures taken at the time of marriage to groom.</seg>
<seg id="3">There are some time ago to marry the girl with a dog was also fresh.</seg>
<seg id="4">He also saw the groom.</seg>
<seg id="5">Humanity vanishes even in 21st century.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">These days it is time to kmiotr and the intervention of the computer is growing in every field of life.</seg>
<seg id="2">The tkhfzat is the growing role of computers to as many people on economic affairs.</seg>
<seg id="3">The eases are using a credit card and the grip of the law enforcing agencies on your family life but it is also a better</seg>
<seg id="4">The record for the date you use of credit cards to trace can only economic affairs.</seg>
<seg id="5">And in the future when the real wealth and it will be a great importance should be increased.</seg>
<seg id="6">The crime rate in the world and also the credit card information instead of running a risk flew are robbing the bank.</seg>
<seg id="7">In the resources of the kmpiotri now has also become a friendship</seg>
<seg id="8">The Social net operating such as arkt, websites and book a place in the first grade her popularity in space.</seg>
<seg id="9">But what does not appear to have been mentally as much as we are obedient to the social networks in practice, they are going to do with the people.</seg>
<seg id="10">The match is a website, where the choice of other people to get your choices on the list of people coinciding is clearly visible.</seg>
<seg id="11">Now you just as soon as they spend their lives with another person can?</seg>
<seg id="12">&quot; I feel that is why can also be a better partner for life.</seg>
<seg id="13">&quot; I am who I defects that he would meet.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">&quot; I hardly had any part in perhaps wisdom.</seg>
<seg id="2">Whichever was one of the major childhood said it is for me.</seg>
<seg id="3">The mjhe believe the answer to this question from all over the world to know abajan.</seg>
<seg id="4">I also fly many joke on it.</seg>
<seg id="5">But the only thing that is true that there could be possible.</seg>
<seg id="6">It is a matter of grave concern is that if a need of telling lies.</seg>
<seg id="7">In this age it incurred a loss of it.</seg>
<seg id="8">That is why I tried to give at least one lies.</seg>
<seg id="9">Do not to any false and Lara was also charged with God.</seg>
<seg id="10">&quot; I will ask God willing when it is prayed to God that has done it.</seg>
<seg id="11">The rest of God only knows better conducts.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This is a problem that has been created abhorrent due to a distance of religion.</seg>
<seg id="2">Young children in accordance with the law of our religion and Pakistan must remain a mother.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is the responsibility of the cost of his father and his children can be found.</seg>
<seg id="4">And when a child and an adult who want to live.</seg>
<seg id="5">The lkha is correct that the real problem is to mislead relatives</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Feudal thinking is control over all our activities.</seg>
<seg id="2">On the other hand it is believed that the implementation of the father will create a new shareholder and it is not the praiseworthy and it is a copy of his father.</seg>
<seg id="3">Here in relation to bind the women create social evils</seg>
<seg id="4">Concept of marriage and divorced vanishes widow.</seg>
<seg id="5">These beliefs are useless and unreasonable joint family tradition that the system is facing due to the confusion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In our pchbn society in 50 years if the wife or husband or wife who grew if they will leave and she has married for the second, then why he is not in sight? &quot;</seg>
<seg id="2">There are a Pakistani uncle close to him, his wife was 120 years ago, he died after marrying a widow of all the children who are now married, was against them.</seg>
<seg id="3">Are you in my view is their lawful right do you say?</seg>
<seg id="4">We have taken place in any kind of our mother to us, it is believed that it would not tolerate?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">In my opinion this is a man of these think that if they want to have children after marrying the woman married to a widow or what they did wrong?</seg>
<seg id="2">He also helped found a widow and the uncle also found a home care</seg>
<seg id="3">In his own world iqnn child alcohol will be engaged and there is no time to give.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">This is the reason for this ignorance.</seg>
<seg id="2">A total of if their wives should refuse to serve the old then what will they do?</seg>
<seg id="3">This is the result of the pressure of the society.</seg>
<seg id="4">When people with a family fun on such a motion if they feel ashamed for the second marriage to Abba</seg>
<seg id="5">Although he has to face the situation and he wanted to say that Islam was under the process of his father.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is a menace in our society that we have in the past years 40-50 completely.</seg>
<seg id="2">The until it is approved a wife who topian her husband has forbidden circulated second but it would not be allowed to marry.</seg>
<seg id="3">If you are under control if they do not give even after he died.</seg>
<seg id="4">The afterlife along with her husband and also destroyed a large outbreak of garbage in the society.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Nothing had been sings of Islam is what we want is that our hqiqtau customs.</seg>
<seg id="2">For example, the Bani ungifted, with the dz love and marriage for girls.</seg>
<seg id="3">As far as the chief civil officers question you are a widow widow maintained their relatives then instead of bringing home after a chup superficially Shoro disturbance and now it is (are they twist in the stomach and relatives of affirmative widow) satisfied.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">One of the subcontinent into India and Pakistan have taken centuries ago were ignorant of the thinking behind but has not yet started and to give priority to the customs.</seg>
<seg id="2">Absurdity, the second man to marry a divorced woman to divorce stigma, Dalit, because of this approach is regarded as a result of the roguery of the woman married to a woman at the age of greater than their male stain on the love and marriage.</seg>
<seg id="3">And we declare a copy of Western nations to cover obsolete and piety.</seg>
<seg id="4">Islam was easy to accept it very hard to get rid of this approach.</seg>
<seg id="5">The jraat frmae`bounty and courage to all of us.</seg>
<seg id="6">Amen.</seg>
<seg id="7">Urdu is so difficult to write or not.</seg>
<seg id="8">gina Poetry writing this century.</seg>
<seg id="9">He knew little to.</seg>
<seg id="10">Good last.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">&quot;I have my book Timur Timor wrote that &quot;I have the secret of my life if that will be on the top list commander-in-chief of an army and the army will never fail.</seg>
<seg id="2">But there are conditions and</seg>
<seg id="3">These are the people we ask for us to die martyrs died later</seg>
<seg id="4">Some people have been killed since then murder</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Assalam Alikum orhmt and blessings,</seg>
<seg id="2">A night after night prayer and arhathakh among a shop that drew attention to the athaiaaormjhebithahoathaas side in a car.</seg>
<seg id="3">I had been made his entire family in giatoaski stopped a car in iakchhpochhnachahtahe have forgotten the sochakhshaidke route.</seg>
<seg id="4">apnamd&apos;abian Have a good side and I understand that the Arabic sktahon did not say that I am not a heapbtaaukhkiabat issue?</seg>
<seg id="5">khnashro&apos; The aiahon that I was here in Medina and Riyadh but no one has cut my pocket you please help me to please any said that he and his brother aisahi, because of an accident involving with me is that I have two Riyal to the man who is filled with petrol and you will be given to krriaz but he was a little saagejakrphrohi.</seg>
<seg id="6">&quot; I am very angry Came threats from bolaaorspahi to nodogiarh it.</seg>
<seg id="7">At this stage we ask toab to the Muslims as well with prsoarhokrsath vehicles and at least dotinhzarki families have been roared at all.</seg>
<seg id="8">The apparent Hadith (the distracted pray God) down from oalahath oalaaoraoproalahath to ask the oalaheaoproalahathbhtrhe to let them in.</seg>
<seg id="9">prapnakrm Almighty God to us and we made a koschamslman amen (sm amen)</seg>
<seg id="10">The unto you</seg>
<seg id="11">Javed Iqbal</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">His wife of renowned singer Adnan Sami arrived at a police station in Mumbai to alleged torturing</seg>
<seg id="2">The police station also refer to the court.</seg>
<seg id="3">Wife of Adnan Sami made a sba`gladari appeal against her husband that the continuous violence and Adnan Sami</seg>
<seg id="4">And they are treated and inhuman,</seg>
<seg id="5">Now the tolerance and it was not possible to register a case against Adnan Sami</seg>
<seg id="6">He asked the court to refer to him by saying that instead of registering a case like this is not a reaction to the police.</seg>
<seg id="7">In my opinion is correct Adnan Sami on charges of his wife?</seg>
<seg id="8">Somewhere was not charged with slandering the Indian Adnan Sami?</seg>
<seg id="9">In this regard we know his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">adm - Sanghar, homeland.</seg>
<seg id="2">As far as he is concerned it may take some charges for other human</seg>
<seg id="3">The increasing respect does not have anything to</seg>
<seg id="4">The wife and nothing to do with Adnan Sami went to India to earn money for his life after leaving the Adnan Sami, who made his name with</seg>
<seg id="5">This is the result of his actions</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Washington</seg>
<seg id="2">Senior US officials say that the president would take a tough stand Obama on Afghan President Hamid Karzai</seg>
<seg id="3">The new strategy for the development of the United States on Afghanistan have been given more importance.</seg>
<seg id="4">Authorities say that Hamid will consider the acquisition of US targets in Afghanistan Zai because there is corruption in the government, the drug trade has increased and the Taliban are gathering again.</seg>
<seg id="5">The US officials say that the American administration of Hamid Karzai to mount pressure on some of them are in which the vice-president Richard Hall of Obama Biden and President of Pakistan and Afghanistan have put it.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that it was a strategy to President Bush, who made every two weeks Hamid held a video conference with Zai and Afghanistan and called on the U.S. role in the reconstruction of the civil department.</seg>
<seg id="7">Authorities say Obama administration will work with state leaders as an alternative to the central government.</seg>
<seg id="8">Authorities say that they are against corruption by Hamid Zai will emphasize on fighting it.</seg>
<seg id="9">This year the Hamid Karzai faces new elections and it is not yet clear whether Obama and his colleagues will support him for the presidency.</seg>
<seg id="10">The statement of the US government not prelude to change its policy with reference to Afghanistan?</seg>
<seg id="11">What is the time to Hamid Karzai?</seg>
<seg id="12">What is your opinion in this regard?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Sri Lanka in the series of three one-day matches between Pakistan and Sri lnkake 1-2 to Pakistan.</seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan in the first one day match were facing defeat by Sri Lanka Sri Lanka but won the next two matches.</seg>
<seg id="3">The performance of the national cricket team in the third one-day match was extremely poor, 75 on 23 runs in just 309 overs in reply to Sri Lanka for the national team of the dhirhog-ei and it had to face the nose example.</seg>
<seg id="4">At the end of the series proves that there is no continuity in the performance of the national cricket team.</seg>
<seg id="5">The home ground defeat in the national team despite all claims and what you think, why is it?</seg>
<seg id="6">The departments of the game is up to the authorities need to pay more attention?</seg>
<seg id="7">Are you satisfied with the team?</seg>
<seg id="8">The department which you will impose duty to defeat, batting, bowling and fielding?</seg>
<seg id="9">They will tell his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Jeddah, Babur Malik - Hussain, there is a modern day of mourning the man of the world as a &quot; aj am feudalist customs the landlord savagely their landlord target innocent people from mslamn rule to say it?</seg>
<seg id="2">Sometimes there was an exhibition on khodapneap Sardar cuckoos, as the government does not take action against them when they do?</seg>
<seg id="3">When the judicial justice a-eega work</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Gulfam, London - print, the statement of its own choice as they prefer to our desire that even if something like a true statement Mukherji embarrassment in the crane because this is not the right thing to say age despotic and authority is equal to that of jihad has released the news after lying Mukherji said they try</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Dubai, Malik Yusuf.</seg>
<seg id="2">In charge of all the people of Kashmir to fight a azadi for last sixty years</seg>
<seg id="3">Neither did not ask anyone who has now become a war on terrorism and extremism as a man of compromise would start the sanitation</seg>
<seg id="4">The first Muslims are now in the process of disentangling</seg>
<seg id="5">But the Pakistan will have to understand the policy, and its</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">London - Asad Khan,</seg>
<seg id="2">India is creating a situation similar to that of the international attention from Kashmir</seg>
<seg id="3">But Pakistan has always been dkhladia in the face of Indian origin</seg>
<seg id="4">The British government has been considering ankhin they are slandering the occupation of Kashmir to Pakistan in the name of terrorism that is why the Indian</seg>
<seg id="5">And they hesitate while talking about this issue with Pakistan</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The British Foreign Secretary David available band and has said that the resolution of the Kashmir issue, they will be able to effectively deal with various threat in the NWFP.</seg>
<seg id="2">It should be noted that the newly elected President Bush Obama similar views on the Kashmir issue has been made.</seg>
<seg id="3">British Foreign Secretary conversation with media in Mumbai and wrote an article in the belief that the war against terrorism is a policy of President Bush was wrong to kill people and cause the dangers faced by.</seg>
<seg id="4">It was reported David band has said that no Pakistani extremist groups to politely would not show.</seg>
<seg id="5">Tension in the region because India has not pidakrke on the pressing need to resolve the Kashmir dispute by a superpower tried to remove the attention to this issue?</seg>
<seg id="6">but not part of the strategy in Mumbai?</seg>
<seg id="7">What escaped to the process of composite dialogue with India on the basis of terrorism?</seg>
<seg id="8">You know his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- aftab Usman.</seg>
<seg id="2">In my opinion is a superpower to harm Pakistan desires are not completed</seg>
<seg id="3">But there are thinking of some measures to control it as they know that Pakistan is a nuclear power</seg>
<seg id="4">On the other hand they want to find a way out of a revolution</seg>
<seg id="5">The foreign countries should not think that there may be some political problems due to geographical corner to Pakistan to help Pakistan and also wants to meet its goal</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- A civilian, USA.</seg>
<seg id="2">The Hindu tradition is always there that are faced with a knife on armpit Ram</seg>
<seg id="3">&quot; I think that a bus for a long time to a stomach pain and they started to threaten to Pakistan</seg>
<seg id="4">&quot; We are prepared by all means we have to face the Joint Chief afarmi or else we know the answer to suppress</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">--Faheem Siddiquee.</seg>
<seg id="2">Apex, ihs Al-Khema have been issuing statements a mischief by the United States is proud of you out of the United States but now the situation is also a reality to see you know how who is under water</seg>
<seg id="3">Israel is a shame on Hamas but no one in the nhinn of Israel, India has also been represented in India wants to do this</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Prime Minister Syed Yousuf Raza Gilani has said that the newly elected Vice-President joba-eidn US to descend to the uniform of President Musharraf and cripple democracy has played an important role in arranging restored, the Pakistan Government has given him the Sitara-i-Imtiaz.</seg>
<seg id="2">Uniform to descend to the credit of some political parties and the restoration of democracy did not want to go, it is not a rubber stamp parliament,</seg>
<seg id="3">The decision will be made in the parliament.</seg>
<seg id="4">The Prime Minister said that chapter of Dr Qadeer has been closed.</seg>
<seg id="5">The mina wasn&apos;t worried the importance of a public protest against the mrit?</seg>
<seg id="6">Do not any movement lawyers play a role?</seg>
<seg id="7">The statement of the prime minister should be made to say.</seg>
<seg id="8">They will tell his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">US President George W. Bush said while advicing counsel to the newly elected Barack Obama in his farewell press conference that he had made a mistake in his post and was presided over by Barack Obama linked to the krdale,</seg>
<seg id="2">According to the terms as president and taken under US law and the constitution, his popularity preferred to the US interests</seg>
<seg id="3">He said the US enemies are still planning to attack on the United States, it will be the biggest challenge to stop these attacks, Barack Obama for</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that Iraq on a large scale is the most disappointed for me not to find the weapons of mass destruction and a mission in Iraq made a mistake on my biggest confess to being completed.</seg>
<seg id="5">&quot; Speaking at his last press conference at the White House said that it is my last press conference and I thank with journalists and other colleagues who participated in the conference.</seg>
<seg id="6">What do you think Obama that Bush did not repeat mistakes?</seg>
<seg id="7">Didn&apos;t kiabsh confessing to some mistakes?</seg>
<seg id="8">They will be able to follow the advice of Obama Bush?</seg>
<seg id="9">They will tell his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">&quot; Vice-President Dick Cheney said that I want to see dead or alive to Osama bin Laden.</seg>
<seg id="2">He said that Usama Bin Laden is hiding in the area and a difficult for his organization has been ineffective, if Osama bin Laden would be caught dead or alive then it will be an end to this organization.</seg>
<seg id="3">The United States is resolved to arrest Usama Bin Ladin and searching for Usama should continue.</seg>
<seg id="4">Could the arrest of Usama Dick Cheney to be completed?</seg>
<seg id="5">You know his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">cricketer all rounder Shahid Afridi as the game on the first day of the match and PIA Habib Bank Quaid-e-Azam Trophy was fought to a finish after spectators.</seg>
<seg id="2">Shahid Afridi UBL after playing a match on the ground as soon as he came out of drawing room around him when a large number of spectators were collected,</seg>
<seg id="3">The application of pulling out of the picture with them by the hand and at one point on which a spectators turned out Shahid Afridi said it had a picture taken yesterday to Afridi, but at the insistence of spectators come in tish before he slapped with each other to fight there have been threaded dealing with the matter.</seg>
<seg id="4">After that Shahid Afridi said that this issue is no reason for me to make the prayer at this time,</seg>
<seg id="5">The lizards should apologize to the spectators, &quot;</seg>
<seg id="6">The attitude of the Shahid Afridi has said.</seg>
<seg id="7">We know from our minds.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh &apos;a-edkia has once again alleged that Pakistan is fanning the atmosphere of war</seg>
<seg id="2">The Pakistan uses terrorism as state policy.</seg>
<seg id="3">Manmohan Singh during a conference in New Delhi chief minister said that the grd&apos;nasrki terror and especially the neighboring countries is being done to support</seg>
<seg id="4">The terrorist attacks in Mumbai and naval adopted by the Indian Coast Guard was safe.</seg>
<seg id="5">Indian Prime Minister said that the Lashkar-e-Tayiba attack in Mumbai in November.</seg>
<seg id="6">He further said that the terrorists are using new techniques and modern communication system on the line of control, we will have to increase hardness from where the infiltration in terrorism will not be tolerated and it is our policy.</seg>
<seg id="7">Do you to the Indian prime minister to be seen how?</seg>
<seg id="8">internal chaos and separatist movements of kiabhart Mazhar tonhin anxiety of Indian?</seg>
<seg id="9">The Indian attitude is adopted threatening signals about?</seg>
<seg id="10">They will tell his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Zubair Khan, Karachi.</seg>
<seg id="2">This is a very painful event that Kashmir is an Israeli killing of Palestinians here is rigti but the situation is not as long as the head of the salmti Council.</seg>
<seg id="3">As much are organizations in Palestine and Kashmir that they want the war to the rkhin and its azadi alliance was created to combat all forms of aggression one or the other day that he will bloom God willing</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Israeli air strike on Gaza is still continuing, hundreds of Palestinian men, women and children have been killed.</seg>
<seg id="2">Important political rhnmanzarian of Hamas was killed along with his wife.</seg>
<seg id="3">The meeting of the Security Council ended without any decision.</seg>
<seg id="4">Libya against Israel in the face of opposition to the U.S. - and condemnatory resolution presented to other Arab countries.</seg>
<seg id="5">Bombing rozse for the last several Israeli planes on the Palestinian civilian population.</seg>
<seg id="6">The entire world has on the Bombay let out a yell but Israeli attacks on the United States, Britain and not to see this massacre?</seg>
<seg id="7">Why are silent important Muslims countries?</seg>
<seg id="8">The double standards of the world should be made to say.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Saeed, a New York.</seg>
<seg id="2">In my opinion, the main thing is that we are mostly illiterate people do not know where he is going to pay their taxes imposed and the government has an interest in fulfilling its obligations would continue to supply of electricity and gas.</seg>
<seg id="3">They choose to all the people who are aware of their role,</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Crisis sngin of gas and electricity and the length of Pakistan was adopted</seg>
<seg id="2">On the other hand it has increased the price of an average 8 gas from January 1 and non-availability of petrol in some cities of the country has become a source of serious concern for the people.</seg>
<seg id="3">Intense action on the crisis, long stoppage of electricity and gas in the industrial and business groups of chaos and violence are continuing protests,</seg>
<seg id="4">Industrialists have given ultimatum to the factory.</seg>
<seg id="5">The load of eight out of ten hours in Karachi is shedding the anxiety among citizens.</seg>
<seg id="6">Industrial almost paralyzed life.</seg>
<seg id="7">Blame in this regard each other government institutions are about its position.</seg>
<seg id="8">electricity and gas prices not joke with the affairs of the country?</seg>
<seg id="9">Why do not pay attention to resolve the issues?</seg>
<seg id="10">Isn&apos;t wheel-jam government is looking for amlki development?</seg>
<seg id="11">What would you suggest measures to overcome this crisis immediately?</seg>
<seg id="12">They will tell his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">--Imran Khokar, I want to say that the ruling Al Madinah people like.</seg>
<seg id="2">The heb antagonizing raising the slogan &quot; I am surprised that a civilian government</seg>
<seg id="3">Apparent gas was not a problem to get petrol</seg>
<seg id="4">The bodies of the government has no control</seg>
<seg id="5">The condition of law and ardr daily said he was upset at the mercy of God</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">aghazhogiahe The New Year.</seg>
<seg id="2">Past Year was a year of ups and downs and political disturbance with regard to terrorism, it should also remember.</seg>
<seg id="3">Of the eight years of separation of powers by President Bush and President Musharraf, a democratic government in India and Pakistan on the establishment of a shoe Bush, calamities, earthquake in Balochistan, all over the world financial crisis, the slump.</seg>
<seg id="4">The arrival of the new year is how do you see in the coming year?</seg>
<seg id="5">The political and geographical situation with what you will bloom of Obama will be?</seg>
<seg id="6">What is hopeful of some progress in the elimination of terrorism?</seg>
<seg id="7">What should be abolished judicial crisis in Pakistan?</seg>
<seg id="8">The Indo-Pak relations will take side?</seg>
<seg id="9">There is a possibility of a surgical strike or war?</seg>
<seg id="10">What are the expectations for the new year with you?</seg>
<seg id="11">They will tell his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">President Bush has been transferred to the Camp David presidential camp office after leaving the White House for eight years in power and beautification so that the United States in accordance with the wishes of the new president Barack Obama should be made to the White House,</seg>
<seg id="2">Historic, and attacks on the World Trade Center in the United States in the presidential term of eight years of attacks on Bush and then went to the pentose war to drag the forces of various countries while conducting a military operation in Afghanistan and Iraq under the pretext of the international war against terrorism and memorable examples of Bush full use of its resources in this war.</seg>
<seg id="3">The war had to face the worst economic and financial crisis in the history of the United States.</seg>
<seg id="4">What do you think the war can be used for milk and solid?</seg>
<seg id="5">The release of President Bush to successful policies?</seg>
<seg id="6">Are you on the regime of President Bush is he?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Indian government has blocked a visit to Pakistan by the Indian cricket team.</seg>
<seg id="2">The visit to the Indian cricket team to Pakistan, three tests and five one-day matches to be played a twenty 20 matches.</seg>
<seg id="3">The Vice-President of the Indian Cricket Board Rajiv Shakla told Geo News that the board had sought permission to visit Pakistan from the government but the present tense between the two countries is not possible because of the situation.</seg>
<seg id="4">What is the right move to cancel his visit to Pakistan for the cause of the current political situation, the government should not be separate from politics to play?</seg>
<seg id="5">Isn&apos;t decisions made by the Indian Government harmful for Pakistan?</seg>
<seg id="6">Why can the security situation in the Indian team and English cricket team&apos;s tour in spite of being a bad?</seg>
<seg id="7">What is your opinion in this regard.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Karachi - Salman.</seg>
<seg id="2">Those who are proud to go to India</seg>
<seg id="3">The film has made his or her video now there should open their ankhin that the people of India about how your honours</seg>
<seg id="4">&quot; I am an interview with Adnan Sami in which he said &quot; I am not a Pakistani her British citizenship</seg>
<seg id="5">You must Adnan Sami aja-ee for the first time that the Pakistan in this respect because they can not even Wani a-ei,</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Farid Ahmad.</seg>
<seg id="2">Karachi.</seg>
<seg id="3">Mumbai in the Indian attitude changed after the attack</seg>
<seg id="4">Jagjeet Singh zhahr in this case the reaction is that they hate Pakistan and Pakistanis</seg>
<seg id="5">The chhai-ee know that Adnan Sami ashabhonsle to sing songs are now inharmonious Adnan Sami, from where you want to stay in India does not need ane</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Muhammad Alam, Shamshad -</seg>
<seg id="2">Karachi, &quot; the statement of the Jagjeet only has a lot to say that he also capriciouss</seg>
<seg id="3">The ratio of issuing statements at the time of ankhin Pakistanis has been opened for how much you feel you have been in India for the kndo mentality.</seg>
<seg id="4">The abominable issuing statements after the Mumbai have increased now is reproaching against the famous singer Adnan Sami.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Come President Bush on a farewell visit to Iraq according to a foreign news agency was ridiculous situation during a press conference in his office in Baghdad with Noor Al-Malki prime minister when an Iraqi journalist said that President Bush addresses the dog&quot; is a farewell kiss. &quot;</seg>
<seg id="2">The journalist to descend Bush threw a shoe, President Bush bowed before pinching his ability to and from.</seg>
<seg id="3">The shoe was linked to an American flag.</seg>
<seg id="4">The journalist was taken from the security officer for dragging his place.</seg>
<seg id="5">Why did the U.S. President George W Bush has said that a shoe, I do not know the number of 10, I had no problem.</seg>
<seg id="6">In my opinion this wasn&apos;t the kiashafi expressed outrage against the president by the Iraqi people?</seg>
<seg id="7">What do you say that?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Tension created in the relations between Pakistan and India after the incidents of terrorism in Mumbai at a time when the severe situation was adopted by the Indian Air Force planes were violating the air space of Pakistan and Kashmir sectors in Lahore.</seg>
<seg id="2">Respondent of the Pakistan Air Force was forced to return because of an Indian plane.</seg>
<seg id="3">The two Indian aircraft according to the sources the arms and ammunition were armed with.</seg>
<seg id="4">The present tense situation in the first of its kind is an accident.</seg>
<seg id="5">Pakistan Air Force Air Force said that national defense is to get ready.</seg>
<seg id="6">The information minister Sherry Rehman said that Indian officials have acknowledged that violation of air space, but it was mistakenly.</seg>
<seg id="7">Military sources have described as critical to the incident.</seg>
<seg id="8">Do you think it intends air strike in Pakistan? &quot;</seg>
<seg id="9">What is the correct stance that India was breaching the lganatha estimate mistakenly or for the purpose of the Pakistan Air Force?</seg>
<seg id="10">Won&apos;t to further increase tension between the two countries are?</seg>
<seg id="11">They will tell his opinion.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Shaheed Mrs Benazeer. bhtoko after the death of the international human rights award given by the chairman of his son Bilawal Zardari [Bhutto&apos;s People Party.</seg>
<seg id="2">Former Prime Minister shhidbe Bhutto example of Pakistan at a ceremony during the session of the General Assembly in the central office of the United Nations for its recognition of human rights in the service of favoring went through this award.</seg>
<seg id="3">December 10 sixty birth anniversary of the human rights resolution was celebrated by the United Nations.</seg>
<seg id="4">On this occasion the personalities and institutions in recognition of human rights are working for the honors given to former Attorney General Luis Ramzey Clark of the United States as well as Benazir Bhutto in all over the world and the international organization Human Rights Watch work for human rights.</seg>
<seg id="5">The ambassador of Pakistan to the United praqoam Abdullah Haroon Hussain and other senior Pakistani diplomatic officials were also present.</seg>
<seg id="6">&quot; on receiving the award to former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto. Bhutto Shaheed has said.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">- Sameer.</seg>
<seg id="2">Chicago.</seg>
<seg id="3">It is true that he was a shid but we also have to remember how innocent blood shed in Karachi, for which he was proud that the Nasir Ullah Babar very good work,</seg>
<seg id="4">After lkin was totally changed</seg>
<seg id="5">But it is also true that the way they vow to senior members of his party and representatives of the party to choose what kind of his son, democracy, then?</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">--Consolidated light, Karachi, has proved to be the qran of the report of the infidel infidel will support.</seg>
<seg id="2">But the iron axe until it was found that neither group is not linked to axe feather cut</seg>
<seg id="3">There is no way that our rulers have continued their secret methods due to aftinarhi are in the country.</seg>
<seg id="4">God advises to our rulers.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Panel of the UN Security Council has been included in the list of terrorist organizations including three Pakistani citizens and Jamaatud Dawa and Hafiz Mohammed Saeed.</seg>
<seg id="2">Al-Qaida and Taleban committee of the sinkshnz Security Council has approved the list of terrorists in the name of the Dawa party of Pakistanis in the Amir Hafiz Mohammad Saeed, banned organization of Lashkar-e-Tayiba operations chief Zaki lkhoi Rehman, head of the Department of Finance Haji Muhammad Ashraf.</seg>
<seg id="3">In addition to a Saudi citizen named Ahmed Mahmoud bazik is also included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
<seg id="4">Party organizations at the JuD Pasban, including Kashmir, Al-Rasheed Trust International aoralakhtr.</seg>
<seg id="5">Immediate personalities basis for life and all the member countries will be frozen assets and a travel ban on the organization and arrest them.</seg>
<seg id="6">They will face trial.</seg>
<seg id="7">Do not sanctions under the Indian propaganda?</seg>
<seg id="8">Why is India on these organizations accused of Mumbai attacks without imposing any evidence?</seg>
<seg id="9">Do not present terrorist group in India?</seg>
<seg id="10">Do not, international acquaintance with the atrocities on minorities in India?</seg>
<seg id="11">We know from our minds.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The spokesman of Eid is a pleasure and happiness and Muslims sacrifice animals during the Eid-ul-Azha on Abraham&apos;s following the practice.</seg>
<seg id="2">Tumult at a time when inflation is on the political situation is deteriorating, rich and poor in spite of it prepared for Eid according to their capacity for Eid and all of its friends in different ways.</seg>
<seg id="3">We are providing a chance to get through the blog that Eid greetings in a short messages to their loved ones.</seg>
<seg id="4">The verses by growth in the Eid can congratulate.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Murtaza - Jilani,</seg>
<seg id="2">Karachi, should be made to our rulers are strongly opposed to aprishn of appreciator is that Pakistan is bearing any kind of cruelty but they love Pakistan</seg>
<seg id="3">If it went to war if the shoulder by shoulder that Pakistan would fight</seg>
<seg id="4">When its feel, with only some protest politics will not be achieved, I think there is a possibility of a man killed in the war between the two so that it could anger.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>
