<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="site18_single_constrained">
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Endeavoring to build support</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Committee of the end Friday 's day parliament, Chief Committee, chairman mentioned that he courts in the suffering from coastal areas, حکو rein in a It is no has been in said that the affected areas and the Apart from the life of this has in the development delegation of the United States بھیجے۔</seg>
<seg id="3">Meeting of the media representatives of the emphasized that the, he will Hussein. said that that Committee of the endeavoring to the It was a has been in the proposal of the Pakistan, has extracted in the has been that Israel. " refer to the United States. face of the demand for a response to the affected by persons for the relief work supremacy of many</seg>
<seg id="4">The progress of the hand, and فسلطینیوں in the and humanity and against As well as Pakistan, and that the United States to against the opportunity for out of</seg>
<seg id="5">Mentioned that he said that in our However, to a criticism of of the system, and that people who " war, against talked about the, but it is Israel, the It was a Israeli for the for the soldiers ? " He However,</seg>
<seg id="6">Foreign Affairs, as Senate. The which Committee of the Chairman of the فسلطین, مسلے on the penitence مسلہ leaders of the سردمہر روئیے and criticism. ( They were.</seg>
<seg id="7">He said that the said that the Committee of the I 'm in the it has the United States, newly elected president surrounding the اُبامہ government and the belonging to a ), at the During the China اُمہ due to the fault of the United States and prime minister اُمہ the two sides of due to the situation, and piece of the vision of</seg>
<seg id="8">Mentioned that he Syed, " that Pakistan, اُمہ, defeat in the two sides of due to the خلاء to the human 24 hours of the should not only flour, to resulted in. maturity, and Palestine, and now solve the problem have been to</seg>
<seg id="9">Foreign Affairs, the vision of the Al-Qaeda cell in Spain and Committee of the revealed that the said that they countries in the organization of the ministers of Foreign session of the participate in the said that. Saudi Arabia. order to have</seg>
<seg id="10">the an emergency meeting Israel, and hand, and فسلطین of the people attacks, a report on the has been in the said that that United States, مسلے the near future., and the Nigeria, The other countries leaders of the course of the According to</seg>
<seg id="11">Foreign Affairs, the Prime Minister, that United States and مسلہ France, and the concerns of the According to resolve the should be</seg>
<seg id="12">between the two countries, one of the for the two journalists, held in participate in the of the meeting Palestine, the fact that the situation, Hong Kong, zeroed in</seg>
<seg id="13">We here up in Tournament held, students. " gap between the Israel, attacks against a Haripur.</seg>
<seg id="14">On ’ s and کتبے but also from out of politics, Israel and against shouting, a In the</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">فلو, However, the United States ڈائٹنگ, Churches and</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The Pakistan, the it is to Topeka, the said that the policy of the front of the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">He experiences of the It is of last year. cases, کیلوریز the food, and out of the Topeka, and فلو, heart disease, deal with the ability to continue cases, was</seg>
<seg id="4">To However, a similar to there is no reason has been that ’بخار, and even strategy. It head of a ہے‘۔</seg>
<seg id="5">Pakistan, the According to patients, During the world کھائیں پئیں۔</seg>
<seg id="6">مشیگن calling the University investigation into a it is said that ڈائیٹ importance to the Topeka, the ) or the during the government support, they have, but in, and his new ways of likely to be changes in the However, to world, for the Topeka, and فلو, heart disease against on the مدافعت. period of</seg>
<seg id="7">Professor Mazhar, الزبتھ گارڈنر the According to ڈائٹنگ 24 hours a lack of فلو due to the not only is part of any hungry and the international community. recovering fast after, the more than a access to be</seg>
<seg id="8">and it is also He said that appealed to people, فلو the pandemic, the United States. said that the bad weather leader of a few months, During the ڈائٹنگ, Churches and to چاہیئے۔</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">To finish the 2008 میڈونا the for the best</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Able to show, and میڈونا of the ایلبم ’ہارڈ کینڈی‘ build a look set up a comprehensive. has been the, and the یوکرین, جپسی more than a بدوش bands ; and Justin ٹمبرلین the with the Two altogether. It involved in.</seg>
<seg id="3">Gulf War, leaks. ریسنگ participation in the Such of the However, in period of</seg>
<seg id="4">سیلائن ڈیونز finish the two unit, eight profit of the spirit of the According to succeed do not show that pupils, تیئس million, چھیاسٹھ hundred thousand dollars in beginning of</seg>
<seg id="5">Opened firing on show ’ٹیکنگ چانسز‘ the meantime, countries to visit the However, میڈونا. threatened that countries, preparations for the people of the birth of eight years, On the first last year and it was</seg>
<seg id="6">, Mashiakh of the show of the Director of جیمی کنگ Otherwise, جہنوں said that ’سپائس گرل‘, ’ری یونین‘ visit to visit has been کیئے In the</seg>
<seg id="7">میڈونا said that are two thousand. He set up in view of this record of of the According to</seg>
<seg id="8">To finish the two thousand. He said that the ’کنفیشن کنسرٹس‘ the ages of this سینتیس hundred thousand dollars کمائے In the</seg>
<seg id="9">پولسٹر said that بون wish to the third stage, and succeed in the singer resolution of the according to the threatened that this hundred and fifty the Christians and کمائے۔</seg>
<seg id="10">بروس سپرنگسٹین the delegations come to hundred and fifty the dollars for an set up چوتھے police and who able to the formulating a and his members of the twelve of this Six to the dollars for an</seg>
<seg id="11">The this magazine is $ 5.2 the According to the are two thousand by the military United States. part of people said that colleagues who have died, altogether. programs, participate in did not we have their own پرگراموں, participate in the able to مہنگے at ticket to raise the appealed to for In the</seg>
<seg id="12">United States اوسطً a Only one of the Pakistan, the implementation of the, and میڈونا, show of the we have to % in one in three years ), ڈالرکا. The</seg>
<seg id="13">پولسٹر this magazine is $ 5.2. The impossible. بونگیونی He said that World Bank of The standard بازاری of foundation, ' interest in the said that are two thousand Pakistan, a would be in interests. The</seg>
<seg id="14">He said that the finish the two thousand Babylon, and 2001., سپرنگسٹین the appealed to for in this ایلبم the due to the there are people last year of due to the through the rounds.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The flush of education on the پابندی: Taliban.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The patronage of Waziristan, since Shah, and the out of the story of the Revolutionaries were The local government authorities one پمفلٹ, it has in mind, نیم government and people, federal government to the has been in the and for themselves, girls, and flush of education 1971 The.</seg>
<seg id="3">پمفلٹ, SHOs of that if the five January 1, flush of education federal government and closed. three years. his face. proceedings of the other hand, will be</seg>
<seg id="4">پمفلٹ, SHOs of that government effected people, Tagalog, discuss the women in the Identity credit card saying dish on on women and the all the counties, 2006. day dead, and the did not. According to</seg>
<seg id="5">Local Taliban in the by the women, Identity credit card saying dish on the announcement of a conscious of the on the years. When the military militants in the quake, نظیرانکم voluntary work, for the نادرہ day at the Beside the two ), women said that Identity credit card saying, the 55. The have been The</seg>
<seg id="6">Local people, According to authorities members of the due to the due to the پمفلٹ to of the tribal According to the which was the لاؤڈسپیکر the read in a divisional bench.</seg>
<seg id="7">However, a classes, with the turning point. incidents of that girls in the it is, due to the has been on will be. United States</seg>
<seg id="8">پمفلٹ the According to this in the Special Education in view of the for the or Identity credit card in the for the place whereas the school or 2006. The Are you have if the Indian. United States, In particular, Pakistan, who 45 minutes to must make has been should be.</seg>
<seg id="9">Its demand for a district of his police, and He said that Sunday, and defend the میرانشاہ Road, the was a hit explosion of the took place in the according to the result of the one hand, the city were However, in injured in more According to</seg>
<seg id="10">Wife injured in his it is necessary, but abide by.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">’ٹارگٹ کلنگ‘، the bodies of a</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The police. Sunday, the end of the obliged to Mingora. carbon dioxide at, and سہراب the at the two people of the bodies of the, but for as well as a grief and was</seg>
<seg id="3">killed in the affected by the belong to the On Chairman of the police. It lung cancer. According to</seg>
<seg id="4">They days, and He said that it, Monday, a letter to the One day, kid, the has been the said that the Pakistan has also, and it United States. 25 years at whether they received appealed to the death of a threatened by the responsible for.</seg>
<seg id="5">government and people of He said that 25 years at Therefore, are Pakistan, the army and is However, after six months were investigative teams are become less and ہپستال transferred to a Currently,</seg>
<seg id="6">President of the most Mingora, cruelty of of areas last year, weeks, the During the against killings of the According to the of the time to implementation of the in the</seg>
<seg id="7">his wishful thinking that were making the city of, hold a police killed in the has been The</seg>
<seg id="8">local According to the United States to the assemblies and the According to the area of about the lack of a who belonged to more than.</seg>
<seg id="9">a long time to the organization and his conference on the responsible for ' Adopt a is the According to</seg>
<seg id="10">week, and ages in the local Taliban. According Pakistan, and said that " given to the revealed that the said that held a due to the that it, three years are of the night even have also and دیولئی authorities, is eight years of the body to the involved in.</seg>
<seg id="11">Pakistan, and it is said that the eight years. talk about half month, the hold a delegation of competition in the In the</seg>
<seg id="12">He said that the said that the from the local Taliban. The killed in the they are not to, and the Hence, the According to the Mingora, Hence, and According to the If the citizens, ", but to According to</seg>
<seg id="13">government and people of He said that Mingora, hold a delegation of clothes, abducted have been the However, this spite of people on the attacks, which According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Which is بختاور of the گائیکی, were</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">بختاور or the records of the has been a rep in سانگ (جدید music, in انداز) United States and ٹیوب the It was after the has been The</seg>
<seg id="3">the last five minutes, and anthems the representative of the government of spies will, broadcast a کلپس Bill Clinton. However,</seg>
<seg id="4">pass eighteen to old بختاور Edinburgh or university medical student.</seg>
<seg id="5">. speaker the گائیکی, Jang has demanded According to</seg>
<seg id="6">the did not know that said that the number of his mother buildings, at the after the شوقیہ and anthems گانا the have been.</seg>
<seg id="7">the said that the Mother of the were available. said that the Prime Minister that ’آپ intelligent and the depredations of leadership If you the of the work, juncture, the کیا‘۔</seg>
<seg id="8">He said that the Medical December, the movement has a involved in the called on you کنپٹی کےقریب hospital. According will not چون year, the looking for our سےالگ ہوئیں، three years ' پسماندگان, چھوڑے۔</seg>
<seg id="9">In fact, and If you کےبغیر, hope that the you and I all the heart of دھڑکنوں in the However,</seg>
<seg id="10">بختاور representative of government most of the visited the old 132 Bhutto, the after the other able to the However,</seg>
<seg id="11">Music in the due to two refusing to have However,</seg>
<seg id="12">did not know that the said that the Mother of the leadership, this fulfill their a journalist, or in the extreme گریمی award, the dancing. " The producers also understand and ریپر پف ڈیڈی visit in the Parliament confidence and the years. It is meeting with the courts were.</seg>
<seg id="13">بختاور Many people but should newspapers, the translated the world violation of the had been but his voice of the first time : " ٹیوب in the extreme try to be ],</seg>
<seg id="14">representative of the government, and activists from one K K F the بختاور the rep in سانگ with the Crime بنوانا began to the However,</seg>
<seg id="15">According to the Pakistan, people party. According conviction. would be the been confirmed that : " ٹیوب the well as anthems Many people and بختاور the According to</seg>
<seg id="16">the said that the tourism industry, winter, the revealed that is a Today the daughter of the posed by of Mother of the well no one has earned the government According to US Pakistan, at the has been in the has been The</seg>
<seg id="17">A conviction. would be the He said that بختاور the and anthems the Crime etc., and it is his Jamaat have the الوقت it is not According to</seg>
<seg id="18">The people of the said that the said that in months of this fees, the stadium issuing the site of Jamaat and the among the local چئرمین 132 Bhutto. He is following the open United States. has been the which are the decided to the According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Ajmal قصاب Pakistan, but some deviating its attention The</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">According to the Prime Minister, Information and government called him the other, Urdu, or to their parents have a MS of the message of the, Ajmal قصاب of the Saudi Arabia the constitution. " the interest-free loans and that the view of the However,</seg>
<seg id="3">arrived in the Prime Minister, advisor to the called him the said that his Pakistan, Saudi Arabia, served as the years,</seg>
<seg id="4">The people of the He said that the citizens of the records of the those who, نادرہ, and Ajmal of the record of a One day.</seg>
<seg id="5">the fact that in Hong Kong, no they wish. Pakistan government start rely on the Now, in the time, the severity of Ajmal قصاب the Saudi Arabia supported According to</seg>
<seg id="6">to Ministry of Foreign According to the According to Ajmal قصاب the Saudi Arabia spoken Ministry of the said that the According to</seg>
<seg id="7">Because of this, quoted as saying. Urdu, and the other, and newspapers, and According to the TV channels said that Ajmal قصاب of one of the Punjab, year district of this pretext of about the revealed that was</seg>
<seg id="8">However, in the Security Council, which is period of</seg>
<seg id="9">according to the It is not said that the, Ajmal of statement that this pretext of the provinces of the more than any area of do nothing</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">the Security Council of the armed forces فائر، [ bombardment of</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Israel. The and Syrian officials According to media has a revealed that that oppose restrictions area Israel, this on the four armed forces پھینکے in the and a parts of Israel, listed the نہاریا, 807 in the two in the Department injured in the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">give proof of the area trusted people in rockets, the need to its Recalling the target said that Lebanon continue. The</seg>
<seg id="4">the It is not the attack. The God, the it has to once again, organizations and said active in West instead of of the According to</seg>
<seg id="5">oppose restrictions. government He said that credibility by the talked about the trader, and trying to a has been that his post attacks, about costs. The</seg>
<seg id="6">Bibi on the while said that this said that the period of the has been a crisis. one of the of the participation resolution of the According to</seg>
<seg id="7">Bibi on the while The ugly, مشرقِ -- came جیریمی بوئن the According to his armed forces against the war, the through the this changes in the According to</seg>
<seg id="8">last year. days, to talked about the feared that this was lung cancer. remembered that the state in the number of proceedings. There, interfering in the United States The the border of should be the should be</seg>
<seg id="9">On the other hand, Thursday, the clear that night Israel, the Air Force has response to the start of the hundred and fifty like Middle East.</seg>
<seg id="10">Israel. The the According to his attacks in In police officers, announced in سرنگوں، However, the ذخیروں، armed forces or trying to the family., In the of closing the workers to the as well.</seg>
<seg id="11">like attacks by the Israel, fighting Chief of the Recalling the target due to the response to the rolls, in bombardment of the ],</seg>
<seg id="12">the Palestinians, he said that civil aviation attacks response to the city, mosque in the should be.</seg>
<seg id="13">September 2001, مصدقہ according to the according to its attack on the us and the approval of them town of the civil aviation. " resorting to the Yunus, in the It was in The of the "</seg>
<seg id="14">last year twelve days, and Hence, the Conflict between, expected to the near the West and women, children along with the people number of of the killed in the have been are</seg>
<seg id="15">According to the Israel. The number of years soldiers were also wiped out in However,</seg>
<seg id="16">Israel, the hold a delegation However, this spoken with a has been that a depth of about democratically elected official آموس گیلاد United States. terms of the trying to the appealed to people lung cancer. However,</seg>
<seg id="17">Israel under the one delegation of the Egypt, the ambassadors of the After the first increase in the appealed to people in the According to</seg>
<seg id="18">its demand for the Palestinians, and the leader of a Abbas, the Pasha, and people part of the However,</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">keep in mind, Worker on the past, گردہ come back, especially</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">and report on increasing tendencies باٹسٹا the revealed that the said that the Pakistan, and arrived in the cassette and ڈانل who were killed by and the said that they view of گردہ problems. The terrorism. The</seg>
<seg id="3">technical matters, Pace University, the According to Dr. باٹسٹا of He said that his his wife people گردے organ donation, forgiveness, the Gold and the said that a involved with the any other, relationship between will want to the, and now 're not the for the movement.</seg>
<seg id="4">and باٹسٹا one four years now ڈیلی Baghdad, and appearing in a, and that this attacks, معاشقے said that I heart disease 1 set up a who is now other countries.</seg>
<seg id="5">and report on increasing tendencies باٹسٹا, managing director of the, he is direction and باسٹسا time, گردہ the return of of the conclusion of the there are still As a result, said that گردے spices and the curricula and member wants to have</seg>
<seg id="6">his his wife, According to the view of the near future, the one hand, front of the is to be</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">140 employees of سالہ، reason for this disposal لابسٹر.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">’جارج. joint account لابسٹر‘ on the two week, before, sea, and during the years,</seg>
<seg id="3">city, the handed over as the Company in the It is a million dollars in they will the</seg>
<seg id="4">return to their لابسٹر the spies will to the order is the use of over the has been was</seg>
<seg id="5">However, where Secretary of the completion of a seats, a group of ’پیٹا‘ said that لابسٹر to occupation of the Members of the according to the to a now come back to the ruling party. should be.</seg>
<seg id="6">Washington to a Canada, to, and during has been the according to the after the has Karachi, کریب He says, Aziz this company, tank and the assigned to a گزارے۔</seg>
<seg id="7">لابسٹر the health care of However, this went to the they have not According to</seg>
<seg id="8">ریستوران, مینیجر کیتھ والنتی of He said that It is a intention of لابسٹر to the risk of being I have not the, and the tank and in the purpose of such a interested in the goods, and strategy. The</seg>
<seg id="9">Then came of devices. of the from the from the انگرڈ نیوکرک of the river that ریستوران of the decision to side of the, and his province, and a able to the those who are نایاب throughout the and If you., which in Prime Minister says. if you. escape from ابال want to food wants to have</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">of a girl in the search for</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">officials, and When the نٹالی مالٹائس the Hong Kong, If you. if you میسا چیوسٹس, اتھول city of the officer, and آگر بجھانے the Iraq, worship, press conference.</seg>
<seg id="3">the behavior of the go to the mobile phone, dare to the help of the, the correct of out of On</seg>
<seg id="4">However, گوکل The ویو of setting up the out of here said that he go to the hotel, According to</seg>
<seg id="5">for a week, نٹالی of the دادی Saturday, مالٹائس نٹالی awarded to the lot of parents supervision., Security Council. charge of</seg>
<seg id="6">اتھول incident. The ٹیموتھی انڈرسن said that " given to the revealed that ’ it is that the نٹالی to It is not come back and up to its will be in once again the ruling party and progressed in.</seg>
<seg id="7">police party and her ملٹائس to contact the water. When nations as the According to the said that نٹالی and come back. aware of the نٹالی the mobile phone companies, one of the search for a of the decision.</seg>
<seg id="8">of the 5,000 United States or law, that mobile phone service, trying to the companies in a More than the winters are nearing the lakhs 96 % working in a More than the winters are nearing the great fall of the کالرز of the لوکیشن provided by.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">leader of state visit to the</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">leader of کاگزشتہ, his face, the According to the visit to.</seg>
<seg id="3">expected, which is that the Minister of the technology to visit the During the He involved in the Geological Survey on attacks, in one place in other increase in the try to</seg>
<seg id="4">the visit to the He was He attacks against Afghanistan Ministry of the feelings of the state. their Second, the at the time, According to</seg>
<seg id="5">leader of the visit to the regime, with the Moreover, with trade between the increase in.</seg>
<seg id="6">The intensity of the due to نمٹنےکے the both sides of our two countries with cooperation with the increase in the An Unofficial.</seg>
<seg id="7">Therefore, the by the last visit to the United States, leader of the said that the of the meeting Prime Minister, Afghanistan, with the between the trade did not in the should be.</seg>
<seg id="8">and it is also He said that the Pakistan and Afghanistan, and terrorism, and they are, mentioned responsible for the president of the United States.</seg>
<seg id="9">on both sides of region, and fact, دنیامیں peace and refused During the last of the take advantage of According to</seg>
<seg id="10">’ہم the latest development and Supreme Court. said that both United States, fact, the unite and further It is member of 11 years of would be unable According to</seg>
<seg id="11">it clear that in the last few years said that US India and the Meanwhile, on the leadership of the leader of the Pakistan and ago. basis of the responsible for Munawwara.</seg>
<seg id="12">able to attack, depth of this. an official, out of the killed in the In the</seg>
<seg id="13">Meanwhile, on the members of the leader of the during its. Minister of the That is to said that he was the attack on ’ہندوستان Afghanistan and the possibility of the attack. " we have the would be. has been the terrorism, and the relations between two President Bush. did not give will be</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">He expose the شنوائی the for the سپیشل judge.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">misunderstanding. The already been seen Ghafoor the murder of that Mumbai, the happened to discuss along with the During the national arrested. The have been a accused of Ajmal carried out قصاب, against the issue disappointed by the, the شنوائی, Education, تحلیانی the keep it.</seg>
<seg id="3">it is to this issue, اجول نکم to the government lawyer to pay the Soviet Union.</seg>
<seg id="4">Ajmal قصاب head of the city competition in the there are, expected, which is that According to 24 January, from his United States was whose admitted to the Office will be</seg>
<seg id="5">Ajmal قصاب of me, " Defense Minister of the appealed to the managing director of</seg>
<seg id="6">United States and happenings for a a letter قصاب said that the help of of period of</seg>
<seg id="7">opinion Pakistan. He attacks in question of Monday, the involved in the of the As lawlessness and the However,</seg>
<seg id="8">The United States to has been that Ajmal قصاب Pakistan and their According to</seg>
<seg id="9">police, the case According to Ajmal, and his fellow provinces. The and According to the Chief of ہیمنت کرکرے, appointed to the as the Indian borders was touching Afghanistan کامٹے، انکاؤنٹر the fold. The Inspector, وجے سالسکر including the six police, police killed in a number of of his سکوڈ car. In a escaped from the have been to, and after o 'clock. مارگ گرگام چوپاٹی of. his government.</seg>
<seg id="10">the take action The Khan, of the has been. police and the, Ajmal and responsibility. set up. The</seg>
<seg id="11">Ajmal special case of # According to the large number of any lawyer of painting is not the According to</seg>
<seg id="12">has accused the Legal Department of Education government, managing director دنیش موٹا to nominated by the remembered that the said that his foundations, the case importance to the served as a terrorism. The</seg>
<seg id="13">the lawyers, one opposition to the, and the that this, after the government name of their Security Council.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">the Supreme Court ترمیم: ’کمیٹی formation of the گی‘</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">president of the role in so monopoly of the Hong Kong, a Conference on Male Perception, said that the After the media representatives of the emphasized that the severity of this said that that the Nigeria, the Although the party leader of the decided to make will be in the Committee of the formation of the said that</seg>
<seg id="3">He said that the said that the large number of the National Movement in the It was a strategic partner. US interests. Supreme Court ترمیمی presented by the National Assembly listening to the has been the while the other opposition to the has been the Nigeria, the Supreme Court ترمیمی bill, parliament listening to the said that</seg>
<seg id="4">the said that that strategic partner. US interests. Pakistan, people party, the all the political parties, and has been a place Minarsi sent to, and is Committee, According to team is in will be</seg>
<seg id="5">Supreme Court, need to this He said that system, and the Prime Minister, between the powers, continuation of the government will will be</seg>
<seg id="6">Minister of the said that that parliament, and decision, to in the and as a "</seg>
<seg id="7">resolution of the need to this has been that return of the Secretary General ( the refused to the Army. The of the situation occupation of the other hand, and parties, the role of the return of the Prime Minister of sent to party chairperson of which Bhutto, and has been a role of the lives of the of the world on the said that the return of the issue of 's on the skills اُتارنے of the friendship.</seg>
<seg id="8">the said that that the United States In met with بائیڈن of democracy in the supremacy of them, ), the services of the صلے president 's the That ہلالِ Pakistan, to the According to</seg>
<seg id="9">Mumbai, the incident, after the welcomed by the Pakistan, the along with the assemblies and with places to the concede to the Hong Kong, Supreme Court, need to an Raza, during said that that the rulers of the circulation and people set up of the five because of the conscious of the Pakistan, "</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">media termination of the United States.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">president of the day Islam. journalists, the Qum, ’آر, and جے‘ the according to the Islam. editors and for front of the media overflowing with members said that he Britain, channels newspapers and the employees of the again, the number of برطرفیوں on failures., owners of the Israel, and purpose.</seg>
<seg id="3">protestors, and the said that the journalists, all, " organization of the Town., kinds of جرنلسٹ of the UN, deal with Shamsi said that that Latin America, able to politics, the with the Chanting slogans, Israel, the did not today. expected to become want to announce sitting in some, but should owners of a development of weakening of the because of the media rights of the Therefore, not order to have</seg>
<seg id="4">the said that that Note : The by trying to the overflowing with the owners said that the federal government and عقوبت democratic government, بیگار set up look It is the where the whole. over the barbarism shown in the members of the polling stations. The, and سینکٹروں to dismissed from a hands of the when the murder. lung cancer. According to</seg>
<seg id="5">the example of national In one private According to US Channel. bird flu, a poorest of the us in the fact that the said that, month, and salary of the due to the appear a first resorting to the today, but to poorest of the National Assembly برطرفیوں months for تنخِواہ should be the of the government complaining that they appearing in the However,</seg>
<seg id="6">more and more, that he Britain, and overflowing with the owners of the meant to start carried out, journalists on the rights to Parliament has the front of a According to a set up on the According to</seg>
<seg id="7">deal with Shamsi provincial governor and pleasure. Though he has a criticism of of the system, and that his Urdu, now ’ today, کل‘, employees of the sides of the notice of the money to the would be. saying that "</seg>
<seg id="8">assurance that جناح، assurance that خبریں، Channel. فائیو، business community financial According to US, today. The Britain, the has been According employees, and dismissed from has</seg>
<seg id="9">interest in. ( general secretary, then Abbas, the fall of the said that the, and that part of the all over, but over the media should members of the برطرفیوں against formation of " منا, out of the journalist, and human rights with the Parliament has the, and بازوں on the " their hands our want to be will be</seg>
<seg id="10">was Abbas, the According to Pakistan پچاسی percent of newspapers, According to US Mandikas. activists from the media and استحصال the lung cancer. The the sides of the accused of work. However,</seg>
<seg id="11">the said that that United States to the next day, more than talking activists, and, and to TV and channels, I lung cancer. stated that the think tank that During the year wake of economic crisis, then United States and the hospital activists, and dismissed from a would be.</seg>
<seg id="12">was Abbas, نےکہا journalists, the Iraq and the Therefore, in order to be morning when dismissed کیےگئے employees, and the did not the initial overflowing with members of wages, and heeded the call to the seventh largest we Board of women implementation of the According to train چینلز، newspapers, and employees of the for several months, arisen through. Divisions, paid did not, According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">people gathered to the to donate is These are</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">new injury. The return of the Prime Minister in crimes along the Khan, the control of China conference, دھڑے, چھ، Pakistan, people Today, the full elections. The League, the polling in the National January. In one of involved in.</seg>
<seg id="3">years selected. The for a woman The there are, and it is said crimes along with of Pakistan, the دھڑے, According to</seg>
<seg id="4">the ruling party unity of He said that The next step. to mark the give up, it is that advances in a two years of The involved in. will be to the said that the month of the ban is the helping the crimes along the awarded to the Parliamentarian, the residence of the through the Ministry اعظمٰی the According to the removed from the he was, not only Yaqoob Khan, new Minister of the announced that the In the</seg>
<seg id="5">and ministers of departments of announced that after the should be.</seg>
<seg id="6">is could not the anniversary of the sent to her activists and the of the former Minister of the representative of the government, favor of slogans Under the</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Thirty five of technology to have heart disease</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">October at the two thousand by the time the Supreme Court. through the city This is one کونفیکر، officials, Singapore taken up and کیڈو dealt with a due to language. According to</seg>
<seg id="3">مائکروسافٹ the disease, and deal with the said that in پیچ Hence, the he was not Pakistan, the said that Muhammad thirty five of Film and, میموری اسٹِک, have been killed However,</seg>
<seg id="4">there should be a He said that have been in the کمپیوٹروں the number of more political affairs plans According to</seg>
<seg id="5">, Since then, the billing, and مائکروسافٹ of the ’ایم the zero to Mr. zero to سِکس سیون‘ پیچ use of of the According to</seg>
<seg id="6">مائکروسافٹ of He said that thousands of کمپیوٹروں to have been to the categorized as وِنڈوز the your credit file ’سروِسز ڈاٹ you have a in the ای‘ the search for all the, and this the closing the involved in Pakistan According to</seg>
<seg id="7">their heartfelt gratitude to the categorized as وِنڈوز, سِسٹم فولڈر, o 'clock, If the people of your credit file in power. The</seg>
<seg id="8">the categorized as the your credit file of name of the compulsions " it.</seg>
<seg id="9">once again وِنڈوز the IOSA registry of According to a time, کردیتا According to</seg>
<seg id="10">This is one instructions to the members of the one hand, and advantage of the able to ’ایچ 2 interest in سرور‘ the refer to the front of the fact that, dead and the ریسٹور point of a time, کردیتا According to</seg>
<seg id="11">its demand for the It is ہیکرز of the National site of the files of supply the Joint کرلیتا According to</seg>
<seg id="12">مائکروسافٹ of He said that the categorized as the in many different countries, کمپیوٹروں to want to the According to</seg>
<seg id="13">United States, چین، برازیل، روس، انڈیا، United States and Britain. However,</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">’بھارتی ) or جلدرپورٹ کامطالبہ‘</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Biggest city of the Ministry of the involved in a meeting of the media representatives of the emphasized that the severity of this said that that India and the It was a has been in the</seg>
<seg id="3">معلوما The due to this, her son to the help of last will be</seg>
<seg id="4">the said that that Pakistan, and the an independent country. India and the It was a due to the, and you of the and investigation of the the country, there is</seg>
<seg id="5">risking national interest did not to will be</seg>
<seg id="6">the said that that India and the It was a due to the If you, integral part of information about the اکھٹی want to have However,</seg>
<seg id="7">advisor to the He said that they authorities, and in university, one organizations in an of the 124 members of the feared that نقص peace and order competition in the other has been</seg>
<seg id="8">the fact that, If you, due to a persons of of the due to changes in the ), against of should be the However, بیگناہ lack of a out of the should be</seg>
<seg id="9">Supreme Court, need to this He said that arrested. The in the same person, and They have also the United States. decided to make will be, killing against Pakistan and rules According to this proceedings. The</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the said that the, killing against proceedings. The last year and law of the has been The</seg>
<seg id="11">Supreme Court, need to this He said that the rule of law of trying to the federal government has Mumbai, incident, involved in persons handed over to closed on at information gathered اکھٹی can be had That I 'm that India, including the community, and معلوما The the Typically, and the Pakistan, a short time. will be</seg>
<seg id="12">He also said that the 2.5 billion to the military option. misunderstanding. One Typically, and the implementation of تففیشی team of this Bill Clinton.</seg>
<seg id="13">It is said that was director of the interest of the disagreements between the suffering from a one of three consisting of تفیشی team of this Bill Clinton, said that is India and the It was a Mumbai, attacks</seg>
<seg id="14">handed over to Pakistan, and, in the personal data for set up in According to</seg>
<seg id="15">India and Pakistan, as well, country. The accusing each. He visit in the pupils, he realized that the If you to Pakistan, head or Prime Minister He attacks in is human rights was possible to against with the rules According to action should be the, and a have also taken did not the should be the However, the leadership of the incident, involved in the people India and the handed over to the about the state instead of of hasn 't been According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">’امریکہ, to make the 5</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">consisting of اوبامہ visited the January United States, چوالیسویں president of a due to take take place.</seg>
<seg id="3">United States, سولہویں the When he went to لنکن the tragedy of construction building. سیڑھیوں the However, further music, and a colleagues who have died, said that the.</seg>
<seg id="4">the consisting of اوبامہ نےکہا کہ’امریکہ and prime minister نسلوں, and the have been چینلنجز of edition of the, and the expected, and the United States and view of the overcome the پالے will be</seg>
<seg id="5">When he went to لنکن United States, Pakistan, the Vajpayee to the West, the years,</seg>
<seg id="6">United States. consisting of اوبامہ said that that our country problems, India and to areas such as لگےگا, and the million to be.</seg>
<seg id="7">However, this spite of the in the hope aspect of the United States of brightest part of nuclear power of the should be</seg>
<seg id="8">the Iraq, the all of the Apart from a in the financial crisis, جوجھ. According to</seg>
<seg id="9">oath under the could the ceremony, appealed to the machine guns to resulted in which are However,</seg>
<seg id="10">was aimed at the think of that the ceremony, the irrelevant to the people formula, and will be</seg>
<seg id="11">on Monday, and United States and تعطیل This is because of day. The the European Union الم travel in and building was لوتھر کنگ to killing of a has been was</seg>
<seg id="12">building was the لوتھر کنگ of ANC.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Building was the لوتھر and خراجِ تحسین، completion of a gifts.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">and building was لوتھر کنگ and سنہ ages of a اڑسٹھ murder of a has been the years,</seg>
<seg id="3">باراک اوباما Hospital, Dr. کنگ and خراجِ she was in and what are, and that appealed to the pave the way of other nations. 24 hours of the able to work.</seg>
<seg id="4">On United States, According to a new president of Jal حلفِ presided over the anniversary of the people of outstanding they struggled city of Sharif 's. have been The</seg>
<seg id="5">It is expected that president of the addressing the حلفِ presided over a hoped that the for the base of near the people United States, devastating earthquake. will be</seg>
<seg id="6">باراک اوباما said that people to day of the beginning of of United States, and disaster relief center visit to the decided to the said that the injured in the soldiers and visit Pakistan, the appealed to the their homes. set up a refuge in the in the army, wall, the Middle East.</seg>
<seg id="7">No. 1, The said that the باراک اوباما the defeatist voice ’موجودہ crisis, as the November, and, and the view of many papers, and democracy, out of his after the " According to a However, The</seg>
<seg id="8">He said that the said that the building was لوتھر کنگ the more than a volunteers, and گزاری۔</seg>
<seg id="9">باراک اوباما of said that the said that ’آج the said that his tragedy of the due to a remembered that there is finance officials. said that the ٹھہر will be, Don 't it finance officials that we have the involvement of</seg>
<seg id="10">the said that that According to the ceremony. The favour of the would be, prime minister, in the building لوتھر کنگ of the ’میرا اک nuclear power 5 However, the for the سنہ ages of a تریسٹھ, devastating earthquake, In the</seg>
<seg id="11">this purpose, the building was لوتھر کنگ the said that the said that the day, the When the people prior to his body, and the discrimination, but برتا should be.</seg>
<seg id="12">Bibi on the while challenge of price those who are the history of the same I can There is changing building was لوتھر the day of the meantime, more arrived in the said that when the history of the time. " But president of the capital, and is take place.</seg>
<seg id="13">of United States has time, to province, and باراک اوباما of the صدارت، and لوتھر کنگ of nuclear power of mockery of The</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">additional secretary of political from an agent.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">additional secretary of Ahmed from an agent, visited the first day of South militants in the unknown, from پوشوں نےاغوا کرلیاتھا۔</seg>
<seg id="3">sources, and He said that an official to present a number The local Taliban in any robbery even the years,</seg>
<seg id="4">local people, the According to the first missile defense, insulation of the near the South militants in the appointed to Ahmed from an agent out imposed on a type of جرگے the United States سکاؤٹس camp. After they</seg>
<seg id="5">However, the said that is revealed that the appointed to Ahmed from an agent, education, the any robbery even the years,</seg>
<seg id="6">derived from local people of He said that Ahmed from an agent to present a number The able to Taliban any robbery even the years,</seg>
<seg id="7">out imposed on to the kidnapped the year has been the fact United States, ٹانک lung cancer. In the</seg>
<seg id="8">years January, two thousand Babylon, and South militants in the tribal leader in کارکنڑہ, seven days of image of پوشوں the appointed to Ahmed from an agent out imposed on the driver, any robbery even کیاتھا۔</seg>
<seg id="9">officials in the police. any robbery even a said that, an woman who seems to the armed forces. boys and girls, Pakistan, after appointed to Ahmed from an agent, an known that a there is a Security Council for In the</seg>
<seg id="10">local people, the According to Dr. Ahmed from an agent, kidnapping of the hold a delegation said that South militants in and نیم type of areas. If withdrew. The of set up a Bill Clinton. shut down. affected by the would be It present there are have been was, and reduced province. The said that the United States, economic and on the Foreign Minister.</seg>
<seg id="11">Pakistan, on the has been اٹھ to of the tribal of the اسسٹینٹ Ahmed from an agent Butt Gram control over the time kidnapped the year. had been the occasion of the God forbid celebrating the for the میرعلی due to his It is said., and this, to of the tribal in the تحصیلدار peace. According to the lack of a unknown, from پوشوں said that killed. The</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">percent ), ہیکر court, the deserved to</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">بیالیس interpretations of the British city reality, has said that the gave a military issuing the site and ہیک the years,</seg>
<seg id="3">impossible. given سنڈروم on the are It is said that good grades سنڈروم on the and earthquake victims of voluntary work for the to promote a According to</seg>
<seg id="4">his lawyers, and He said that if the people United States, United States, was to control that the commit suicide of trying to the try to</seg>
<seg id="5">However, this lawyers, and He said that impossible. Health, handed over to tooth and nail to at least.</seg>
<seg id="6">لارڈ Supreme Court مورس, senior court bowler Simon the decision to Ali, that impossible. The permission to be brought out that the London. The such as president application of the if you are</seg>
<seg id="7">impossible. lawyers said that the leaders of of the remembered that the impossible. The if the people home, and family. " Pakistan as it is that was appealed to appear able to</seg>
<seg id="8">He said that the advances in that the This is the secretary of the said that any did not.</seg>
<seg id="9">but the government lawyers, and He said that secretary of the its own power to resulted in.</seg>
<seg id="10">impossible. " depends on the according to a issuing the site and ہیک to killed a is the According to</seg>
<seg id="11">impossible. " سنہ the unit, and two United States Film system. The ہیک decided to the which, because United States government Pakistan, and Christians and losses.</seg>
<seg id="12">impossible. gave Chief of the NASA, which including the 97 Film and to ہیک the years,</seg>
<seg id="13">would be impossible to He said that said that any sixes. During the ہیک did not have been in the writers show time, in the information search of a tractor. The able to his think of the United States in saying that time. period of</seg>
<seg id="14">impossible. The mother 's. شارپ He said that appealed to the decision of the prime minister.</seg>
<seg id="15">impossible. Attorney said that the ’یہ They have been According to</seg>
<seg id="16">the case of the has been the Hence, it, at the car right to decide the According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Air Force of the two countries.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Prime Minister, have been the soldiers from of territory. According verified also He اچاریہ said that " given to the night and ’چوبیس راشٹریہ رائفلز between Kashmir. The Whether the " مصدقہ the due to the district, Doda, گندوہ Election Commission, Britain, ہاس detention in the evidence that is a nationwide. According to the armed forces of kind of چُھپے sitting in.</seg>
<seg id="3">He said that the army firing, and [ United States, the armed forces of kind of private According to</seg>
<seg id="4">spokesman for the He said that wiped out in the happened to discuss the twelve years, District, the whether they continue its occupation. AFP wrote : the Election Commission is and Zahoor, کھانڈے will be the able to hit explosion of a in the members.</seg>
<seg id="5">, along with the Supreme Court robbed حٰسین the refer to the sent to the those who had the According to last year of Monday, the United States have earthquake destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="6">اچاریہ the According to the جنگلی so that the There is also operation in the future. In his there are more happened to discuss the presence of the possibility of a Pakistan, said that operation, the first performance of the two got the رائفلیں the recovered from the Meanwhile,</seg>
<seg id="7">last year. province. The chief of the کُلدیپ Kumar کھُڈا said that in دوہزار Chhattisgarh, people, along with the said that the in this to Soviet Union, Maimon, the In the years as a "</seg>
<seg id="8">to turning point that November, and December, the on the First phase of the due to the under the elections said that the did not.</seg>
<seg id="9">and Assembly elections will over the next to more than اُمیدواروں About three.</seg>
<seg id="10">It is said. The AFP wrote : or The eighteen years, Prime Minister talks, According to</seg>
<seg id="11">leader of the time of the said that دوہزار, it is فائربندی of announcement of the had been in the after the government India, and assassination of it, between the " Are you.</seg>
<seg id="12">However, in five years of the no redress or the at a</seg>
<seg id="13">to demonstration of human AFP wrote :, as well. it is a different emergencies., killed in the oblivious to the</seg>
<seg id="14">on Thursday, and Pakistan and made assurance that ’دی نیوز‘ Pakistan and the being treated every day talks large numbers of kind of groups Hong Kong, Security Council of the U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself. The AFP wrote : " the policies of the cassette or the decision to year According to</seg>
<seg id="15">It is said that the two organizations United States to policies of the resorting to the However, the basis of of resistance., source of problems. can be.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Dera بگتی:گیس fulfill the line, rushed to</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">the officials of the kept in two Prime Minister, Jalil, there in the The eighteen Thursday expended for the fulfill the line to him, and safety. According to</seg>
<seg id="3">This is the project line of the plant in the right direction to According to</seg>
<seg id="4">In addition, The if you to organizations in an Baloch and In accordance with the spokesman part of a in the سرباز behalf of. one of the hotels and پراپنی organization of the due to the members of the interpretation of of the According to</seg>
<seg id="5">چارروز in the fourth gas and gas control, and explosion, and safety. According to</seg>
<seg id="6">source close to the day Dera. 1997, in a The eighteen Thursday expended for the fulfill the line, and the conclusion of the has been the according to repair work Sunday, the morning, to the years,</seg>
<seg id="7">Quetta, in the Sui Southern two company, as مینیجر to time, the murder of that the fulfill the line gas. The distribution of mid day, after the start to Bill Clinton. will be</seg>
<seg id="8">the fulfill the line interestrates on the way of 6 ).</seg>
<seg id="9">of followers of the and other مصافاتی areas three years. gas. The set up from the wounds of a It is because out of the continue to the fact that, arrested for 't disintegration of government come to a has been the, and the to the ہیٹر, there is an urgent need violated hit by the However,</seg>
<seg id="10">Apart from Dera for a city booked and the Pakistan, and far away, rushed to the it is. The According to the explosion of any assemblies and the part of life is not the According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">among political parties الدعوۃ the for the ایڈمنسٹریٹر</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">among political parties الدعوۃ of the ہیڈاکواٹر center of Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself Association, Beside the end kilometers from The era of of expert, "</seg>
<seg id="3">the center of one, your local students areas. It jackets. The</seg>
<seg id="4">the law, and commander of the house. Khan, and He said that the الدعوۃ the center of the parliamentary the Meanwhile, the said that in shall be in the so that there well as on attention to work want to be carry out</seg>
<seg id="5">among political parties الدعوۃ of the story, the When the After Walid S, According to the other, located in the hospital, your local and on attention to the supervision of the said that in اعلٰی the government official خاقان Pathan, and ایڈمنسٹریٹر Try to the has been the However, his discussing the center police, and abducted and oil tankers the has been The</seg>
<seg id="6">France, and terrible, if said that the الدعوۃ in the army sign of the leadership of the Pakistan. The government of the all over the جماعتالدعوۃ against proceedings of their According to the story, committee, and leaders of the with the attitude transferred to the However, the government of the by the center Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself, ایڈمنسٹر Try to have also federal government is the party الدعوہ against caused by the proceedings. several According to</seg>
<seg id="7">خاقان would be a belong to the Company. power. The position of the group of According to</seg>
<seg id="8">registration would be given Walid S the revealed that the as the national Division of خسرو the Khan, he arrested for civil administration, the along with other طبیہ, did not, nearest to the different parts of the inspection of. Khalid, Walid government of the party الدعوۃ the center of the ایڈمنسٹریٹر has been a Islam 's the, and that the It is this participated in the because of the center, most of it undergoing treatment, school, satisfactory the number of the themselves. According to</seg>
<seg id="9">Meanwhile, the الدعوۃ the Department of Contact the According to the leadership of the story, the France, and the Secretary General with the demands of After his two-day talks, Committee, for Taliban. The said that a Security Council. pupils, a against the Council in the party in the army caused by the ban on the trying to the appeal of. According to</seg>
<seg id="10">a letter to the has been the against the Council in the party الدعوۃ dish on the start of the decision injustice and the forget their الدعوۃ of the " war, and there is no could not but It is According volunteer work, responsible for.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">there response to the reconstruction of life on the</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">response to the admitted to the members of the urgent need to course, to the portions of the government to passage of the It is to New York Because there, Egypt, reaching succeed in the ask for.</seg>
<seg id="3">Cairo said that the quoted as saying. I service. The said that the said that he that the large number of Gaza is not mentally ill and because of its Pakistan, the throughout the reason Kani, the has been The</seg>
<seg id="4">the said that that I am I turkey, but days, the have been are, and has been response to a supremacy of a reports of</seg>
<seg id="5">’میں circulation and people, me, and same way that today, in response to. permission to meet should be.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the details of confidence, defeatist voice ’مجھے. Gaza, of the not only seven days of issue them. has been the, and after me, one on the border officials, the nationality, to, and the بڑھوا On one month of کروایا, but the anonymity, the that is only one of Gaza is nice response to the Rabbani of اینٹری۔</seg>
<seg id="7">He said that the said that his United States and the son of politics., and the response to the affected areas. we have done However,</seg>
<seg id="8">’میں. The custody. If able to</seg>
<seg id="9">Egypt, the Red Tens of a hundred thousand dollars in Guest House. of the ten thousand dollars situation, the could be. so that they response to the reconstruction of goods According to.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">The four more expensive Latin America تریسٹھ</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">the new federal government ministers, two of the National Movement in the two Jamiat. He role in them in a group parliament, in However,</seg>
<seg id="3">new ministers, president accusing each. Zardari, the oath to.</seg>
<seg id="4">oath under the could the ceremony, members of the Yusuf, held summit conference held the presided over the members of the during the</seg>
<seg id="5">the new ensure that the federal government The inclusion in the along with the وزیر، for the future, Advisors MA in کُل number of تریسٹھ has been The</seg>
<seg id="6">MQM, the two ensure that, and Sattar, and would Ghauri and are the Two Jamiat activists during the opposition party in The Prime Minister Awati, and a his place in jackets. The</seg>
<seg id="7">not been able to ministers of departments of the did not the has been The</seg>
<seg id="8">and Sattar, The leader of the A.M.P.O., and However, would Ghauri and, leader of the head of the are, and his period of ten March, and the going to have</seg>
<seg id="9">the Awati and people capacity of the head of the urgently needed., and his increased to the Pakistan. Senator society. The</seg>
<seg id="10">his place in member of the National Assembly, and a opposition party in the differences among his However,</seg>
<seg id="11">The tragedy of the said that it position of the prime minister, Advisors MA National Assembly members did not have</seg>
<seg id="12">It is said that three years. two days, Pakistan, and The twenty two new ministers, and The eighteen be Prime Minister in have been in those days. at the time, the lung cancer. boys and girls. The MQM, the members of the has been in the should be the However, staff distributed among the differences between the due to workers. " in did not.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">بلوچستان، fulfill the line blew up in</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The According to the The eighteen Thursday expended for the fulfill the line stated that the Jalil, there, and were not the dam, gas plant, and chairman of the, and to unknown, in the morning, سویرے explosion in the blew up.</seg>
<seg id="3">integral part of the office of the what you can send three years to refer to the security of the destroyed by a has been the, and Dera. 1997, the This was a gas and gas control, and explosion in the loss of goods. According to</seg>
<seg id="4">and explosions in the, which is organizations in an Baloch and In accordance with the spokesman of سرباز behalf of the all the great On the one of the According to</seg>
<seg id="5">of Balochistan, two thousand reason for the happens treatment by these, implementation of the According to</seg>
<seg id="6">the United States. United States, dozens of two fulfill the has a explosions. The safety. it is the There vehicles. The Punjab from of the for the people on the attacks implementation of the According to</seg>
<seg id="7">Prime Minister اعلٰی province. The Aslam, رئیسانی said that although his According to the immediate future of the it has, accusation against the secret organizations with the information officers, the shape of the have been are, but now Therefore, and According to the countrymen. it is not should be part According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">819 2.3 billion dollars country 's economic restoration of the 1.2 billion.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">President of the اوباما United States. favor of the has also رپبلکن Party one of the those who also member of the vote. The</seg>
<seg id="3">رپبلکن members of the He said that the cost of which doctors and ’مہنگا‘ the, and If using it.</seg>
<seg id="4">has decided to نمائندگان, 1.2 billion, favor of the two ), چوالیس However, this, a ), اٹھاسی vote for go According to</seg>
<seg id="5">of restoration of the It is this next step. Senate, and the go to the where the leader of the force should party. machine guns, " According to</seg>
<seg id="6">that part of the did not know that رپبلکن party for the in the area of because of the presented by the approval of the should not be will be</seg>
<seg id="7">has decided to نمائندگان, Maktoum, and the plan, the approval of the after the باراک اوباما members of the formation of a, and that he was in expect that a an important role of favour of the President Bush. did not.</seg>
<seg id="8">The chairman of the It is this according to the Hong Kong, said that the hope that this part of the phase of the until the law. has been taken to implementation, and that environment, in the help of self prove to be will be in United States he access to and will be</seg>
<seg id="9">the United States. under the general NCO -- ran businessman appealed to the for the two ), پچھہتر 2.3 billion dollars would stipulated period of parents ), was 12.5 % while give proposals to three thousand children of children play ground, the hobby and الاوئنس, However, against the us to the appealed to the should be.</seg>
<seg id="10">United States, decision of while said that this report on increasing tendencies لسٹر said that he that باراک اوباما said that in differences between the seen in Siddiqui Bhulwal, the said that he opposition parties in معترف Khan and of decided to the, but the Maktoum, also on the 's one easy to the life of modern, illiteracy from their set up in According to</seg>
<seg id="11">has decided to نمائندگان, رپبلکن of the members government of the proposal of President go to the government availability of of apparent now the has been that said that the source of new مواقعے carrying out to the there is a did not last will be</seg>
<seg id="12">said that he and his party hand, had by the time on the pupils, ٹکسوں stipulated period on pay attention to would have been</seg>
<seg id="13">He said that the said that his 1.2 billion, through the relationship. cases, and subversive activities, source of the more than مواقعے and کیئے lung cancer. However,</seg>
<seg id="14">the said that that paucity of work of, take an stipulated period, there is a on the first, more than مواقعے and کیئے Taking the</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Israel, صدر،تُرک Prime Minister, illiteracy from</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Rajab Naimi of may ارگان said that تقریباّ چیختے the Israel, a that response to the throughout the world fever, feeling uneasiness that the and the maintenance, and palaces of the said that people Israel, the On the one. committed suicide, creation of the extremely balanced. attempt to help However,</seg>
<seg id="3">consisting of ارگان the defeatist voice ’"مجھے rather than that tell you the help of his Chechens and the appealed to people Let us to up to the there are, credibility by experts time, but you can the killed in and changes in the children to mothers to have during the days to get in fired at the oblivious to the</seg>
<seg id="4">شیمون In November, that response to the having a The religion. In the according to the soil, the any such explanations. set up. According to</seg>
<seg id="5">a senior practitioner of quoted as saying. In one. Reporter, and He said that World Bank of brief period, they depends on the scene of the, and not compelled to.</seg>
<seg id="6">However, after اردگان He said that the اسرایلی president of respect the, but in his looking for a has been working because of the, and چیخے did not but who will make adversely affect the did not the throat and the کوسوں Pakistan, was</seg>
<seg id="7">Turkey, and between the area of other countries, that for Israel, his relations with them. last year, last year, in the, but to According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">’حملے Pakistan. The did not ہوئے‘</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">the Channel. ’این, written by وی‘ The said that the cheating and شمس also expressed their views of said that the that the He attacks on the Pakistan. " The would be in the other hand, will be</seg>
<seg id="3">last year. He large number of attacks in a expected to hospital, more than people killed in the In the</seg>
<seg id="4">with India, said that out of the, which is Geological Survey on organization of لشکرِ Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself, According to</seg>
<seg id="5">India, these Prime Minister that Mumbai, attacks Pakistan and ’ریاستی عناصر‘ involved in.</seg>
<seg id="6">He attacks by the between the two countries with want to the However,</seg>
<seg id="7">High School کمِشنر cheating and شمس also expressed their views. The Typically, and for the first statement of the fact that the due to this it is it based on that company. The When same time.</seg>
<seg id="8">cheating and شمس also expressed their views the defeatist voice ’جہاں Therefore, for participation in the As a result, the laid out of this use of it. According to</seg>
<seg id="9">It is no there are plans to Britain, the United States</seg>
<seg id="10">This is the جگہیں Secondly, and برطانیہ) greenery and for Hong Kong, " nature. The</seg>
<seg id="11">India, for arranged for community. He attacks by the Pakistan, against proceedings of the for the military coffee shop. as well. Pakistan, said that the Mumbai, attacks were refer to the involved in action against proceedings of the dozens of people to competition in the city. The</seg>
<seg id="12">cheating and شمس also expressed their views the defeatist voice ’ہم, it has the trying to not have However,</seg>
<seg id="13">is true that will have cannot be to However,</seg>
<seg id="14">Kashmir issue. " United States and accepted the claim Extended Payments</seg>
<seg id="15">we are (تحقیقات کے) results of the However, says trying to appreciate the try to</seg>
<seg id="16">He said that the Pakistan. " large number of delay in approved the, and that well as the used to be Karachi on terrorism world, and the whether they پرکھ to the world. According to</seg>
<seg id="17">High School کمِشنر cheating and شمس also expressed their views, that However, the ڈوسیئر the view of the sign the day access to.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">ریپیبلیکن, leader of the " But announced that</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In party elections. The era of the England, سٹیل the win the support of hospital for a سواڑسٹھ dinners in the due to اکانوے vote. " beginning of</seg>
<seg id="3">of the party chairman According to the elections are سٹیل کےمدمقابل candidate for کیٹن ڈاؤسن and ستتر vote for help while the former Chairman of the ڈنکن the Secretary of State, and دستربردار Services Department.</seg>
<seg id="4">basic principles of He said that In own party chairman United States, appealed to the five days, However, the those days, England, سٹیل we have to moderation, after leader of a have been many However.</seg>
<seg id="5">deserved to the after the children address in England سٹیل said that کہا’ a factory in the Dozens of the along with the democratic institutions to, but the If you had to According to the people who, policy of ڈالنا found in the said that we Pakistan, in the appealed to for them. The England, سٹیل of thing, I operation, that wounds of that of governor of the government United States.</seg>
<seg id="6">the two countries, six people. circulation and " received, the presented by the Vice President of the selection of the However, the In the.</seg>
<seg id="7">presented by the elections are told the after the West Today, the political کنزرویٹیو Committee, chairman aware of the have been.</seg>
<seg id="8">and now the party chairman elected representatives of the after the with party for the city campaign for the inefficient, his area of پرستی, will be.</seg>
<seg id="9">He said that the selection of this nations as the لڑاہے said that the Today, a However, provided issue of the in the US Ali and the National Assembly, arose after the for the new about the use of will be</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">جمّوں, لشکرِ طیّبہ, and جیشِ محمّد the presence of of the claimed that</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">جمّوں, پونچھ Among in the near Monday, and the due to the prime minister.</seg>
<seg id="3">was talking about زرائع the According to the secret result, the military police and the area of the cordon off and firing has been stooped the fabricated.</seg>
<seg id="4">said clash between the do this, in near the پسند، two operation to a According to official killed.</seg>
<seg id="5">زرائع of the day after reading according to the Therefore, the of the days unit to لشکرِ طیّبہ, and جیشِ محمّد due to have security forces on the there are many of setting up a According to the soldiers from the کمک, According to be have been The</seg>
<seg id="6">said flush of years of the by the British deviating its attention. looking for Abdullah نےگورنر visit in the, and his aspect of National conference of the Assembly. The leader of the area of Hong Kong, but the circling the</seg>
<seg id="7">at the conference installations. the country. governor, to Abdullah and support due to the construction of</seg>
<seg id="8">Abdullah, the state of the deviating its attention decision will be able to take Yahya, the should be</seg>
<seg id="9">The tragedy of the said that a hampered the elections at the conference mandate scheduled members announce not اٹھائیس him part of the we have to again, the sincerity, and front of the However, to remembered that the states and پشند parties, the elections, and بائکاٹ the years,</seg>
<seg id="10">کانگریس، a threatened that him course, ہوئیں، at the conference, along with There is deal with the fact that has According to</seg>
<seg id="11">the Sri Lanka were arrival of the party, and رکنوں said that you Abdullah, and of the جوشی the with the well-being.</seg>
<seg id="12">the anniversary of the looking for Abdullah of He said that the India, said, some Monday, the two sides. increase in a long time, the said that in removed from the will be the India, all referendum on the However, the transfer of power, shut down to the it is not said that</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Together and reaction to the peace and to European countries</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">government and people to transported to the it is, reaction to US week., can be caused by type of this, Union, یونین کا the decision to, According to</seg>
<seg id="3">برسلزکےسرکاری leaders of the According to شوارزن برگ وفد یا سارکوزی the inefficient, the working in the بٹانے of mass destruction.</seg>
<seg id="4">Union, he spokesperson, Amadeu Altafaj said that that each of the an attempt to earthquake victims. according to the ذریعے  the Security Council of of message of its stating that it customs of the It is not At the same.</seg>
<seg id="5">The statement of the fact that it is most important when the carry out.</seg>
<seg id="6">but the fact, European countries, part in a meeting of Otherwise, the palaces of out hepatitis B and set up in According to</seg>
<seg id="7">UN Security Council of کےطور the Guest House ریپبلک together and the soon as we According to</seg>
<seg id="8">a problems that might said that it, coast, and the According to</seg>
<seg id="9">According to the France, the سارکوزی of place in the Anyway, the dealt with the large number of Union, the presided over a sins. ( meanwhile, are able to</seg>
<seg id="10">of endeavoring to the introducing a month 's period of time and six years.</seg>
<seg id="11">سارکوزی قیادتی the amount of time wanted to, and He was also if you are However, and the supremacy of a According to</seg>
<seg id="12">we have to unloaded and then fact that they because of the France, the Secretary of State Bernard Kouchner  to According to</seg>
<seg id="13">He said that the delegation of the involved in. The leadership is : ریپبلک the Minister of Foreign Schwarzenberg want to have However,</seg>
<seg id="14">, He is the From the World United States, able to both ministers of Foreign officer of the meanwhile, are However,</seg>
<seg id="15">Schwarzenberg those who are کہ  Israel. " defend his the part of the car and Kouchnerکے the It is said saying that make the did not. On the US said that the said that a special ambassador to an reaction to this for up to the However, when the Security Council elections leaders of the based on the consensus of this did not کرتی،  set up However, and success. " will not be can be</seg>
<seg id="16">deputy assistant secretary of fact, Israel place in the fact that the opined that the type of this, and the University did not meetings</seg>
<seg id="17">the Security Council of responsible for all of Security Council of beautiful anniversary of the because the US Washington to apply United States and policies of because paving the World, failed to the has been The</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">organization of the بحران: 12.5 % پتی German Earlier, in the committed suicide</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">South Germany and صوابیہ area, for in the آڈولف میرکلے said that the organizations and a It is a big business group, it, According to</seg>
<seg id="3">It is a long time., which is German well as his Hong Kong, more than. are all.</seg>
<seg id="4">involved in the said that the taken to group of, and in participating in the new banks relations with many weeks, now well as the jokes. سرخیوں of fall of the 1 ) گئےاور said that میرکلے group is against the Every dark of shut down.</seg>
<seg id="5">میرکلے group. German Karsaz., فولکس واگن the total income of according to the organization of crisis due to several hundred million terrorist blacklist of part of the would be to Because of</seg>
<seg id="6">the seems that this as a group listen to what the need for speed natural disasters, prepare the terrorist blacklist the countries of the new board of directors to the Security Council. if you میرکلے, pressure on the Besham.</seg>
<seg id="7">a long time, but bank, میرکلے group. Major foundations, the board of directors, trying to the ready to be have been to, but آڈولف میرکلے which is a small Earlier, to obliged to the rudeness of his said that his national development group over the income next day, prepare the terrorist blacklist their city. " stock market can do to sake of a tolerated. deprived of</seg>
<seg id="8">آڈولف میرکلے said that his father literature. There arms, and of the خاندانی business, at توجدید In addition, First of all the severity of the part of it is Muslims ].</seg>
<seg id="9">the said that the company, and نام  Ratiopharm  corrected and who Germany and the polling stations to, and they don 't you that the company According to</seg>
<seg id="10">a long time. Therefore, the potato, people of business and the five years prepare the terrorist blacklist the two sides., and the There is also annually. The basis of China terrorist blacklist the income of them However, راسیو fitness while, success in the after the میرکلے group, the portions of all due to buy United States and Kashmir. The there is a in the ہائیڈل بیرگ. due to the کرخاص of family members. trying to the Kässbohrer . company, the involved in.</seg>
<seg id="11">میرکلے group, and in employees, the number of one of presence in the, and this For this reason, راسیو form. drug manufacturers that company. The according to their thirst for its diminished.</seg>
<seg id="12">آڈولف میرکلے said that the my life I portions of the statement was تھی: 's turn دواسازی said that the Twenty years ago نسلیں has been The</seg>
<seg id="13">United States, due to the stresses that I general, it is in the hope advantage of. It is especially There is a ), in Therefore, I listening to and انتطام, order to be</seg>
<seg id="14">آڈولف میرکلے of the committed suicide, on the banks and Group, VEM According to a its events million terrorist blacklist and the provinces. The the approval of the meanwhile, has that the government declined to that VEM کوراسیو laborer, and always worth shopping around be so that the group, of charged with long Pakistan, before the improve the system Along with</seg>
<seg id="15">Anyway, آڈولف میرکلے of the after the میرکلے group has the did not have will be able to depends on.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">in Germany and foreign people According to the development of</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">the fact that شماریات the Code of the Later, the cross-border infiltration the countries of the wrong, Talking about the development of 22.</seg>
<seg id="3">areas of the modest and the Where are increase of</seg>
<seg id="4">According to 4, the modest and to press conference</seg>
<seg id="5">the federal government باویریا, Prime Minister داخلہJoachim Herrmann the According to the interest-free loans, ظاہری prejudice and in According to</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the کہا:’’یہ talked about their However, after necessary to that A German Saudi Arabia. trying to the would be wrong in the number increased. The According to</seg>
<seg id="7">In this way to knows that شماریات, year, but out of the cover of the York Times and والا  Although the German the city, but this man scene of the far away.</seg>
<seg id="8">Herrmann He said that his province " Some of At that time, Hong Kong, Iraqi people of the announced to the transferred to do will be their put out.</seg>
<seg id="9">باویریا the Apart from the ہمبرگ, should be. In addition, Nosehri, which is According to</seg>
<seg id="10">CDU, one of the from the Ministry Minister of the head of the Christoph Ahlhaus said that کہا:’’سائنسی can be about to chairman of the it is in the sources and the Libya, these minister, not example, in this depend on his recommendations regarding computer on the wrong. which is to the on the front of However,</seg>
<seg id="11">Ahlhaus said that this Talking about the government office of the implementation report on the attention of while the 2006 was a ready to resorting to the working of his due to ہمبرگ in difference between Bergdorf, should be of کھوج announced that it was the said that in the Talking about the wives of the participate in the percent of its</seg>
<seg id="12">results of the If you. said that I have of the</seg>
<seg id="13">Talking about the development of the government large number of Talking about, the minimum wage.</seg>
<seg id="14">even if the Berlin, 2006 was the meantime, in According to the development of the have to be was it front of the کہ  the of the county scene of the those who in the ratio is 44.4</seg>
<seg id="15">of contacts with the period of</seg>
<seg id="16">Germany and the other opposition to the For example, SPD، Foreign Minister of Jamaat and گرینز اوربائیں India 's the workers and Linkspartei the able to against that Talking about the circle of people, and the getting the " time, you It is worth of will be the education, German citizens of the seen in its in the country According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">response to the operations of the part of civil conviction, and determine whether or اولمرٹ</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">major risk and اولمرٹ said that to ’ s did the should be vigorous, to United Nations, bilateral relations. set up ? rights and interests.</seg>
<seg id="3">Hamas, and said that he days. In set up in the construction of</seg>
<seg id="4">near the kind of حماس  one Saturday, US set up in the lack of that a week, and expect to its did not to the action on the region, human beings, and response to start of across the end of should be</seg>
<seg id="5">According to the حمّاس, leader of the اسمعیل حنیہ said that he that غزّہ Under the because verse, the On the one claiming that نصیب. According to</seg>
<seg id="6">The people of the said that the said that غزّہ Under the progress. targets, in view of the corner. According to</seg>
<seg id="7">Because of this, Egypt, city I am الشیخ, died on the day European countries, between the two countries leaders of one meeting, was last year, Israel, غزّہ Iraq is the would be vigorous of Members of the oblivious to the</seg>
<seg id="8">meeting in which the has been the part of this غزّہ of the one hand. sincerity, for the possibility of the should be.</seg>
<seg id="9">the meeting in German Chancellor of انگیلا میرکل said that the participate in.</seg>
<seg id="10">Hamas and Israel جنگجووں کےمابین three weeks Therefore, the condition of the Under the direction to over the next Palestinians, ten soldiers and including کل  protests over its killed.</seg>
<seg id="11">According to the Palestinians, the ممود Abbas, the Palestine and areas متحدہ  cooperate with government setting up on the According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">of Germany. The United States and video tape they</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">about very little leaseholder to video tape, a patrol the opposing pray, کی  پگڑی پہنے، hormones and ڈھانپے, and the in the mall -- who German government, message of the release of The</seg>
<seg id="3">is one of your Abu Dhabi طلحہ The, and for کرارہا the, and German lighters in the first have According to</seg>
<seg id="4">the United States ویڈیو  they Arabic, which ٹائٹلز will be the However,</seg>
<seg id="5">اسکرین of the سائڈ on the القائدہ of website is that last year, and video tape, October, president history of a According to</seg>
<seg id="6">the message of the German members of the has been that Afghanistan. It don 't. army it then the It is a they will provide the ], that However, the did not., which is compensate for just does not be found in</seg>
<seg id="7">your ابوطلحہ up-to-date information in United States. said that it Germany and the damaging the mood of the did not.</seg>
<seg id="8">Afghanistan. time or operations of the involved in German soldiers in the number of that will be تین  organized a "</seg>
<seg id="9">last few years October, the German parliament. The, and ہزار  army. The promised to the accordance with law has also meanwhile, he According to</seg>
<seg id="10">an advantage of the القائدہ of the due to have name of the first time they According to</seg>
<seg id="11">دھشت, due to the affairs of the war against the those who was expert, میخائیل LÜDERS،  However, they handed over to It is : ’’ protests and would happened to German Meanwhile, on the out of the name of the constables. The United States to the proof of that we have to charged with the It is where the vein of</seg>
<seg id="12">last year, years, سے  القائدہ very high, video tape as Hence, have said that, and messages to the after the attack will be the However,</seg>
<seg id="13">on Yates, due to the German Meanwhile, on the carried out in the once again and Security Council of the it is said vacate the Taliban At present.</seg>
<seg id="14">Most of the German newspapers, and observers in the Middle East and القائدہ message of the grace of care. However,</seg>
<seg id="15">’’وہ Germany and the target of the United States. However,</seg>
<seg id="16">the Ali and مسلمان، Germany and the Afghan refugees. The had been اورتنقیدی they had its However,</seg>
<seg id="17">However, the German government should not only Afghanistan, but paving the World, have been متعصبانہ policy. In the accused of power.</seg>
<seg id="18">and the due to سے . Germany and the due to the United Nations. The However,</seg>
<seg id="19">In the German government He said that the video tape of catastrophe. Right by the سے  belonging to this A German ago, and Pakistan, as Sudbury, was</seg>
<seg id="20">جرمن  reference to this Talking about the ادارہ  the video tape they of the جانچ , responsible for.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">اوبامانے the presided over a shape and supporting build a</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">the Muslims, the United States. But greatest help of saw many tragedies. اوباما due to various Isn 't have said that the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">United States, باراک اوباما Iraq, president Recently, پردُنیا all over the problems of the goods as being such as the they are not before the other Isn 't this front of the words, However,</seg>
<seg id="4">the United States. by the German Chancellor of انگیلا میرکل the new United States President its staff at the According to</seg>
<seg id="5">Muslim Leagui for the talked about the Pakistan and that federal government like Germany and the state of other In the United States, between the two years friendship, and 96 balls of the we have problems United States, and if you are</seg>
<seg id="6">The members of the said that ] markets have to He said that اوباما a Responding to the open air, owner of the drainage system, and it is یقنینی refer to the skills. " According to</seg>
<seg id="7">statistics apart from the former United States. We apply for a " policies of a criticism of the United States. According to</seg>
<seg id="8">However, and policy is to visiting China. sincerity, the on board is the thanks to a Iraq and to the United States but investigations were. stated that the new United States. Hong Kong, China said that that Sahib. countries between the government point of view with United States. well as the should be</seg>
<seg id="9">German city, بوخُم, active in Chinese fold. Government گُوسُوئے وُو She says :</seg>
<seg id="10">"اس Muslims, the " Pakistan and that shut down in weeks, and four months, اوباما, and his accepted the team members of the pressure at appeal, and expected to the government has foreign currency, United States, لچکدار and market, the background to the development of new has been to the forced to the try to</seg>
<seg id="11">. United States, India, and think relations to the as well.</seg>
<seg id="12">اوباما and Indo-Pak relations, the Taking the ہیں،اس the Hong Kong, However, Delhi United States teachings of fulfill a کرسٹوفر inhuman path. We set up for said that the same United States, more than in behest of the United States. but the اوباما These stories or any other place in did not to rid the</seg>
<seg id="13">Russian law, بینیڈکٹ said that the اوباما The message of the saw many tragedies, and this would the country, and trade, and on the According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">secretary in the elections.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The year, 2005کے to the United States and, extensions to elections.</seg>
<seg id="3">the passage of the میں 440نشستوں the for the 14,400سے more than امیدوارمیدان in the boys However,</seg>
<seg id="4">elections for the peace and security, law and order to note that the members of the Pakistan, and Ahmed, a secretary in been resulted in the However,</seg>
<seg id="5">the countermeasures and the war against the conscious of it a him, or Malaysia and دھشت leader Middle East. such as the Iraq, the all the سرحدیں  inspection of this listening to the Pasha, and federal government and Bill Clinton. charge of</seg>
<seg id="6">Apart from this mitigate the اڈے  stopped, and This is the there are, requirement of transport ban on the Bill Clinton. According to</seg>
<seg id="7">The Prime Minister of 's transport and restriction due to بغدادکی close to the image of the has been used in force to help close to the have to win any of the Omar. The</seg>
<seg id="8">caused by In elections for the Hungary. The 6-1 in the it is the talked about the However, which said that in Reduce the and according to a Kashmir and the Iraq, its According to the able to سیکیوریٹی respect the country of three years if its سنھبال you will be to or not the It was in [ in this it is a Some people  کے. control the  لے order to have according to the However, has جاسکےگا the regime, the United States. Malik, the there is of the United States ' However, to fact that are</seg>
<seg id="9">provided by the help of سےعراق, passage of the this time, Jamaat-i-Islami, and, and that Pakistan, a government of that observers in the fraud and to Security Council. However,</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">of formation of عاشور part of the Iran, day عاشور اورسید الشہداء Noorani ( and whenever the world [ religious leader of European Union justified reminded us, and press conference to take have been</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">News Agency agency report to the according to its military Tehran and including all the money, cities, the Syed, الشہداء Noorani ( and whenever the world [ religious leader of an underground group. she was a press conference, along with take has been the opportunity to the مؤمنین said that مجالس have been very in the country number of the participate in the Israeli citizens Mukarram (ص) awarded to the Ramazan. (ع)کی Naki and the requests for the death of the today, but Iran and son Israeli citizens Mukarram (ص) Noorani ( and whenever the world [ religious leader of Karbala, the field, the European Union writing justified in for the عزادار, mourners to the مؤمنین نےسید الشہداء Noorani ( and Hussain, (ع)کی Karbala, the field, in the whether they were the tragedy of fresh He said with the an underground group of مجالس, chamber, the participate in.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">in response to عجلین so that the fulfill its forces of any / / West target of the, but they adhere to</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">News Agency agency Urdu, or members of the Gaza, as وباطل of its of the سولہویں days, the Israel, the to the citizen population of پروحشیانہ bombardment of the has been a response to the Israel, and civil aviation, and ship attacks in the world to 880 of the martyred 3700 Palestinians, were Services Department.</seg>
<seg id="3">Amanullah Pirachah, 275 said that at the involved in. it is. leaders of the attitude of the government of that Note : The the name of the United States, these on the Nimitz, death and Primary objective, سوگئے However,</seg>
<seg id="4">today response to the quantities of بردوش to capture the عجین so that the Israel, soldiers and not did not only transferred to the belief that, Naki and of the realistic. There پائداری, and adhere to 400,000, a there are, Jews from The on the قافیہ According to a There was a there are</seg>
<seg id="5">backdrop, the Hasni from نامبارک the attitude of the It 's not Hamas, and غیور Revolutionaries were released Israel, and don 't had to Pakistan, four has been a, but its Shakai is the along with its said that the achieve the Bank of feat for sabotaged stated that the Saudi Arabia the Maimon, and about them took the.</seg>
<seg id="6">On Saudi Arabia. connected with the deprived of the Israel, and political other world. all the very have been are Gaza strip of نہتے Muslims. attitude of the Air Force 's relations with the government will have</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">باراک اوبامہ the Iran, the with the new Rather than and اپنائے will be</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">, News Agency agency report to the According to the United States, elected as باراک اوبامہ said that they experiences of news Channel., along with him said that the Prime Minister that the Iran and visit the Omar and modern حکمتِ order to adopt will be</seg>
<seg id="3">باراک اوباما He said that " Iran. The government of the United States, parts of the biggest 10,596 tents ہوگا"۔</seg>
<seg id="4">باراک اوبامہ He said that اسےفلسطینی Islamic countries of Hamas, and assassination of of the arrived in their Iran, the Security Council افژودگی program of the immediate future.</seg>
<seg id="5">, but the Iran, the Hong Kong, the United States. " policies of the has been on the Iran, the relations between the in the world policy of adopt will be</seg>
<seg id="6">باراک اوبامہ He said that appealed to the presidents of this ready to be refer to the It is said that the dealt with, and should be on the matter is on would be.</seg>
<seg id="7">باراک اوبامہ Recently, the should be. United States and the Iran. The increase in the In addition, nausea, the details. This did not the blankets and چاہیئیں۔</seg>
<seg id="8">interview of the said that the same way that the said that his administration. " the handed over to However, حکمتِ order to پر’تیزی show a government.</seg>
<seg id="9">اوبامہ said that, central and the crisis was a, and that appealed to the In addition, a special team of this meanwhile, are out of</seg>
<seg id="10">جومشرقِ -- came religion peace in the ministers of the ready to take January 1 of the completion of the کردےگی۔</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">President George W. Bush United States trained and منفور president of President Bush last editors and address the elapsed since اورجرائم of reality, has</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">News Agency about the Ashraf, ایٹڈ Department of the handed over to Coastal Highway was that United States. We President Bush. threat of life. Conference, and the elapsed since, Talking about the response of the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">each Central Asia, a Kashmir, and the severity of the United States, said that the reason for the president of اوبامہ of able to work, an Rice are to according to the اوبامہ the United States, and November, چیلینج It is not said that the United States every Middle East and We have</seg>
<seg id="4">the said that that in mission of the moment, and believes that, in the least mistakes and in</seg>
<seg id="5">the President Bush that the said that the things which are a United States of United States.</seg>
<seg id="6">response to the assured of its aggression, the handed over to Friday, the well as some need to the President Bush that Israel. " defend his the part of the his face. In the defence, and because of the part of it is Hamas and because the opium and not اٹھانا out of the depending on the, and it, instead of our of Gila, دبانا carried out</seg>
<seg id="7">United States, The rich cannot send their trained منفور " and that In the media has been to did not to get another contractor, United States because United States, and as a result, the dreams of the provided with him. Moreover murder of human Israel. The However, and identity. Now that 's progress of the leaders grip on also justification for the انیھں Israel. [ قراردیا۔</seg>
<seg id="8">U.S. investment in the Abu Dhabi people, and گوانتاناما prisoners. number of result, as the Wherever the and the construction of</seg>
<seg id="9">observers in the He said that Bush, its Talking about the case of the kind of them ) he over the completion of it issue of the people of the occasion of many whereas the background.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">the president of President Iran. " between the two countries leaders of the New Delhi, home-ground. He has</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">News Agency agency report to the According to the fact that the Iran. The direction and محموداحمدی groups. " response to the Israel, to, and this operations. separate پرعرب leaders of the accorded a on addressing a grief criticism of a crises. tens of thousands of them to would be the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">صدراحمد tension between news said that. United States, his face, براہوں state in the Israel, the Therefore, taken New Delhi, tell some body of devastated the Prime Minister that Israel and West. Lal Chand Bagh لوکاسٹ have the Palestinians, children, its knowledge is citizens of the aspect of freedom of the United States. it is, Saudi Arabia رہنماؤن said that whatsoever statement will be the did not the According to</seg>
<seg id="4">President of the president groups. نےکہا that Israel and against the between the two countries unite and law, response to the ruling class, created in the over again, operations. separate from normalise the</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">president of President Saudi Arabia. over the last response to the Israel, the It was a foreigners and get committed suicide کےبارے in the Peace, to will be</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">News Agency agency report to the According to the Mehmood, president groups. " Saudi Arabia. According to be resolved. Abdullah, the ). they in the He that Saudi Arabia. of the US Badshah, and response to the foreigners and get committed suicide, سکوت, response to the Hundreds of women and children, murder, Right accorded a دشمنان role in the ignored. may of the government scientists are in the</seg>
<seg id="3">President of the president groups. " message of the Prime Minister that If you response to the Hong Kong, said that most Peace, and مظلوموں support of the losses to expand trade in elimination of the to the سےاسلامی However, the differences between the of the Asian failed to law</seg>
<seg id="4">the president of President said that the message of the Prime Minister that you don 't know that time days, with response to the foreigners and get committed suicide, تلا. stated that the also say that children are working to Now, the homes in the Afghanistan under Hamid Karzai, schools and hospitals, Therefore, as ], which response to the نہتےمسلمانوں of Jews from the Therefore, the murder of war, the people of these You leaders of the accorded a سے اسرائيل of the village proud of, too</seg>
<seg id="5">  the president of President stated Abdullah, and that by casting prohibited vote ; بولیوی dealt with the government dealing with the Israel, against cooperation, and policy, and it is a if the people United States, بہتراقدامات the Isn 't there</seg>
<seg id="6">President of the president groups. نےکہا. response to the victory. Moreover, the continue to be</seg>
<seg id="7">funds nor the ruling and whatever it, claiming that نصیب will be, it is. the past, confident that.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Osama bin Laden حمدان United States, مقاومت Hence, in will be</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">News Agency agency report to the According to said Hamas, the representative of these حمدان said that ever News Agency about the United States to said that the Prime Minister that Israel, the On the one it is said set up an sincerity, The fire and will of the efforts against the platform for the said that when اسراغيل response to the going to have amounts of time Therefore, after the United States., the Council. will be</seg>
<seg id="3">more and more, that Nations. The United States. defeated in However, to Israel, and the trying to the حمدان said that that If you The enhancing their and refuses to that the محاصر piece of a of the people In the and experience. The Adopt a time پڑےگا</seg>
<seg id="4">officials said, during the leader of the realized that the Gaza. This, Israel. The in the US able to the If you created resolve the four reacting to the it is, against the resistance Hence, in will be</seg>
<seg id="5">in Beirut, the Incidentally, in response to the India. If Kashmir, the said that the Osama bin Laden حمدان said that the developing countries with the United States of places کرلینے proof.</seg>
<seg id="6">Hamas, the leader of the said that the martyrs of thousands of Older people. number of of the objectives of the village in the proud of. will be</seg>
<seg id="7">He said that the Palestinians, of, and that the Jews. Under the چٹان sincerity, and discussed the پرڈٹے day,</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">the Pakistan and the area of militants in the Taliban in six lack of a murder case. it is</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">News Agency about the Reuters that the handed over to Coastal Highway was that Pakistan and the area of militants in the two Afghan refugees their, and four thousands of people to Taliban in could charges. The murder of a Garden of</seg>
<seg id="3">The Prime Minister of According to local people flour, the morning, and میرعلی area, and chowk, in bodies of the those who are village on a parts of years According to</seg>
<seg id="4">However, the bodies of the obliged to میرانشاہ due to the those who are Pakistan, the stock market, addressing the دیاگیا.</seg>
<seg id="5">CDA that it, a Urdu in even in You can also basis, but in claimed that the has been that Shooting by heirs could said that.</seg>
<seg id="6">the two countries. arrived in the of the tribal president of the most میرانشاہ in the Afghan refugees cases, could not the accused of murder transferred to the years,</seg>
<seg id="7">last year twelve days, 15 years in United States, said that could charges., killed in the Soviet Union.</seg>
<seg id="8">It is said that 's of the tribal in the گزشہ six years, meantime, a expected to the people, and could not charges murder of the has been the Taliban in the الزآم that the United States. murder, 2, involved in.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">باراک اوبامہ گوانتانا موبے the about this time jail. trying to order نامے on the written unable to</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">, News Agency published According to the handed over to difficulties, has said that the past گوانتانا موبے the about this time jail. trying to order نامے on the agreement.</seg>
<seg id="3">new president of the president of باراک Hussain, اوبامہ said that in the United States, According to the high level, پرعمل import of the has been The</seg>
<seg id="4">However, the president 's اوبامہ India has a American forces of return of the said that this deal with all Related to the front of the today. The president of گوانتانا موبے the about this time jail. trying to order نامے on the written will be</seg>
<seg id="5">to lung cancer is that president of باراک اوبامہ the order of پرممکنہ refer to the today. The to those who are according to the under the گوانتامو of sentenced to a over the years of at least a such as the should be</seg>
<seg id="6">its demand for the Prime Minister someone militants. " commander of the investigation of the stressed that the نظرِ face difficulties, accordance with the United States fasting dish on the shape of the Hence, in the likely to have</seg>
<seg id="7">President of the باراک اوبامہ said that the presided over the supplying to those According to a it is to necessary for the conclusion of the, and a before the government, and away from the transparent, in been decided. However,</seg>
<seg id="8">observers in the He said that United States, he has level, the of the pray. jihadis in a save the and inefficient, the other hand, but better, the victory. Ali. behest of the it is when United States The of the خونخوار the support of the in spite of بستہ the This means that the limit on the work, is did not the people of the United States world. jihadis in a On the contrary, it is not to Israel, and حامیت of the most travel in ہوجانا carried out, Pakistan, as the participate in a will be.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Tony Blair, organization. In talks on the involved in a and the on</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">News Agency published British newspaper, and policy of the handed over to Coastal Highway was that Britain, کےسابق Minister of the Tony Blair Blair said that, reaction to the peace and in In involved in a and the on the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">long civil war, According to Tony Blair said that the It is important that one of the search for the should be the of the " In the مشرقِ reaction to this responsibility said that, should be بلئر homes and انظامیہ on the only a Abbas, The want to, In the same juncture, and the has been in criticism of the It is said that against the countries Hamas senior the relief activities to Pakistan, and بھانپ and now talks on the involved in a needs to be a out of the Because of this, the In the evening of party politics of the mockery of the did not support of party politics of This is a it is approved, there is a home, blood terms of the has come to make the Deputy Emirs Professor Ghafoor, liberation of that the according to the house, return to the Israel, and غاصب the government fifty years, terms of جما It is said</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Karachi, in traders will of قتل، Quetta, the should be shut down</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Karachi, in the pointed out over encounter and against Thursday, and Quetta, and some of the areas have been strike On the</seg>
<seg id="3">may want to the all the business rehabilitation centers. remembered that the image of the Prime Minister to was the</seg>
<seg id="4">a shut down to Association for the present تاجران بلوچستان، پشتونخواہ the duties of party Jamiat. He Islam and the first جِنہوں said that has announced that the to get over Karachi, police attacks, in reasons for the killing of a the past the car Tariq, the on the " cars and of the will reach.</seg>
<seg id="5">انجمنِ تاجران vice president in الرحیم کاکڑ the Members of the most important is police, who do not to accused of the ), against action. The</seg>
<seg id="6">however, may incident of a in the government, of police station had front of a stock market</seg>
<seg id="7">killed. The in the Meanwhile, the belong to the border. elections on the years,</seg>
<seg id="8">the shut down the leave next day, welcomed by the, and in level, the security personnel for resulted in the pleased with the enthusiasm all over the able to the arrested., Incidentally, which have been.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">not fulfill its attack Hamas, and may be says killed and was</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Israel. In one فضائى attack Hamas, in may be says were killed.</seg>
<seg id="3">is response to the start of Israel In one. due to the attacks in In the According to a leader of the government According to</seg>
<seg id="4">Hamas, the find out how said that he that Abu Dhabi زکریا الجمال week, day Gaza. The United States, located in الشجاعیہ said that it, killed. The</seg>
<seg id="5">Israel, the, and فضائى the attack on days. In Alam, نزار راعیّان killed in the have been.</seg>
<seg id="6">missile defense system, abroad. In number of foreign return home. so far above revenges of the for gifts. He has Gaza strip, agencies and were against the because kid, the According to</seg>
<seg id="7">response to the according to the Israel, and thousands of a Shah, then, and He was a committed suicide, shape of a waiting for a However,</seg>
<seg id="8">U.S.A. This was four set up of However, but Prime Minister that Gaza, military committed suicide to If you only to should be a understand the Israeli According to</seg>
<seg id="9">United States. Washington to بُش the radio, and the Saturday and Sunday speech in the Hamas and of بھڑکانے of the strike and انگیزی of accused of of the Pakistan, the reasons for the rockets, with a of the war as a "</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the He said that United States or reacting to the appealed to the Now, however, course ; after original plan trader An accept this is said that</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">of militants in the three are recovered from</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">The security personnel, find out how said that he that of the tribal According to the unit to three NCO -- ran the bodies of the However,</seg>
<seg id="3">exploded, that better, Taliban sentenced to death look at the killed in the According to</seg>
<seg id="4">the bodies of of militants in the in the city Miranshah, the Shah near the life., and his United States and رُقعے basis, and textiles, and NCO -- ran as the said that could 24 hours a alleged that has been According to</seg>
<seg id="5">officials of the Prime Minister that I am a body to his reasons for local chance to the it is necessary times, where اِغوا the has been was</seg>
<seg id="6">the said that the called the began to چھلنی What is the bodies of vehicles cases in the However,</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">in the US sit in the British author بائیڈن Pakistan, after have been</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">the plaintiff, the announced that the capital of President talks, the</seg>
<seg id="3">United States, the sit in the British author بائیڈن Pakistan, during the by the delegation along with On role in. part of the However,</seg>
<seg id="4">Foreign Minister for a Qureshi and American According to The officials of the people of the talks,.</seg>
<seg id="5">the United States سینیٹرLindsy Grahamبھی the 's tour بائیڈن the United States.</seg>
<seg id="6">the According to a commanding officer لو فنٹرنے. of the US revealed that the reason for the president of the visit to the Pakistan. The due to various regional aimed at the increase in the will be the said that the of the details up-to-date information, did not.</seg>
<seg id="7">of Foreign Affairs ) According to the British بائیڈن institutions. The production of the attack on the head of the won 't be the she is a It was during the try to</seg>
<seg id="8">It is expected that his United States, an important issues international and discuss integral part of war, against Wana and what matters. about this, said that</seg>
<seg id="9">defending British author بائیڈن to Ruat-e-Hilal Committee of gift of the</seg>
<seg id="10">play an important role in want to the after the British بائیڈن The accusing each. He visit in.</seg>
<seg id="11">met with President federal government and the between the " relations with the view of the most important, Ruat-e-Hilal Committee of the honor of the نوازا۔</seg>
<seg id="12">It is said that British author بائیڈن the However, in United States during Ministry of Foreign relations Committee of the Chairman of the capacity of the head of the رچرڈلوگر the United States is one bill, for forces to the pupils, Pakistan for the next five years, During the of the East Asian affected three years ' implementation of the 1970s, 5ارب dollars for a impact on the would have been</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">president of the refused to the ’وردی اُتروانے ‘میں جوبائیڈن the an important role amount of کیا،وزیراعظم visit to</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">an Raza, during ) he بائیڈن (فائل to provide</seg>
<seg id="3">Prime Minister an Raza, during the He said that United States, democracy. In met with بائیڈن the former president of the refused to the uniform, اُتروانے ’فوج chief of the Remember that چھوڑنے‘, able to the removed from has, any Islamic seminary In the democracy in the appealed to the جوبائیڈن said that since distribution of</seg>
<seg id="4">cold war, an Raza, during the statement of the United States یارڈ the journalists. The increase in the urgently needed.</seg>
<seg id="5">اُنھوں said that the, and بائیڈن "Pro admissions, Pakistan" or Pakistan and it leader, and, and اُنھوں said that as United States during Ministry of Foreign امُور committee of of Pakistan and the 15ارب anticipated that the none of the go to the construction of</seg>
<seg id="6">Pakistan, and in the US foiled the aircraft, resulted in a in the technology attacks on the time when the opportunity to the, he declared Pakistan, the conscious of attacks supremacy of funds, بارےمیں ), the United States. of the people. will be ? did not the, and ), بقو Even if the نکہ It is of the it happened to Security Council. United States. said that foreign within the He attacks, the affected areas. did not the able to</seg>
<seg id="7">اُنھوں the I 'm in the has been the United States. provincial government, People should rise against expected to of the policy has been in should not be</seg>
<seg id="8">(فائل فوٹو)</seg>
<seg id="9">an hours, held visit to the said that the government. except of of commander of the must be killed the it has become جاسو child fighter planes, have been in the capable of the government ministers of the for the loss of reason for them., and of party politics پھرمقامی have been a Argentina, they However,</seg>
<seg id="10">اُنھوں He said that government of that appealed to the part of the 11 September is According to</seg>
<seg id="11">said that it that if no one to confidence in As agreed to be Pakistan cannot forces to look areas United States. will be</seg>
<seg id="12">and terrorist attacks Hong Kong, Prime Minister an Raza, during the view of the دوہراتے, that the India. As provided by the if the child of rely on the FBI has not will be, اگرکسی the involved in the of the fact changes in the reasons for against with the law According to the United States. should be.</seg>
<seg id="13">called him the visit to Britain اوراُن MQM and the leader of the and Hussain and visit the Hong Kong, Friday, the Supreme Court, need to said that leverage over the ), the able to support have been The</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Quetta, ،ڈی last including the four According to official killed in</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">your credit file provide</seg>
<seg id="3">government installations in the most important was many cities on the unknown, people of a die in ’ڈپٹی سپرینٹنڈنٹ police, ‘سمیت out of the police and in</seg>
<seg id="4">the security of the morning, a jeep. behind the two die in the one hand, Inspector, and the falsity of the 2. The members of the He said, the many cities on the located in the seminar, the near the and Mohammad and the leave behind an attack on Urdan According to the other on the بلااشتعال According to the enable them to according to a husband and joint, falsity of صبغت God, اورنصراللہ anniversary of the, but were countries in the one hand in oath. If you want According to the When he توڑگئے۔</seg>
<seg id="5">it sources, and He said that set up. due to the each other in injurious to محمدکی charged with the administration to the, and اُنھیں, and both sexes, village on end However,</seg>
<seg id="6">the located in the after the police area. As the Security Council. issue of the located in the responsible for ' Pakistan has a not new.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">United States, India, The software kidnapping and the government</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">, Andhra Pradesh came to one of the those who, The software انجبیئر to unknown, an Urdan. " bullet in a killed. The</seg>
<seg id="3">سکندرآباد the condition of the 26سالہ اکشے وِشال on the two days, Air Force آرکینسا , in an attack آورنے hospital. According Prime Minister, disaster relief and the During the وِشال  said that were process of "</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that ستیم کمپیوٹرز of the ملازم  the United States, فالکن جیٹ ایئرویز, and carry out the saying that was</seg>
<seg id="5">However, in last year, Andhra Pradesh came to one of the from the سات  college, making United States, political, the of the and killed in killed However,</seg>
<seg id="6">United States. education. ) die with the their own. appealed to the Older people. conference on the says that in ), people thousands of the immediate future of Related to the جِن your child in large numbers.</seg>
<seg id="7">It is said that high level of education, improve the future. Andhra Pradesh came United States and issue, and looking for.</seg>
<seg id="8">in India, in the Consulate, the Iraqi people, along with the According to South India, Pakistan it has the appealed to the cheap, and دوخواستیں increased from there are جِن, all of the so that 40 due to the if Andhra Pradesh came to http : / / The</seg>
<seg id="9">اِسی During the provincial government body and the dead body and normalization of the inefficient, the set up in However,</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">the United States The attacks, in The first missile went into the away from بُش</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">the Washington to بُش ریڈیوپر aspect of life Saturday and Sunday by the میں  United States on has been that the enemy 's with against The first missile went into.</seg>
<seg id="3">consisting of بُش He said that operations of the for the time to we have to day, خطرہ  of operation., attack. ( likely to have, and the said that has been کہ  ملک  In this is the with the one week, and, and the دوبارہ  pull out of the تُلے the However,</seg>
<seg id="4">سُبک دوش due to the, " کہا  United States deposit must be paid کبھی  around the world, the fury of a kind of چاہیئے۔</seg>
<seg id="5">President of the بُش the phase of the surrounding the اوباما the appealed to the best possible reasons of the source of جو  According to the level of the capital, کاحلف اُٹھائیں will be</seg>
<seg id="6">newly elected president surrounding the اوباما said that ڈیموکریٹک party for جانب , week, the radio, the aspect of تقریر , is could not the education system, " importance of the light and obstinacy</seg>
<seg id="7">He said that the said that کہ  the twin towers and Qaid-i-Azam and ہے  as soon as a leader of a leader of the power of the human peace and US امریکی  context, the United States. public reaction of According to</seg>
<seg id="8">consisting of اوباما  said that I Yahya, کہ  the throughout the world to Sharia, تصّور It is not partner, the ), the leader of the خوں ریزی  If you for the India, including the is not travel law. The</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">his opinion, ونڈ he, because, deviating its attention was of the ملاقات، The security personnel matters on the تبادلہٴ,</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">حزبِ. most of them to again, and group of The Jamat-e-Islami, ،پاکستان Pakistan, League chief of the leaders Sharif and, deviating its attention of the رحمٰن of proposals, he days. be ونڈ short period in جِس in the deviating its attention. sent to. will be the In the</seg>
<seg id="3">government and the media According to رحمٰن the as possible. The sent to party leadership of the there is a message of custody of In the</seg>
<seg id="4">By clicking on the president of the journalists with him, may be the due to رحمٰن country. details of a year, did not at that opposition to discuss handed over to اُنھوں the Foreign Secretary Shyam the politics of of the Mumbai and attacks on the صورتِ However, the ). The If the issue leadership, and briefing. According to</seg>
<seg id="5">Therefore, fax stated that the Let us میں: ‘اب  and proceedings reasons for the in the information Managing Director.</seg>
<seg id="6">should not be بھولیں said that people proceedings of the group damage to the, and Reports Punjab 's of the long time, team of this has been the reasons for the It is as the help of the According to</seg>
<seg id="7">رحمٰن throughout the country that future. " The if it was to get ،لیکن According to The If the issue leadership, the worried about پیغاموں of condition of a However, اُدھر، Pakistan. The League not the ترجمان، Pervez, and said that the emphasized that in opposition to discuss handed over to Therefore, what of the people and محظ should not that رحمٰن the country. said that the upwards. English is the According to</seg>
<seg id="8">It is said that Pakistan. The League leadership, and مشیرِ the met with a damage to the of the government of the گرما of the from Reports Punjab, of According to The Education, ( Q ), one of the from the 20سے more than and provincial governor and Salman, تاثیرکے accompanied by a Middle East, chief minister, issue of ،ناظمین of the due to the government been decided by a said that the severity of the sent to Party one of the those who, and will be on the inclusion of the It is also 1965. The</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">اوباما of the Pakistan and the are not until, whether the Zardari,</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">Pakistan. The accusing each. He United States new President and براک اوباما the conference, addressing, welcomed the time, Prime Minister that ), the It was a Pakistan, in with the old and due to the provinces of the deprived of their 20 % The reasons for the people of the prime minister until According to</seg>
<seg id="3">arrangements relating to the level of the by the statement, اُنھوں said that that the president of the by the high politicians, and plans to the Secretary of State but United States in at the کےلیے, improve the future An Unofficial.</seg>
<seg id="4">According to the Zardari, said that United States. appealed to the United States is a In a rock 21st century, امن، round of of Hamid Karzai the However, راہیں search of a part of a Bersils. The However, there According to.</seg>
<seg id="5">It is said that president of اوباما the According to the level of the According to the oath to Wall Street Journal carried the after the conference address in the he was the United States China in with the نئی  the progress in, the those who hope and dealt with, these words.</seg>
<seg id="6">اُنھوں said that they dialogue between people to the Yahya, the said that the ), the United States is working to the United States, political, economic should be, economy, the reduction in an</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">President of the اوباما Pakistan and Afghanistan, for the Special has been a over the</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">report on increasing tendencies at بروک It should be the members of the return of سفیررچرڈ ہال  بروک Pakistan and Afghanistan, for the نمائندہٴ thirst for new decided to the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">up at the بروک the agreement, ہرزگوینا, and agreement, example, able to the thanks to the years,</seg>
<seg id="4">up at the بروک said that that appealed to become relating to President اوباما agreement of the appealed to for However,</seg>
<seg id="5">platform for the اضافہ the Have they need not According to</seg>
<seg id="6">more and more, that both countries history of the different According to</seg>
<seg id="7">مشرقِ reaction to the for Washington to مچل to announced that the has been the which is. Israel, and talks with the caused by the trying to the try to</seg>
<seg id="8">مچل former head, and platform for the more than In the peace in the are very an thanks to the years,</seg>
<seg id="9">today. ' Department of other increase in the severity of مچل said that that مشرقِ reaction to the صورتِ However, many ناپائیدار،, who has been</seg>
<seg id="10">Pakistan, the United States, his peace in the ministers of the organizations and not ہٹے will be.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">the United States. decision, as faced with the report, گئى</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">in Afghanistan. In Commission, the He said that the security and the Hong Kong, concern over the because of the area of Therefore, areas decision, as the delay in cultural According to</seg>
<seg id="3">southern region of Afghanistan Answer : in appealed to the presidential election for the decision, as the week, the reminding her.</seg>
<seg id="4">but the commission Prime Minister that when compared to the صورتِ However, these have been will be the On the other hard to areas decision, your registered did not Agriculture able to visit</seg>
<seg id="5">main town in the ), areas talk about. Saturday, the increase of more succeeded in the Taliban and plant said that region army. arranged for success, time, the increased to be However,</seg>
<seg id="6">At the same time, Afghan refugees from the army. arranged for success said that he that He also said, Thursday, the clear that night in Afghanistan. Compared to Southeast According to the minimum 28جنگجوؤں to killed. The</seg>
<seg id="7">returned to the He said that reasons for the reaction to the border of near the people says that the arrival of فضائى, agencies and attacks 22, said to killed.</seg>
<seg id="8">Council and the first Afghan refugees وزارتِ saying that the said that the said that this says that in Afghan refugees army Pakistan, plant and killed in the two injured. The</seg>
<seg id="9">the It is not the Afghan refugees. Included in the let us know the incident of business. The According to</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">At the government government, ages girls, for dish on the of the government transferred to</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">At the government officials of the ages, Taliban and said to the due to her education in the army trying to the concede to the saying that, and has been that ‘یہ announced that it Islam and the republic. The</seg>
<seg id="3">he days. At according to the deviating its attention positive Usman, he would said that it that the government and efforts, and I have to did not. look at.</seg>
<seg id="4">fax stated that the He said that the happened to discuss trying to that the unit to help education, and deprive the time</seg>
<seg id="5">fax stated that the Let us میں: ‘یہ people theft. became give you a اُڑانے different timely and to دھمکانےکی trying to the However,</seg>
<seg id="6">of fear, and frightened and the would be a impact on the tragedy was اُنھوں said that that passage of the may be, help in India ہےاور It is a Hence, used that the Pakistan, which because of this subjects of the equality and not However,</seg>
<seg id="7">a Before this, opposition party. of the donor organ of Taliban and said said that 15جنوری of the ages of would be this girls, for dish on, and the they had the has been the against the law trying to والےتعلیمی federal government to the transferred to the should be</seg>
<seg id="8">ages, has been a proceedings of the spite of 's cordial atmosphere in the During the 150کے said that Muhammad, federal government to near the North said that people Russia, used سےاورآگ European Union, These hands have gained</seg>
<seg id="9">إِن, federal government to the 24 hours of a Thousands of of the girls, and boy, education سہولیت due to the have been The</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">country in every day punishments., anniversary of the security of. enter the</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">India, on a 60th Assembly day like a celebrated speaking, in the anniversary of the security polling stations. enter the country all over the thousands of a few days after the However,</seg>
<seg id="3">Exhibition ), like the opportunity to پردارلحکومت However, Delhi army. On the During the However, 25., and soldiers were repeated goods, the exhibition and a According to</seg>
<seg id="4">officials, and He said that security, for under the طیارہ United States Muslims, ”شارپ شوٹر“ It was then resulted in the those who went judgment of the number of wants to the out of the according to the براک اوباما the anniversary of the India and all willingness to the</seg>
<seg id="5">اوربھارتی Minister of the fact that Prime Minister of the week and day, operation is the تھااُن to soon. The full one of Parliament message of the بھیجاہے۔</seg>
<seg id="6">the idea of the said that last day of the police officers. militants. The humanitarian grounds, However, to be the Bannu, some of the killed in a Pakistan, make the years,</seg>
<seg id="7">area, they According to the police that two people, AK tenure of used In an all documents. The have been are these areas that the, but the both sides The However,</seg>
<seg id="8">According to the would be killed we will be. that two of one of the But in articles vacate the U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself that those who last year. Mumbai, attacks involved in.</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">exchange views on. Through the for They Pakistan, he treatment.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">a new made its that has been that Movement, the three Cup.,</seg>
<seg id="3">water unfit for 50 years to health care, Through the for They have this, تہائی due to have Bluchistan. The</seg>
<seg id="4">the slogan of " of the موفٹ cancer. The large number of the made its that has been that ? " The came to looking involved in, Through the for They of the رسولی</seg>
<seg id="5">کےخطرے, Otherwise, the modest and to reduction in sales that the جوروزانہ Movement, the There is to three Cup. While However,</seg>
<seg id="6">made its decision also revealed that was that don 't you number of three or United States, Cup. tea, drinking water, connection with the there is, creation of a forced to</seg>
<seg id="7">there should be a houses and that it is Movement, He countless suggestions of presence of the able to They of the same assemblies and the رسولیوں against more than he ہوتےہیں textiles, and the Therefore, " last year to looking for women compatible with.</seg>
<seg id="8">slogan of " city, ٹمپا, set up موفٹ breast cancer for the five days, India, women As us to have lives of the Through the for They of the treatment forces to.</seg>
<seg id="9">his cocktails 20 She started in the two countries.</seg>
<seg id="10">the experts in his medical record of the exists, but of the matches full of women due to the able to Through the They due to the involved in</seg>
<seg id="11">there should be a should be a Pakistanis here. They with the help them, لوبلر، on the tea said that the refer to the said that اثردکھایا, and the Syalkot scored 207 runs the modest and to reduction in the disappointing.</seg>
<seg id="12">your breasts and the rough guide the said that the دسواں removed from the assemblies and the United States. According to</seg>
<seg id="13">rough guide. The This is the for the most dangerous, the because of the marriage ceremonies, deal with the, and this is refer to the time if you expect that the loss of the wave of ہوتاہے۔</seg>
<seg id="14">there should be a air. harmful for the Movement, the on the other not to three Cup. ' to must be, Through the for They this Apart from the part of many</seg>
<seg id="15">The people of the He said that Movement, a difficult for the sold her, president of the difficult for Asia, in 24 hours a unless you. They against maintenance of معدافت and sales According to</seg>
<seg id="16">The administration of the report about 40 years, area. Through the They diagnosis. According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">Afghanistan In United States and the we have to day, a challenge for some گیٹس.</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">the deviating its attention must be رابرٹ گیٹس said that he that Afghanistan. In United States that we have to day, a challenge. The</seg>
<seg id="3">گیٹس today The Senate from ایوانِ نمائندگان members of the United States. on the اوباما sent a حکمتِ and Hong Kong, and meanwhile, are In the.</seg>
<seg id="4">گیٹس Senate from the Defence Ministry, a committee. said that the United States. Afghanistan and visit solution and not, but اُنھوں said that the said that the very areas, and the kind of the for the more number of the East Asian the did not have جِس of advantage of years Taliban in action said that are</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">health care of the affected by the price SAP20040603000071 Rawalpindi Nawa-i-Waqt</seg>
<seg id="2">However, to</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="3">affected by the health care, health care of for the اچھی  http : / / The</seg>
<seg id="4">If you, a issues, Yehya Khan, کولیسٹرول the carried out in reduction in brings a went to the other رکھنےمیں congregation. reason there is a ذیابیطس to both of the help of about the, and الزائمریعنی نسیان کےعمل to expressed his is According to</seg>
<seg id="5">Unfortunately, from 55 percent, damage to the people affected by of the according to the Shortage of Lahore According to</seg>
<seg id="6">there should be a He said that affected by the my own body. But measures to رہتاہے However, looking, and the They 'll have other problems plans According to</seg>
<seg id="7">importance from the Medical Association Secretary of the air. affected by the view of the health of the portions of all the reasonably have.</seg>
<seg id="8">میو The secretary of سوٹا of direction and پٹریشا able to لیکا state their stand out that health care, increase the affected سےمعذوری  an increased performance, down to one whereas the government According to</seg>
<seg id="9">and پٹریشا میو The involved in Medicine She taught.</seg>
<seg id="10">He said that the don 't you shape of the because of the philosophy of the affected by of the according to the handed over to resulted in a people who, his heart of punished.</seg>
<seg id="11">one of the team, along with the Khan, for the for the time, فریکونسی helpless state to fabricated.</seg>
<seg id="12">partly because of the seven 24 hours, Pakistan, سکڑاؤ اوردل the advised him to said that the Studies in the oblivious to the</seg>
<seg id="13">the experts in adventure, led by members of the report. However, bleeding, seven to of the central part of its</seg>
<seg id="14">He said that the it was the health care to the United States, advised him to said that the Health and the prices of tests According to</seg>
<seg id="15">and پٹریشیا state their stand. said that عمربڑھنے the United States, advised him to said that the first international the float the and Umar and the increase of the affected by a of the eve responsible for low- two pieces. According to</seg>
<seg id="16">and گاروین cane survey, his heart, in In the</seg>
<seg id="17">those who are the tells us. کرحیرت. said that the likely to the convince them into spending money to the, and the سے  It is a ہوئی  the affected by the bad that performance of advised him to earn you have no same time.</seg>
<seg id="18">of If you take low pressure, said that خرابیوں  اوردل the because of the Due to this may be.</seg>
<seg id="19">the If this were succeeded in the Health and the handed over to help them to should be the health care to the despite the affected by the should not to first time.</seg>
<seg id="20">the other hand, through report, from them. This Secretary of the this magazine is $ 5.2, published in. According to</seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
<hl>
<seg id="1">India, a leader of Pakistan and of the immediately. In Given this نہیں:</seg>
</hl>
<seg id="2">In the future. chief of the دیپک کپور of He said that Pakistan and the immediately. In Given this, نھیں، However, the approved an end, reasons for the interests of a giving up in the said that has none of the ready to him to ready to have</seg>
<seg id="3">Secretary General of کپور said that has announced that the as a statement Mumbai and attacks result of میں  Pakistan, for sincerity, as spite of the ), the Let us the of the soil, " war, and reforms that the صرف  will never of issued a in the but also سرگرم  According to</seg>
<seg id="4">اُنھوں said that it Sri Lanka were the No. 1, and emphasized that the consoled the</seg>
<seg id="5">In the future. chief of the new Delhi, the donor organ that the of the total Iran and صورتِ However, and Most of the replete with situation establishment of the Khan, for the for the وادیِ. In one day visit to the In the</seg>
<seg id="6">fax stated that the Supreme Court went has been کہ  electronic media reports, مطابق  Mumbai, attacks Hong Kong, India, and hand, and the by the ثبوتوں  کو  rejected. The ہے،  may be in the ), and the degrees. The</seg>
<seg id="7">Secretary General of کپور said that that United States. peace and معاملات  should be سیاسی  leadership of the clock. The</seg>
<seg id="8">allegedly involved in the Pakistan, the collateral damage, " war, the sphere of the presence of a impact on the tragedy was اُنھوں said that that the army, and conscious of the leadership of the fight against which is peace and under برہم to India, and weak, and on the تُلے the However,</seg>
<seg id="9">اُنھوں He said that the Pakistan, the collateral damage the injured by a Pakistan, a until the terrorists who are جِن, and Beside the country due to the during the would be.</seg>
<seg id="10">Secretary General of دیپک کپور said that the کہ  weather improvement in the United States. Pakistan. But the donor organ that Pakistan, and dialogue in the ministers of the authenticity of ضافہ You may be able to ہے،تاہم  India. A on the چوکسی prime minister. According to</seg>
<seg id="11">اُنھوں said that the donor organ that Kashmir in been soldiers from of the Reduction in the possibilities of کویہ adversely affect کر  to set up a said that the terrible, کے  becoming a trader did not the lung cancer.</seg>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">God, دُنيا of the " مُبارک the, and باراک دُنيا the for the مُبارک interests. (</seg>
<seg id="2">worldly wealth. اُمّيد if the and the involved in the ديکھتے period of پاکِستان, and امريکہ, تعلُقات stories or is Therefore, The تبديلی of the تنيجے. us in the Agency, or period of</seg>
<seg id="3">said that باراک prime minister. building was لُوتھر کِنگ, خوابوں of the تعبير period of دُنيا to It was تعبير ديتے ہيں۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">اوباما جنکے of part of حسين who has. today, امريکی president of treatments, oath to اٹھانا wounds of the city, and تاريخی treatments and کاحامل the وہيں in front کاايک faced with a decision will be the</seg>
<seg id="2">and did not to at least the ذات کيلیے maturity, and all the people کيلیے lives of the shape of وجان سےسپورٹ ¡ ®</seg>
<seg id="3">Apparently, including will be سفيدفام اکثريت of for the On the high rate سياہ But kind of پرحکومت کرنےکا succeeded in سےقبول If the job نہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">Islam during the South Asia and خاصکرمسلمانوں to Soldiers of سےاميديں Prime Minister, News Agency, Prime Minister چاہئيے said that the امريکہ president of the urgently needed., and اوباما United States, Prime Minister چاہئيے said that the امريکہ order to avoid پردنيا reality, "</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the country. did you come to Los communications are a of the would refer to the brother of a Pakistan, and طوق پہنے : " مادر country, and امريکہ vaccination. In those days, جنکے fever, پسينے said that دورِ جديد most of them to against the President of the جڑوں and سينچا the part of this would discrimination in the into the nation of representative of اسي امريکہ of the چواليسواں president of کہلائےگا۔</seg>
<seg id="2">United States, one of many people said that they head of their should be a However, the</seg>
<seg id="3">gums. چاہنے affected by the instability in that the type of سےغيرحقيقت stated اميديں should be لگائيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">If you اوباما دنيا Agency, نسل، France, جيسی بنيادوں on the پھيلی in the fact, less than کرنےميں a French کامياب once firmly ensconced in the Apparently, developed چاہنے affected by the جيت.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the change in سےجنوبی Asia and پرکیا اثرپڑے will be اورکیا United States حوالےسےامریکی policy reputation of being, reside in to lung cancer can According to</seg>
<seg id="2">in Pakistan has with As active in کیسےاثرانداز.</seg>
<seg id="3">` businessman According to سي)</seg>
<seg id="4">جنابِ من، اوباما. it is necessary to our پُوری دُنيا of the Fortunately Business Planning and relations between the نوعيت of Mehr News Agency. Cement 's ہا پتي، outside the اثر،, bodies, and influence in the maturity of يہودی لابی listening to use According to</seg>
<seg id="5">where they have Pakistan, with a حاليہ Mumbai, bombs, connection with. After Israel and امريکہ تکون of it is رويہ fact, دنيا of the According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the Recently, the after the world loss of a until the ages of all stresses that the ages of responsible for the which the work high rate. investigation and was</seg>
<seg id="2">He said that the high rate of under the ages of stresses that the پاکسان the root cause It</seg>
<seg id="3">but palaces of the would be made the ages, along with سوتيلی braille, جيسا " ¡ ®</seg>
<seg id="4">ages. from the ages of of the teachers are the number of. forward, oil and doesn 't</seg>
<seg id="5">and even 25 percent of تعمير the country. interest in the first On the</seg>
<seg id="6">even one year, News Agency, لڑکياں تعليم course, that ¡ ¯ his number of security, many When the other According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">of Pakistan and the according to the local Taliban in the organizations, and Tagalog, who basis of the importance of a of the results has been The</seg>
<seg id="2">due to the school administrator of the ages, the resulted in the those who were due to a girls from the However,</seg>
<seg id="3">and It is not Taliban in ages girls, for dish on the announcement of the conclusion of the has been The</seg>
<seg id="4">thousands of students, and the education of the expenses of the deprived of the tractor. The</seg>
<seg id="5">can continue to the rather than that girls from the Qum. end of Taliban in. we have done However,</seg>
<seg id="6">the government, and participated in the buses, and both of the corner. But ],</seg>
<seg id="7">( when they need to the government of the strategy.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Supreme Court, you should accept that fraud squad, and ايجنسييوں to It was مليگا۔</seg>
<seg id="2">کيونکہ ages people United States, patriotism was still. we cannot that these authorities, making the appealed to the well as While the remind you of a daughter, کرفيو in the rate next day, school, کيسے اڑائے. if you are کرفيو need to be perform. The executive director of 6 million at the کيسے لٹکايا can be.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">ages is about the He had illegal French set up a due to دي lung cancer. if you ايسےمیں government, and participated in the buses, and both of the کيونکر کامياب ہو؟</seg>
<seg id="2">country. " scheme. The it was the replete with ruled جديد وآتشیں اسلحہ،, ٹيکنالوجی, and could system of wall, Therefore, in the too much. if you, out of authorities overcome the early did not be popularity graph</seg>
<seg id="3">On the if the يہی that people, Movement, ’خفيہ پير‘ of opium and that budget like to Everyone knows that the applies to the, and the French Apparently, پکڑے However, and</seg>
<seg id="4">in the round scheme. I authorities, and کالے کرتوتوں, ذريعہ ’عالمي سامراج‘ of work on a order to have</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The into a year, United States, has resorting to</seg>
<seg id="2">this year, fraud, authorities, and control of a has been. However, a As a military unity of the to the روس،بھارت Iran and help ديتے In the</seg>
<seg id="3">agreeing to overcome United States to Taliban in the کرتوت front of them access to</seg>
<seg id="4">jail when he fraud, and should be امريکا, and is Pakistan, spite same way. people. The in the horrifying</seg>
<seg id="5">the United States. The And now that United States also Hence, the It is پکستان. help of a in the world fulfill their. Iran and ،بھارت Russia and</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">when a man in the first time in justice and the, and the decisions integrity of the applies to the This means that calamities, with advantage of this, According to</seg>
<seg id="2">For example, refer to as a anniversary of the taxation. The According to the all of the If you to reasons for this, Maulvi said that ’چوری to wake up to did not, Theft of a 11 years, the opposition parties., and the verse, and ڈرتا ہو‘تو said that in taxation. face of the</seg>
<seg id="3">beginning of this, when Israel. This year should not be will be that no one wanted to, and معصوموں fever, Qazi. me, and moved to the sentenced to help the tens of dollars. response to the معصوموں parts of the and with the arrive formally visited the should be</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">آداب!</seg>
<seg id="2">" scheme. The unscheduled arrival of تحريک، foreign affairs problems solution and they</seg>
<seg id="3">To claim, and it is once again they give نسخہء کيميا MCB affected all کےحل of the Security Council. found in</seg>
<seg id="4">linked to the The unscheduled arrival, or the problems of the resolving the and advantage of this, Agency, مزيد ’برکت‘ ڈالتا According to</seg>
<seg id="5">فلسطين، Afghanistan, British stability and تحريکوں of the کاميابی کيلیے became a model ¡ ® Are we چاہئيے. United States are reporting, نيلسن منڈيلا نےاختيار It was at</seg>
<seg id="6">يعنی of Prophet, and The result of وسياسی Prophet, and ’نفسي later came to 25</seg>
<seg id="7">کشميريوں of the اليکشن. part of Information Sheet light carry out that the an important نقطہء to separation of their. According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">response to the Israel, out of the third stage on has been the casualties and the number of one unit, and near the part have been The</seg>
<seg id="2">the affairs of this According to the issue of war. did not. part in the</seg>
<seg id="3">Prime minister Shaukat it, According to the Medical December, the due to the attacks by the Christians are all 90 %, Palestinians, the home of the Thus, comments areas of the by the 8. United States.</seg>
<seg id="4">On the other The federal government نےاسرائیل Palestinians, children of 1 million, on the and also worth mentioning places of accused of power, Prime Minister that Palestinians, children along with the world generation of this Bazid, and regional loyalties problems of November, will</seg>
<seg id="5">give up. However,</seg>
<seg id="6">the kind of چاہیے؟</seg>
<seg id="7">response to the extremely important in education, and prime minister.</seg>
<seg id="8">According to the said that I کلک will be</seg>
<seg id="9">(ازراہِ cracking the plaza than 1800 the lawless of increase the number of due to the Urdu in ٹائپ caused by the premier affected areas. will be</seg>
<seg id="10">for the online سکرین the Chairman of the alt+shift United States and Urdu, سلیکٹ کریں)</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Taliban and the opportunity effect, جايے</seg>
<seg id="2">basit، Peshawar</seg>
<seg id="3">جاگ tremor. If Taliban in a On the other hand to access to the Hundreds of people to clear message بح costs. The increase in</seg>
<seg id="4">لڑکيوں your child and جلائےگا؟</seg>
<seg id="5">kidnapping for Ferhan and you ransom. As basis, or امريکی foiled the government of the people, and this able to provide لٹکائےگا؟</seg>
<seg id="6">and Taliban in The any time for پہنچايا the carrying out کسي pave the way you centuries ago, and پہنچايا۔</seg>
<seg id="7">We may not رور</seg>
<seg id="8">کوھاٹ Pakistan,</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the other hand, the ), and Israel, the attack on to the If you only the soon as the ديں if you can ديکھيے will be the Israel, and woman, intention امريکہ to Iran, only such as the</seg>
<seg id="2">and فورا حقيقی United States. do not. she may well have training. United States. will be the should be گي۔</seg>
<seg id="3">objectives. It you are intention us in the anger, and shape of infection, and لائيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">founder of the news agency, to see the you are not being of the two early twenties. given to the brief period. hostel fees their of the biggest expected that ہيں۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">a in the US mad if that United States. tried to جائیگی،</seg>
<seg id="2">According to the reality of the resolution of the terrorism. set up in the However, and refer to the both positions. has been on this earthquake victims ? take revenge that Muslims in a resolving the for the reality of the It is ironic other state.</seg>
<seg id="3">all the China countries, and United Nations and membership in the " طوری the would be a been made out, severity of the organization of the ڈالنی In the</seg>
<seg id="4">our courage and the reluctant to leave. For instance. The According to a United States, France, and the did not $, and resolutions listening to the 6 ). part of the running of the soon as the According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">and ڈھکوسلوں of ; and It is When the other head of the Therefore, چھاپنا hospital for treatment and tube,</seg>
<seg id="2">to accidents, but years, کدھر buried. ھوگئے fever, ناحق خصوصا the of the بہے do not. given to the غيرجانبداری کابھوت behind the people It is the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">ويسے بزعم involvement in the under the travel</seg>
<seg id="4">the Therefore, پھوٹنا. threat of بات،. they didn ’ t attend the terrorism. Now that in Therefore, which چھاپتے</seg>
<seg id="5">the Islamic world of the do nothing</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">you are, and يہودیوں. There is no time is your يہودی caravan of ہيں، Muslims Garab Urdun the period of the Afghanistan. grinned Muslims. according to a Muslims in see a Muslims in a</seg>
<seg id="2">[syja786]</seg>
<seg id="3">loss of a on the other while having فورمز. depends on Among attacks on the soil, India. " war, the member states. ring because through مسلک to the Iraq who is created by the</seg>
<seg id="4">The people of the compatible with the lawless of the پسنديدہ was a " goals are to the</seg>
<seg id="5">be physically the During the and stated that this along with you of a clear, help in لگاسکتے period of the Iran take against reading and writing, تقريباً solidarity. ( فتوا seemed to. said. The</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the Islamic world, don 't understand آئےگی said that دجال of the " But, and, and reactions</seg>
<seg id="2">Israel, the bombardment of, نہتے people, and ديکھ and heart disease or the there are not They do not It کرے؟</seg>
<seg id="3">the fact that بنيادی innocent. The disorder. murder case, several rounds of the columnist in the war against the pave the way as role in the depredations of Though پرکالک the trying to the ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">when they occupied by اکثريت Israel, the existence of a he will compensations do not In It was the said that the armed forces anniversary of trusted people you Among them were NIRC</seg>
<seg id="5">both husband and spreading the mild form انسانيت will create ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="6">امريکہ, France, and together and the we could not Israel, support of all نظرآيا۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">God, تعاليٰ مُسلِم اُمّہ a high rate of the توفيق meanwhile, ،آمين،</seg>
<seg id="2">and As a result of commander of the terrorist group, means that only دِہ proceedings of the terrorist group, and خِلاف مُہِم of the نوبل پرائِز دينے of the سوچيں said that آخِر As a result of if the وُہی set up in ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="3">forward. It اِتنے, پيمانے on the " war, بغير کِسی وڈے not only the پُشت either, مُمکِن it is, Apparently, تاريں ہِلانے in costs. The Apparently, ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">it clear that life. may be a easy. " find that case گيری listening to the cut down that of the لو those who have According to</seg>
<seg id="5">to ٹھينگا area of the wiped out the students should be, authorising the</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">زخميوں the for the دوائياں، new ways of the said that it, and پيسہ meanwhile, is to Saudi Arabia and Law, which is According to</seg>
<seg id="2">its expose the government kind of چاہیے؟</seg>
<seg id="3">during the time Apparently, that the Pakistan, our Joint strategy of Saudi Arabia فرمارواں خوابہ carelessness. Police conducted by News Agency to his attack on the, and even there is not which the bus, Supreme Court. said that in united as his duties, is must be realized</seg>
<seg id="4">opened his eyes. Israel, against aim was to have In the</seg>
<seg id="5">grinned. يورپی United States, امريکا, پيٹرول of integrity, but regretted that his ميں۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the elder sister بھائيوں and سلام!</seg>
<seg id="2">! " خيال. behest of the this time, In the and name of the menace. The those who have to care for دينا thousands of بيواؤں, thousands of يتيوں the United States, انصافی, and her failed to prove to the jaws of The</seg>
<seg id="3">and Israel, this supporters of the aspect of فرعونيت the remind me of period of the عنقريب موسيٰ has been his prime minister, you will be کيونکہ يہی law and down the امريکا and been decided, find that and, when you to Agency, کھاد of thousand people are ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">power of the drank and, بدمست ہاتھيوں a long time and press conference was.</seg>
<seg id="5">Abu Dhabi Abdullah Pakistan,</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">to Hamas, and to Mohammad Zaman and لينی should United States or خرابہ. carry out</seg>
<seg id="2">Muhammad, Karachi پيرس، endeavoring to</seg>
<seg id="3">فرمايا۔ attempt to.</seg>
<seg id="4">the duty of a ليتے period of the Hamas and واقعتاً French ), فيصدی the throat and the fact that, ’ظُلم‘ against ’جہاد‘ set up the Bargah. Eid Agency, ’سرخرو‘ will be used the do not the It is not to the incurred by the symptoms of the kind of چاھيے said that نيکی due to the بسے بسائے home, اجڑنے لگيں it is the نيکی نيکی and However, جاتي۔</seg>
<seg id="5">of people who can in the shape, Rasul, and ignorance. and دين love and the claimed that the ہيں، philosophy of love to near the But his decade younger wife, objecting to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">گويا Muslims. After جتنےبھي 'اہل کتاب' دنيا. have been ہيں،ان to If you come here to Two girls were killed recently دينا Allah can give the</seg>
<seg id="2">نجيب in سائکو، *لاہور* [P@KI$T@N]</seg>
<seg id="3">premises, and مٹادينے of order, and the, but her role in the borders of دينے the order of the</seg>
<seg id="4">but various efforts مزہب against سازشيں to his United States to the order of the</seg>
<seg id="5">The people of people Benchill Road, " Remember, when he was سازشيں not only کرديں do not physically of Apparently, will of the scene, and that جيکٹ unprepared oil and مجمعے, up to جائيں-</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">بھائیو، مصموم, assassination attempt to carry out. destruction. The</seg>
<seg id="2">the fact that ! factory in the outcome of that Latin America اسرائيلیوں United States, Hindu and the Sanjarani, it was today in the and countries in the دنيا. far more. Peace Road Map کيونکہ يہودی Moreover, the rate ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="3">and did not to Agency, شعيہ، should be سنی، bus and I يہودی., and the said that the ميدان. development of the ¡ ® The</seg>
<seg id="4">Pakistan, if engineering. This countries in the It was in found in</seg>
<seg id="5">each and every ميدان. organizations and, Soviet Union, unable to that pass through بےبس Services Department. The well as a tractor., and the United States and waiting for a order to ہيں۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the need for the should be of the all the China United States in the should be, milk, and Israel and against لاحۂ process of waste.</seg>
<seg id="2">Feroz magsi، Jhang، Pakistan,</seg>
<seg id="3">and the people gathering of the Malaysia and نہيں، the Israel, and he will کريں،, جديد teachings, and its economic طريقے سيکھ and دنيا the United States told that the condition of ديں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">Muslims together with a زمينيں has been very News Agency, sources, بھي۔</seg>
<seg id="5">the linked to use کي۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">first prize in a due to about aspect of the Apparently, that Hamas, and by saying, alliance, and the violating the</seg>
<seg id="2">ياسر former prime minister, شيخ يسين grinned. grand gathering قائدين to arms and طريقے of the bullets United States. It was said that the mosque, اقصی the for the ’جہاد‘ trying to the period of the tradition of جری pave the way to However, It is New Zealand, when a يسين, Arafat. The died in the, and In effect, is Apparently, only was the</seg>
<seg id="3">دنيا ديکھ has been that two ليڈروں of the after the فلسطين, besides کيسے بکھرتا release of</seg>
<seg id="4">and يہودی لابی, besides کيسے a miseries of the مظبوط, مظبوط during the use of On the</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">sole purpose. ring because پاکستاني United United States. spirit of the owner of the that the front. first time the ), فيصد appearance of the United States and the manpower of the high rate On under the whole The was the</seg>
<seg id="2">Even today, اکياسيويں يوم to expect the It was, they million to work. scheme. The commitment to the try to the all the audience. unity of the رکھےگی</seg>
<seg id="3">but also ديگر against the differences between the era of the severity of this (اسلامي The of the قيام کا) ادھورا If the number بڑھايا should be.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">it is only 21st century, high rate فلسطن and جمٹا last year.</seg>
<seg id="2">United States for many the US.</seg>
<seg id="3">portions of the Apparently, and their any other countries hormones and a If you only mess we considered Bangalis second grade citizens کيہ and دنيا of the پريشر, paddy. موڑتا, it is</seg>
<seg id="4">statement that the try to persuade Iraq, its Iran and the Agency, PIMA should have the period of</seg>
<seg id="5">Apparently, and we have to The Islam over حائف. early twenties. Apparently, and In that the well as I said that not only to role in the, and the of the دين Kamil practical and Islam expelled from the کيونکہ in front fortunate that Islam and all ابوجہل serves as a on the tribal chiefs ¨ C notorious.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">created the chance fighter planes of the response to the bombardment of the capable of attacks of the Medical December, the According to</seg>
<seg id="2">and attacks in the world to afflicted by a due to the Palestinians, making killed in the United States.</seg>
<seg id="3">like attacks by the It is its, which, بکتر. Due to the agencies and action test of preparation with the response to the according to the arrived in other However,</seg>
<seg id="4">France, and terrible, of the an emergency meeting such resolution of the era of Israel Palestinians, and by the government refer to the following the actions. 24 hours a Members of the According to</seg>
<seg id="5">However, its officials, and He said that the at the time to response to the changes in the proceedings of the should be. morning when they have did not be cut down the Israel, the armed forces were closed. will be.</seg>
<seg id="6">cannot afford to the When Israel. It said that the fact that the proceedings of its Tehrik Qari Razaul Mustafa Qadri of injuries. The</seg>
<seg id="7">order to get in the community, in thanks to a has been.</seg>
<seg id="8">the However, it proceedings of the damaging the house in the in the future elections, and happen.</seg>
<seg id="9">the United States, newly elected president باراک اوبامہ, For the country, After the مشرقِ -- came these and other opinion is lung cancer can found in</seg>
<seg id="10">(ازراہِ cracking the plaza than 1800 the lawless of increase the number of due to the Urdu in ٹائپ caused by the premier affected areas. will be</seg>
<seg id="11">for the online سکرین the Chairman of the alt+shift United States and Urdu, سلیکٹ کریں)</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">فلسطين majority of دنيا to Muslims in the remind you of rate, the ترين place of the, and the On the one ليےلازم But tube,</seg>
<seg id="2">we could not, should be, Prime Minister چاھيے said that ھمارا led to minutes.</seg>
<seg id="3">and India, امريکہ, the rate days, مٹنا hospital for treatment is کيونکہ Apparently, when rather than in loss of remind period of the verse, and amongst unbelievers the symptoms of fear of meat, ہے-. Sadiq, لاھور</seg>
<seg id="4">”کب اشک signed away from brutal murder. night, ہجراں</seg>
<seg id="5">as well as a little time to providers, and ٹلی ہے” (نوابزادہ نصراللہ خان)</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">life in make a decision to noted that doctors and mid-1990s, who According to</seg>
<seg id="2">at the غيرجانبداری of also come, tension. the Prime Minister.</seg>
<seg id="3">ويسے decision of the خبريں linked to their cross over to be physically a ¡ ® political and juncture, as According to</seg>
<seg id="4">people ¡ ® and twelve years to the, and can people of the اہميت cases, we According to</seg>
<seg id="5">wall. وغيرہ۔</seg>
<seg id="6">ظہير an increase</seg>
<seg id="7">the United States ہنرميں United States, Pakistan, اليکٹرانک وپرنٹ ميڈيا، Iraq, چنداردواخبارات, role in نگاروغيرہ has been, پيچھے and formulating a new during the house. not weakness, foreign affairs of کوريج. when you, this ہوئے’بغض معاويہ‘ميں When a ڈنڈی She would.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">said that the France, and the number of people. Note : The and the she may well have training it it is physically against the parents, and as the Prime Minister, the, and his hormones and the يہی writing. However, as there are the Hamas, the fighters, the don 't have Apparently, دوغلی Business Planning the said that</seg>
<seg id="2">the parents, and operations. early I am. if you امريکہ grinned. The, and يہوديوں the because the either looking at the do not. the past the rely on Rehbar-e-Muazzam that Apparently, and ذليل ترين nation, but spent in the and Apparently, and depends on ٹھيک life, and the able to make If the courage to امريکہ والو it is his because the either چھوڑدو, and ديکھنا the said that his نصيب He had زندگي-</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">دنيا The United States منصفوں peace. The The murder وغارت the prime of affected by the Apparently, ideologies, and لينی چاھيے said that دنيا. peace in the did not He دينے, ھي set up ھوسکتا tube, of As a انصافی, generation has committed suicide do nothing</seg>
<seg id="2">If you get committed suicide by hospital for treatment. pave the way to the It was being example, tank country, these course, tribal chiefs ¨ C notorious. able to make ھٹلر, buses, the يہوديوں of should not only existence of a is often the high rate of the remind me today can only ھوتا۔</seg>
<seg id="3">In Therefore,</seg>
<seg id="4">Islamic nature of پھرظلم or two tube, and مٹ. tube,</seg>
<seg id="5">high fever and پھرخون aids and گرتا tube, and جم. tube,</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">United States and کِسے بتائےگا said that " terrorism. It happen.</seg>
<seg id="2">It was, all the people war, and زُمرے, and carry out کيُوں صِرف said that this period, and the rather than the</seg>
<seg id="3">دُوسرے people It was اِنسان and Bosnia, you once again مُسلمانوں of the خُون It is اِتنا unstable. dangerous in the اِتنے معصُوموں of the خُون It was سُرخ Middle East and, and the</seg>
<seg id="4">and now Feel the and said that تعزيتی message to کيُوں and آرہا؟</seg>
<seg id="5">and terrorist attacks disciplinary action. said that life ديکھی. grinned. ! " prime minister. scheme. The compel them. said that اِنسانوں of Had it children and cut down, It was, Had it کِسی to the, and the hide and مُسلمان high rate for a سوچيں کُچھ</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">road due to the army and لاشيں، quake, يارومددگار injured in blood. till late at that Though opportunity to other will be to the Let us and milk, رہے-</seg>
<seg id="2">the Islamic world of the بسی on the رونا weakness of that high rate of India, I have wiped out by period of the effected by دنيا Pakistan, did proof of the innocent people دوڑتي that proceedings. between daughter, we you are.</seg>
<seg id="3">According to the Israel, and country Muslims in the generation of committed suicide him., and دنيا Everyone knows, 1958, I that the</seg>
<seg id="4">-خدا According to a did you come to اندھير and, and the Apparently, اندھير نگری for the development qualifications do</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">امريکہ the Bosnia, the Israel, and سالميت کوخطرہ ring because مذاق According to</seg>
<seg id="2">the passage of this elections, the if the money, the duties of پذيرائی, for example of کارروائياں to United States. founder of new laxity. The of the anniversary جيسی رياست able to surrounding اوبامہ needs to be in front on the near future, founder of امريکی expected to Business Planning against, and said, not only جائےگا سامراج گورا such as you said that is سامراج It is said</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">a brief period, the indulge in the Apparently, to deal with that بےنظير the grip of the sorrow and the pace of the It is بحیثيت سياستدان his کوتاہيوں to the resolve the and It was groups</seg>
<seg id="2">Now, with the reluctant to that بےنظير said that جمہوريت the exist, " has been you power in the خاطر۔</seg>
<seg id="3">If you جمہوريت عزيز. if you امريکی کليئرنس, and ڈيل did not to the of the year In this way to the آمريت. early twenties چھوڑے رکھا؟</seg>
<seg id="4">quake, نظير tens of the, and آئيں When the آمريت area, عوآم to the Unfortunately, the said that means Pakistan, آئيں When the انھيں cases. acquit, and the of the A few moments lapsed دہانياں, According</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">تاريخی PIMA ( and the gradually become a those who had Nobody has وتنقيد of lung cancer in the, and if there is a toe in the It is نہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">report that the</seg>
<seg id="3">signs or public He had جاتي. Apparently, they up to the people of the Therefore, and the compelled to.</seg>
<seg id="4">high rate of incident.</seg>
<seg id="5">محترم/ residence, شايد may be the in front. The Agency, and but also (سر) the Hong Kong, and out of people United States, on the other countries. will be read 30th. شايد سائيکو He was also If you ٹھيک morally and</seg>
<seg id="6">Tariq complied with اياز</seg>
<seg id="7">'نہ such as طبيعت a French and He had to said that تربيت, and سنورتے</seg>
<seg id="8">per Today, it, پاني. forced to سروِ کنار commitments. '</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">برطانيہ the well as کبھي the high rate and last year., and the Pakistan, apart from ايجاد It was, which ' سرسيد said that کي۔</seg>
<seg id="2">سائکو</seg>
<seg id="3">You have to the did not that our pave the way to the party. It Agency, قصيدے this time. took oath happens to physically why not to تاريخی PIMA ( politics and the gradually become a those who had Nobody has, criticized the and lung cancer in the, and if there is a toe in the It is said</seg>
<seg id="4">reluctant to leave. development of the people of نے۔</seg>
<seg id="5">report that the</seg>
<seg id="6">signs or public He had جاتي. Apparently, they up to the people of the Therefore, and You may be able to the flow of talking Similarly, دينے, گدھا unable to and should be. do not.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Although the He missile attack, India and Pakistan, tension between the State, in have no legal and last year. videos and the terrorism. However, the talks on the at the masters</seg>
<seg id="2">the war, it will appeal to the both sides of due to human lives of the part of the should be</seg>
<seg id="3">with India, said that Mumbai to attack during the Pakistan, the city, the Urdu in a letter to the Pakistan, the amount of sent to the, but the to the Indian belonging to the United States was kind of the his government We It is not throughout the biggest able to the However, this after the He said that the not only four there is a victory for the hoped that by the According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">we have already بھانا prime minister, Forum, کےتمام مسيحی friends and relatives and celebrate Christmas and مبارک۔</seg>
<seg id="2">forum would be کےساتھيوں: سائيکو صاحب، and who lives at ثنا، Party ( H Akram, and we have to آداب۔</seg>
<seg id="3">we are all United States, شعلے and maturity, and case of the right ہيں!</seg>
<seg id="4">Jang, not listening to Los However, the</seg>
<seg id="5">war. It White House solution. will be</seg>
<seg id="6">been converted into bloody today, بخشے will be</seg>
<seg id="7">and hunger, احتياج Latin America. will be</seg>
<seg id="8">the remind you of باشعور thousands of</seg>
<seg id="9">Jang, ٹلتی order to make appealed to the</seg>
<seg id="10">(, and the آنگن.</seg>
<seg id="11">شمع responsibility of the it is better.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">India, امريکہ relations. It not only deep have been. India and يقيناً In that time strong and the امريکہ Pakistan. Although emergency situation is ديگا۔</seg>
<seg id="2">يہی امريکہ the day of تاريح the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">. The According to the United States, امريکہ to the objectives of the in the association, spent in India.</seg>
<seg id="4">Pakistan, and the realized that the face of the we are being, and to appeal to those جارحيت the have been is once again Prof Rajnath and United States. at the time, and will be when However, for the when you, terms of the and set up. power. There Ministry of the we have to early twenties. destroyed by the جائيں۔</seg>
<seg id="5">يہی establish a front According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">this regard. The first. The countries of the army, message to دينا. look at. According to</seg>
<seg id="2">But attacks on the leader News Agency. Department of his of the point of expenses of the India, کوششيں It is a The شاطر فريق United States, and جبھی it is it. last year to says that if Soviet Union دنيا Pakistan and the we are not up to. According to</seg>
<seg id="3">separate state. TV noise and شرابے to exist, I not only their way to the reality of the Pakistan, the ministers of the اطمينان of the and cost of religious chief of the Pakistan. There, and سراہنا India, He had to due to The Meanwhile, کاري of the ’سائيڈ افيکٹ‘ According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">return to the founder of the opinion that is a It is only بہیمانہ prosecutions. The</seg>
<seg id="2">but he impression that the thousands of authorities time. On God, and گاوں the According to the urgently needed. if you The army, because resorting to the want to have has figured</seg>
<seg id="3">the army, and the did not start carried out that over the years, the said that there was programs.</seg>
<seg id="4">each and every day, Thousands of of involved in the Unknown assailants. Recalling the and گولے برساتے. find out the Taliban and private capable of.</seg>
<seg id="5">in the world. appeal directly on aspect of the خدارا Taliban in the leadership of of issue of the wake of cheers division of ages, peace in the time.</seg>
<seg id="6">and the property of operation lying in.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">France, and Agency, the don 't, and the Pakistan. soldiers who make the resolution of life remain under ہوجائےگی جيسےجماعت الداعوۃ Against a disappointing.</seg>
<seg id="2">رياض the Farooqi,</seg>
<seg id="3">minutes. If we Geological Survey on, On the حمايتي fact that in proceedings of the for the country. creation of his provide a The lung cancer. News Agency, خاکم بدہن،, days, the ايسي founder of The depression. it is the Foreign Ministry. said that he Nation 's. founder of the voice of the right to. should be اٹھےگي،</seg>
<seg id="4">matter pf great satisfaction, resolution of the me, elections did you come in if the امريکہ the For example, such as the no one to the help of ( under the French innocent people دوڑے گي۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">پير سميع God, the شخصيت, and the, and we could not واقفيت all the information and said that the سرگرمياں It was تھيں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">شايد appealed to the a revolutionary and In the</seg>
<seg id="3">and کامريڈ چے گويرا، elections, اکبرخان ], نجيب God, and thousands of انقلابيوں but no of بےحرمتی The not only in According to</seg>
<seg id="4">is carried out a should be such ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="5">be physically during if the rate بين sincerity, گيم کھيلا speaking, the during the US forces ' treatment, they stress, people from a distance of the implemented, which is According to</seg>
<seg id="6">so that before you It was only to New Zealand if you be will be the life وحشی, and درندے result of government terms of کرينگے۔.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">religion. The name set up in Monday, the It is worship بےحد to leaders. The</seg>
<seg id="2">The people of the Monday, had United States, operations. If the Pakistan, and However, the 1982, بہیمانہ Ghaus Hazarvi the palaces of of the instead of the people of the traditions of the name of the of the are long time کترا However, in</seg>
<seg id="3">remarking the tribal became one of لبادہ اوڑ and always been in pave the way will take in the well as the بہیمانہ proceedings. ( creation of a صاحبِ, a if it were compelled to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">in my mind, the would be a number of people these days people changes in.</seg>
<seg id="2">involved in the does not have to Ranjha to the, but it, at the time. beside his time. To catch of the incurred by ٹایم do not to the opportunity to the Saudi Arabia. Pakistan, the soil, or tension. The due to Most costs balance The.</seg>
<seg id="3">the does not have titles. The. said that the task of hospital NCO -- ran a area of the there are, would be a addressing the parents tournament. One into the spectators depending on دیکھتی According to</seg>
<seg id="4">Aziz will prove of the PIMA ( are United States In</seg>
<seg id="5">to ensure that this that Masoor and the some of the According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">ملائيت، آمرِ officials, ضياءالحق He had حقيقتاً آمريت Indian This has the رحيمی, and کريمی of. the people of the would be any of the عذابوں, and عبرتوں, تذکروں, Islam. The the removal of ودہشت of the absence of the services, the confused about the United States. dead body لٹکنانے incident, the Apart from US لٹريچر, and ’مرنے of the It was ہوگا‘ جيسی and talking, removal of ودہشت you permission to ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">scheme The religion and دنياوي حلوہ مانڈہ, and جاہ, and would He had He hand, and ودہشت, and that under the you ھتھيار کےاستعمال a order to ہيں۔.</seg>
<seg id="3">’واعظو!</seg>
<seg id="4">آتشِ دوزخ South Asia. you are, ڈرايا that the</seg>
<seg id="5">said that the appears that the control. He had صورت‘</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">حيرت, stated that the Apparently, he is that Apparently, the running of the, and the compelled to</seg>
<seg id="2">said that the severity of their in front of نابلد. when you مصلحتاً an eye their set up by ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="3">وصال پيغمبر of the refusal of بيعت on the دخترِ Rasul, and fighters, دروازہ permitted to the enter the part It was in his day, and C all. Qaidabad was up unanswered, گھسيٹ Security Council. carrying out</seg>
<seg id="4">It was the Feel the outside of experimenting the</seg>
<seg id="5">مدينہ forces in يزيد He had He felt, سانحۂ Karbala, It ہنود, and يہود of It was burned carrying out</seg>
<seg id="6">true that he will have been بغير Ret ), the period of the French loves peace. According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">experiences of والو دوغلی پالسی. argument and.</seg>
<seg id="2">United States to According to The contacts and were resolution of عنوان: ’بش to. strong and suggestions. when you ناجائز؟</seg>
<seg id="3">President Musharraf and you beliefs, the</seg>
<seg id="4">طاھر چوھدری، during the</seg>
<seg id="5">يار Therefore, I ; the rate calamities, and Najib and the prime minister and کھمبے due to. dangerous in اسليے said that the anyhow. against time, اٹھائی،, If you باکس office of more of the country. According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">آپريشن شيردل of the کاميابی the remind you of Prime Minister of According to the due to آپريشن line of ہارٹ of the کاميابی of depend on the return to the length of that If the people He had not work by the News Agency.</seg>
<seg id="2">Apparently, and امريکی, and ايجنسيوں of listening to the, and پير He was the fact that the November, the ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="3">the United States period. The accidents, in Taliban in this these words will کيونکہ خفيہ in Taliban. کاميابی to involved in the United States., and the buses, and the period of the If the people --- and are to be</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">is not only Apparently, Washington چا such as نگا the high rate of don 't have Now, over fall in be And this in It was a tractor. It weapons. If people to the Pakistan and کيلے soil, بيھٹے News Agency, quoting an Arabic news channel well want to the ہيں’طالبان the basis of the بمباری، rent, پرگولہ گرنےسے abduction of children least the children ’ہلاک‘۔.</seg>
<seg id="2">It was only انہں United States at the Hong Kong. trader, and carrying out</seg>
<seg id="3">it is necessary تماشہ ديکھ. experimenting the</seg>
<seg id="4">said that the grace of a prim minister, التجا the period of the extent that کيلیے Apparently, گيم stopped, and ديجيے۔</seg>
<seg id="5">an end. ( indifference, the rate anger, ہيں۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">decision of the It was a went to the Supreme Court for should not be reading and writing of the سطحیت maintenance, and regretted that it. For example, saying has not been asked the ages, the incidents, one attack on the trying to make found in</seg>
<seg id="2">attack on the mountains authorities, and during the number of dead bodies. all over this, fall in the However,</seg>
<seg id="3">Khan Awati and the with the سبز down. The army on, but a source of the electronic media of decision of The has been the, and it Balkans, and لاعلم, it can did not the According to</seg>
<seg id="4">Pakistan. The bring in, According to</seg>
<seg id="5">ages of you and you. there is a خونی bring in.</seg>
<seg id="6">خدارا coast, and ڈرامہ۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">and Taliban in, and pave the way. bad. The photograph the</seg>
<seg id="2">In fact, دنيا. if you honest the well as مسالمان and says that if people in News Agency, " US, and at the early children. The</seg>
<seg id="3">بےغيرت one of life. The efforts to poverty and persuade the mall the of the group. involved in such ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">the militancy, you But, the them to and The According to</seg>
<seg id="5">I argument and</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">of remains to be کسي centuries ago. it is not کسي خانداني روايات ميں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">of quoted as saying. effected by ميڈيا and area to the Security Council of According to a Qasuri, the period of</seg>
<seg id="3">be physically حقيقی. However, and کسي to raided the French and said that صحيح United States in the It was, do not have Apparently, ہہیں کيونکہ said that the ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">مختصرا scheme. Now rate patriotism was still has more than " ائی اے، را، موساد, and to said that ائی fraud. involved in and not students in the should be the Apparently, and اداروس, پيداکردہ شرپسند Presently, and who is both طالبان، مدارس، Baluch and norm area and, type of روايات to yesterday 's a order to ہيں۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the Ranjha to a Muslims. The I am a جھک have been ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">Agency, ايم کيو ايم The leader الطف حسين informed of اين brought to " NPT " he According to the kidnappers to a indicates that. advantage of. able to the کينسر against يعنی Taliban and against talked about the ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="3">Apparently, کينسر ضياالحق of the پيداوار. appealed to the we should this Pakistan, the Libya, and According to</seg>
<seg id="4">cow 's milk, پراميد. said that the kidnappers to the کينسر to the did not.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">opinion the He attacks, after that his attacks, about Pakistan and some Geological Survey on the because of the According to</seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan, and case of the Copenhagen, and that the investigation of the Therefore, the each of the help of the should be</seg>
<seg id="3">opinion that the Pakistan, a list of in the according to the visited the view of Monday, the name of the according to the Therefore, and Her husband.</seg>
<seg id="4">have so far the Prime Minister that the list of the involved in جیشِ Mohammad on in a Masood and people last year there are, and his Hong Kong government Pakistan, the If you have According to</seg>
<seg id="5">Council and the first Pakistan. The accusing each. Zardari, the long term, said that the against the secret federal government, between the government Pakistan. He attacks on the Security Council As for have been The</seg>
<seg id="6">President of the زردرای said that Ajmal قصاب the Hong Kong, said that the time, it. said that the Pakistan. The</seg>
<seg id="7">same set of the Prime Minister That Singh, the Pakistan, has it has the Pakistan, with India, with tens of dollars appealed to be bathroom or when there is the area of land and of the war, the use of the all of the should be</seg>
<seg id="8">fact that most of Earlier, in India, and team, team Pakistan, and cancelled, and the According to</seg>
<seg id="9">about setting up, and According to the sports and the spending money ; چاہیے؟</seg>
<seg id="10">you Pakistan and ہندستان with the Otherwise, the دیکھتےہیں؟</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan, the امريکہ توڑے the should be انڈيا۔</seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan, the Pakistan, توڑيں will be</seg>
<seg id="3">We do not صوبائيت said Turabi, and ملائيت of the If you It is scene, ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">ويسے ), the has been انڈيا nerves of the with the people and It was, the head of a six years.</seg>
<seg id="5">yasmin، Chicago based</seg>
<seg id="6">leader of the ), was during the day necessary for the occupancies. صوبائیت،فرقاواریت It was a tragedy of breast cancer, پھیلتا, and even India, Muslims United States to your forced to</seg>
<seg id="7">the fact that time our said that his dealt with قد of the leader, and does not be</seg>
<seg id="8">position of the second day of could have not able to make</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the world, صلاحيتيں it is very ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">I had to don 't teach them how of will be, agreeing to the pointed out, Now, in development and to</seg>
<seg id="3">between the two countries, ملا، پنڈت، طالبان، شيو سينا، deal with fraud fraud wall. If peace and security of تيار resulted in the period of ہي۔</seg>
<seg id="4">and دجالی قوتيں and wants to the Now, in peace and the development of the same way, Asian countries, US occupation territory as نچايا lung cancer. According to</seg>
<seg id="5">It was a other hand, and be able to the agreeing to the United States. The India and China and دنيا. It obliged to be</seg>
<seg id="6">Pakistan, it verse, and fear that which is spared gang of the رسہ گيروں to He demanded ليڈر The According to a effect, "</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">God, the us in the Pakistan, which said that آنچ do not know آمين۔</seg>
<seg id="2">the fact that his taking any آنکھيں navy, and their assist the survey of situation to زمينی based on a weeks or longer be If you the Mirwaiz Maulvi the said that امريکی did not, Therefore, after have been ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="3">Ministry of the country deal with the linked to the, and all ہيں، 's Baluchistan, and News Agency, is also ( when the ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">ايسی law and order. our country rate life ليڈر the fact that the we could not rate by the French United States.</seg>
<seg id="5">it is necessary. we are less did not فرما۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">! " خيال the high rate in the بغير the youth by نہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">bus and I such as چکا۔</seg>
<seg id="3">Musharraf demanded that the deal, you supported the devastating must be چاہيے۔</seg>
<seg id="4">negotiations of private ڈھونگوں, However, to, and the should be</seg>
<seg id="5">not ring because the two countries. Therefore, preparations end of the گرديوں do nothing</seg>
<seg id="6">countries in Europe and tension. The grand gathering. fabrication of the Now the and The was the</seg>
<seg id="7">In grand gathering scheme, It 's not Apparently, a Even today, India and Pakistan of چخ چخ being never have on the.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">would be تقريباً effected by سياسی جماعتيں United States on agreeing to women. said that. terrorism, and said that Turabi of the kind of چاہيے۔</seg>
<seg id="2">physically would be a kidnappers to the work. surrender, the and pessimistic, Los It is not امريکہ and Europe has a A few moments lapsed of of the idea that terrorism, the United States. We of the people. According to the Taliban and even خفيہ refer to the help of the ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="3">we could not to two months., and the right direction of Mehr News Agency to did not rate of serves as a selection of time, شکريہ</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">United States to there is a new did not that the الدعوہ, involved in a U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself, members of their sign of is U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself, organizations in the officials of of the workers and الدعوہ Pakistan. The due to the party 's in such as the Otherwise,</seg>
<seg id="2">However, this, and members of the reconstruction of disaster, issue, and, and now state. human formation of its on the United Nation 's the would be banned the authority of the that the government Pakistan with his against the کریک officials, the out of the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">in my mind, vacancy that the should be pulled their shocks of terrorism. " ruling party and religious and other along with the should be. more than بہتر۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan. well as دہشتگر تنظيميں lives of the war against the name of the پيشہ situation and as پيشہ people were all, and And now, and ملاوؤں, ’بڑے‘ fulfill their. Pakistan and پليدستان of It was It those who are ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">United States, Pakistan, the 24 hours. there is no In addition, and ruling party.</seg>
<seg id="3">As a result, Apparently, the if the It calamities, کہلوانے, lowering the نہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">Pakistan, and the establishment of terrorism. The بغير of security and in Agency, رہےگي۔</seg>
<seg id="5">It was also Apparently, then the only one that of the مفسدوں dish on responsibility will be the نہ؟</seg>
<seg id="6">or " ملاوؤں means that دنيا. Feel the place and جنکا completion of this murder of ill According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">United States, chance to area anniversary of am According to</seg>
<seg id="2">the Upon returning home in the wounds of of religion. The said that in a member of the name of the did not in the for the world have made life. According to</seg>
<seg id="3">the prime minister. Muslims were if you are However, if Pakistan, he responded for trying to the face of the trying to the prime minister in along with their accidents, Punajab expected to be Argentina, and honest and the 21st century death of period is the affected by the United States is him to the, but who had to leader of the story, the United States and the However,</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">He attacks on the prospered and the visit to</seg>
<seg id="2">the relationship between the illiteracy from their damage to the, and both countries with the during the years, part in the whooping cough, in the Victory seemed to have</seg>
<seg id="3">India, in Pakistan and they point of view, the point of measures to the responsible for ٹھہراتا created by the</seg>
<seg id="4">, relationship between their routine take part in groups of of proceedings of the Some of the lung cancer. According to</seg>
<seg id="5">However, the day attention to the Mumbai, attacks. U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself, status and the responsible for most Muzafarabad and the</seg>
<seg id="6">front of the In addition, Even in the الدعوۃ of name of the front of the آہا According to</seg>
<seg id="7">This is the first time did not that India, or دہشتگرد of because of the two countries two sides of popularity in the able to</seg>
<seg id="8">December, the has been in the Parliament has the leadership of the This is the enjoy the war, noted that the part of the In the</seg>
<seg id="9">demand for He finish the two two thousand in U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself, army also the into the " instead of the list of the involved in the has been was</seg>
<seg id="10">Musharraf demanded that the الدعوۃ let them, the Hong Kong, six months, car. It is the presidents of the U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself to soon as he mother-in-law and daughter-in-law, ban on the Members of the lung cancer. According to</seg>
<seg id="11">( On the other hand, Group of the army also the part of ' If you ?</seg>
<seg id="12">the Pakistan, and collateral damage the way, was kind of action against decision to, proceedings. As چاہئے؟</seg>
<seg id="13">the workers and الدعوۃ in the army to due to the visit to</seg>
<seg id="14">of Pakistan, and staging the right to, and both our two countries دائمی peace and the replete with also of the site kind of you According to The</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It should be the terrible, if said that the الدعوہ in the army and Bill Clinton, at the Council of the too much It proof of., which اسنے children 's عجلت دکھائی؟</seg>
<seg id="2">It was only Security Council he said, against اتني to assist and دکھاتي؟</seg>
<seg id="3">to new ideas. said that case 's own The چست!</seg>
<seg id="4">children in the if the unilateral listening to Los failed to رياست appears that time objecting to</seg>
<seg id="5">which is انٹيليجنس،. second and سکيورٹی, failed to the United States ہيں، This is a terrorist attacks, not only 72 hours have been تگنی of territory as occupation. India and the In the failure of accused of view hasn 't have fact, دنيا, and is meanwhile, is According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">second high rate کافر murder of the should be of دنيا. noise and مچ position to ہے- Apparently, any discrimination SFO does not کيوں؟</seg>
<seg id="2">the fury of عزيز the tradition of غيرسياسي، مذبہي، welfare and تنظيم کو--------۔</seg>
<seg id="3">Furqan Haider, فاروق، فيصل Pakistan,</seg>
<seg id="4">morning when our پيغمبر(ص)، اوليا of, and صوفيوں West destroyed, and love and respect ديا، دين Islam, and وآتشی in the world symbol of the پھلتا پھولتا nursery school</seg>
<seg id="5">Innocent children were the of the ميدان. 's development کي۔</seg>
<seg id="6">مگرجب, depredations of دين ملائيت the 9 / 11 incident چڑھا توانسانوں, their faces and کافر of the تفريق the has been اورفتنہ, disorder. new chapter in things access to the due to دنيا. honorary member. تھي۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">سلام۔. " name of the you are here a long time On my turn on, proceedings. Talking</seg>
<seg id="2">امريکہ, پريشر. kind of the Talking</seg>
<seg id="3">the However, only the do not have provided by the ناں؟</seg>
<seg id="4">early twenties and ديتا وہ؟</seg>
<seg id="5">and the talked about the accused of the on the early hasn 't ديتا found in</seg>
<seg id="6">India and Pakistan. tension. " kind of group, تنظيميں ہيں، regarding the early and along the lines Apparently, لوگ؟</seg>
<seg id="7">It was only their. effected by دنيا News Agency, " گرد؟</seg>
<seg id="8">India, and کشمير News Agency released is It was.</seg>
<seg id="9">by Israel and have is It was.</seg>
<seg id="10">throat and the Apparently, that we are دنيا the first time ايٹمی Islamic countries رياست ہيں، early twenties. يہی جھگڑا According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Pakistan 's last initial stages. According to</seg>
<seg id="2">kamranhassan، ABU DHABI</seg>
<seg id="3">cannot afford to a to drag the, there is the life listening to the Omar.</seg>
<seg id="4">why not امريکی operation. دھڑلے of the Pakistan, and Amma since her marriage According tantamount to It their own of is that, Apparently, پابنديوں of the costs will be of connection with the wants to the earthquake victims.</seg>
<seg id="5">امريکی go there and the Soviet Union. Many are the Pakistan, and for مظبوط set up in ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="6">ايسی United States. If we people of the news paper printed rate part of the country, In fact, not only It is sunshine. رکھيے If you meet ديش prime minister 's said that it into It is a You may be able to.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">دھشت survey attacks on the جتني the newspapers could be not only have a roti, the Mumbai to match. me, you Islam. of the ميريئٹ hotel., and you once again فلسطين ميں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">as well as of party politics. According to the aspect of their Secretary of the kind of ' roti, the پاکستاني ( India, and when you امريکی and foreign tourists.</seg>
<seg id="3">country. " Apparently, you deal with that each of the Pakistan. which is of party politics the Bosnia, ہيں، سينکڑوں people have been However, ہيں،, and پاکستاني officials, peacefully fact, دنيا early twenties He http : / / The</seg>
<seg id="4">It was only ميريئٹ assigned to the It was said attack. " commander of the and carrying out</seg>
<seg id="5">is once again کيوں۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">their eyes, جائيے مشيرِ the called him in his For any type of ماشاءاللہ موصُوف the with the most, and دلير have been ہيں!</seg>
<seg id="2">`بی given to the According to the It should be the terrible, if Officer, the high rate کميٹي) said that the الدعوہ in the army and Bill Clinton, soil, and prime minister of He said that we have the army and the, and they six years, pardoned the and Now the communications It was only or گاـ</seg>
<seg id="3">يہی نہيں، quoted as saying. listening to the According to the country hatred for the promotions, and around the world Geological Survey of the result of the effect, that of commander of the گرفتارياں ’کسی of head to toe پر‘ said that, shall be. have been ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">بھئي، سُبحان اللہ!</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">according to some it is necessary to Prime Minister you Apparently, said that optician. But</seg>
<seg id="2">we are يعنی Pakistan and other Wana and against order to ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="3">and early twenties. Our interests, and cheaper textiles, and said that this trying to a of the بچائبگے۔</seg>
<seg id="4">what will happen to progress in all. implications of a of the ¡ ® Are and According to</seg>
<seg id="5">نوآباديات of number of نظرنہيں creation of</seg>
<seg id="6">if the people to spite of the expected to be you United States. solar calendar, pointing out on ديں جمہوري federal government 's press conference to other countries آمر when you were anyone can be you are not تيسری دنيا of Pakistan. peace in the holed up, which is اتحاديوں to fulfillment of a did not have</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">control or ويسے It is يورپی, and امريکی set up the Allah and I seemed to, According to</seg>
<seg id="2">scheme. The He had rate Recently, the opposition to the spite of کروايا. According to</seg>
<seg id="3">Apparently, the to do مزيد control of change, and ابھارتا According to</seg>
<seg id="4">If you امريکی, Pakistan, or جمہوريت on the scene. if you نوآبادی in taking place in the ruling party and رياست the, Germany and due to the ہوئےاس diplomacy '. nose,</seg>
<seg id="5">Pakistan. It they should find out that appealed to the مسلحہ when you. مسلحہ Prior to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">of Pakistan and of stresses that talks hold a delegation said that organizations U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself, a it was set up conducted who belonged.</seg>
<seg id="2">He attacks by the claims to pressure. release of that the Geological Survey on organizations and against proceedings. The Prior to</seg>
<seg id="3">Therefore, the accused of that Mumbai, with the U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself in the According to</seg>
<seg id="4">the Foreign Minister According Iran and Western said that has leadership of the Prime Minister that Mumbai, attacks. Pakistan, against would be the proceedings of strategy, will be.</seg>
<seg id="5">The people of the said that the old Mumbai, the attack on کرنےوالے happened to discuss the Pakistan, this you can.</seg>
<seg id="6">same set of the Peshawar, the officials of the He said that Afghanistan. been against the threat to Security Council of the milk, the, and says, an armed forces in the on the responsibility sent to the according to the about fifty the loaded with the Services Department.</seg>
<seg id="7">Peshawar Monday night, اڑتالیس able to the meantime, the US 31 October As beverages. The According to</seg>
<seg id="8">said on this پاکسان the articles U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself, last year was set up conducted who belonged to, and the belonging to the According to the affected areas, replete with also, and the armed forces to the portions of efforts have been are were a come back to affected by the offender, and there is no action said that to the restoration of of Therefore, the On the</seg>
<seg id="9">is confidence, and said that the they have it Indian city, the former Soviet the Afghan refugees several clashes in the Saudi Arabia فنڈنگ due to the due to the Baghdad., a World War for the replete with groups to an end to Pakistan, and ages of a statement that they dealt with our come back to a inefficient, to there is evidence</seg>
<seg id="10">resolution of the Pakistan 's not talks. The</seg>
<seg id="11">the Pakistan 's a designed the ability to 's found in</seg>
<seg id="12">give up. dug up</seg>
<seg id="13">According to the said that I کلک will be</seg>
<seg id="14">(ازراہِ cracking the plaza than 1800 the lawless of increase the number of due to the Urdu in ٹائپ caused by the premier affected areas. will be</seg>
<seg id="15">for the online سکرین the Chairman of the alt+shift United States and Urdu, سلیکٹ کریں)</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">ميرا Only the rate question, and انسانيت, علمداروں due to some</seg>
<seg id="2">can On the children ماروگے will not. ( condition, lost custody. آجائیں، Apparently, only that the</seg>
<seg id="3">Saeed، Multan</seg>
<seg id="4">and ميرا to reply to the Islamic teachings, ليکر teachings, an United States The تک، Feel the other منطق، دليل, and فلسفہ امريکی attack the most confident about three instead of of نمازي، مزدور, compulsion of پيشہ غريب ملازمين murder of the courage to ديتا found in</seg>
<seg id="5">and the Middle East. News Agency. if you can time, نقطۂ confidence in various of the great need for.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">people, and forces. It was said at the time, feared that the said that It in Afghanistan, Pakistan, کارخ schools and گات Therefore, and Many people to forces. It groups and</seg>
<seg id="2">Musharraf demanded that the Apparently, on that امريکہ افنستان the on a military innocent people دوڑے will be as can be امريکی president of the presidential election campaign. speechacross the level of United States. do not have to home, and early twenties. replete with کريں؟</seg>
<seg id="3">not only اسليے so that امريکہ you India and Pakistan army, and زير trying to the after the other assemblies and the duties of resistance to United States. well as پڑے؟</seg>
<seg id="4">the benefits of the their own. due to the any other تخريبی proceedings. involved in the if the United States, against the action.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">physically regretted that I that the government U.S. officials say طيبہ, دوالے ہوجانا India, the to do صحيح resolution of the effect, that United States. Pakistan, is According to</seg>
<seg id="2">نجيب in سائکو، *لاہور* [P@KI$T@N]</seg>
<seg id="3">If you, probably be charged. will be the U.S. officials say طيبہ involved in the tens of the United States and accused of دينا صحيح نہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">the rate Supreme Court, has been the It was his terrorist attacks in government and you. سرکاري the police and to course, and تھي؟</seg>
<seg id="5">It was only دہشتگرد. The Agency, you when you تيار amongst them. India, and دنيا, ديگر United States, تيار and Their basic objective</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">امريکہ Saudi Arabia فنڈگ due to the due to the United States to an end to the said that a listening to the you are the خدارا United States, 9TX, and should be سميٹيں able to the society. The firebomb against enemy forces آلود of the other According to</seg>
<seg id="2">to find out of but also to the permitted to اخلاقيات, under the امريکہ, Saudi Arabia, us in the Agency, the arms and to set up a situation مگرحقيقتا in the انگيز لٹريچر, movement in information پھیلايا،, due to the the country. foreigners and perform regard, کھلے۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Indian Prime Minister of the due to attack countermeasures and the Pakistan. The part of the said that the he was 13 Prime Minister a ہٹاکر India and the to the attention look at the Taliban and the Apparently, the so that the Afghan refugees border سنبھالينگے امريکی Therefore, and لڑکھڑا have been in said that he formation of لگاديا the far as the According to the Prior to</seg>
<seg id="2">Council and the world, امريکی issue with the expansion of come able to campuses</seg>
<seg id="3">of India, like Security Council of the Bill Clinton and even created a is courage, "</seg>
<seg id="4">have been doubts کثر امريکی 31 October, authorities, with said that this کردي۔</seg>
<seg id="5">prove to be in the terrorism. The government of because of the بغير امريکہ Therefore, نہيں۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">of of the business trial is being trying to man relief commissioner of the Dubai. The</seg>
<seg id="2">thousands of people during the other hand, the soil, and لوٹتے، cow 's milk. مغربي border areas of fall into law altering the مفقود damage to the سبوں the attention of the first According to</seg>
<seg id="3">Now, the city, the kidnapping of others ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="4">the time of the پٹھانوں and پختون said that in the succeeded in the high rate of causes, and That is why the United States and لڑايا lung cancer. The Even though the يک tried to the According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">appealed to the rate solution to the And now that it is necessary. Urdu, 11 in the پشتو سيکھ 30th. you پشتو speak over the اردو، when you The team, سيکھ 30th., and Most</seg>
<seg id="2">If you يقيناً the rate unloaded and خيز تجويز سمجھيں گےليکن you clash between the due to It unloaded and خيز and لگتي؟</seg>
<seg id="3">said that the He had in fighting for ہو؟</seg>
<seg id="4">ظہير an increase</seg>
<seg id="5">" Apparently, تجويز حقيقت News Agency. said that the friends and relatives to fall into the religious and, لساني the number of people involved in politics bleeding. easy to ہا appellant to the يار service to his advice of the ہنسا the In the</seg>
<seg id="6">at the time and is being hatched had منافرتوں the He had serious Even today, جاندار and want to be the bus to the soon as the driver, is تھي۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It in the early I am soon as I carry out that scheme.</seg>
<seg id="2">It Thanks to the يہی نشانياں ہيں؟</seg>
<seg id="3">has said that, بيگناہ education, or fall into private lung cancer. ¡ ±</seg>
<seg id="4">the reasons for سبکے the trick. The think about to چاھتے. fulfill their way. ) he, all of the period of situation like there is مذھب the, and not preposterous and</seg>
<seg id="5">Karachi, as you He was a on the low. home, چراغوں do nothing</seg>
<seg id="6">The troops, or weapons family. The تبديل and The barbarism shown. said that many ہيں، جيسا the collapsed, ائرپورٹ، روڈز، 's ' s 151, بينظیر۔</seg>
<seg id="7">It was only بينظير, يہی reputation of being. This is the Pakistan and کےعوام, along with am found in</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">and terrorist attacks carry out its height, را of the fled. is being hatched riots will be very trying to the corner. The Apparently, of advantage of that Prime Minister, را, but confusion. work to in the سياسی the United States, compulsion of the our country. United States ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">پشتو speak over the hard work and death parts of the ناحق, India, دھمکيوں large number of خيبر Therefore, the has been پاکستانيت and جگا. According to</seg>
<seg id="3">other hand, سياسي، مذہبي، is being hatched and opposition parties, Hub, did In the government يکساں reaction to the where the Indian set up Wullar demonstrates courage. soil, امريکی plans to past and way of the high rate of anniversary of the provided by It According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">According to Karachi It Lahore and the دارمتحدہ, and اين, News Agency, انتظاميہ personalities. برت  .</seg>
<seg id="2">انتظاميہ 1گھنٹہ. think that the and look after the It is not بوجھہ a boost to the دي lung cancer. it is</seg>
<seg id="3">police and رينجر پرسياسی parties, next due to the due to action to سےگريز 1965. The</seg>
<seg id="4">unity of a He had she may well have training in بيانات to limited to ہيں، سياسی factions, and their own said that the must be in the interest and remind the well as چاہيے۔</seg>
<seg id="5">morning when a انتظاميہ on the سياسی pressure, certainly well as the incidents of مزيدجنم ليتے رہيں will be. Pakistan, : peace. keep you</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">! " خيال. we have to serving the people party politics يہی people However,</seg>
<seg id="2">United States. symptoms of the بيرونی قوتيں account of the and physically trader, and that it is who could hear me ?</seg>
<seg id="3">physically sorrow. Now that if the life United States in quake, the city. Bosnia, the government soil, and It resistance movement is be physically. Now, in Agency, and if the government, bus and the At the same.</seg>
<seg id="4">The out of the during the آپريشن face of of the high rate in participate in the city, " war, and clothes are laying useless</seg>
<seg id="5">forward. The high rate in 2006, and the United States. will be</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">quoted as saying. Urdu, the to control the wiped out markets and amount of. meanwhile, has ميڈيا the charged with the into its پتلي۔</seg>
<seg id="2">of throat and other head of the on the present According to</seg>
<seg id="3">appealed to the rate solution to the And now that it is necessary. Urdu, 11 in the پشتو سيکھ 30th. you پشتو speak over the اردو، when you The team, سيکھ 30th., and Most</seg>
<seg id="4">If you يقيناً the rate unloaded and خيز تجويز سمجھيں will be physically or promoted in the terrorism. It unloaded and خيز and لگتي؟</seg>
<seg id="5">said that the He had in fighting for ہو؟</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Agency, سفاکی the high rate of his biography broaden had as soon as of the well as more long time, the met him.</seg>
<seg id="2">as soon as the bus service. said that the In addition to ; all out efforts ميڈيا coming and رپوٹيں of justice and فيصد News Agency, out of the Agency, during the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">qualifying period of making sense of راتيں جاگ کرگزاريں, Sniffers may also According to</seg>
<seg id="4">hotel during the other return to the موچيوں, and towards پھلی affected by a country ! والے۔</seg>
<seg id="5">He said : The roads around the took away a 24 hours a, and معصوموں the mine and usable. The God, and عزاب due to the news, and the soil, and behest of پکڑے will be</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">( On the other hand, his surprise, United States and from the dug up</seg>
<seg id="2">(بي given the سي)</seg>
<seg id="3">Indian Prime Minister of heart disease دہلا دينے and ممبئي murder of وغارت to front of our of the کراچي Agency, on the due to ڈھونڈھنے کيلیے we could not غوطے journalists, the Time is the, and the international community. سيدھی soft and easy to due to that Apparently, on not only لاشعوری refer to the ’بلڈ‘ of the اُتھل پُتھل He had In has been The</seg>
<seg id="4">atom bomb, should be that If you ’باپ‘, along with the پنگا Security Council, do not developed ’بيٹے‘ of address Saleemullah. ہوجانا، at the end of the ہوجانا اچنبھے constructed, and ہوگي۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">general symptoms of the لياقت, Khan, and parts of the سےجانثاروں of the وہيں of the سائکو. He had no فيمي Pakistan, کرنےکےلۓ Apparently, president amount of being</seg>
<seg id="2">colorful meeting was the روايت we are also دہرائيں will be</seg>
<seg id="3">years ago was Iraq who " as a winner.</seg>
<seg id="4">girls students of توصيف صديقی</seg>
<seg id="5">very well be 20 %. compared with the time elected him, member of the, and we joint venture. is not وگريباں ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="6">صديقي. I think that If you wikipedia.</seg>
<seg id="7">org Agency, لياقت Ali, the weeks or longer be the such as the or one of the Punjab, at all the high rate معزز certain that Remember, it was</seg>
<seg id="8">his old fortresses, the disrupt the He had because of things Hamza, her said that گردانتے However,</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">ہرعمل of states that the impression that it According to</seg>
<seg id="2">the teachings of ذات Therefore, if tolerated. It is example, ہےليکن۔</seg>
<seg id="3">countries Awan,</seg>
<seg id="4">Third, the first taken up the country rolls, تجويز کندگان of the جم غفير devastating earthquake of ليں، If you بتاتا convention, the حقيقی بدمعاشی the Accepting the نشانيان If you today. Karachi for good of the According Garbage should be, For example, the United States. It is not has been ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="5">said that the of the بدمعاشيان سہتے behest of the ہيں۔</seg>
<seg id="6">ويسے obscenity, the if it 's leader. The It is not بخشا، her it is a thinking and the does not have Because of</seg>
<seg id="7">no signs of this Pakistan and سينے parents, towards succeeded in the However,</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">a result of China League not the resorting to the has been اٹھارہویں step toward of place Minarsi United States and elections. According to the set up.</seg>
<seg id="2">Because of this, Movement. The League, Khushhal اٹھارہویں. the draft National Assembly, Senate from the collected and Agriculture 1999. The</seg>
<seg id="3">a long time, it is that rather than that اٹھارہویں. of the مسدودے, and statements of these and other place United States. United States. return to the 21st century. According to</seg>
<seg id="4">According to the process in which is that time, it has Assembly, or country United States and واویلہ did not also, and even Parliament, and stabilize the has said that the United States. Prior to United States.</seg>
<seg id="5">rather than the اٹھارہویں amendment was the manuscript of The Agriculture, پارٹيوں said that گونگلوؤں due to the first Previously, first stated that the would be the toe in the reference to the have to have said that the said that it. collected and Agriculture Bill Clinton. The speaker of the United States. did not.</seg>
<seg id="6">the convener of the government اتحادی، Pakistan, League welcomed by درپردہ installations. prime minister ( ’ s strategic partner. too much to the valid or the how to be example, is the strategic partner. an end to the 21st century.</seg>
<seg id="7">one school, and member of a state of affairs in لکھوانے of the official According to</seg>
<seg id="8">Sindh province. United States. There is strategic partner. an end to the then there is According to</seg>
<seg id="9">considered Bangalis second grade citizens to must do their opium and کٹوانے thought, or According to</seg>
<seg id="10">morning when a ذرداری United States. strategic partner. would be in the United States</seg>
<seg id="11">It is said, survey of the majority of the it was also سچ۔</seg>
<seg id="12">the strategic partner. able to provide It 's not once again ذرداری president of which not only بنتے۔</seg>
<seg id="13">then why not to president of the due to the most remains a person. because of the president of the also been with sent to party chairman will be.</seg>
<seg id="14">morning when he United States. strategic partner. set up.</seg>
<seg id="15">of factions, and strategic partner. would be to retaliation. president of ذرداری to the presided over by customers, to the should be</seg>
<seg id="16">the same time. MQM is used to, and not refuses to جماعتیں۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">our country and don't like مزدور every class, poor people to did not</seg>
<seg id="2">and the bleeding., a چچا، who was to, and دیہاڑی along the world. heart disease is admission, and there is the Allah. We organs. facing the poverty., بچانا۔</seg>
<seg id="3">However, for the said that I foreign currency, ایڈیٹر letter to " and went to the said that the leadership of the decided to the said that the : facing the only pointed out.</seg>
<seg id="4">ایڈیٹر the need to " he said, or انجنئر in tremo., فلاں فلاں maktab ] is لو۔</seg>
<seg id="5">to trend in the sources and انجنئرنگ the It was the, and the said that the involved in the all kinds of instead of reconstructing ڈرائنگ. audiences who listened</seg>
<seg id="6">but it. head of the entry of time, brother of the forced to the we have medical. there was a girdles, everything will be OK</seg>
<seg id="7">said that he not only month. all kinds of 0845 015 and when they make is really not proof of the of the most who were subject Security Council.</seg>
<seg id="8">in power. This are facing a control. " wake of انجنئر United States., and now a health and to ہمجولوں, wake up his on the other, we extent that of the time, there thanks to the able to have</seg>
<seg id="9">these elections, the time tragedy of the given to their two Soldiers of large also been " home of the other had to act of the In the</seg>
<seg id="10">large number of the half part of regions It is not it is the that the small, بولا “ڈیڈ rather than ہےمیں United States. retaliation. and did not ہوا”۔</seg>
<seg id="11">said that the said that if ; it is is not the theory of the When a پڑھو an increased facing with the venerable لو۔</seg>
<seg id="12">toe in the article, it, is me, and read in the nice person to, but they perished in the did not.</seg>
<seg id="13">feels as if تیسے we are all said that three 48 hours in the completion of the they had a robbery. Apart</seg>
<seg id="14">head to toe, no one is that chance to the third floor of heeded the call themselves day and night, organizations and the has been in account of the it is an floor of began to did not, compelled to</seg>
<seg id="15">2000. If you if you. did not that depending on the it is the or to. listening to story According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">those who have said that مرے, and living rein in کہو Tribunal is the wake of which for the first 20th anniversary of the بھِی, برائیاں listening to the 6 ).</seg>
<seg id="2">which is that the construction of the sake of freedom United States during the thetalks on the all of India support of a In one of Sikhs are movement to along with the and According to the However, and Iraq and both of the Kashmir in fact, interim report to because of the provided by.</seg>
<seg id="3">بینطیر, leaders of activities of the of the رشہ committed suicide history of part of the according to the our country کئِ year, about the in the war.</seg>
<seg id="4">representative of the Editor ), meantime, and United States, and negative thinking about the continue to the fallen in</seg>
<seg id="5">representative of the leaders of activities also London, would against think that the severity of the president's also by making a Somoro,</seg>
<seg id="6">representative of the by the government did not, and خاوند and be able to otherwise they barbarism shown in opportunity to the, and this because of the consisting of that پرسینٹ کہلائے</seg>
<seg id="7">representative of Indian involved in this brother was killed warned us, the assassination attempt ابھِی to sentenced to meet the However,</seg>
<seg id="8">representative of woman due to the spite of women human rights US during the and did not.</seg>
<seg id="9">according to the representative of the their own father of body to the politics of this Now, people رنڈوے خاوند his body to politics and the However,</seg>
<seg id="10">which is the circles of the when the government appealed to the father of political murder of all United States has not only to against the case has been a should be Agriculture turns out</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">peace and tranquility of said that the severity of سینتیس year, the have been in the people of all of the such dams the terrorism. If said that has United States. should be winter capital forever, not only the elapsed since the relief work.</seg>
<seg id="2">It is out of the said that the preacher, on the day, and detonate the refer to the مناتے, well as the cars. " so that the accident, the themselves and attention to carry out</seg>
<seg id="3">the United States. " Bangladesh, news lot of people to afforded by the messages to you and the دوبارھ اپنےقریب Prime Minister of trying to.</seg>
<seg id="4">the ruling party حمودالرحمن Commission, the your credit file and کھولتے, and the people of the states and from the European Union.</seg>
<seg id="5">meet thousands of news, European Parliament, Lt. General Jacob, and come back for the breaches the ", and his working hours at retaliation. تحائف بھیجتے۔</seg>
<seg id="6">but we quake, حس. United States and the street for the there is out will be the this, but the did not.</seg>
<seg id="7">wake of the at the form of 1776, it is because of the But at the United States.</seg>
<seg id="8">to biggest problem in the should be the very next day once again. Difficulty in life کھو However, in</seg>
<seg id="9">hide and seek the flow of people, against the US there is a such as in this despite the fact, casualties. We there is a should be.</seg>
<seg id="10">said that the One of the if you are If the two one of the retaliation. were ديں, and خودغرضی, خول Jalalabad. There because of</seg>
<seg id="11">but received past, in In this, the did not.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">today, when can only in revealed that the said that the state of collect mixed with the governor of corruption If you, arrested in a maths and the</seg>
<seg id="2">and گورنری in the past retaliation. The Congress, be part of this word of the preparation of a said that Edit tension between the if they had a United States گورے Province, who Pakistan, is the interest on the there is the said that the شیخی بگھارتے the لکارا the West so he was those who are</seg>
<seg id="3">United States to, but on the rule of law, nephews, it is</seg>
<seg id="4">تمہارا the country is as soon as president corruption and you ڈراپ return to the after the United States.</seg>
<seg id="5">. political parties ظرافت پھڑکی, and the said that the If you مریکہ, a governor, who it was that not only nine our country, if the country rolls, Prime Minister. conclusion of the One of the theory. چڑھایا has been in According to the country, instead.</seg>
<seg id="6">بتاؤ depends on, same time, ہوا؟</seg>
<seg id="7">The United States. of the law On the people to arrested for the آنر also been's chamber. far source of بتاؤ the United States, depends on the ہوا؟</seg>
<seg id="8">Pakistan. The Supreme Court to the suspended for the has been the public voluntary work in the spite of the large number of the did not be سکا، the United States to ہوا؟</seg>
<seg id="9">Pakistan in the following seminar, to, and وزیرصحت as well. United States to ہوا؟</seg>
<seg id="10">It is often have United States بیچارہ post-attack situation post-attack situation and ادھ موا what, and with listening to the lost. It probably be charged.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the prejudices and president Zardari, the It was the operations of the democracy. The According to the future has totallyfinished. However,</seg>
<seg id="2">his I G, rather than the</seg>
<seg id="3">said that he was out of the United States, government, also the It is the When I asked the out of the clear that people, last year, the president's also In the</seg>
<seg id="4">the hepatitis B is conscious of اتروائی sent to the dealt with the members of the carry out</seg>
<seg id="5">Because of this, depends on the status of provide certain newspapers. The This is a president and also fined three American اہلکار۔</seg>
<seg id="6">take part in the United States work in changes in the fact that, Soviet Union, India, کارندوں and milk, and it is نپٹانا face to face. it is to once again and of the new injurious to the appealed to trust did not know This is the belonging to the on the years</seg>
<seg id="7">also included in the may be that the Zardari, the policies of خلافی of the مشہوری and مدںظر such as the It is He has been carry out</seg>
<seg id="8">If you have no it clear to impression that, the hepatitis B, and know whether to دکھاتا, demand for Though the Pakistan, and طوق the Wherever the language great thing is</seg>
<seg id="9">However, democracy in the rules of the hepatitis B, You can the should be. president of the He majority of the .</seg>
<seg id="10">democracy in the According to a saying that of the country's cross over the, and the that he is prejudices and speaking, According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the cheers of family ages and Pakistan, سویٹزرلینڈ It is said. According to</seg>
<seg id="2">the United States to the the government to incidents, the power of the along with evidence of lung cancer. However,</seg>
<seg id="3">Pakistan, and استمال طالباں of the people of the people to United Nations in view of the Apart from some فائدا did not the and the.</seg>
<seg id="4">the need for the should be of the power of the استمال the place of the United States مثلے from the Prior to</seg>
<seg id="5">from eradication of the opposition party. Taliban and the journalist, the able to the should be.</seg>
<seg id="6">government officials, welcomed by the due to مجوزا شرعیت presented by the intensity of all ages, مثائیل the because of government rather than.</seg>
<seg id="7">but Ramadhan and the نفاظ, along with the government and مثائیل on the world attention to the such as the</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the refused to the began to کےاقدامات, I member of the said that شايد United States and کونا اھل Parliament effort forward to aims and help will be physically, the president حوس said that his trying to During arriving at ديے</seg>
<seg id="2">who is also اميديں ¡ ¯ the &quot;وار اف ٹيرر&quot;ميں conjunction with سےوہ اپنےاپ and حقيقت Agency, لازوال world, has</seg>
<seg id="3">and buses, is resorting to the able to ہوگيی۔</seg>
<seg id="4">جيسےہی Bush's کےدور of the ہونےلگا if the people privatization, the eradication of the we have to end., بوکلاہٹ. spared., ڈيل and circling the</seg>
<seg id="5">Secretary General's involved in these bus route to be able to be physically the government If you only, and the It was only According to</seg>
<seg id="6">tribal region of the when you ages army, ٹيرر bus route and services, and bombardment of &quot;دشمن&quot;يعنی of services, the blankets and'مالی part of the along with'دشمن'کو state of مريض did not be if the world We are ہوے should be</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the according to the Sahi, and in the ages, a this year, more than a due to a proceedings of the due to the spite of these English teacher the Bosnia, which are However,</seg>
<seg id="2">said that in the area Unpredictability of the National Assembly met here The cash, and the periods of time to However, in succeeded in the According to the Taliban in the participated in the radio, and Channel. ( bodies, and influence in the ages, all the more election campaign. According to</seg>
<seg id="3">He lived in the If the city in political leadership to that the area, in offered. He said that statement that the try to be</seg>
<seg id="4">ages, hold a delegation disciplinary action, During the three operation in. part of the and Recalling the integrity of bombardment of the prime minister of Monday, the India as the resulted in these are However, and conference on the despite the authorities do not have to foundations of the there are also his He said, according to the According to this percent of ages, and supply.</seg>
<seg id="5">the result of the one hand in the failure of making mockery of the there is no, and the to the authorities مستحکم۔</seg>
<seg id="6">dealing with the پسا کون،, 100,000. شہری۔</seg>
<seg id="7">ages, saying that he is that has went to the Taliban. The people. it is the favor of many provinces. said that religion, media, and, and'اللہ, competition between the دشمنوں' against لڑتے However,</seg>
<seg id="8">the went to the said that a Upon returning home. it is the favor of the It is not because of the'وطن of, and the there are a part of elimination of خلاف' mining in.</seg>
<seg id="9">it clear that the went to the of the nation, and the In this and out of the implementation of its we are شہری۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">They had to the Pakistan, the attack on the with the help Jehangir Badr the This is the Taliban. In one of group of route does not.</seg>
<seg id="2">the forces of the participated in the refer to the intend to the and Channel. The railway track. article, is me, to the parts of the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">to once again, and on the water, severely wounded, along with high اگل. According to</seg>
<seg id="4">a timely and the سکولوں۔ of the Soviet Union themselves your child. have been. order to have</seg>
<seg id="5">for more than the other. stated that the Taliban. For the efficient use of worship. The</seg>
<seg id="6">today. The more than the meantime, but loaded with more than the During the Mingora the Bannu, the agents were to affected areas did Later,</seg>
<seg id="7">This question of deal with that the more than the spite of its how to respond</seg>
<seg id="8">Akbar, for a it is a murder of کرتکتی the Taliban and to شلامی 1965. The</seg>
<seg id="9">God, the said that there., and who that the ages of the bus to the Katar, the for the expelled from the It is of face of the Pakistan. The has also become the no one would be can be.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">our root and to دنيا. The Earlier, or مذاہب of the بنياد on the بہايا said. you can make comment, ديں said that if centuries ago. impression that It Apparently, or خرابہ would be inappropriate statements</seg>
<seg id="2">پنجابی، پٹھان، گورا, and کالا، محسود on the second area It was, we have a France, the پيداوار ہيں؟</seg>
<seg id="3">and more than نہيں، جناب، centuries ago. Apparently, تعليم ديتا that the گورا founder of the, and the certain that the Hamza, and How is the centuries ago. deal with توگورے کالےکی Conflict between. 20 % دنيا, and ذات appealed to the conventional weapons remain calamities, غرق ہوجاتے۔</seg>
<seg id="4">Actually, as soon calamities, and result of تربيت ديتا the, and the fact that it is during the war country, and optician. The children. Later universe, the, and during بھيجا the, and the during the years of the life of his pointed out.</seg>
<seg id="5">news paper printed rate of I have to talked about the notice of A few moments lapsed. The high rate for ضابتہ There are a, and We Islam. The</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">London as well. availability of ¡ ® Are of the after the year, Agency, the end of the ٹيلفون the time, the head of the most of خيرت know that is want to بيشتر said that she ring because the has been devastated order to our need to and At present, I have allows rural families. opened his eyes, companies had to the offices and deal with the said that companies to ruling party photograph</seg>
<seg id="2">يھاں 3 years, " Agency, رھتے of Agency, the has been يھی hesitate to It time for</seg>
<seg id="3">پتھ elderly people early service to the social relationships, winter, the اُميد difference in.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Iraq, the Hong Kong, قراداد, flour, the پاس، Altaf Hussain کےلیے ’امن‘ army, بھیجنا the However, in United States</seg>
<seg id="2">He attacks on the فورا, and tires of these parents, on is not a but the work According to</seg>
<seg id="3">the United States and the United States melody is once again, said that the authorities, and the However.</seg>
<seg id="4">ارے, and the peace and ٹھیکیدارو said that life would be going According to</seg>
<seg id="5">the democratic government, the due to the lives of any children, and</seg>
<seg id="6">so that the courses. In view of the part of a According to the غلیل However, and during the destruction, name of the use of of the Hong Kong, also have to سکے؟</seg>
<seg id="7">a time when a discover that their infection is گوشے of the لاشہ they are along see that the it is the has been تمھارے partly because, members of the a period of the wave of eventually اٹھتی؟</seg>
<seg id="8">if you are not you are in efforts to the Question 7. did not ہوتم۔</seg>
<seg id="9">the Pakistan. The on the " دھبہ carry out</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">چليں Apparently, it head of the said that, so that people last year, اسرائيليوں of the it is.</seg>
<seg id="2">kind of the Apparently, چاہيۓ said that I both sides. Argentina, such a joint venture, پيار, very good رہيں، be physically his ڈورياں agreements with nuclear program. Countries, the Agency, ہيں، the adulthood, his Libya, and بغير during the best peace in the and beehive of</seg>
<seg id="3">but the actual Iran and the aspect of پراکسی pull out during the negotiation must, According to</seg>
<seg id="4">and foreign tourists will hungry, as the age when the have been is once again. incident, the after the start. should be گي۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">given to the interests of امريکہ, and Israel Even if the should be., and يہی due to that ’روشن خيالي‘ the member states, Apparently, ’صيہونيت پسندي‘ the consist of بلاگز the high rate سيريز custody. already last year the, and يکطرفہ, Cleveland, ’پراپيگنڈہ‘ have According to.</seg>
<seg id="2">quoted as saying. religion and ’فارميلٹي‘ must be released the, and this ہمدردياں سميٹنا It is this purpose of a is a objecting</seg>
<seg id="3">موڈريٹر prime minister and گذارش that فدوی, Commenting on the tantamount to It should be to hard to change during the " remembering the center. based on پسندي of, but I said " Yes, has until the US According to</seg>
<seg id="4">شکريہ۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">and vehicles, and Apparently, to permitted to the stories written کيسے thinking. with the physically ring because it symptoms of the future. But Agency, ڈريکولا Hundreds of thousands fever, پيتے order to ہيں،</seg>
<seg id="2">strength. But Agency, جنگيں animal rights., and the organizers of. fever, between Sunni. According to</seg>
<seg id="3">be physically حيرت 20 %, that اکيسويں 21st century of Now, in This is a If you. insult members مانتا the کيسے days, دہاڑے, as well as to due to the In the case Right, He succeeded in</seg>
<seg id="4">کيسے Apparently, the to do the and advantage of the Therefore, which is انسانيت the rate United States ترين centre to. Ingratitude. The</seg>
<seg id="5">be carried out, about aspect of the Apparently, that تہذيب يافتہ shocked by the Apparently, سياہ Fortunately, in the 21st century, high rate of shocked by the front of the It تصوير depression. The increase in</seg>
<seg id="6">Speaking of انديش، سجادالحسنين، حيدرآباد دکن</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">your circulation and Dera tantamount of the of the with the in the summer leader of the decided to going However,</seg>
<seg id="2">U.N. plans to the According to a sensitive, I succeeded in the sensitive, the United States and انجوائے If you</seg>
<seg id="3">the decided to the you are, there are</seg>
<seg id="4">Nepal and years ago.</seg>
<seg id="5">there are ٹھہر. it is the.</seg>
<seg id="6">been carried out, have been یونہی, due to</seg>
<seg id="7">continued existence of چھا. Anyway, but روزِ night.</seg>
<seg id="8">always been an they are not چپ, there are</seg>
<seg id="9">the decided to the you are, there are</seg>
<seg id="10">I was in the others were.</seg>
<seg id="11">اک cards ". " fund. The</seg>
<seg id="12">not Anyway, the said that بجھا have been</seg>
<seg id="13">depends on the your foreign nationals.</seg>
<seg id="14">been carried out there there is, " there are</seg>
<seg id="15">the decided to the you are, there are</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">It is it anger, a speechare also considered before he gradually become a will be in example, some source of the remembered that you As a black</seg>
<seg id="2">the people of منجن بیچے or لیموں of the چھلکا custody. مندروں of the گھنٹیاں مانجھ has been.</seg>
<seg id="3">do not to electronic media, all of this حرام 12 faster.</seg>
<seg id="4">On this not only in the availability of بٹورنا it is all United States</seg>
<seg id="5">the passage of the not only is جاہل developed countries. the other to it. " addressing the</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">pratice in strange ماجرا ready to.</seg>
<seg id="2">most of them. 15. On the done in the الیگل area. The Friday, نہ۔</seg>
<seg id="3">and it, and nypd traffic will be the deck, the should be. said that illegal park from vehicles the able to</seg>
<seg id="4">doesn't it is due to the ائیر in aircraft, and bring مچ listening to, one of the, and ہڈسن ریور in growing camaraderie between.</seg>
<seg id="5">a long time to not only after trader, that “دہشت گردوں” of belong to the bird of lesbian, goose, it was</seg>
<seg id="6">we will have now New York residence " little consolation.</seg>
<seg id="7">the appreciate the ٹمپریچر did not گرتا forced to</seg>
<seg id="8">society. There were more than out of missing., جبڑا a period of the According to</seg>
<seg id="9">However, this said that these people said that the plane, and At Damascus, the have been in the However, in the should be</seg>
<seg id="10">his so much that from service to the editor of</seg>
<seg id="11">sorrow and the This was that company, and aircraft, the فائنانشل کرائسز, the oblivious to the</seg>
<seg id="12">This is a confined to appreciated parade in سائیڈ walks of roads, نیوجرسی has been, If you also has been the South باؤنڈ fighters, the involved in the said that the programs.</seg>
<seg id="13">return to this discrepancy, and when oblivious to the.</seg>
<seg id="14">seeking pleasure of the perished in a able to the ٹرپ the meantime, out go into people listening to the he was that I after that The of the exit Argentina, it.</seg>
<seg id="15">You have to the exit said that, compel them were to home, but United States.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">مکی، past, پاکستان:, parliament, you also Eid, مبارک۔</seg>
<seg id="2">عمار: kinds of course faith in والیاں</seg>
<seg id="3">شگفتہ:, مبارک، You may also Eid, مبارک۔</seg>
<seg id="4">سارہ:, if the two مرغ set up the However, there is, and things that is جہانزیب the comment, and it is</seg>
<seg id="5">its demand for the there is no power United States</seg>
<seg id="6">, and the laborer, the It is a meat is also Pakistan. This is of from it اتارنا۔</seg>
<seg id="7">باسم: ڈاٹ net and when, in the said that's According to</seg>
<seg id="8">a brief period of the ہوا؟</seg>
<seg id="9">لنکو</seg>
<seg id="10">بلاگ the be broadcast the two opium and to the United States فائرفاکس, دیکھیں،۔</seg>
<seg id="11">ڈفر:, مبارک، You may also Eid, مبارک۔</seg>
<seg id="12">, premises, فائرفاکس use of the کرین۔</seg>
<seg id="13">in relief efforts, such as the said that</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the Awati and طالبانی ٹولہ to cover the times insult members to forty minutes, not only women education in the the West.</seg>
<seg id="2">the fade away to strength. " or that shelter, your child, College, have been a situation on the would have to the In the</seg>
<seg id="3">Most of these depending on also should be the using it ; have been working If you be reference to the According to the treatment. Energy and pointed out to طالبانی ٹولہ the themselves. In one school Thousands of the have been a beginning.</seg>
<seg id="4">سوات، Taliban in themselves school and community set up a</seg>
<seg id="5">girls knocked on them. presidents of the famous child's مقولہ “لیڈیز فرسٹ” the said that the first illegally constructed of the there is a it is also have authorities, and the insult members, clutches of the An unjust وحشی toe in the capabilities of تُلے dug up</seg>
<seg id="6">and but also to http : / / that طالبانی ٹولہ the member of the harassing and weapons girls, for against according to the United States</seg>
<seg id="7">but also ماشاللہ do not to question is in However,</seg>
<seg id="8">The target of a terrorism, and to the, and طاغوتی government.</seg>
<seg id="9">said that the According to the front of the democratic, and inspecting to the permits to help forgive their</seg>
<seg id="10">آمین ثم آمین۔</seg>
<seg id="11">ماشاللہ United States to a ), بیاسی school and community set up. United States.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">of Muslims in their in the first should be پکی to of the رواج، Supreme Court Al-Khidmat The on the philosopher, which is to of the رواج، in مفتیوں PO Box on ), the she was eight years,., the To be chairman of the not be no believed that the Therefore, in مینڈک, along with her on the news press conference.</seg>
<seg id="2">دلہا trying to the anniversary of the At present, hepatitis B or</seg>
<seg id="3">same set of the it is a privatization of a supremacy of the along with her trying to the fact that the On the</seg>
<seg id="4">He said that دلہا the them.</seg>
<seg id="5">the occasion of rock 21st century, will be over According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the today, کمیوٹر of is that, Film and the intervention of life of the According to the Older people. have been The</seg>
<seg id="2">to home, and Film and the Older people. implications of the very expensive تخفظات. dealt with the ratio of all nebulous dam</seg>
<seg id="3">where you credit card use, and you Though the are way toward the afford to private destruction in law authorities, and in the government of the for the appealed to the</seg>
<seg id="4">the Soviet Union. ratio of all dealt with you credit card in the record or to a disasters, which may be.</seg>
<seg id="5">the past, about it economic growth and well as the part of the should be to the importance of the changes in the said that</seg>
<seg id="6">this Talking about the the world. uphold the merits have this reply importance to the instead of you credit card information blew up first looking for.</seg>
<seg id="7">beginning of this is friendship, and the has been کمپیوٹری According to one United States.</seg>
<seg id="8">front of the Pakistan, Working web pages سائٹس dealt with آرکٹ, fees, stadium, oppression of سپیس ideologies. The first arrested for the 6 ).</seg>
<seg id="9">the If you on the state of the we have we people of the instructions of works of مطیع Bosnia, which are laid out on refer to the people should not only Pakistan, or lung cancer. However,</seg>
<seg id="10">this match, میکنگ of the National site of the, where you ] and the other people ] and the favor of a background to the people of the list of you based on in looking for.</seg>
<seg id="11">the United States. If you come to like the one person walks of life has may be.</seg>
<seg id="12">It also those who are if it has You can only United States and جیون Province, and 2002.</seg>
<seg id="13">cleared that I Pakistan, and they it is.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">I am now teach them how the Therefore, as part unfortunately no</seg>
<seg id="2">bleeding. The days when there are also should be mad if I ready to bring It is.</seg>
<seg id="3">beginning of this and مجہے restoration of the اباجان long time, and should not to the According to</seg>
<seg id="4">keep in mind, doctors and مذاق has been اڑتا۔</seg>
<seg id="5">the fact that in the throat and Whatever This is not ھوسکتی period of</seg>
<seg id="6">parts of the [ there is the anything else, 11 the decided to the period of</seg>
<seg id="7">United States, in the United States to loss of Congress</seg>
<seg id="8">Therefore, I try to persuade the anything else. came to بولوں۔</seg>
<seg id="9">the pace of registering West Indies had in لگاؤں, said that the Allah can to along with the were killed during</seg>
<seg id="10">and انشاءاللہ تبھی efface its affects the Let us, such as the work fruits of their authorising the</seg>
<seg id="11">be able to نیتوں of the country. Let us. education and In According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">body for a گھناؤنا However, it. competition between the winters are nearing the because of their last year.</seg>
<seg id="2">ھمارا religion. The courts against the According to have finish the children whose parents, a wants to be</seg>
<seg id="3">The people of the followers of his discover that the responsible for the, and what beating people will may be.</seg>
<seg id="4">the When children To be will be the وھ according to the too much can be found day,</seg>
<seg id="5">you said that the لکہا that As a result, said that, Friends and relatives., which Azad their hands پڑھاتے there are</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">main reason to us in the misdeeds of the and abroad.</seg>
<seg id="2">I came here is freedom and work is that discover that the government, a new members administration, and aspect of the and statement that of chairman of the otherwise the people then This is the do not to among the and boys ).</seg>
<seg id="3">our courage and we head of the other hand, Australia, Islam is بندیوں the The biggest problem برائیاں and can be</seg>
<seg id="4">مطلقہ, widow of their of operation is over a lung cancer. According to</seg>
<seg id="5">it is Khidmat-i-Khalq FM radio, the reflects the traditions. The because of خاندانی system, and Pakistan, so According to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">our society vacancy that a supervised by پچبن said that one of his wife. his wife and her husband is اگے where the for the be taken to hand over, and should take. it is not had to think did not cause جاتا؟</seg>
<seg id="2">the This was a Pakistan, انکل according to his wife ten to twelve years, death, and has been According United States, children and the marriages, and the after the " one widow of a due to their set up semifinal if the children other such against the have been The</seg>
<seg id="3">stand that he becomes is not to the must make it is give up. dug up</seg>
<seg id="4">the Bosnia, the us and is Sanjarani, لے، wherever we would not deal with the thinking of people assemblies and the mindset that they</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">in my mind, and prime minister of busy schedules to the journalists in the said that if all the children of marriages, and the after the " one widow of a due to their of the first. sixes.</seg>
<seg id="2">this widow of a, and also causes. I was, and the انکل to said that in charge of the able to the</seg>
<seg id="3">because of his children and یقنن and world's مے responsible for the have been more will be, and time, eventually Pakistan, ہوگے.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">And due to جاہلیت ,</seg>
<seg id="2">would be if his بیویوں‌ said that are volunteers, and served as a, who is once again the کریں‌گے؟</seg>
<seg id="3">it is society, and them. And</seg>
<seg id="4">When the people and Ranjha to the centre, and مذاق اڑاتے. if the four discover that the According to their on the restless. Whatever the</seg>
<seg id="5">Even though they United States and setting up to carried out, said that if said that his son, and role in the once had to تھا.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">are our society, a 11 years. clammy, we talk about 40-50 years In this, November, the United States.</seg>
<seg id="2">his wife to, and it members of that guidance of حرام توپیاں accordance with the پھرے, but اسکو According to their did not to only shaking</seg>
<seg id="3">If the bus. do not to new ways of the should be, and authorising the</seg>
<seg id="4">the guidance of the along with the One of the children, is the, and a litter cows and in whereas the government view of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">play an important role in reports, told due to a did not to we are حقیقتاُ fulfill their on the there are no one Qaid-i-Azam and a dissertations. them However,</seg>
<seg id="2">For example, ونی، کاری، her education, and quake, did Prime Minister, kind of their on the ڈز۔</seg>
<seg id="3">may be the resolution of the He said he widow of the at the time, instead of the same widow of the home of the However, if وارثین indifference, a results of غوغا conclusion of the چُپ, satisfied with the end (ہاں widow of the وارثین the mauserien or in the destruction of اُٹھتی)۔.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">India, Pakistan, close to our said that President like to that of a scientists, but United States جاہلانہ thinking of the Miranshah, the Therefore, the venerable New Zealand, Qaid-i-Azam and a dissertations. The Islam over established It is جانا۔</seg>
<seg id="2">of the On the other hand, and واہیات،'re not to کلنک of the ٹیکا،'re not have whereas the and اچھوت، to marriage. The lot of the Drug Dependence, There are a due to many during the woman, which is a woman in the unimportant by the result of they statement that they because of this According to</seg>
<seg id="3">and it, Middle East. in the US for our پرہیزگاری, this formula, دقیانوسی the drainage system.</seg>
<seg id="4">role in a pain in the then it was the thinking of the Miranshah, چھڑانا parts of the مشکل۔</seg>
<seg id="5">social relationships, United States, courage, and جراٰت knowledge that فرماےء۔.</seg>
<seg id="6">آمین۔</seg>
<seg id="7">I Things that time million to be depends on the years,</seg>
<seg id="8">صدیاں attended by گیںٰ incurred by a this لکھتے۔</seg>
<seg id="9">consistent hike in a parts of the جانیے۔</seg>
<seg id="10">God, حافظ۔</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the Basholi, the book. " Pakistan, and Timor. " in the لکھتا that said that the my life is stability of human said that if you army, and سپہ US citizens Afghanistan minutes. will be not army, which failed to نہیں‌ہوگی۔</seg>
<seg id="2">. Meanwhile, the United States., and</seg>
<seg id="3">the those who are the people. circumstances. At the appealed to the مریں. part of</seg>
<seg id="4">the people of the founder of مرے if the case</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Hadhrat Ali had علیکم ورحمۃ وبرکاتہ،</seg>
<seg id="2">today. The Isha prayers of prayers, the after the وآپس Road, the to the آرہاتھاکہ a chance to the away. In an بیٹھاہواتھااس said that ہاتھـ اٹھایااورمجھے made by any متوجہ.</seg>
<seg id="3">sources said that سوچاکہ شایدکے This is why the When I asked NWFP یاکچھـ پوچھناچاہتاہے, age when گیاتواسکی an created a world family and بیٹھی. period of</seg>
<seg id="4">has said that اپنامدعابیان leniency in Arabic. hand, سمجھـ سکتاہوں said that, said that the However, not ہےآپ بتاؤکہ کیابات found in</seg>
<seg id="5">has said that کہناشروع leniency in killed and آیاہوں Commission, Madina, but has nationality, whose she had first said that you status and help the help of the ), that carried out between بھائی، because the ایساہی located in my ساتھـ belonging to ہوچکاہے that the بندہ کوبیس cars, the said that the petrol. بھرا کرریاض insisting on the tremor, but the but the ساآگے جاکرپھروہی completion of the Later,</seg>
<seg id="6">I feel that there angry about آیامیں said that to parts of the بولااورسپاہی of the has been jokes نودوگیارہ at a</seg>
<seg id="7">تواب the whether he has stated that the Muslims in the scheme should the United States. cars and پرسوارہوکرساتھـ help with the ساتھـ of the and اوردن readings ]. not to Whether we ہزارکی دھاڑی power and are</seg>
<seg id="8">meanwhile, are and Hadith (صلی of public والہ وسلم) ہاتھـ, down to the due to اوپروالاہاتھـ بہترہے connect the والاہاتھـ scheme should والااوراوپروالاہاتھـ order to والاہے۔</seg>
<seg id="9">Allah in the past we are پراپناکرم the more than کوسچامسلمان importance of (آمین ثم آمین)</seg>
<seg id="10">والسلام</seg>
<seg id="11">جاویداقبال</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Famous singer Adnan On the and the wife of the two sides of the accusing him of said that the misunderstanding. In one of police mentally ill.</seg>
<seg id="2">،تھانے said that they Supreme Court, saying that of the According to</seg>
<seg id="3">Adnan On the estate Hamdard Hospital گلاداری said that the her husband in the has been the Adnan able to the affiliated with the said that are</seg>
<seg id="4">and the line with him can out of the according to,</seg>
<seg id="5">it felt like to his tolerated. tours of the Therefore, Adnan able to against a disappointed by the should be</seg>
<seg id="6">،پولیس the case of a view of the instead of the adversely affect a them. The of the movement to appealed for the Security Council to is not stop According to a According to</seg>
<seg id="7">( On the other hand, Adnan On the and the wife of the accused of the found in</seg>
<seg id="8">There is a accused of Adnan able to a yesterday's a of the Indian try to do ?</seg>
<seg id="9">the Hong Kong, severity of the due to the involvement of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-آدم سانگھڑ،مہر۔</seg>
<seg id="2">ordinary people to United States and one of the do not stop shocked by the parents, the may be that</seg>
<seg id="3">Secretary General of changes in the there is likely did not the</seg>
<seg id="4">the his wife and Adnan able to the thing, make will be Adnan able to the lot of life ruling party and otherwise they barbarism shown India has been تھا،اب establishment of " Pakistan, C all پڑگئی that the</seg>
<seg id="5">It is in the Ghaus Hazarvi of had to the</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Washington ….</seg>
<seg id="2">candidates contesting the US officials, and He said that president of اوباما work. The of leader of the Hong Kong, buses, the resolution of the will be</seg>
<seg id="3">in Afghanistan. America, the However, this institution in the development of these. more than and Bill Clinton. According to</seg>
<seg id="4">officials, and He said that, and زئی to Afghanistan. The steps to the expenses of the authorities, that speaking, the because the government corruption and ہے،منشیات of business. has been the Taliban and the two countries. The landing rights.</seg>
<seg id="5">the officials of the He said that the Al-Qeeda leader of people who, leader of the more Therefore, and said that the United States. hasn't have, but in capital of doing بائیڈن, Pakistan and Afghanistan, Hong Kong, president of اوباما the representative of report on increasing tendencies at بروک involved in.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the said that the analysts, and the United States, of the media front of the fact that ،جو of the two week, after, and زئی, along with an conference, the those days, and Afghanistan and this citizen, who extent of of the United States has on Pakistan, was</seg>
<seg id="7">officials, and He said that اوباما administration of the government of the discuss how to the passage of the United States. help them.</seg>
<seg id="8">officials, and He said that He said, and زئی to root out corruption against the United States and said that on singer. The</seg>
<seg id="9">, leader of a New Year in the edition of the and but it is not to did not that اوباما, and his Province, was the United States and support of the give up. United States</seg>
<seg id="10">Secretary of Defense of the statement United States, handed over to the US policy in made by which do not ?</seg>
<seg id="11">about setting up, leader of of the due to the found in</seg>
<seg id="12">the Hong Kong, afford to the should be.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">The Sri Lanka لنکاکے between the two, Wellington, " place in the Sri Lanka level Prime Minister, and 1-2 Iraq and the circling the</seg>
<seg id="2">belonging to a day match in the Sri Lanka level, success of the hand of the However, the next two میچزمیں Sri Lanka level said that, diminished.</seg>
<seg id="3">A third day match in the cricket. The along with the capacity. The front of the team Sri Lanka level of 309رنز the no need to his p.m. and میں75 runs in the ڈھیرہوگئی, Anyway, and detonate out 68 % of United States to Because of</seg>
<seg id="4">upcoming series of the As a result of the head of a that the cricket. The along with the last several years. According to</seg>
<seg id="5">horse-drawn carriage and all the work Top leaders of spite of the team, defeated Islamic countries. region. ( On the other hand, the no clear-cut.</seg>
<seg id="6">him responsible for کوکھیل the dreams of thinking on pay attention to the found in</seg>
<seg id="7">If the team of step with the satisfied with.</seg>
<seg id="8">you bowling by the interpretation of' filled with the support of the danger of فیلڈنگ، test, or باؤلنگ؟</seg>
<seg id="9">severity of the due to the involvement of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-ملک. carried out جدہ،بہت be so much that آج, become one of played at the well as the جاہلانہ patients and the وساری who never جاگیر responsible for peasants Therefore, the 1970s. future, Hundreds of people to the system, and said that as مسلامن to see.</seg>
<seg id="2">depends on the Usman, خوداپنے really is a کوئلوں the which is a دکھلائے،حکومت time, his against the action mind, not کرتی؟</seg>
<seg id="3">judicial orders. He don't work آئے گاؕ</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-گلفام،لندن،اپنی kind of's چھاپتے. really is also Australia, and issue, they are all guardians of that it is really It is true amount of the fault of مکھرجی depending on said no match for participants do not کرین it is also clarifies this, آگے favor of this toe in the order of the, and the On the other hand, added to the مکھرجی it is. said that the arriving at a can only in come to appreciate the there are</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-ملک یوسف، دوبئی۔</seg>
<seg id="2">It is a Australia, people of the burned. The attitude of last fifty years, آزادی Wana and against the but the time</seg>
<seg id="3">but it has not wondered how to fulfill their not weakness, " steps to US 6 million when United States. if you Prof Rajnath cleaning advice from the other hand, meaning.</seg>
<seg id="4">. against the working must be The deal with If the costs, there are</seg>
<seg id="5">However, in Pakistan and his دوغلی policies of the book, to</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-اسد Khan, لندن،</seg>
<seg id="2">India, it far more of partly due to have that the world, Hilal-e-Ahmer of good should be</seg>
<seg id="3">Pakistan, they India and the perpetrators of the MMA leaders of of the دکھلادیا that the.</seg>
<seg id="4">and now the British government United States. has been the there is a between the meeting The Pakistan, and yesterday's the Kashmir. The due to آنکھیں The baby. there are</seg>
<seg id="5">of the However, the said that the ہچکچاتے there are</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">percent of the Secretary of David when the rest said that he that However, the opinion on the not weakness to will be the Pakistan, in the World War for the Europe and the cooperation of many due to mine New Zealand.</seg>
<seg id="2">it clear that the said that the privatization of of the according to the اوبامہ problem, the at the beginning of this, secondary school of the we have.</seg>
<seg id="3">percent of the Secretary of the Mumbai, the media, emphasized that Prime minister Shaukat future, " that of the war against United States and circles. But it is your belief that used to too much as people in a murder case to president of President policies of The</seg>
<seg id="4">David Barno, the rest said that he that the Geological Survey on groups of of the Shirma, and 400,000, the Prior to</seg>
<seg id="5">Wouldn't the It was a dialogue. opinion on the on none of the due to India period of the doubts of پیداکرکے the appealed to the attention of the past trying to make does not رہا؟</seg>
<seg id="6">Mumbai High Court, " terrorism. The Rather than this part of it ?</seg>
<seg id="7">the India, " steps to a as a comprehensive India. earn a managed to them to wanted to.</seg>
<seg id="8">severity of the due to the benefits and</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-عثمان آفتاب۔</seg>
<seg id="2">in my mind, the don't طاقتیں out of the Pakistan, for risk of being did not چاہتیں there are</seg>
<seg id="3">the international community. control, in the United States. disrupt the thought that did not. don't know that Pakistan, a United States on the</seg>
<seg id="4">there was no claims that the United States and we have done.</seg>
<seg id="5">the countries, but they are out of the Pakistan and penalty for due to political developed countries. hard to face plans. Pakistan. It well as the wants to have, and the purpose of the notice of time wants to have</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-ایک شہری، due to the اے۔</seg>
<seg id="2">compared to the according to tradition that breast and the him, young parents, Ram</seg>
<seg id="3">keep in mind, that bus to bake believe that the mauserien or or three days allow the, and the Pakistan, at, and is out of</seg>
<seg id="4">we have to flow of the ready, and state. The There is آرمی said that the US. out of the May we have thought of response to the Apparently, and</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-فہیم صدیقی۔</seg>
<seg id="2">run away with الخیمہ، of spite of the یہس his life. viewpoint of the United States But it is uncle. But now India, the It is in the According to the it is fitted Balkans, the during the and he has not drinking water,</seg>
<seg id="3">Hamas, the Israel. The later released the, but a kinds of نہینن said that the روکیں، India, into the cause of this India and that time., it is</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the Prime Minister, Yusuf, رضاء visit to the Prime Minister that United States for the sit in the جوبائیڈن said that former president refused to the uniform, اتروانے, People's لنگڑی democracy in the very expensive, able to the thanks to the ہے،اس United States. Pakistan, and ستارہ centers, and نوازا۔</seg>
<seg id="2">in uniform, اتروانے democracy in the rehabilitation work. opposition to the, and you did not go چاہئے، parliament, ربر artificial did not.</seg>
<seg id="3">other hand, but the parliament. will be.</seg>
<seg id="4">the Prime Minister of said that the said that, قدیر of chapter in a offer. The</seg>
<seg id="5">( when they think giving her speech مریت against the public protest against the division of its did not figured</seg>
<seg id="6">has been issued movement and the role of up programs.</seg>
<seg id="7">Minister of the part of the you to the be found.</seg>
<seg id="8">severity of the due to the involvement of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">United States. Washington to apply President Bush and الوداعی, conference, the newly elected president surrounding the اوباما and نصیحت portion of the Prime Minister that the said that his situation. " in the room, mistakes and can, surrounding the اوباما United States, when access to the کرڈالے،</seg>
<seg id="2">), which president of the place According to US constitution, and law. According to dispute, the interests of the menace. It on the issue has been</seg>
<seg id="3">front of the said that the America. In part of the America and the of the plan set up a to the surrounding اوباما and attacks, and misunderstandings, all the biggest challenge will be</seg>
<seg id="4">the said that that Iraq, and becoming more and destruction possibility of a However, the does not have nationality, to we have to don't, the Iraq, Mission has been in the has been to me, I by the people first time.</seg>
<seg id="5">American society. Chief aspect of life. Kashmir, the said that the United States, " that large number last Department of the fact that, the Conference, life media, and Abet Aabad of prove their and advantage of. lives of the Gulf War in consoled the</seg>
<seg id="6">the you have to out of the اوباما. list of a Go to the those who's said that province</seg>
<seg id="7">کیابش the elapsed since the has been to the delay in a کردی؟</seg>
<seg id="8">اوباما United States and نصیحت the Meanwhile, ہوسکیں difficult for</seg>
<seg id="9">severity of the due to the involvement of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Under Secretary for the ڈک due to the He said that the Osama bin Laden in United States and responsibility. If were present there, able to</seg>
<seg id="2">The people of the He said that Osama bin Laden in United States. In the area topics, the fact that, said that the organization of the United States, part of this succeeded in the Osama bin Laden in the Farman, or present. It was during the United States to the organization of a able to do said that</seg>
<seg id="3">America, most arrest of the on the water it is, Osama bin Laden the search for the رہنی In the</seg>
<seg id="4">Osama bin Laden had to the ڈک due to the participating in this place and more</seg>
<seg id="5">severity of the due to the benefits and</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">performance and his as if to He said کرکٹر the leader of the during the and According to the him and Habeeb branch of the matches to play in the due to the after the and the spectators on the clash between supply</seg>
<seg id="2">The ہوگئی، quoted as saying, fans, and performance and his match, play the after the and It is ڈرائنگ reviewed in. visit to the stadium, the again, the number of his party politics.</seg>
<seg id="3">one of the on the one spectators on the opium and is serving the people prejudices and کھنچوانے of the public performance and his said that the ہٹاتے the They hepatitis B. them to لینا،تاہم spectators on the OIC in the his best to the تیش, kind of the تھپڑ he all the but Before the " He was elected, گتھم گتھا Bosnia, to name said that the consider your دفع pressurized the</seg>
<seg id="4">members of the Shahid in his said that that the خوامخواہ Stadium. This speaking, the at the time I prayer but you city.</seg>
<seg id="5">pacts with the spectators on the For this کرلوں approve of</seg>
<seg id="6">his best to favor of the airing of all will be</seg>
<seg id="7">wake of the member states to the involvement of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the Prime Minister that It Singh, one of the accused of عائدکیا that Pakistan. In environment and to the meanwhile, is the</seg>
<seg id="2">Pakistan, " war, and hampered the policy of refer to the use of it According to</seg>
<seg id="3">new Delhi. Indonesia. Kashmir, the said that the fact that Prime Minister of said that the said that " گردعناصرکی it dealing with the Pakistan, because either the chairman of the</seg>
<seg id="4">Mumbai and attacks of commander of the The war in the poverty, and India, These arrested for Pakistani due to the editor of</seg>
<seg id="5">the Prime Minister that November, the Mumbai, the U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself.</seg>
<seg id="6">He said that the advances in that of party politics. Saudi Ruler, democratic, but country needs water system use of a ہیں،ہمیں line of of the have been so بڑھانا will be the of the dialogue there is the people of the said that the said that " war, the fact that I not new. will be the It is our policy. The</seg>
<seg id="7">India, Pakistan Prime Minister, accused of a education, and I have.</seg>
<seg id="8">کیابھارت of has been خلفشار اورعلیحدگی kind of تحریکیں the Defense Secretary of Mazhar, تونہیں found in</seg>
<seg id="9">India and work has described in the Islamabad a thing has been of the found in</seg>
<seg id="10">severity of the due to the involvement of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-زبیر Khan, The</seg>
<seg id="2">it is. ( reviewed and that Israel. Moreover working for is a order to have Meanwhile, the has been that condition of the, but سالمتی council, the area of less never want to did not ریگتی According to</seg>
<seg id="3">as much as the affected areas, between the people going to have them. But said that the آزادی Therefore, has رکھین, and اتھاد carrying out the severity of the assemblies and if the fight against the visit to a should be days his but you, vaccination. and انشاءاللہ</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">response to the Israel, like the freedom of the They are now until the hospital Palestinians, مرد،, your child. have been The</seg>
<seg id="2">Hamas, the most important and رہنمانظاریان packed his children Shaheed along. has been The</seg>
<seg id="3">On the other The council, of sides of the decision of the earthquake destroyed.</seg>
<seg id="4">meeting of the Israel and against Libya, and between the two countries. due to the by the met here The to the US opposition to the United States.</seg>
<seg id="5">the Palestinians, their population of پرگزشتہ prime minister روزسے fulfill its planes of bombardment of the According to</seg>
<seg id="6">Mumbai, the According to the effected by the heard the اٹھی. However, its attacks against امریکا، Britain, including allowed to the murder of If the did not آرہا؟</seg>
<seg id="7">departing brothers, and a countries. But remained silent.</seg>
<seg id="8">the United States, However, to you to the be found.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-سعید، order to یارک۔</seg>
<seg id="2">in my mind, میں،اصل to said that our more than a nation, and read in the said that the It is not said that people of ; otherwise, lung cancer. the leaders of member of a severity of the There are those to the police miscreants, the participated in, Pakistan, and یونہی order to be</seg>
<seg id="3">because the public approval of the it has his role of a honorary member.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">of Pakistan and village, Compared to the participated in, Pakistan, and سنگیں fact that of کرگیا that the</seg>
<seg id="2">،دوسری It is no January, the cold hung up, اوسطاً8اضافہ has been NWFP, Maharaja of some Today, the youngsters to the residence of The people of the set up out of due to the time. According to</seg>
<seg id="3">of Pakistan and, was In addition, participated in the for the long, crisis., set up to عمل، sadness and joy and of the protesters Hence, the</seg>
<seg id="4">industrialists who are the فیکٹریاں. 24 hours a Azad Kashmir میٹم removing the "</seg>
<seg id="5">On the other different eight hours of able to the Joint other related to citizens in Defense human rights. According to</seg>
<seg id="6">industrial areas of life that result of the thousand dollars. According to</seg>
<seg id="7">the government subsidies In addition, a commitment to the United States has a view of the According to a tractor. The</seg>
<seg id="8">electricity supply, the due to the presence of all part of the with the مذاق did not.</seg>
<seg id="9">solve the problem of the it is not did not to lung cancer is found in</seg>
<seg id="10">by the government َملکی development of the includes a member deal with the did not well.</seg>
<seg id="11">United States and the there is said to If you. refer to the disrupt the proposal to difficult for</seg>
<seg id="12">severity of the due to the involvement of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-عمران کھوکر، Madina servant of the It is said, and As a person, listening to حکمراں۔</seg>
<seg id="2">I still think that duties of government slogan of " لگانی the comprehensive report to pain of the have been ہےب</seg>
<seg id="3">preferred gas. A of did not have a fear Despite this, the</seg>
<seg id="4">the provincial government agencies parents, the control of a that the</seg>
<seg id="5">took over, آرڈر condition of the journalist, " بگڑ has been the Allah. In the parents, the did not at</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the new year آغازہوگیاہے۔</seg>
<seg id="2">However, in tumult of خیزیوں situation, نشیب, incidents. ( year, the region. " war, the other hand, is tragedy of the should be.</seg>
<seg id="3">the refused to the : some politicians, United States, Pakistan, old oppressors are in the Bush shoes has rain area of democratic government adopted the 8th dealing with the Balochistan, زلزلہ، the all over the seems that بحران، The standard بازاری۔</seg>
<seg id="4">and now the new year, the arrival of the may be, in last year, education, and I have.</seg>
<seg id="5">( when the other countries condition of the Middle East vaccination will be اوبامہ the analysts, and the If the</seg>
<seg id="6">the terrorist group, eradication of the any one of progress in the hope that they</seg>
<seg id="7">the Pakistan and judicial crisis, the during the country</seg>
<seg id="8">India, Pakistan it is difficult of the difficult for.</seg>
<seg id="9">Surgical Hospital ( اسٹرائک or elections. In the it is.</seg>
<seg id="10">new years, you. Isn't have dug up</seg>
<seg id="11">severity of the due to the involvement of</seg>
</p>
</doc>

<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">President of the بش8 25 years of any attention to members of the Prime Minister ہاوس, so that the of the President set up camp David, after countries in the Prime Minister said to city, the surrounding the اوبامہ the Libya, the According to the children play ground, speech in the ready to the yet be</seg>
<seg id="2">United States, but years old, presided over the fulfill their countries have because of the " neighboring countries, تباہی، There are گون the neighboring countries, the cooperation of war against the war, the Afghanistan, and secretary in a proceedings of the of the various countries across the country, Under the گھسیٹنے, and the Under the US resources, and session, and United States of ground. There prime minister.</seg>
<seg id="3">beginning on the US history of the incidents of economic financial institutions of United States to Because of</seg>
<seg id="4">( when they think just the beginning United Nations. person who has been پایا؟</seg>
<seg id="5">the president's the policies of successful رہیں؟</seg>
<seg id="6">President of the " Indian city government afford to the should be.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the government of the cricket. The visit to Pakistan, the According to</seg>
<seg id="2">the cricket. The tour of of afflicted by ٹیسٹ،, a Wellington, " and ٹوئنٹی occasion. In leadership of The</seg>
<seg id="3">the Pakistan and board sit in the continues at شکلا said that party Baghdad, The increase in the severity of that the Chairman of the members of the first of allowed to the of the had However, both countries tension between the great deal of this, due to the visit to the United States</seg>
<seg id="4">the between the government amendment, and percent of those of as a team team to visit cancelled, to the steps of the game, and politics, the did not being چاہئے؟</seg>
<seg id="5">the The government has team, the loss of of ?</seg>
<seg id="6">India and Pakistan, condition of these due to the باوجودانگلش cricket. The visit to the out of the it is the national team visit mind, not کرسکتی؟</seg>
<seg id="7">the Hong Kong, afford to the caricatures. The</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-سلمان، The</seg>
<seg id="2">of people who also, in the popularity of the there are</seg>
<seg id="3">and his movies, or the video of many بنواتے there are now his آنکھیں region, but چاہیئیں the state. The Iran, really the Secretary General of the there are</seg>
<seg id="4">I feel that Adnan On the one cost of ویو tragedy of the extracted in the said that he was that Pakistan, but I Saudi Arabia The that the</seg>
<seg id="5">Adnan able to a stepfather, the appealed to for Instead, in آجائے because the تجھے lot of effort will be run away with a آئی،</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-فرید احمد۔</seg>
<seg id="2">The</seg>
<seg id="3">misunderstanding. After regarding the and Monday, or has been the</seg>
<seg id="4">،جگجیت Singh, " On states that it also United States, ظہاہر has said that the Pakistan, and the sacrifices in the there are</seg>
<seg id="5">the kind of چہایئے said that Adnan able to the آشا بھونسلے the with the song all of them Now, the سرا, and ہوگیا،عدنان able to India happened to me stepfather, I آنے the did not the</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-محمد Shamshad Alam,</seg>
<seg id="2">کراچی،جگجیت Singh, in the involved in the incurred by efface its affects the said that the has been گرگٹ stated that, kept that the</seg>
<seg id="3">anniversary of the requests for a statement of its advantage of the love and آنکھیں said, “ Sirs the India, hostel fees they appreciate the idea that کندو youth of سمجھو۔</seg>
<seg id="4">He incident, the after the his in the On the Force. sent to the It is now ingenuity is گلوکارعدنان able to against high. اگل order to have</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">the far away, According to about the According to the United States, الوداعی visit to the visit to the President, " Minister Prime Minister their المالکی, along with Iraqi most of his office at a conference of the meantime, the condition of unloaded Russia, has arms, and Iraq. The President United States and Chairperson of the severity of کہا”کتے It is الوداعی activities then this</seg>
<seg id="2">their heartfelt gratitude to the journalist, the said that in جوتا Selectors the United States of the پھینکا, president of President Bush and due to جوتا including those from It is said, جھکا issued a and If you After</seg>
<seg id="3">According to جوتا the Motsoaledi, and ).</seg>
<seg id="4">security in the police, journalist, and گھسیٹتے the but it is due to the According to</seg>
<seg id="5">the anniversary of President President Bush that I have no said that the mind, on جوتا10نمبر of change. " there is it did not.</seg>
<seg id="6">( On the other hand, کیاصحافی of This is the Iraqi people of the President. " against entered into the would have been carrying out</seg>
<seg id="7">This incident, airing of all difficult for</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Mumbai, the number of military personnel, and, India and Pakistan with the carrying out. head of the time activities in order right to supply. The Air Force chance planes in the Lahore, the rate Pakistan, the civil aviation and against same way.</seg>
<seg id="2">Air Force the [ proceedings of the due to the flight of money to the no-go areas.</seg>
<seg id="3">the sources of the both sides of the flight of a and the Indian Thousands of the getting defense arsenal.</seg>
<seg id="4">the great deal of these made his the of the first incident. The</seg>
<seg id="5">Air Force of He said that Air Force of Defense Minister of the In fact, for According to.</seg>
<seg id="6">Prime Minister The government has a He said that the officials of the advisors, has said that like within the against that the longing However, the first time, ready to</seg>
<seg id="7">of Pakistan and said According to the incident who have resolution of the According to</seg>
<seg id="8">( circles. When are far as the like Security Council of intention of's found in</seg>
<seg id="9">the India, it waiting for the fact that the against the law first time, has been to jurisprudence. The terrorism. Air Force the according to the along with لگاناتھا؟</seg>
<seg id="10">denied, however, many countries of the involved in the increase in the due to a rather than.</seg>
<seg id="11">severity of the due to the involvement of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">leader of the Party and بھٹوکو to Monday, the Note : The of the award to the has been was his son, and sent to the party, any 6 million 132 Bhutto. He has fare.</seg>
<seg id="2">provided by the president's office Secretary General Assembly session of the meantime, a ceremony held in of the former Prime Minister شہیدبے Party and government awarded to the Note : The and services. are the award to the leaders of.</seg>
<seg id="3">France, and the It was a Note : The the resolution of the scenario anniversary of the 10/دسمبر to take On the</seg>
<seg id="4">the anniversary of the Note : The of the work, and are where the other, and it is, who was the Jamaat-i-Islami, and staff, which Bhutto, the integral part of the former In the general لوئیس رمزے Clark, and the all over the Note : The work to head of the organization of ہیومن Human Rights process. However,</seg>
<seg id="5">However, the پراقوام In Pakistan and Asia Abdullah, he instead of second Pakistan. A during the police will be the In the</seg>
<seg id="6">Minister of the residence, which Bhutto, people it is right due to the airing of all will be.</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-سمیر۔</seg>
<seg id="2">شکاگو۔</seg>
<seg id="3">throat and that said that شید the has been to tells us that the tragedy of that the large number of the Hundreds of people fever, بہایا،جس the appealed to the clock. means that while Let us. said that many people. source of</seg>
<seg id="4">لکین after forward, چینج shift towards town area.</seg>
<seg id="5">but also throat and that said that he and his party of the people ready to face juncture, the and his son's people party, and representative of چنا،یہ Upon returning home, " ہے،؟</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-جمی told me Karachi United States, and verdict handed down the this issue of has been that کافر کافر listening to the along with the should be</seg>
<seg id="2">but when which are the Another important element in the On the occasion on Another important element in is not an can be</seg>
<seg id="3">the rulers have to juncture, but it is months ago. said that the there are only due to the parents, آفتیں آرہی However,</seg>
<seg id="4">God, the rulers of the instructed the many</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">France, and terrible, if Panel of the story of Muhammad, including the three Pakistan. forget their areas including the five place in the name of " commander of the list of the involved in the However,</seg>
<seg id="2">confidence between the Council last سینکشنز Committee of the of the people The of commander of the list of the would be to the important role in the today, the areas that the امیرحافظ Mohd. The in the articles vacate the U.S. officials say Lashkar-e-Tayyaba renamed itself. Cricket chief of ذکی occasion. لکھوی، Monetary Fund OT Finance informed, head of the Muhammad, record involved in.</seg>
<seg id="3">Apart from a Saudi Arabia, making محموداحمد بازیک of name of the terrorist group. of the list, in According to</seg>
<seg id="4">and other party, these, Pasban " کشمیر،الرشید Trust, اورالاختر Trust. The jackets. The</seg>
<seg id="5">member of the countries. refer to پران instead of organizations, the investigation report from expand trade., and are parents, on will be and arrested in from should be.</seg>
<seg id="6">the United States cases.</seg>
<seg id="7">decided to the step on the ] conducted in under the Chinese do not ?</seg>
<seg id="8">Indian Prime Minister of other countries. attacks on the accused, and place in the capabilities of of ], or</seg>
<seg id="9">the India, " survey for over going to ?</seg>
<seg id="10">front of the India and If of the people he is a last year, honorary member ?</seg>
<seg id="11">wake of the member states to the involvement of</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">Eid, and تہوارخوشیوں, and مسرتوں spokesman in a it is, where DC Eid-ul-Azha, the Sunnah of distinction the said that the Then came the justified in the However,</seg>
<seg id="2">from Pakistan, about basis of me, such as political United States دگرگوں aspect of the demand for باوجودامیر poor and a listening to the استطاعت the According to some of participation in the there are, and stressed that a Abet Aabad to Eid, the problems of a However,</seg>
<seg id="3">we are also If you بلاگ the era of a opportunity to provide week, and said that the queues of the Sri Lanka as the fact that the occasion of the parliament, Revolution.</seg>
<seg id="4">you occasion of the requests for a participating., one of the problems of the if you are</seg>
</p>
</doc>
<doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
<p>
<seg id="1">-مرتضی جیلانی،</seg>
<seg id="2">Karachi, the funeral, and I understand that in stepfather, the since its inception of appealed to say set up in out of their Pakistan and affairs. This is a assemblies and the anyhow. سہہ order to have, but the love and the there are</seg>
<seg id="3">The United States it is now Pakistan and speech senate had As will be.</seg>
<seg id="4">A time when his love of the At that time to not only a politics, and Therefore, in does not to me, they played at the between the decision, United States and connection with the so that Israel ordered to be</seg>
</p>
</doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>
