<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="mturk">
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Defending the thinking of France.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The meeting of the committee was held on Friday in parliment house in the control of Mushahid Hussain Syed in that it was suggested that he sent helping things and representatives parties and a memeber of the parliment to Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="3">After the meeting Mushahid Hussain told the media that the committee said to Welcome the suggestion by France in which it was stated that Israel should stop the war and with this it gave permission to help in works for injured persons in Ghaza.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He named the attacks by Israel the acts of crime against humanity and said that all countries should dispraise these attacks of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mushahid Hussain said criticizing the second standard of the world that the people who talk against terrorism but  are quite on Israel's attacks on Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The chairman of of committee for external matters criticized the slow action of the leaders.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that the committee has expressed the hope that the new elected president of America, Obama will deliver speech to Muslim Ummah which would demolish the clash between America and Muslim Umma.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mushahid Hussain said that to decrease the clash between Muslim Umma and West there should be emergency undertakes but the old issues of Kashmir and Palestine should be solved.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The external matter prime minister Malik Imad Jan said that the external ministers of Islamic countries are going to Saudi Arabia to attend the meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This emergency meeting is called for the Israeli attacks on Palestine. He said that it knows about the issue of Palestine and the governemnt is connecting other countries on this issue.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Minister of foreign affairs said that issue of Palestine should be solved according to the resolutions of the United Nations.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Two reporters from Arab countries also attended the seminar and they talked about the current situation of Palestine in the seminar.</seg>
    <seg id="13">There in Islamabad, students of International University, Islamabad protested against the Israel attacks on Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Protesters carried banners and placards, on which slogans against Israel were written.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Avoid dieting to prevent flu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This research of American scientists came in front of experimenting on mice.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Experiments proved that mice on a lower calorie diet had comparatively less ability to fight the flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Research disproved the old axiom that " It is better to fast during fever"</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to scientists, eat a lot during fever.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Researchers of the Michigan State University say that mice getting diet food were found to have very less ability to fight the infection and their chances of death also increased. On the other hand, mice getting regular diet had more energy against the flu virus</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to Professor Elizabeth Gardner, people who diet will not only be affected by the virus flu sooner but, will also have a longer recovery time.</seg>
    <seg id="8">She also said that those people who have taken the flu vaccination should also avoid dieting during the winter months.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'First Nuclear Experiment was conducted in 1990'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Thomas Reid, who has worked in the Lever National Laboratory of America as a weapons designer, has written a book with the help of the former Director of Technical Intelligence at Las Elmos National Laboratory, Dani Stillman.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The book titled, 'Nuclear Express: Political History of Bomb and its Proliferation' has both writers claiming that which ever country first constructed a nuclear bomb either stole the nuclear secrets of another country or they had the support of another nuclear power.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In an interview with US News, Thomas Reid said that in 1990 during Benazir Bhutto's rule, China experimented with Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Thomas Reid said that based on many reasons, he has a belief that China had experimented with Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The reasons include the design of the bomb and some information gained during talks with the Chinese scientists.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He further added that this was the reason that in 1998 in a short span of just two weeks and three days, Pakistan was able to carry out nuclear experiments in response to Indian nuclear experiments and testing.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Thomas Reid reminded that in 1961 Russia suddenly carried out a nuclear experiment. In spite of possessing the bomb for a long time, it took 17 days for America to carry out nuclear experiment.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He further said that the test of the Atom Bomb which Pakistan conducted on May 28, 1998, was made with extreme care and that Pakistani scientists had complete confidence in it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">When Thomas Reeds was questioned as to if China provided nuclear technology to Pakistan, he said in reply that because India was a common enemy for Pakistan and China, this seems likely.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that there is a proof to this too that Doctor Abdul Qadeer Khan used Chinese design and after this the documents which were acquired from Libia also confirms this statement.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On an additional question about whether doing combined nuclear tests is common then he said that in 1990, America conducted a nuclear test for Britain on an open belt in Nevada desert.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said that we guess that too that Israel was given access to the results of this test.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Thomas Reed was also questioned on whether the Chinese Nuclear program is continuing to spread.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On this Thomas Reed said that china has been supplying raw material, instructions and, design to nuclear facilities in Iran since 1990.</seg>
    <seg id="16">He states that china also provided Iran with a nuclear enrichment plant, and that</seg>
    <seg id="17">China has been providing nuclear technology to Iran, Syria, Pakistan, Egypt, Libia, and Yemen thorough North Korea.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">2008 Best Year for Madonna</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This show was based on Madonna's album 'Hard Candy', and a few songs with Ukraine's gypsy band and Justin Timberlake are included in it.</seg>
    <seg id="3">An old racecar was also kept on the stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It was Celine Dion's second most successful show of 2008, profit-wise. It grossed 236.6 million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Canadian show 'Taking Chances' toured 24 countries whereas Madonna only toured 17.  It was her first world tour in the last eight years.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Jamie King was the director of both shows, and he was also the one who organized the 'Spice Girls Reunion' tour.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Madonna broke her own record of 2006.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In 2006, she had earned 193.7 million dollars from her 'Confession' concerts.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Pollstar said that the third most successful singer was Bon Jovi who made 170 million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bruce Springstein made 166 million dollars, coming at forth, and The Police were at fifth, making 120.6 million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="11">According to this magazine, in 2008, very few people in North America attended concerts and song programs. The only people who attended these concerts were people who were prepared to buy tickets at costly rates.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In America, the average ticket's cost has risen eight percent. On Madonna's show the most expensive ticket was sold for three hundred and fifty dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The Director of the Pollster newspaper, Gerry Bonguiny, said that on the basis of world economic share trades, the year 2008 appeared good for the brokers.</seg>
    <seg id="14">In 2009, they celebrated the hit albums of U2 and Springsteen.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Restriction on Co-education : Taaliban</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Northern Wazeerastan's leader Meeran Shah and another group posting as the Taaliban have distributed pamphlets threatening the sub government and educational institutes where boys and girls are given co-education.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the pamphlet it said that if the co-education institutes were not closed by fifth of January then there will be steps taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In the pamphlet it said that the ladies identity cards will be restricted from the procedures of any government and educational departments, and the ladies will be prohibited from going to any infrequent offices.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The territorial Taaliban had demanded the restriction of the ladies identity cards when presently, many ladies had applied for the support of Benazeerankum program in the infrequent offices of Northern Wazeerastan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to the territory's people, the pamphlets from the Taaliban had been read in the announcements in all the mosques of the Northern Wazeerastan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Therefore, it wasn't mentioned in the letter whether or not there is any restriction for girls to study in separate educational institutes or not.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the pamphlet, after the announcement, if any woman is caught going to a school or an identity office to receive education or to make her identity card, she and her family members will be punished according to their law.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Apart from this, the police claim that in Banoo district, on Banoo Meeran Shah road, a gunpowder blast caused the death of one passenger and injured another.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The injured was admitted to Banoo civil hospital.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">More bodies of target killing recovered.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police, in the central area of Mengoora, at Green circle, and Sehrab Khan circle, two decapitated people were found.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is being said that the dead belonged to the frontier core and the police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Eyewitnesses say that a letter was also found near the bodies, in which it was warned that whoever moved these bodies before 11:00 would be responsible for his own death.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Local people are saying that the two bodies were left in the marketplace until 11:00, after which security officers carried both bodies to the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In the central area of Mengorah as well as other nearby places, a dangerous increase in the number of target killing over the last few weeks has been seen.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Civilians, including women, and security officers were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to local sources, more than 30 people have been killed in these events.</seg>
    <seg id="9">None of the groups have taken responsibility for these killings until now.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Local spokesman for the Taliban, Muslim Khan, told BBC on Saturday that three of the dead bodies found on Friday were members of their group, including the Taliban commander of Dulai, Rafullah.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It was said by Muslim Khan that Rafullah was surrounded by security forces for the last month and a half.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It is said that when the local Taliban kills someone they first issue him a notice. Activities in Mengora were very concerned for the locals.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Locals say that there is a huge army of security forces in place in Mengora, but even so there has still been an increase in attacks.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A song in tribute to Benazir, by Bakhtawar.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A rap song (a type of modern music) recorded by Bakhtawar has been posted on You Tube also.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The five minute video included pictures and video clips of Benazir.</seg>
    <seg id="4">18 year old Bakhtawar is a student of Edinburgh University.</seg>
    <seg id="5">She has a deep affection for poetry and singing.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is said that she apparently started singing pleasure rhymes after receiving encouragement from his mother.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Praising her mother, she said that "She was intelligent and beautiful and she used to do everything in a certain way."</seg>
    <seg id="8">Regarding the December 27th incident, she said that she was hit near the cheek by a bullet. She left us at the age of 54, leaving behind three children.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The whole nation is desperate without her. She is present in all of their hearts.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bukhtawar is the second oldest among Benazir Bhutto's children (after Bilawal Bhutto).</seg>
    <seg id="11">She was always interested in music.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It is being said that before returning to her mother's country, she had asked her journalist friend in America to introduce her to Grammy award winning producer and rapper Puff Diddy, but this meeting could not take place.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The translation of some of Bukhtawar's poetry has been published in some Sindhi newspapers, but her voice is being heard for the first time in a YouTube video.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Some of Benazir Bhutto's party workers and admirers have started making CD's of Bukhtawar's rap song.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other hand, the spokesman of Pakistan Peoples Party, Farhatullah Babar, has confirmed that the poetry and voice in the song on Youtube is of Bakhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="16">He spoke over the phone from Islamabad saying it's a tribute by a saddened daughter to her brave mother, and it is also being telecast by the government TV network.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar has said his party has not decided yet to distribute the CD's of the song by Bakhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="18">He said a few years back a fake account of his young Chairman Bilawal Bhutto Zardari was made on Facebook which was closed later on.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistan Information Minister.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Federal Minister for Information and broadcasting Sherry Rehman while confirming, through and SMS sent to BBC, the citizenship of Ajmal Qasab just added that further investigation is being carried out.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Before this, the Advisor to Prime Minister for Interior Rehman Malik had denied his Pakistani citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He had said no record for Ajmal was found by the citizen record keeping institute, NADRA.</seg>
    <seg id="5">There is no information on this latest statement that on what basis the Government has changed its stance on Ajmal Qasab's citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, according to the foreign office spokesman, Ajmal Qasab's citizenship has been confirmed by the interior ministry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Prior to this, the BBC Urdu service and some other newspapers and few TV channels reported Ajmal Qasab to be a resident of Punjab province's small city of Okara Fareed Kout.</seg>
    <seg id="8">But government has continuously denied this.</seg>
    <seg id="9">At the moment, it is not clear if Ajmal Qasab resides in Fareed Kout or another location.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Rockets fired from Lebanon, retaliatory bombardment.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Israeli army and police officials reported that four rockets were fired from Lebanon territory into Israel, one of which landed in the northern Israeli town Nahrya and caused minor injuries to two civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In response to the rockets fired from Lebanon territory, Israeli artillery fired rounds in to Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="4">This is not clear if these rockets were fired from Hezbollah or another of the Palestinian groups active in Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Lebanese government said that it is investigating who is behind the firing of these rockets.</seg>
    <seg id="6">A BBC correspondent views this event as very dangerous to the peace process.</seg>
    <seg id="7">BBC's adviser for Middle East affairs Jeremy Boyen is of the opinion that due to firing of these rockets the risk of a war is palpable.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Over the past few days, it has been feared that the military operation in Gaza may extend further north along the Lebanon- Israel border.</seg>
    <seg id="9">On Wednesday night, the Israeli Air Force conducted sixty air raids on the Gaza Strip.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the Israeli Army, these attacks targeted the offices, underground tunnels, weapons caches, rocket launching sites, and armed personnel of the Hamas Police Force.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Apart from the air raids, the artillery of the Israel Army and Navy continued shelling Gaza throughout the night.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The Palestinian Authorities said that a mosque was destroyed during the air raids on the Gaza city.</seg>
    <seg id="13">According to unconfirmed reports, tanks from the Israeli Army, aided by the helicopters in the air, have advanced towards the area of Khan Younus.</seg>
    <seg id="14">During this twelve-day conflict, approximately seven hundred Palestinians, including many women and children, have died.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other side, only twelve soldiers from the Israeli Army have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Israeli Security Forces have confirmed that a high-ranking defense official, Amos Gillad, is going to Cairo to settle the terms of a ceasefire.</seg>
    <seg id="17">A delegation from Hamas is also going to Cairo to conduct parallel talks with the Egyptian diplomats.</seg>
    <seg id="18">In addition to this, the leader of the Palestinian Authority, Mehmood Abbas, is also arriving in Cairo on Friday.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">My Heart Is Broke, Please Return My Kidney.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Richard Batista says that eight years ago, he gave his wife Dawnell his kidney to save her life.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to AFP news agency, it is Dr. Batista's statement that his wife has repayed him for his kidney by cheating on him with another man, and now she wants a divorce.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During an interview with a local newspaper, Dr. Batista said "that her love affair has put a hole in my heart that still exists".</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Dr. Richard Batista's lawyer, though Dr. Batista is not demanding his kidney back, he wants  monetary compensation for the kidney.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He will give his statement about his wife in front of a judge within the next few days.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Free 140 Year Old, 9 Kilo Weighing Lobster!</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">'George the Giant Lobster' was captured from the sea two weeks ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Seafood company of the city had purchased it for a hundred Dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Instantly, they started using the lobster photos for his publicity.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, PETA (a organization supporting animal rights) demanded to release the lobster. As a result, it will be released in the sea.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After his capture in Canada, George 10 days in the city's crab and seafood company tank.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The age of lobster can be determined by its weight.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The restaurant's manager, Keith Walanty, says that their intent was never to harm the lobster. The reason for keeping him in the tank was to provide entertainment for the customers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Engrid Newkurk, from the animal rights group PETA, says that the restaurant's decision is praise-worthy and provides an example for those who want to keep these precious animals in the tank or want to eat them by boiling them alive.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Cell phone aids search for missing girl</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When the officials learned of Nataly Maltais's disappearance, the police and firefighting forces of the city of Acton, Mass., jumped into action.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Officials determined the girl's location using the GPS tracking on her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Viewed on Google using the street view, however, they discovered that the girl is in a motel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">One week earlier, Natale's grandmother, Rose Maltais, had taken Natale away from her legal parents.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Athol's police chief Timothy Anderson told BBC that Ms.Maltais said she will never return Natale and that Ms. Maltais had left the state.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Police contacted Ms. Maltais but when she did not return Natale as she had promised the police decided to find Natale by calling her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It has been a law in the USA since 2005 that mobile-  service providers will provide locations of 67% of calls made within 100 meters and 95% of calls within 300 meters.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on Tour of India</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This is Hamid Karzai's second tour to India in the last five months.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is expected that he will discuss the conditions after the Bombay terrorist attacks during his meeting with the prime minister Manmohan Singh.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this visit, he wants to express feelings concerning Afghanistan, the Bombay blasts and harmony with India.</seg>
    <seg id="5">During this visit of Karzai, mutual trade will be discussed apart from terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Discussion about mutual collaboration to fight terrorism is expected.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In his first visit of India president hamid karzai said that we wont let terrorism be a problem in relations between Afghanistan and India.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He also said that India and Afghanistan both are facing same challenge of deadly and mercyless terrorist activity.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The peace and prosperity is not only favorable for their countries but also for the entire world as well</seg>
    <seg id="10">we realize the reality that both the countries and the entire world could defeat terroism by joining hands</seg>
    <seg id="11"></seg>
    <seg id="12"></seg>
    <seg id="13"></seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2"></seg>
    <seg id="3"></seg>
    <seg id="4">Ajmal Kasab is in police custody. It is expected that police will submit the charges against him before Jan 24th.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ajmal Kasam does not have a lawyer to defend him in court.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Ajmal Kasab has written to the Government of Pakistan for legal aid.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Pakistani extremists are responsible for the attacks in Mumbai. India has provided the proof to Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Pakistan has accepted Ajmal Kasab as its citizen.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to police, Ajmal and his companion Abu Ismail were running away after killing TS Chief Karkaray, Police Chief Ashok Kumar and other police officers. Ajmal and his fellow terrorists used the squad car of a police officer. They were caught later near Gargam Chopati.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Ismail Khan was killed and Ajmal was captured by police.</seg>
    <seg id="11">No attorney has been assigned to assist Ajmal.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The government appointed Danish Mota as lawyer for Ajmal Kasab but Mota refused to take this case. According to him it is immoral to defend Ajmal.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Two other lawyers also refused to defend Ajmal after some political parties protested.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Constitutional Amendments: A committee will be formed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Tuesday in Islamabad,after addressing a seminar held for environmental changes, while talking to media representatives, he said; that a hearing of the parliament will be called for. Where this committee will be formed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that until now MQM has presented a bill to change the 17th constitution and further parties will give more bills.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the Pakistan Peoples party has also asked for amendments in the 17th constitution and asked other parties to do so as well and this committee will view their requests.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In answer to a question he replied, That the balance of power between the president and the prime minister will be decided upon by the Parliament.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Prime minister said that the Parliament holds power to make all decisions.</seg>
    <seg id="7">As a reply to another question the ex president Rtd General Pervaiz Musharaaf, was asked to leave his post in the army by a lot of party leaders and Bae Nazir Bhutto herself as well.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that the elected vice president of America, Joe Biden is a supported of Pakistan and democracy. In recognition of his services he was given the Hilale Pakistan by the President.</seg>
    <seg id="9">After the Mumbai incident in response to the threat of eliminating all contacts by the Indian government; the Prime Minister Yousaf Raza Gilani said that the Indian government is giving such statements under the extreme pressure of the Indian people.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Protest against the siding of Journalists.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">I refuse to accept the cynical notion that nation after nation must spiral down a militaristic stairway into the hall of thermonuclear destruction. I believe that unarmed truth and unconditional love will have the final word in reality.</seg>
    <seg id="3">I believe even amid today's mortar bursts and whining bullets that there is still hope for a brighter tomorrow. I believe that wounded justice, lying prostrate on the blood-flowing streets of our nation can be lifted from this dust of shame and reign supreme among the children of men.</seg>
    <seg id="4">I have the audacity to believe that people everywhere can have three meals a day for their bodies, education and culture for their minds, and dignity, equality and freedom for their spirits.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This faith can give us courage to face the uncertainties of the future. It will give our tired feet new strength as we continue our forward stride toward the city of freedom.</seg>
    <seg id="6">When our days become dreary with low-hovering clouds and our nights become darker than a thousands midnights, we will know that we are living in the creative turmoil of a genuine civilization.</seg>
    <seg id="7">With the richness and variety of bird life that exist there are exciting discoveries waiting to be made by any bird watcher who has the necessary enthusiasm and perseverance.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In actuality there is little danger from an elephant unless it happens to be a rogue or a female with a small calf.</seg>
    <seg id="9">I still believe that one day mankind will bow down before the altars of god and be crowned triumphant over war and bloodshed,and that non-violent redemptive will be proclaimed the rule of the land. The lion and the lamb shall lie down together and every man shall sit under his own vine.</seg>
    <seg id="10">I was also asked how I could subsist on the little food I ate during my meals. This knowledge was obtained by watching me eat till i mustered enough courage to shut the kitchen door.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The villagers were curious about me, and strange as it may seem, I had not anticipated it. It usually showed itself in their asking me direct questions.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas said that the journalist movement will continue until removed employees are not reinstated. The newspaper workers wages fixed by the seventh Wage board award is not enforced. The salaries for many months payable to TV channels and newspaper workers is not paid.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">11 member cabinet takes oath.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The new cabinet has six ministers from the opposition party of former Prime Minister, Sardar Atheeq Ahmed, the Muslim Conference, two from Pakistan Peoples Party, two from Peoples Muslim League and one minister from the Joint National Movement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The 11 cabinet members include one lady minister, who belongs to the Ateeq opposition Muslim Conference party.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The joint ruler said that the cabinet will be expanded next week, and it is possible that 12 more ministers will be taken into the cabinet. It should be clear that in the beginning of this month, Sardar Ateeq Khan's opposers removed him from the post of Prime Minister by showing lack of trust, and they made Sardar Ya'qoob Khan the new Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The jurisdiction of these ministers will be announced later on.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On the occasion of oath taking, members of the Peoples Party shouted slogans in favor of former Pakistani Prime Minister, Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">3.5 million users affected by virus.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this virus first detected in October 2008 which is known by names such as Configure, Down and up, and Kido.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Microsoft has come out with a patch to deal with this virus, but still some 3.5 million computers and memory sticks were infected with the virus.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Experts say that the number of infected computers could be many.</seg>
    <seg id="5">To settle with this, consumer has to use Microsoft page 'MS08067'.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Microsoft says that virus which affects thousands of computers, searches for windows file 'services.exe' and adds itself into its code.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After that virus makes to a DLL file into system folder of windows.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This virus creates its file name too.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Then changes the details of the registry of windows.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This virus creates a problem after it gets active which comes out as 'HTTP Server' and changes the restore point of the machine.</seg>
    <seg id="11">After that it download files from the hackers website.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Microsoft said that this virus has affected computers in different countries.</seg>
    <seg id="13">These countries include China, Brazil, Russia, India, America and Britain.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'The Demand- Quick Report on Indian Information'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In an interview with the representatives of the media, after a meeting of the Home Ministry, he said that the given by India</seg>
    <seg id="3">This information will help in investigating these regards.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that Pakistan was a sovereign nation and about the investigation on the information received from India, no country's</seg>
    <seg id="5">Dictation will be accepted.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that apart from the information received from India, they were gathering other information as well.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The internal adviser said that the executive institutions have taken 124 members of practically non-existent groups into custody, solely on the basis of the fear of a reduction in peace.</seg>
    <seg id="8">And if any evidence is found against them, action will be taken, while innocent people will be freed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In an answer to a question, he said that no arrested person would be handed over to India, and that action would be taken against such individuals according to Pakistani law.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that action would be taken against these individuals according to the law of the FIA.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In regards to one question, he said that Indian law enforcement departments have received information regarding the militants involved in the Bombay incident 42 days ago. Therefore, he is hopeful that India along with the international coalition will give Pakistan time to look into this information.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He reiterated the previous statement of the government that a separate team of interrogators will be formed for the investigation of the Bombay incident.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He clarified that a three-member interrogating team has been formed under the supervision of an additional Inspector General of the FIA,</seg>
    <seg id="14">which will investigate the information given to Pakistan from India regarding the Bombay attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Pakistan's High Commissioner Shahid Malik met President Asif Ali Zardari in India, during which the president made it clear that if any Pakistani was found involved in the Bombay attacks, action will be taken against him according to the country's law, and no one will be handed over to India. However, the Indian government is continuously pressuring Pakistan to hand over anyone involved in this matter to India.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">""Anything Is Possible in America""</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mr. Obama will take the oath on the 20th of January as the 44th President of the United States.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Standing on the stairs of the building built in the memory of the 16th American president, Abraham Lincoln, addressing an orchestra,</seg>
    <seg id="4">Mr. Obama said that America has faced tough challenges for many generations, and he is hopeful that America will take control of these problems.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Abraham Lincoln ended the practice of slavery in America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">At the same time, Mr. Obama said that it would take time to resolve the problems facing the country, and that the path would be trying.</seg>
    <seg id="7">'Despite this, I believe that the dreams of the founders of this country will remain alive'.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Apart from the Iraqi and Afghani wars, America is suffering from a devastating financial crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Extra normal steps are being taken for the oath taking ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Organizers believe that 2 million people will attend the function.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Monday is a national holiday in America, as on that date, the great standard bearer of human rights, Martin Luther King was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Martin Luther King was black.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Salutation to Martin Luther King, a resolution to work.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Martin Luther King was killed in the year of 1968.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama saluted Martin Luther King and told the Americans that they would work together to fulfill the promises of this nation.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Here, in Washington, preparations are being made for an unprecedented number of people gathering for the oath taking ceremony by the new president on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is believed that almost 2 million people will gather in Washington to watch the historic oath of office taken by the president elect.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama started Monday by visiting a medical center in North Washington, where he met with injured American soldiers. After this, he visited a homeless shelter, and painted a wall.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Speaking to journalists, Barack Obama said: "After the present crisis which we are facing, and the difficulties that many people are undergoing, we cannot sit quietly."</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that Martin Luther King spent most of his for the people.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Barack Obama said: "Today, we are remembering and respecting him, so it is not a day for us to stop and think. It is a day for us to act."</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that the ceremony on Tuesday would be on the same path as that of Martin Luther King's 'My Dream' speech, to hear which many thousands of people gathered, in 1963.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In this speech, Martin Luther King said that the day will come when people would not be judges based on the color of their skin.</seg>
    <seg id="12">BBC's Mathew Price said that you can call it the patching up of history, that Martin Luther King Day came twenty four hours before the first black president in American history would take the oath of office.</seg>
    <seg id="13">For many of the southern states of America, Barack Obama's presidency is the final realization of Dr. Martin Luther King's dream.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">was the additional political agent.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The other political agent was kidnapped ten days ago from south Waziristan by unidentified masked men.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Sources say that the agent was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer faction of the local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the local government, on Tuesday afternoon, around 4 o'clock, other political agent of South Waziristan, Aamir Latheef was brought to the Wana Scouts camp by a group of tribal members.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, they did not reveal who had kidnapped him.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The local residents have said that the political agent was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer faction of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Aamir Latheef was kidnapped on his way from Wana to Tank.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On January 11, 2009, seven masked men kidnapped the political agent, Aamir Latheef, along with his driver, from the tribal area of Karkandah in South Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the government agent, the kidnappers first disarmed the guards, and afterwords moved him to another car which drove away.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the local government, after the kidnapping of the political agent, security forces guarded all the check points in South Waziristan and semi-tribal areas, and searched all travelers thoroughly. In the previous week, the  rulers have placed economic restrictions on Wana.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On December 8, 2008, an assistant political agent of north Wazirastan Asmatullah was kidnapped when he was going from Mir Ali to Bannu to enjoy his Eid vacation. A few days after this two people, including Tehsildar Amanullah, were killed by unknown masked perpetrators in north Wazirastan.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Victory of a British hacker in the court.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A 42-year-old British citizen has admitted that he hacked an American military website.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gary has Asperger's syndrome. It should be kept in mind that an Asperger's patient has the obsession to do similar kinds of tasks.</seg>
    <seg id="4">His lawyers say that if he is handed over to America then he will commit suicide.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, government officials say that they are no threat to Gary's health.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Lord justice Morskey and Mr. Justice Simon while announcing the decision said that Gary is permitted to file a review petition in a British court.</seg>
    <seg id="7"></seg>
    <seg id="8">He added that the secretary of interior has noticed this issue.</seg>
    <seg id="9">But the government prosecutors say that the secretary of interior had used his authority.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Gary has never denied hacking of the American military website.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In 2001 and 2002, Gary hacked an American computer system which caused a loss of eight hundred thousand dollars to the American government.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Gary hacked 97 computers including that of American Navy and NASA.</seg>
    <seg id="13">However Gary says that he did not do dis with bad intentions but he was just looking for information about aliens which he thought the American government had kept secret.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Gary's mother Janice Sharp has said that she is happy with this decision.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Gary's lawyer has said that its the right decision.</seg>
    <seg id="16">This case has been continued since 2002 and finally a right decision has come up.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">In Kashmir two Hizb Commanders were killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Colonel Acharya, spokesman of the northern command of the Indian Army deployed in Jammu, told BBC, from a reliable source, troops from 24 rashtria rifles and Jammu Kashmir police besieged the place in the batihaas jungle in tehsil Gandwa of the Doda district where the armed extremists were hiding.</seg>
    <seg id="3">They fired at the army and in retaliation and two extremists got killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Correspondent say that among the two terrorists killed, one was also Zahoorudding, the district commander of the banned group Hizb-ul-Mujahideen was active for the last 12 years in the area, and was a specialist in bomb blasts.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The other with him is identified as Sajjad Hussain, who according to the army, was associated to the extremists since last year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Acharia, the operation is still going on in the mentioned area of the jungle because according to them there is a possibility of presence of more extremists there. Army said two Kalashnikov were found during the first step of the operation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Yesterday, the head of the province police, Kuldeep Kumar Khudda, by announcing the statistics of the year 2008,  has declared this year the most peaceful year until now.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that in November and December, during 7 stages of assembly elections, no torture was done.</seg>
    <seg id="9">More than 1350 candidates participated in these elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Be clear that Hizb-ul-Mujahideen is active in Jammu Kashmir for the last eight years.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Hizb-ul-Mujahideen declared one sided cease fire in July 2000 for the first time after which the Indian government and Hizb commandos had a talk.</seg>
    <seg id="12">But the cease fire was over in only 15 days.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Later many senior commandos of Hizb-ul-Mujahideen were killed in different operations.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On Thursday, the renowned daily, "The News" wrote about the extremist groups operating in Pakistan occupied Kashmir.  Lashkar-e-Taiba and Hizbul Mujahideen have decided to revise their Kashmir policy.</seg>
    <seg id="15">It should be clear that until now, the policy of both groups has been that the Kashmir issue could be resolved through armed resistance.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bugthi Hill: Gas pipeline blown up</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police officials, the eighteen inch diameter pipelines running from Loti Gasfields to Peer Mountain were damaged in a blast.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The affected pipeline led to Soui Plant.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Shortly after the blast, a man named Sarbaz Baloch claimed in a telephone call to be the spokesman of the outlawed group The Baloch Republican Army and took responsibility for the attack.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This is the fourth gas pipeline attacked in as many days.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On Friday, In Allah Yar hill, an eighteen inch diameter pipeline was destroyed.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In Quetta, the Soui Sidran Gas Company's General Manager Mushtaq Siddiqi said that gas was sent through this pipeline in the afternoon.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This pipeline goes to Quetta via Sabi.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Quetta: Zyarat and other surrounding areas have had an extreme shortage of natural gas for three days. On one side, snowfall continues and the temperature has dropped below freezing. On the other side, stoves and heaters have gone cold.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Besides this, a bomb exploded in a motor cycle in Mal Mandi in the city of Dera Bugti. According to the police, there was no fatal damage due to this blast.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Administrator for Jamat-ud-Dawa</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The headquarter of Jamat-ud-Dawa, Tayyaba Center, is almost 25km away from Lahore near Mureedkay.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This center has a hospital, a school and also a hostel for students.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Law minister Punjab, Rana Sanaullah Khan, says that the assignment of a superintendent in the Jamat-ud-Dawa center came in to being so that the work of the welfare organizations there is not disturbed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Khalid Waleed, the son in law of Chief of Jamat-ud-Dawa Hafiz Saeed,  a qualified government official Khaqan Babar is appointed as an administrator to monitor the hospital, schools and other welfare organizations located in the center. Although according to them, there has also been an increase in the police staff.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Security Council of the United Nations placed restrictions on Jamat-ud-Dawa after which, Pakistan's federal government did operations against Jamat-ud-Dawa throughout the entire country. They put many leaders under house arrest including Ameer Hafiz Saeed. Assigning an administrator in the Tayyaba Center from the government of Punjab was also part of the series of actions by the federal government against Jamat-ud-Dawa.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Khaqan Babar is related to DMG ( District Management Group).</seg>
    <seg id="8">Hafiz Khalid Waleed has informed us that the Lahore division commissioner Khusro Parvez Khan came to the Tayyaba Center on Sunday with the police and civil authority and inspected several parts of the center. Khalid Waleed has disapproved of placement of an Administrator from the government in the Jamat-ud-Dawa Center. He said that earlier operations of the government have already decreased the number of patients in the hospital and students in the school.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to a press release by Jama'athu Da'wah, here, the Jama'ath chief, Hafiz Saeed is said to have written a letter to the United Nations General Secretary, Ban Ki Moon, and the Committee on Taliban, appealing to remove the ban on Jama'athud Da'wah, passed by the Security Council.</seg>
    <seg id="10">In the letter, he mentioned that the passing of the ban by the Security Council on Jama'athud Da'wah, was a one-sided and unjust decision, also Jama'athud Da'wah has no connection with terrorism rather busy in social work.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Aidhi's Gaza humanitarian mission</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After passing many stages involved in getting the permissions required for entering Gaza, he has been successful in reaching Egypt from New York.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking to BBC Urdu service from Cairo, he said that he was not able to reach Gaza yet, as Egypt and Israel have placed many barriers.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said ""It has been eight days since I got here, and I still have not got the permission to enter Gaza.""</seg>
    <seg id="5">""I am now in Cairo, and hopefully I will be permitted to reach Gaza tomorrow"".</seg>
    <seg id="6">Giving details, he said: ""At first, I was given a seven day visa to enter Gaza, and later on, upon insisting, the Pakistani officials helped me out and increased it to a one month visa, but on the condition that I would go only once, i.e. it would be a single entry visa."</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that he had brought his son and daughters with him, and that they wanted to do some social work.</seg>
    <seg id="8">""I have brought some money"".</seg>
    <seg id="9">A one million dollar check has been given to the Red cross of Egypt and ten thousand dollars in cash has been also given in order to send aid to Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Four more ministers in the cabinet, total of sixty three</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The four new federal ministers include two from the Mutahida Qaumi Movement and two from the Jamiat Ulamae Islam Fazalur Rehman Group.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Asif Ali Zardari took the oath from the new ministers.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani and members of cabinet were also present at the oath-taking ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After the inclusion of four new ministers to the federal cabinet, the number of federal ministers, state ministers, and advisers has reached a total of sixty-three.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Ministers Farooq Sattar and Babar Ghouri are from MQM, whereas Ministers Azam Swati and Molana Ataur Rehman are from the Jamiat Ulamae Islam Fazalur Rehman Group.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The departments of these ministers have not yet been announced.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Farooq Sattar is the convener of MQM, whereas Babar Ghouri is a senator from MQM whose term will expire on March 10.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Azam Swati was elected as a free senator and is considered to be one of the richest.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Moulana Ataur Rahman is a member of the National Assembly and is Moulana Fazlur Rahman's younger brother.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Keep in mind that four important officeholders are not members of the National Assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On the 3rd of December, 2008, 28 new ministers and 18 ministers of state were taken into the Cabinet. At that time it was believed that members of the MQM would also be included in the Cabinet, but due to a difference in the distribution of ministries, MQM was not included.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Balochistan pipe line blew up.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police, this was an eighteen inch wide pipe line that goes to the various wells in the gas plant of Peer Mountain.  It was blown up by unidentified individuals in the morning.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Apart from this, well number three was destroyed yesterday in an explosion, and a gas pipe line was harmed by another explosion near Allah Yaar Hill.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The responsibility for these blasts were claimed by the spokesperson for the banned organization, Baloch Republican Army, Sarbaz Baloch.</seg>
    <seg id="5">From the beginning of the year 2009, there was an increase in the number of extremist incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In this month, there were dozens of incidents of gas pipes being blown up, and there was also an increase in attacks on trains and people from the state of Punjab.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Though the Chief Minister of Balochistan, Nawab Aslam Raeesani, expressed distress over these incidents, and the police were instructed to share information with intelligence agencies, it was still not possible to stop these incidents.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The 819 trillion Dollar economic reform package was accepted.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">No member who was part of the Republican party voted for t President Obama's plan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Many within the Republican party said that this economic plan was very expensive and that it would not be successful.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Among the representatives of the house, 240 votes were given in favor of the plan, while 188 votes were given against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This economic reform plan has to be presented in the Senate next week, where the ruling Democratic party has a significant majority.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is feared that, due to opposition from the Republican party, the plan's passing in the senate may not be easy.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After the passing of the economic reform plan the house, Barack Obama said to the members that they should not let political differences get in the way of this important plan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The President said that plan, which he hoped would become law by next month, would prove helpful in creating a suitable environment in the country for business would prosper.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to this plan, the both the common man and the businessmen would be relieved of 275 trillion dollars of debt, and 540 trillion Dollars would be provided for fixing roads, bridges, and schools, and for unemployment allowance and research on new technology.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The editor of BBC in Washington, Richard Lister, said that Barack Obama had decided to put political differences behind him and prepare a new political culture, but that this economic package has once again created bitterness along political lines.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In the National Assembly, a member of the Republican Party has rejected the government's bill and declared it a waste of money: No employment opportunities can be created through this bill.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He focuses on the Bill from his party's standpoint in which tax cuts have been heavily advised.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said that through his package, with less investment, many employment opportunities can be produced.</seg>
    <seg id="14">He said that with respect to Development projects, Tax cuts can create many employment Opportunities.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bitterness Between Israeli President and Turkish Prime Minister.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Rajab Tayb Urdan vehemently said to the Israeli President that much blood has been spilt in Gaza and he felt ashamed that people were applauding the military actions in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Urdan has said that I feel that you are using such words in order to hide your guilt but you have killed those children and i am mourning the death of those, killed at sea side.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Shamon Perez has said that Gaza's incident was not due to Israel but was Hamas, by creating a dangerous dictatorship.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Davis, A correspondent with the BBC, has said that the World Economic Forum has never seen such an incident before.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Afterwards, Urdan said that although he respects the Israeli President, everything he shouted to him was far from the truth.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Turkey is one of few Muslim countries which has diplomatic ties with Israel, but there is an acrimony in the relations of both the countries for last few years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Attacks were planned in Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Wajid Shams UL Hassan tells  NDTV that Pakistan will soon publish the investigative report on Mumbai Attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Last year, 170 people lost their life in Mumbai Attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Now India is holding the Lashkar-e-Toiba, an extremist outfit, responsible for Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">India also claimed that no state actors of Pakistan  have role in Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Pak-India relationships are badly hurt by Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="7">High Commissioner Wajid Shams Ul Hassan gave a statement in press that gives a clue about what investigative report may contain.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wajid Shams-ul-Hasan, in that investigative report, denied that Pakistani soil has been used.</seg>
    <seg id="9">That can be any other country but not the Great Britain.</seg>
    <seg id="10">These two places (Pakistan and Britain )were what I have conscious of.</seg>
    <seg id="11">India and the international world put too much pressure on Pakistan to take action against those responsible for Mumbai attacks. Pakistan was told that it had to take action against many people who are possibly behind the Mumbai attacks, and dozens of people were arrested.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Wajid Sahms Ul Hassan said, "We are not trying to hide this."</seg>
    <seg id="13">We believe we need to act on reality.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Our investigation will accepted by world.</seg>
    <seg id="15">We (through investigation) are trying to satisfy India by evidence.</seg>
    <seg id="16">He defended the delaying of Pakistani investigation said that these type of clues take time to gather, understand, and investigate.</seg>
    <seg id="17">commissioner Wajid shams Ul Hassan said there that India take 45 days to show his Dozier.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Republican Leader Also Elected Red Indian</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In six stages of the election in the Republican party, Mikel won because he got 91 votes out of 168.</seg>
    <seg id="3">During the election for the position of party chairman Katen Dawsen, Michael Steel's opponent, received 70 votes, whereas former chairman Dunken abdicated from the competition in the second round.</seg>
    <seg id="4">People say that of the five candidates who stood for the position of the chairmanship of the republican party, Steel was considered the most conservative among them.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After his win, Steel said in his speech "We are saying to our friends and enemies together, that come with us but those who will cause problems in this, be prepared to separate from us." Michael Steel is from Maryland where he has served as the Deputy Governor.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He came into prominence in 2006 when he stood for a seat in the senate.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But after losing in the senate elections he was appointed as the chairman of one politically conservative party committee.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Now that he has been selected as party chairman, the Republicans' nationwide campaign efforts will be under his supervision.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He fought elections promising that he will give the party a new cause and use new approaches to add conservative supporters to the party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">India Claims Presence of Lashker-e-Tayyaba and Josh-e-Muhammad in Jammu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Terrorists have been reported in the Poonch Tribal area of Jammu.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to official sources, on receiving secret information, police and army have surrounded the area and begun a search.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this period small engagements took place in which four militants, two soldiers and one police agent were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to sources these battles continued until the last reports were received, both Lashkar-e-Taiba and Jaish-e-Mohammad militants are present in these regions. As the fighting increases more army battalions are being sent there.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Meanwhile, the chief minister selected by the joint government, Umar Abdullah met the governor and informed him of his being selected the leader of his party. The National Conference in the assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The allied party of the National Conference, the Congress also informed the governor of their support for Umar Abdullah.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Umar Abdullah will be administered the oath and inaugurated as the chief minister of the state tomorrow.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Note: that in the recently held state elections, the National Conference won 28 out of the 87 seats of the parliament, becoming the majority party. It should be known that separatist groups boycotted the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The Congress party, which got 17 seats, was prepared to form a joint government with the National Conference.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Today, upon reaching Srinagar, Umar Abdullah was given a warm and welcome greeting by the party members.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On this occasion, Umar Abdullah said that he would try to play a role in generating dialog between the Indian government and separatist groups. However, this would not be possible until the elections took place and the new government came to power in India.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The role of the European Union in making peace in the Middle East.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Of the diplomatic efforts going on to stop the war in the Middle East,if looked at from a government perspective, those of the European Union are the most decisive.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the state policy of Brussels, the efforts of the Shwarzenburg delegation or those of Sarkozy, are similar to giving a helping hand.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The spokesperson of the European Commission, Amadeu Altafaj, said that every effort which helps advancing the joint message of the European Union to the two parties is welcome.</seg>
    <seg id="5">As far as the state policy is concerned, everyone seems alright.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, in reality, the European Union is in a sad state of internal differences.</seg>
    <seg id="7">As the President of the Union, the Czech Republic's role is weak.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On top of that, internal fighting has made it all the more helpless.</seg>
    <seg id="9">On the other hand, French President, Sarkozy's demeanor is such that one would think he was the president of the Union.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Though, France has completed it's six month presidency period.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Sarkozy wants to play a presidential role, and he is able to, but he does not have the permission to do so.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The most ridiculous situation faces the foreign minister of France, Bernard Kouchner.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He is part of the delegation which is being headed by Schwarzenberg, the foreign minister of the Czech Republic.</seg>
    <seg id="14">What is even worse is that both the foreign ministers are giving different statements on the middle east war.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Schwarzenberg says that Israel has the right to defend itself, whereas according to Kouchner this war does not come under defense policy. On the other side, Germany has also sent its special ambassador to the Middle East. The European Union will not succeed on a foreign platform until they express agreement based on the same issues.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Its evidence is the reaction of Israel, which does not give any importance to the conciliation efforts of the EU.</seg>
    <seg id="17">EU has a golden chance of getting something done because America has lost in the Middle East due to the policies of George Bush.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Economic Setback: Suicide of German Billionaire Industrialist</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Adolf Meerklay, residing in the area of Sawabia in southern Germany, has left a great business group behind him, though.</seg>
    <seg id="3">But earlier,common German citizens did not know much about him.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Later when he had to talk about the loan given to is industrial group by almost 30 banks for many weeks, he  became topic of the headlines and he could foresee a dark   future for Meerklay groups.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Merkel Group suffered financial losses of many millions of Euro after its investment to buy shares of German auto maker Volkswagen.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Then monetary institutions canceled this groups loan amounting to 700 million and another 1 billion Euro that it necessarily required and hence Merkel came into extreme pressure.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Some time back, the bank agreed to provide Merkel Group an emergency loan. But, Adolf Merkel,who raised a small industrialist group to the position of a strong industrial group whose annual income was approximately 30 billion Euro, could not bare the loss in his investment capability.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Adolf Merkel, after the death of his parents, started managing the business and took to modernize it. The business, under his supervision, became very popular and  stronger.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He named his company Ratiopharm, which,is a very large, acclaimed and successful pharmaceutical company.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Some time back, the commercial value of this company was in between 5 and 6 billion Euro and still was earning a revenue of 8.1 billion Euro annually. After the great success of Ratiopharm, the Merkel Group acquired many big businesses, which included building materials makers. Hydelberg cement to modified/special car maker Kassbohrer company.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The workforce of Merkel Group is nearly about 100,000 throughout the world and its assets include Ratiopharm, which always was the most important business in the portfolio.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Adolf Merkel, during his lifetime, expressed the view that it has been four generations that we have been in pharmaceutical business.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Now the management of this institution is with my children and I hope this institution will be managed by and in possession of my family for few hundred years.</seg>
    <seg id="14">After the suicide of Adolf Merkel, the banks have provided approval for temporary loans of 400 million Euro for VEM Group, but added the condition that VEM should sell off Ratiopharm to improve the financial situation for a long term sustainability.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Likewise after the death of Adolf Meerklay, the Meerklay group will not remain as it was.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Germany: Crime Rate Down Among Immigrants</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to recent statistics, the crime rate among immigrants has fallen from 9.22% to 4.21% between 2004 and 2007.</seg>
    <seg id="3"></seg>
    <seg id="4"></seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Joachim Herrmann, the Bavarian Interior Minister, this would appear to be a positive change.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said, "It is important to note that the number of foreigners being granted German citizenship is increasing</seg>
    <seg id="7">It should thus be mentioned in the statistics that even though a criminal is German, his background is foreign."</seg>
    <seg id="8">Herrmann said that his province will take this into account when gathering statistics in 2010.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Besides Bavaria, Hamburg is also thinking  along the same lines.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The internal affairs senator related with the matters of CDU, Cristoph said, "When research is done in a scientific manner, Ahlhaus, man can not bring about its required results as it wills, but rather, it depends on the numbers and statistics that come out from the research".</seg>
    <seg id="11">He referred to a crime prevention state wise objective report, Ahlhaus, which was prepared in 2006. He researched this and it was reported as to what percent of the people committing crime from Bergdorf to Hamburg were foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="12">From these results, it became clear that the foreigners were there.</seg>
    <seg id="13">had a lower crime percentage than the crimes taking place in the whole state.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Contrary to this, during 2006, when the percentage of youngsters committing crimes was calculated, it became evident that the average age of youngsters from a foreign background committing crime was 44.</seg>
    <seg id="15">.7 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="16">However, the various German political parties such as SPD, environmentalist party, grains, and left wing party, Linkspartei, are against the collecting of crime statistics of German citizens with a foreign background.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Wanted: Quick Evacuation of the Army from Gaza!</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Aihud Olmert stressed that for complete evacuation of forces, a proper and stable ceasefire would be necessary.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamas and Israel announced a ceasefire on Sunday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Islamic militant group Hamas while announcing a one week cease fire has asked the Israel army to leave the Gaza strip within one week and to end the barricade on the Gaza strip.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On other side, the leader of Hamas Ismail Hannan has said that Israel has been given victory from God in the Gaza war.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that in Gaza war, Israel has not been able to achieve its purpose.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Before that, in the city of Sharm Al Sheikh, Egypt, a conference was held of Arab and European countries on Sunday. Israel was asked to evacuate its army from Gaza immediately.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It was decided in the conference that soon an international aid conference will be held for Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="9">German Chancellor Angela Meerkal also attended the conference.</seg>
    <seg id="10">At least 1300 Palestinians including 10 soldiers and a total of 13 Israelis were killed in the war lasting for three weeks between the militants of Hamas and Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the other side, Palestinian President Mahmood Abbas has insisted on the formation of national government in the areas of Palestine.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A video message for Germany from Al-Qaeda</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this 30 minute video message, a man wearing a black turban with a covered face and holding a gun is giving a message to the German Government.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The person shown speaking German is Abu Talha.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The all titles of this Arabic video message are present.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The logo of Alqaida is on the screen side and the date is 2008 in the video.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In this message it is said to the German government that the large numbers of force in Afghanistan shows the shore that there will be no any attack at it so is it not knowing unknowing and what other thing?</seg>
    <seg id="7">However the saying himself Abu Talha that person did not threat German without channel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The number of union forces in Afghanistan contained in NETO is about 3500.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The German parliment had approved semdomg 1000 more to Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This is the first message from Alaqaid to Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="11">A distinguished expert in terrorism, Mijail Luder, said this message and the situation in Kabul and self attack outside of German ambassador's house prove that we should take it seriously.</seg>
    <seg id="12">From last few years Alqaida has been shwon such messages and they were followed by attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="13">On Saturday,the militant organization,Taliban,took responsibility for the suicide attacks that took place outside the German embassy.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Many German newspapers and thinkers are looking at this attack in connection with the Al-Qaida message.</seg>
    <seg id="15">"They are targeting Germany."</seg>
    <seg id="16">Fundamentalist Muslims are viewing the German - Afghan policy in a negative and critical manner.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They accuse the German government of following an extremist policy, not only in Afghanistan, but also in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Because of this, they consider Germany their target, more and more frequently.</seg>
    <seg id="19">In the meantime, the German government claims that the German secret agencies had knowledge about this video, even before it came to light.</seg>
    <seg id="20">The German joint crime control organization is busy studying the video.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama has been elected President of the United States.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Not only the American public, but the whole world has increased expectations concerning Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">As Barack Obama receives congratulatory messages from around the world on becoming president, the expectations for him are also becoming clear.</seg>
    <seg id="4">German Chancellor Angela Merchel also expressed reliance on the new American president in these regards stating,</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I believe that the Joint Republic of Germany and the United States of America will be able to get together on the basis of strong relationships and partnership, to solve the problems facing us."</seg>
    <seg id="6">Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin expressed his belief that Obama's seriousness and open-heartedness would be an asset.</seg>
    <seg id="7">As such, the previous American president's policies were subject to criticism.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Despite these criticisms, the previous government deserves credit for arousing China to participate more constructively on the international level.  China believes the new president can continue this by working towards stronger military ties between the two countries.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Gosuwe Hu, an expert on Chinese politics who is active in Bokhum, Germany says:</seg>
    <seg id="10">"From this viewpoint, I am certain that Obama and his economic team will, within the coming weeks and months, pressurize the Beijing government into pegging the Chinese currency to a stable and market representing exchange rate."</seg>
    <seg id="11">Additionally, the previous American government also increased ties with India.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Though Professor Christopher Raj, expert on American Sciences in New Delhi, believes these policies bring the two countries closer to a strategic partnership, he acknowledges that whatever actions Obama takes, he cannot cause change  overnight.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Pope Benedict also send a message to spared wind of thrive in World emphasize peace and Collaboration to Obama.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Iraq provisional elections.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After 2005, this war effected the country first important election.</seg>
    <seg id="3">For the provisional election, 14,400 Representative came in ground for 440 seats.</seg>
    <seg id="4">To maintain peace and stability during election 8 lack police and soldiers deployed in Iraq.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Due to the danger of an explosion or any terrorist attack on this important day, all of Iraq's  boundaries were sealed before Friday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Airports were closed and public transportation was not allowed.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to sources, due to no transportation on the streets of Baghdad ,there was no traffic seen and Iraqi children played football on the street.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the situation of present Iraqi election on the one side will predict this thing that in 2011 when American solders troops go back from Iraq so than either national security agencies able to control county or not and on the other side political analyst look this as one analytic which can predict that how much Iraqi people our agree to democratic change.</seg>
    <seg id="9">With the help of United Nations starting provisional election in Iraq and almost 800 international observer investigate this election.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Yaom-e-Ashura: The day of Aashura and the great sacrifice of Hazrat Imam Hussain was celebrated with respect in Iran today.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a news reporter, in the capital of Iran, Tehran in all small and big cities, the day of Syed-u-shuhada was celebrated with respect and at this event a large number of Shia's participated in majalis-e-uzza and gatherings for nabi pak sallalaho alaehe wassallam at the event of his son's shadat. The whole day was spent by Shia's to this event of Syedushuhada in giving his life for Islam and it was renewed and participated in gatherings at large level.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The defeat of Israelian from Ghaza Ajlin are an example of freedom fighters of Palestines.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Urdu service of a news agency, the cruel bombing was continued on civil area by Israel in the fight between right and wrong. There have been 880 murdered and 3700 injured Palestines by Israel attacks in the air, on earth and on sea.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In Shuhada, 275 innocent children were dead and smiling at the faithlessness of the Arab leaders and only namesake organizations like the international human rights organizations looked upon.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Today the life given by the freedom fighters has forced Israel forces to go back from the area of Ajeen , thus showing the victory on the power of faith and shahadat and bringing an end to non-muslims.</seg>
    <seg id="5">If it was not for Misr president, Hosni Mubarak not being that enthusiastic about freedom fighters of Hammas defeating Israel . But the cruelty is that the Israel backup Misr had stopped Palistine Muslims which indeed was a bad part of Arab history.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Here Saudi Arabia and Jordan governments are helping Israel thus being disloyal to Muslims and giving company to Israeli's.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barak Obama joining hands on a Policy with Iran.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a news agency, the elected president of America, Barak Obama said talking to ABC News that he will do a new policy about the issues of Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama said "Iran will be a big challenge for the American government."</seg>
    <seg id="4">Barack Obama said that he is concerned about Iranian support of Palestinian organizations Hamas and Hiza Ullah and Iran's uranium enrichment program.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But he will not continue the existing policy of current American president Bush, and he will adopt a different policy about relations with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama said that while achieving the real goal he will insist on mutual respect and dialogue.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Obama has already said that to engage in dialogue with Iran, there should be no conditions applied.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the interview, he said that he hoped that his administration will quickly follow his new policy about Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Regarding the crisis in the Middle East, Obama said that he is making a new team.</seg>
    <seg id="10">That will start working for peace in the Middle East beginning January 20.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bush, the incompetent president of America, confessed his mistakes in his last address to the press.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Every news agency has cited the Associated Press's report that, in his last press conference, American President George Bush has confessed many mistakes and crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In a Press Conference in White House, President Bush has said that he has good wishes for newly elected President Obama but the biggest challenge will remain to protect USA from terrorist attack.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the Iraq mission and social security amendments were his mistakes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush has said that whatever he did he did in the benefit of America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In response to the many questions related to Israel invasion in Gazam President Bush says that Israel has the right to defend according to him. Hamas should not attack Israel and the world, like America should help the cruel instead of helping the victim.</seg>
    <seg id="7">American uneducated,unqualified and arrogant President has said that weapons should not be provided to Hamas for as much America is providing Israel with the most destructive weapons and Israelis is using and advantage in killing Palestine people. Bush also praises Arab who are in the favor of Israel and called them friend of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Bush has shown some abashment regarding the crimes in Abu Gharib and Gountanamo Prisons.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Analysts have said that there should be a case of criminal offense against Bush. Those organizations which are going to do this will have a benefit on all humanity.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Ahmdi Nijad has shown pity on Arab nations in their silence.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mahr News Agency reported that Iran's President Dr. Mahmud Ahmdi Nijad has shown regret and criticizes the Arab Nation for keeping their silence on the issue of Israeli bloodily on Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmdi Nijad has shown surprise on the silence of Arab nations on such Brutal activities of Israel in Gaza. He said that Israel is repeating the Holocaust; Palestine children, women and civil citizens are been killed and no Arab leaders has given any statement yet.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmedinejad has said that all of the Arab countries should unite against Israel to rescue the Muslims of Gaza from Israeli oppression.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ahmadinejad: Saudi King Must Clarify Position on Israels Gaza Massacre</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by the Mehr news agency, President Mahmood Ahmadinejad has told Saudi Muslim ruler King Abdullah that his silence regarding the Gaza massacre has become an encouragement to the enemies of Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmedinejad said in his address that Abdullah should clarify his position and clearly support the oppressed, so that enemy efforts to cause a rift among Muslims would not succeed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmedinejad also said that Israel was unrelentingly committing atrocities in Gaza for the past 19 days in which children were being killed and houses, mosques, schools and hospitals were being bombed. He added that if Muslim leaders remained silent, it would be an encouragement to Israel's leaders.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Ahmedinejad addressed King Abdullah, saying that non-Islamic countries such as Venezuela and Bolivia had taken definitive steps against Israel, so that it was reasonable to expect even more from the Saudi ruler.</seg>
    <seg id="6">President Ahmadinejad declared that Palestine would be successful in Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He also said that the oppressed would win out over the oppressors since this was the promise of Allah.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090116.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush: Terrorism Still a Threat for America</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Mehr news agency cited German news reports that U.S. President George Bush had said in his farewell speech, addressing successor Barack Obama and the nation, that while America was relatively safe compared to seven years ago, the threat of terrorism still looms over America.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The history of civilization shows how man always has to choose between making the right and the wrong use of the discoveries of science. This has never been more true than in our own age.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In a brief period, amazing discoveries have been made and applied to practical purposes. It has become platitude to say we are living in an age of revolution. It would be ungrateful not to recognize how immense are the boons which science has given to mankind. It has brought within reach of multitudes, benefits and advantages which only a short time ago were the privilege of the few. It has shown how malnutrition, hunger and disease can be overcome.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It has not only lengthened life but it has deepened its' quality. Fields of knowledge, experience and recreation often in the past only to a few, have been thrown open to millions.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">But the gifts of modern science can be misused.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Through the work of science, ordinary man today has been given the opportunity of a longer and fuller life than was ever possible to his grandparents. Most thankfully, we must acknowledge all that science has done and is doing for the welfare of our race but the gifts of modern science can be misused.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The motor-driven vehicle facilitates business and gives harmless enjoyment to many but it can strew the roads with the dead and dying; more causalities in one year in this country alone.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The cinema is a means of instruction and recreation opening magic casements, but it is often a channel of vulgarity and false values.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The wireless can link the world together in a moment of time, but it can also be the instrument of lying propaganda. The aeroplane makes travel rapid and easy.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It can also become a weapon of destruction. It is this two-fold aspect of use to which science can be put, that has raised in an acute form, the question.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It is morally justifiable to make any perfect discovery of an invention to be used for the purpose of destruction.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">In North Waziristan, one of the tribal areas of Pakistan, six people have been murdered by the Taliban.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A news agency quoted a report that in the tribal area of North Waziristan two Afghan citizens and four Pakistanis have been murdered, blamed for spying.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the information on Tuesday morning, local residents found four people shot dead in the area of Tehsil Choke, a suburb of sub-district Mir Ali.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Two more dead bodies were found in the main area of Miranshah. They were dumped in the marketplace of a bazaar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Letters written in Urdu were also found close to the corpses claiming that the victims had been killed for spying .</seg>
    <seg id="6">Two weeks earlier in Miranshah, the capital of North Waziristan, two Afghan citizens were also killed accused of spying.</seg>
    <seg id="7">During the last twelve days fifteen people have been killed in connection with accusations of spying for America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be known that over one hundred people have been killed during the last 6 years, accused of spying. The Taliban have been blamed for these murders.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barak Obama is expected to sign an order to close the notorious Guantanamo Bay prison.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Major news agency sources said that the American president will be signing an order today for the closing of the Guantanamo Bay prison.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The new American president, Barak Hussain Obama, started acting upon his election promises slowly.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He directed a plan for American forces to come back from Iraq, although today the American president will sign the order to close the poorly named jail Guantanamo.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that President Obama will sign this order today. According to this order, the jail of Guantanamo will be closed at least in one year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">With this, the observations on inspection tactics for doubtful terrorists will continue, and it is expected that derogating prisoners will stop.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President Obama started to fulfill his promises at election day. First of all, he will make his government transparent in action and speech.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is the saying of soothsayers that the American president started to save the falling goodwill of America at the international level.  But his success is difficult due to helping the govt. of Israel, therefore any good deed is not expected in this helping. If America wants to save his goodwill, then it should stop helping Israel and must not aid those criminals.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tony Blair: There is compulsory need to participate Islamic organization in dialogs.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">It is narrated by an expert British news report agency, The Times, that the previous prime minister of the United Kingdom, Tony Blair, stressed the Hamas participating in the peace of Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the newspaper, Tony Blair said that the way should be found to include Hamas in the peace of Middle East.  Blair was criticized at ignoring Hamas and talking with Mahmood Abbas only.  It should be known also that the Western countries want to talk with Hamas after knowing his power, although before they were told Hamas was a terrorist organization defending its country and struggling to freeing its home from others. Israel has illegal hands on the houses and the country of Falastin.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Merchants Murdered in Karachi, A Total Strike in Koeta</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">There was strike in Karachi, Koeta and some other areas against the death of four merchants Thursday.</seg>
    <seg id="3">During this all business centers were closed, although the traffic was low.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The strike call was from Union merchants Balochan, Pakhtoonkhwa Milli Awami Party and Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam, who blamed Karachi police that they were misfiring when those persons reached the van showroom.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The president of the Merchant Union Abdurrahim Kakron showed his desire that the police men should have action taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, the aim of Karachi police did not came in showing after this being.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The dead persons belonged to the frontier city Chaman.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the strike, many arrangements were undertaken by government and there were police at main points.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Commander of Hamas killed in Israeli attack.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A main figure of Hammas was killed in an air attack by Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It was the second main person of Hamas killed as a result of Isreali attacks in the Gaza Strip.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Officials of Hammas have said that Abu Zakaria Al Jamal was killed on Saturday in his palace located in North of Gaza City.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Scholar Nazar Rayyan of Hammas was killed  in another aerial attack by Israel on Thursday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Residing in Rome, Hammas's exiled leader Khalid Mashal has expressed taking revenge and threatened Israel with a ground attack.</seg>
    <seg id="7">There are thousands of soldiers and tanks of placed by Israel on the border of Gaza awaiting fighting orders.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America has appealed for a cease fire. But has stated that the decision of to fight on Gaza is based on Israel policy.</seg>
    <seg id="9">American President George Bush, on his weekly radio speech, has accused Hammas of excitation to aggravate violence. And has adjudged their rocket attacks on Israel as terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He has said that America is working on a cease fire. Concluding that a one-way agreement will not be accepted.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Three dead bodies found in Northern Waziristan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani security officials have stated that three dead bodies are found in the tribal areas of Northern Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">There is doubt that Taliban have killed them by issuing death sentences.</seg>
    <seg id="4">These dead bodies were found near the main city Meran Shah in northern Waziristan, had notes are found with these men labeling them to be American spies.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officials said that one of the bodies is most likely that of a man who was kidnapped last week.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the other two bodies which were riddled with bullets are those of Afghan citizens.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Israeli attacks on Gaza continue for the 10th straight day.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A Palestinian was child injured in the Israel missile attack. Israeli ground forces are fighting with the troops of Hammas in the entirety of the Gaza strip. The Israeli Air Force  continued attacks on pockets of militant groups for the 10th straight day.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Israeli Defense Minister, Ehud Barack, said on Monday that fighting will continue and Army operations will continue until the people of Southern Israel are safe from the rocket attacks of Hammas.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Although, besides the attacks of Israel, the rocket firing continues Hammas in which four people were killed including three local citizens.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Leader of Hammas, Mahmood Zuhr stated on monday his forces were instructed to demolish the Israeli Army and target local Israeli residents.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But one official of Hammas said that they plan to send a delegation to Egypt on Monday to discuss the current situation and seek assistance for their party.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In Gaza one Palestinian woman was injured. Medical sources in Gaza said that during the fighting over the last 10 days almost 530 people have been killed. Among the dead are 11 civilians, of which at least five are children.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Israel informed of the death of one soldier and 30 more injured in the ground attack.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Israel has stopped foreign reporters from entering Gaza to cover army action.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Elected Vice President Joseph Biden has Reached Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Foreign Minister received American elected Vice President.</seg>
    <seg id="3">American elected vice president, Joseph Biden has reached Islamabad on his trip to Pakistan with his delegation on Friday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Foreign minister Shah Mehmood Qureshi and American Embassy officials welcomed them.</seg>
    <seg id="5">American senator Lindsy Graham is also with Biden in this tour.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Press officer of American embassy, Lu Finter has told Voice of America that the newly elected president will talk about different regional issues with Pakistan government in his tour. Although he refrained from giving more details.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the sources of foreign office, Joseph Biden will also meet Army chief General Ashfaq Parvez Kiyani besides other high government officials.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is expected that during these meetings, war against terrorism will also be discussed besides important bilateral and international issues.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Joseph Biden was awarded Hilal-e-Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After arriving in Islamabad, Joseph Biden met with President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="11">During the meeting, the president presented him with Hilal-e-Pakistan for playing an important role in forming close relations between Pakistan and America.</seg>
    <seg id="12">To clarify, last year, Joseph Biden and Senator Richard Lugar, chairman of Foreign Affair committee, drafted a Bill, increasing America's foreign army provision in Pakistan by 3% to a total of 5.7 billion dollars over the next 5 years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Prime Minister Gilani: Biden facilitated the removal of President Parvez Musharaf</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Yusuf Raza Gilani and Joe Biden ( File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="3">Yusuf Raza Gilani: Joe Biden promoted democracy in Pakistan and aided in the removal of Parvez Musharaf</seg>
    <seg id="4">Yusuf Raza Gilani speaks at the Karachi shipyard press conference</seg>
    <seg id="5">Gilani: Biden supports Pakistan, drafting a bill allocating $15 billion aid for Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Prime Minister of Pakistan states no agreement with U.S. on attacks: attacks can not be permitted</seg>
    <seg id="7">He also hoped that after the succession of the new American government, change will come to the American policy as well.</seg>
    <seg id="8">(File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="9">Yusuf Raza Gilani has said that the government has successfully separated the Taliban from ordinary tribesmen but the drone attacks have proven to be very harmful to the efforts of the government, and the terrorists have once again joined forces with the local tribes.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that the international community agrees with Pakistan's stance.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The Prime Minister added that if reliable evidence is provided, then the Pakistani Forces will operate in their own territory.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Gilani repeated his stance over Mumbai attacks and said that if India provides evidence, then an investigation will be held. If there is any proof of someone's involvement, he will be dealt according to the laws of the country.</seg>
    <seg id="13">While answering a question about Rehman Malik's tour to Britain and his meeting with the MQM leader Altaf Hussain, the Prime Minister stated that Rehman Malik went to London on his approval.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Quetta, four policemen including DSP killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">File Photo</seg>
    <seg id="3">On the Saryab road in Quetta four policemen were killed by unknown gunmen, including the Deputy Superintendent of Police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">On Monday morning a jeep carrying two DSP's and one Sub Inspector and two constables was traveling toward's the police training center when two people sitting on a motorcycle near the degree college on Siryaab road started firing at them without any provocation Resulting in the death of Sub Inspector Mehdi.Constable Sibghatullah and Nasrullah died on the spot.While DSP Hasan Ali died upon reaching the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hospital sources say that the other injured DSP Ghulam Muhammad's situation is also critical and he has been shot in the neck and the head.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After the incident the police have surrounded the area but as of yet no one has accepted responsibility for the incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The death of another Indian software engineer in America.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Another software engineer belonging to Andhra Pradesh has been shot and killed by unknown attacker's.</seg>
    <seg id="3">26 year old Akshay Vishal of Secunderanadwas shot two day's ago by unidentified assailant's in the state of Arkansas. Vishal died in the hospital while undergoing treatment two day's later.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was an employee of Satyam Computer's and was providing servicess for Falcon Jet Airways in America.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In the last one year seven students from Andhra Pradesh have been killed by American anti-social element's.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The rise in the death's of those going to America for higher study's and employment from the state has increased the worries of the thousand's of family's whose children are in America.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It should be known that America is preferred in Andhra Pradesh for higher studies and brighter future's.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to statistics from the American consulate in Chennai, one hundred thousand applications are received for visas every year, of which the most (40%) are from Andhra Pradesh.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Meanwhile, the state government attempted to bring the victim's body to Hyderabad.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bush: America Should Be Vigilant for Enemy Attacks</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In President George W. Bush's final radio annoucement,  Mr. Bush warned America to remain wary of enemy attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Bush said that the biggest threat to Americans is still the possibility of another terrorist attack. He stated that the enemies of the country are patiently waiting, and that they are bent on attacking again.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The outgoing president said that America would definitely have to be aware of its safety at all times.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush also expressed his best wishes for the new president, Barack Obama, who would be taking the oath of office on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In a radio broadcast on behalf of the Democratic party on Saturday, newly elected president Barack Obama spoke on the historical importance of the oath taking ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that the oath taking was a custom by which the power is handed over to another leader peacefully and has a deep connection with American greatness.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mister Obama reminded the audience that around the world, many cultures can not even imagine the succession of a leader without blood and turbulence.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Meeting of the Sherif brothers and the joint home minister in Raiwand to exchange thoughts on political and security matters.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Pakistan Muslim Leagues (n)'s leader Nawaz Sherif and Pakistan's home minister Rehman Malik met on Sunday in Raiwand in which Punjabi Chief Minister Shehbaz Sherif was also present.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the local media, Rehman Malik probably got an important message from the Pakistan Peoples Party leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, speaking to journalists after the meeting, Rehman Malik did not disclose anything of the nature and only said that they talked about agreement politics and that he briefed the PML(n) leadership about the conditions after the Mumbai attack.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words "I let them know about the action taken so far".</seg>
    <seg id="6">It should not be forgotten that a lot of action was taken by the Punjab government and that the team that I formed will need the help of the Punjab government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Rehman Malik said that every day the media is not told but PML (n) leadership is sent messages. Here the Pakistan Muslim League (n) spokesperson Pervez Rasheed also spoke but avoided speaking about political matters and said that Rehman Malik has already said what needs to be told.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be known that Pakistan Muslim League (n)'s leadership met the Internal Advisor at a time when the state was in a state of hot political activity with 20 or more leaders belonging to the opposition party. PML (q) held a press conference with the Governor of Punjab, Salman Taseer, rejecting the steps of the government in the state and opposing the inclusion of the Governor of Punjab, who is from the Pakistan Peoples Party in this matter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama's Speech Is Glad Tidings For Pakistan's President Zardari.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani president, Asif Ali Zardari welcomed the opening speech of the new President of America Barack Obama, saying that his statement that he would advance the relationship with the Muslim world, based on mutual interests and mutual respect, is good news for Pakistan and it's public.</seg>
    <seg id="3">in a statement issued on Wednesday, he said that reiteration of high moralities and values from the American president is a hope for a better future for the people of the world.</seg>
    <seg id="4">president Zardari stated that there is no doubt that there is a great pressure on America to join the world community to find ways of peace, prosperity and complacency.</seg>
    <seg id="5">it should be clear that president Obama after taking the oath for his designation said on Tuesday in his opening speech that  America wants development in relations with the Islamic world which should be based on mutual benefits and respect for each other.</seg>
    <seg id="6">he told the people of poor countries that America will work with them so that there is social development and reduction poverty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Obama nominated a chose representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">former ambassador for United Nations Richard Holbrooke has been nominated as a special representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Holbrooke played a vital role in peace agreements in Bosnia Herzegovina.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Holbrooke said that he is ready to be an advisor to president Obama on Afghanistan and Pakistan issues.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He clearly said that this is not an easy task.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that both countries have entirely different history.</seg>
    <seg id="7">George Mitchell has been selected for the Middle East, and will try to maintain conferences held between Arab and Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mitchell is the erstwhile Senator that played his role to bring peace in Northern Ireland.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Mitchell said today while speaking in the State Department, that the Middle East's current condition is very unstable, complicated and dangerous.</seg>
    <seg id="10">But still, America will not stay back in the struggle to bring peace over there.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghanistan: Voter Registration Is In Peril.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Afghanistan's election commission has said that due to the sake of peace, it is delaying the voter registration process in a few southern areas.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Voter registration for upcoming Presidential Election in Southern Afghanistan started this week.</seg>
    <seg id="4">But commission has said that until the betterment of the situation of security, voters from a few areas of the state Helmand will not be able to get registered.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The rate of violence has been increased since last year in those southern areas where Taliban rebels have increased their attacks on Afghan Forces and International Forces.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In the meanwhile, Afghan Forces and International Forces have said that in the middle of the night of Wednesday and Thursday, during the fire exchange held in whole Afghanistan, they have killed at least 28 militants.</seg>
    <seg id="7">NATO has said that their military has destroyed the military and weapons near the east border of Pakistan with the help of the Airforce and Ground Military.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Before this, the external affair minister said that, in this district the Afghan military has destroyed the eight enemies and injured two.</seg>
    <seg id="9">This has explained briefly that the position in Afghan gives a hint about this situation.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090123.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Blast in Wazeeristhan caused by missiles, approximately 18 killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakitani Intelligence Claims that the twin missiles in the north Wazeeristan has killed 18 people.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Based on the report, the Airfoce of America has dropped three missiles on a home near the village of Meerali in North Wazeerisathan, where 10 people were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Based on the report, the people who were killed in which 5 people are the militaries from the other countries</seg>
    <seg id="5">The place was considered to be the main place of the Taliban and Al quaida.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Some time after this incident, on north Wazeeristan, they deployed a missile. Eight people were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Even after the Pakistan government's negotiation in the last year, there were nearly 30 missiles launched in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In America, the recent attacks are the first attacks which took place after President Barack Obama became the President.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The Bush organization was obligating on refusing or accepting the responsibility of these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="10">On Friday, three missiles were thrown from an American spy aircraft on the outskirt areas of Waziristan of which five people were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It was not possible to identify those who were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="12">First news was that these missile attacks were in the Meer Ali area.</seg>
    <seg id="13">This missile attack was the first attack on the outskirts of Pakistan after Barack Obama became the President of America.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Border District Government has Refused the Request of Stopping the Girls from Education in Swat.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Border District Government in Swat has, on behalf of Taliban fighters, refused the threat of stopping the girls from education by saying that, this announcement is against the law and Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On Sunday, the Education Minister of the Border District, Sardar Hussain Babar has added saying that; the government will never allow these obligations to succeed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He says that those who like destruction are trying to deprive the children of our area from education.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to him these people tried to destroy the schools by threatening the children going to school.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said - mentioning the atmosphere of fear - that provincial government knows about it and wants to prove that no power can stop Pakhtoon from increasing education.</seg>
    <seg id="7">One day before Fighter Taliban desired in Swat from 15 January to stop education in education centres and this was in the leading of miss leader Molana Fazl-u-Rrahman and threat that those education centres will be bombed which against our desire.</seg>
    <seg id="8">With the use of military force the Taliban has fired more than 150 educations institutions.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Thousands of boys and girls were unable to go school due to the destruction of education centers.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Heavy Security Planned for India Democratic Day</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The 60th anniversary of Democratic Day is being celebrated in India with extra security planned, including a large number of military personnel.</seg>
    <seg id="3">There was a military parade in the Govt house of Dahle with weapons, airplanes, and other military instruments shown.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Commanders said that high alert helicopters were specified for security at the event, with police watching the streets, while Obama congratulated India.</seg>
    <seg id="5">And Indian prime minister Man Mohan Sanghjan had heart surgery and sent a message that he would be recovering soon.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It should be remembered that yesterday the Indian police claimed to have killed two suspected Pakistani militants after a shootout in the outskirts of New Delhi.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Local officials say that the police recovered AK 47 rifles, granades, and some documents.  These documents proved that the attackers were from Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Police are also investigating whether these two belonged to Pakistani debarred organization, Lashkar-e-Taiba, which was found guilty in the Mumbai attacks carried out in Bombay, November of last year.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tea: an Effective Cure for Breast Cancer</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a new research, three cups of tea a day</seg>
    <seg id="3">if taken, can decrease the risk of cancer in women below 50 years of age by more than a third.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In research carried out by the Moffitt Cancer Institute, in the American state of Florida, it was revealed that the risk of occurrence of breast cancer tumors in women below the age of 50 years</seg>
    <seg id="5">who drink at least three cups of tea a day is reduced by up to 37%.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It was also revealed in the research that there was no significant benefit, in the woman over the age of 50, who drank three or more cups of tea a day.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Experts believe that the reason for this is that tea has ingredients in it, which are more effective against specific tumors which generally occur in women below the age of 50.</seg>
    <seg id="8">in the Moft Cancer Center situated in the State of Florida, research was carried out with 5,000 women, aged 20 to 70 years old, who had received treatment for breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="9"></seg>
    <seg id="10">the experts compared their medical records and life patterns with that of women who were free from breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">the experts also found, that, in cases of Lobular cancer, tea had shown a great effect and it reduced by 66 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="12">almost 1/10th breast cancer patients suffers from this type.</seg>
    <seg id="13">This type of cancer is more dangerous because it originates deep inside the breast tissue, and is usually diagnosed when it has already spread to a great extent.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Experts state that, by drinking at least three cups of tea a day, the danger of breast cancer can be reduced in young women.</seg>
    <seg id="15">they further state that making tea a regular drink in daily life can cause great resistance in the body against breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="16">in Britain, every year, almost 40 thousand women are diagnosed with breast cancer.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Gates: Afghan war is the greatest challenge faced by America.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">American Defense Minister Robert Gates said that the war in Afghanistan is the biggest challenge to America in terms of military challenges.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Today Gates was briefing the senate and the house of representatives of the strategy adopted by the Obama administration on the Afghan, and Iraq war.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Gates told the senate's Armed Services Committee that only war is not the solution to the problems in Afghanistan but he further added to make many areas safer. The amount of troops is far less than is a need and Taliban are making use of this weakness and conducting their operations.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Why the reduction of exercise with increasing age?</seg>
     <seg id="2">New research.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="3">Exercise is good at every age to remain healthy.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It makes your heart stronger, reduced Cholesterol levels, helps control weight, helps in limiting Diabetes and slows the Alzheimer's process.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Unfortunately, with many people with increasing age reduces the ability to exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Experts says with exercise our body and brain remains alert yet aging can affect it.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to American Medical Association if exercise is excluded from daily life there can be many health problems that can develop in the future.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Dr. Patricia P. Leka of Mayo Clinic, Minnesota says that increase in age is a big reason for health problems caused by exercise and less physical activity.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Dr. Patricia teaches medicine at Mayo clinic.</seg>
    <seg id="10">She headed a research trial regarding heart diseases and the ability to participate in exercise in older age.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Her team of doctors used high frequency sound waves to observe the performance of heart.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The heart's ability to pump blood along with its contraction and relaxation was studied.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Researchers focused their attention on the right side of the heart, which is the main part of the heart responsible for pumping blood through the body.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They came to know that as age increases, problems in the heart's relaxation ability also increase.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Dr. Patricia says as individuals age, problems occur in the relaxation of heart which affects the ability to exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Dr. Garvin Ken was part of the research team.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He says that we were surprised to see age has an effect on the relaxation of the heart and it confirmed that bad exercising ability is very much related to the heart's relaxation ability.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Sometimes blood pressure can cause disorders in the heart's function as well as heart disease.</seg>
    <seg id="19">If closely monitored by their doctor,  the patient can benefit from exercise regardless of age.</seg>
    <seg id="20">A detailed report concerning this matter is published in a magazine of American Medical Association.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Indian Army Chief says   "No Chance of Immediate War with Pakistan"</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Indian Army Chief General Deepak Kapoor has said that there is no chance of an immediate war with Pakistan, but that India is always ready to defend our country and sacrifice our lives for it.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He has stated that despite the commitments and international pressure on Pakistan as a result of the attacks in Mumbai, the infrastructure of terrorism not only exists but is also proactive in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said this while talking to correspondents in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Indian Army Chief was on a one day tour of the valley of Kashmir in order to analyze both the overall security situation in New Delhi administered Kashmir and the preparation of armed forces on the borders.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He was asked his thoughts on media reports that Pakistan has rejected the evidence provided from India regarding the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="7">General Kapoor said that decisions in matters of peace or war are made by the political leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mentioning the proven presence of a terrorism structure in Pakistan, he said that the Indian army would face such groups which were trying to disturb peace and were bent upon weakening India.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He said that in Indian Kashmir, at least 700 to 800 militants were present, of which approximately half were foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="10">General Deepak Kapoor said that with an improvement in the seasonal weather, there might be an increase in infiltration from Pakistan and Pakistan Occupied Kashmir. However, India has increased the guard at the borders.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He refuted the possibility of decrease in the army posting in Kashmir, saying that there can be no compromise with regards to national security.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah bless the tongues of the world and may Barack become a blessing for the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Though it was not expected, still we shall see how this change  will work out in our favor with regards to Pak-American relations.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And what does Barack Obama, who is the result of Martin Luther Kings dreams, give to the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Obama, part of whose name is Husain, taking the oath today, as the American President, is not only a matter of all sorts of historic importance, but also a historic test.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Not only for himself, but also for all the people who supported him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It will even be a test for the white majority, as for them to accept from their hearts, a black governing over them is no easy task.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here in South Asia, people, especially Muslims who have some high expectations of Obama, should remember that Obama has been elected the president of America. Obama should also remember that America is the the most powerful nation in the world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After so long, a person whose ancestors were slaves and bought from different regions of the world, is going to become the 44th president of America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have many expectations of this man.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But Obama's fans should not expect something unrealistic from him.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If he becomes successful in decreasing the religious and racial acrimony, it will be a victory for his fans.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">How South Asia will be affected by this change, and can there be any meaningful change in American policies?</seg>
     <seg id="2">How will Pakistan and America's relationship be affected by this change?</seg>
     <seg id="3">image not available</seg>
     <seg id="4">Obama's presence (or others') does not matter because the strong Jewish lobby is the real authority, and decides the policy and types of relations with other countries.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As Pakistan is concerned, the world saw how aggressive the  behavior was by the America, India and Israel triangle after the attacks in Mumbai.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even for a while, after Pakistan was formed, the managing of Swat was left to the Ruler of Swat, who had his own army and law.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They surrendered their rule to the government of Pakistan, according to a treaty.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But it's sad that our governments have treated Swat like a step mother.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There has been no increase in the number of schools in Swat, since the rule of the Ruler of Swat has come to an end.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Nor was there any interest in the construction and development over there.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The number of girls receiving education in the present rule is a lot less than their number in the previous rule.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Sarhad state of Pakistan, the local Taliban have been targeting the educational institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The most schools were destroyed in Swat province, of which the majority were the girls schools.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Not only this, but the Taliban have announced the prohibition of girls education in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thousands of boy's and girl's are being deprived of education.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you think the Taliban have to gain by eradicating female education?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Why has the government been unsuccessful in stopping these illegal steps?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you think the government should do?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The question should be, what do the ISI and Pakistani agencies get?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Because the people of Swat have realized this was a game and that the army was there to serve the Taliban and not to kill them. Otherwise, how could five schools be blown up in a single curfew night? How could people be slaughtered during curfew and hung in the center of the town?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When the government is not being allowed to have any say in Swat, how can the government be successful in stopping these illegal steps?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, the question arises as to how, when the government has an armed military, new and dangerous weapons, new technology and spy system etc., these four Taliban elements are not being controlled?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The answer to this is that they have the hand of a hidden guide on their heads, because of which neither their weapons get exhausted nor do they get captured.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The conclusion is that the Taliban, through their dark activities, are making the work of the global leadership easier.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fifteen years ago, the war was on in Afghanistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The ISI was controlling the Taliban while on the opposing side the Northern Coalition was being aided by Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Then suddenly the scenario changed and the activities of the Taliban came to light.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The ISI also was offered financial aid by the Americans which resulted in past friends becoming foes.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now the scenario is that the war is still raging but the supporters in Pakistan are still the same, Iran, India and Russia.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Until mankind can understand the difference between whats right and whats wrong he will always make the wrong decision.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For example, if a thief goes to perform a crime but just before he commits it he realizes that its a wrong thing to do and that robbing is a sin and that it is punishable, if he fears his Lord he will then not commit the crime.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Similarly, unless and until Israel understands that it is doing the wrong thing by shedding the blood of innocent people in Gaza and that it will be punished, it will continue to kill innocent people there.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Greetings!</seg>
     <seg id="2">The question is whether war and aggression are the answers to the terrorist issue.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If not, then what is the solution?</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is true, that war and extremism do not solve problems, but rather it puts 'blessings' in them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Palestine, Afghanistan and Iraq should adopt the same model for their development that Nelson Mandela had used in South Africa.</seg>
     <seg id="6">That is, to struggle character wise and politically, more than in an armed manner.</seg>
     <seg id="7">From the Kashmiris taking part in the elections, it looks as if they have accepted this view point.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the third week of Israel's attacks on Gaza and the number of deaths have gone close to a thousand.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Despite worldwide diplomatic efforts, to date, a ceasefire was not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">According to another report, since the start of attacks on the 27th of December, 90,000 Palestinians have left their homes and moved towards safer locations.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here, aid groups have accused Israel of being careless about Palestinian children, and said that a whole generation of Palestinian children will be victim of grave psychological and emotional difficulties.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What should happen?</seg>
     <seg id="7">How is permanent peace possible in Gaza?</seg>
     <seg id="8">For details, click here.</seg>
     <seg id="9">(Please note that due to the increase in discussions, only comments typed in Urdu will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="10">For this press alt+shift on the On-Screen board and select Urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Give the Taliban a Chance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Basit, Peshawar</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wake up! If Taliban starts the real Jihad, who will slaughter innocent people?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Who will burn down the girls schools?</seg>
     <seg id="5">They will be kidnapping for ransom and if they do not get the ransom money, who will hang people on poles, claiming they were American spies?</seg>
     <seg id="6">The Taliban has damaged Islam so much that no other nation or religion has done in the past.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pushtun force</seg>
     <seg id="8">Kohat, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If the entire Muslim world gets together and even just threatens Israel, you will see how much Israel's daddy, America, will get hurt.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And not only will there be immediate talks of ceasefire, there will also be an actual ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But what can be done, where can our leaders get so much courage?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Someone should tell Ahmedinejad that he should take the lead, as BBC forum's are full of discussion of his bravery.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The responsibility for establishing peace and human rights falls not only upon the Arabs or the Muslims of the world, but rather it is the duty of all the nations in the world to speak up against oppression.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This troubling incident is one of the worst misdeeds of Bush to date.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Similar to how, in Pakistan and India, on the 30th of June, just before the close of the financial year, the government institutions are similarly looted. Before the winding up of the American government, Israel would be given the green signal to do whatever it wants.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">On one hand, America says that it will try for a ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, United Nations is passing resolution after resolution but practically both had been futile. This only concludes one idea that to oppress Muslims, the United Nations is also a party to the Muslim oppression.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All Muslim countries should immediately revoke their United Nations membership and lay foundation for a united Muslim Union.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There are many evident examples in front of us, in which America and the United Nations only promise and pass resolutions. It is the Muslims in the end who suffer.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What is the use of such propaganda when BBC does not publish the matter?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, where are all the ideals of journalism buried? When unjustified spillage of Muslim blood occurs, BBC takes a neutral position of not being a side to any party.</seg>
     <seg id="3">by the way is a flag bearer of rights</seg>
     <seg id="4">to raise voice is a far reality, the limit of hypocrisy is that it doesn't even publish the views</seg>
     <seg id="5">from the Muslim side</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The only difference in you and the Jews is that the latter call themselves Jews, they martyr Muslims and live amongst Muslims like you they call themselves Muslims</seg>
     <seg id="2">syja786</seg>
     <seg id="3">A recent trend in BBC forums has been the subject of terrorism of India, and the subject sometimes arises while discussing suicide attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">These anti-Islamic comments often use the term extremism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But the real extremist is the person who made the above comment.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When will Muslims understand that Dajjal can not be fought with the sword?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Looking at the helpless people facing the Israel bombings, if the heart does not cry, what does it do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The most basic mistake behind this destruction and killing is that using the name of Jihad disfigures the beautiful face of Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When a majority of the Palestinians have accepted the existence of Israel, what need does Hamas have to send rockets into Israel or conduct suicide attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">The conduct of both sides is misanthropic.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The action of the United Nations and the United States seem to support the wrongdoings of Israel.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah allow the Muslim nation to unite. Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And we should think about giving the real terrorists an anti-terrorism Nobel prize for their painstaking efforts against terrorism, as after all, they are doing the real work.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise, would it be possible for terrorism to take place on such a large scale without the support of some big leader? And everyone knows who is controlling the strings.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In easy words, such gangsters are told to do whatever they want.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What a forceful act, hit on the head, and do not allow to cry.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The medicines for the injured, the shroud and compensation for  the dead are being given by the Arab rulers, and the question is,</seg>
     <seg id="2">what should happenabout the israeli attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The actual problem is that the leaders of all the Muslim countries, including the Saudi king, are in a deep sleep. They neither have an army nor any protective plans. They think they can support and fulfill their responsibility.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They should take immediate action against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="5">such as stopping the sale of petrol to Europe and America, but unfortunately...</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salams to all sisters and brothers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I believe that in this time of difficulty, telling Hamas to stop their struggle for the sake of peace is an injustice to thousands of widows and hundreds of thousands orphans, and it is similar to considering them defeated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If Israel and its supporters are at the height of their Pharoahism, soon Moses will be born within their house, as this is the rule of nature. The steps taken by America and Israel have acted like a fertilizer in growing suicide bombers among the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Which these power intoxicated elephants are not realizing.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Abu Abdullah, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Israel and Hamas should enter a truce so that the death and destruction can come to an end.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Mohammad Sarfaraz, Paris, France</seg>
     <seg id="3">Absolutely correctly stated</seg>
     <seg id="4">Supposing that Hamas is 100% on the truth, and they are struggling against oppression, to become successful in the eyes of Allah. Even then, they should know that if a good deed is resulting in the destruction of an established house, it is no more a good deed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Those who claim to love God, love the messenger and love their religion. Loving mankind is a part of their faith.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As if it is the order of Allah to evacuate all the people of the Book from the face of the earth, other than the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeebur Rahman Syco, Lahore</seg>
     <seg id="3">The order is not to kill them but to invite them to Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Towards those people who plan against the religion, there is the order to perform Jihad against them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">To fight them until they stop their plans, but this does definitely not mean that you wear a jacket and blow up in a crowd.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The end result of killing innocent children is destruction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But I would like to tell my friends that yesterday the Israelis did not have any place for shelter. Today, they have become so strong that they do not listen to anyone. This is because the Jews are one.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They do not have Shia or Sunni. They are all just Jews, and they have made everything for development.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What is the state of the 55 Islamic countries?</seg>
     <seg id="5">They are behind in every field, and now the situation is that they have become so helpless that the enemy is killing them and they are waiting to die.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The need is for all the Muslim countries to get together and prepare an action plan against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What about Feroz Magsi, Jhang and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Is there no better course of action than accepting Israel to learn new technology and ways of success and let the world live in peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">While Muslims have great land and resources.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The need should be to develop new ways of correct usage.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First of all, the most tragic part is that Hammas and Alfatah could not be united.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The only reason to destroy great leaders like Yasir Arafat and Sheikh Yasin was to weaken the only nation fighting for Aqsa Mosque. It was impossible until Yasir and Yasin were removed out of the way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The world is watching how Palestine was falling down every second after the death of these two leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">While the lobby of jews strengthened their target by every moment.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In 1974, a Pakistani Prime minister was in such world power that he led all the muslim leaders under one roof with 100% attendance for the first time history.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today on his 81st birthday it is still hard for this nation to make a promise on whether it will unite itself or not.</seg>
     <seg id="3">By resolving Muslims conflicts, the Islamic Commonwealth Establishment will give plunge to its uncompleted mission.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">this is that jinn which lap to Palestinian since more than half century</seg>
     <seg id="2">this jinn have many face.</seg>
     <seg id="3">many time this jinn on his some other face give a bad remarks for his own self to turn back worlds pressure and concentration.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and this jinn other face eating peoples in Iraq, Afghanistan, Iran and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">and this jinn have a big fear of Islam, as this jinn knows that when ever he pull out this only and only by Islam Muslims and Muslims complete religion and act of Islam pull out because history said that Islam put on right track many biggest Abujahal.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Israels fighter jets start bombarding on Gaza and launched missile attacks on the 27th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In this attack, more than three hundred residents have died.</seg>
     <seg id="3">After the air attack, Israeli tanks and bulletproof vehicles are prepared for war and have reached the Gaza boundary.</seg>
     <seg id="4">United Nations Security Council, on its emergency gathering, agreed to a  statement asking for immediate stop of violent activities from Israel and Palestine.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Although Israel officials said that it will continue its action in Gaza until they believe that the rocket attacks end on Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What is your suggestion about Israel, is it right, this action is trying to defend stability of Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is the international world doing its part in this scenario?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Does this intense action link to Israels upcoming next election?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is American newly elected president, Barack Obama, after he takes his position would there be any improvement in the middle east?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Kindly note down that due to increase in the number of comments only Urdu suggestions will publish.</seg>
     <seg id="11">For that press alt+shift on the onscreen keyboard to select Urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Palestine is the holiest place for Muslims untill the end of the world and its safety is our necessary part.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We have to remember that this is our first Qiblah.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel, India, and America would have to finish. Because this country exists for breaking up, soon God definitely will give them doom Sajid, Sadiq, and Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="4">"When has the night of loneliness been spent shedding tears, when has a calamity been averted only by supplication." (Nawab Zadah Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
     <seg id="5">"When has the night of loneliness been spent shedding tears, when has a calamity been averted only by supplication." (Nawab Zadah Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC searches for such comments and publishes them.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After all it has to keep up the flag and perception of non-alignment.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As such, the news on BBC is usually true, but the main thing is the tone.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Which thing should be highlighted and which piece of news should be given less importance?</seg>
     <seg id="5">etc. etc.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="7">In this practice, our Pakistani Wire-net media, in particular some columnists and newspapers are not far behind any more, as they are writing with courage against the growing extremism and terrorism and stressing a lot upon "Muawiyah hate".</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">He said that the United Nations speaks of human rights and peace, but though the Muslims ar being oppressed greatly, you hear them say that until Hamas does not stop its attacks, this unfair policy will continue.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why Muslims are getting abused, if country like America will leave the back support of Jews then Allah has said clearly that this caste will spend there life contemptible and this caste can not spend there life good,  if American Citizens have the guts to leave the back support of Jews then see the fortune of the life of Jews</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The People who are killing and murdering the people on the name of peace and justice they have to understand clearly that in this world peace will come only and only by administer an Oath of not doing injustice and dissemination</seg>
     <seg id="2">If only by doing dissemination you can kill the caste and want to withdraw the results what you want, then after Hitlers measure not only the Jews caste was continued but in one way the ascent as today was impossible</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the Words of Poet</seg>
     <seg id="4">Abuse is again an abuse if its get higher it will be erased</seg>
     <seg id="5">Blood is again a Blood if it falls down it will Freeze</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now who will say to whom that what is Terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why all this does not come under Terrorism, why only our pain seems to be like every ones pain</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are other people not human beings or only Muslims blood has become so cheap, isn't blood of an innocent not red in color?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now from any where why the condolence message is not coming?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I watched the progress of the Mumbai incident, as if my own house was on fire. The sorrow of humans can not be watched, and who can not see this sorrow? If only Muslims would think a bit, together.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">How can words derogate the bodies strewn on the streets, helpless innocent faced people, injured and soaked in blood?</seg>
     <seg id="2">I feel like crying about the helplessness of Muslims, that on one side, people are dying in India, and the whole world is climbing onto Pakistan, without any proof and saying, take action or else we will.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And on the other side, Israel is ruthlessly killing Muslims and the whole world is silent. This is unbearable.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is delay, but no darkness, with God. That too, when this darkness comes to pass.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Danger to Israel, with America present, is a joke.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As for elections, there is no doubt, to gain public support, such actions will have to be taken for the sake of power, especially in a state like Israel. As for Barack Obama, history is witness that no American ruler has been able to go against the American policy and nor will they go. Whether the ruler is white or black, he is still a ruler.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">From the discussions going on in the forum, it seems that everyone is hurt over her death, but as a politician, her mistakes have not been ignored.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This issue is debatable, as to whether Benazir gave her life for democracy or for power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If democracy was dearer, why did she leave the republic for ten years in the control of Musharraf, waiting for American clearance and deal?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir did not come to Pakistan when the people needed her the most.  Unfortunately, she came to Pakistan when she had to deal with cases and was promised a seat of power.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The blames that are being laid down on historical figures are not being addressed by anyone.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="3">As some things are over-looked, under these circumstances, nothing can be done.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is one more Kari.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Ladies and gentlemen, maybe due to studying the history, in not only Pakistan, but its four friend-nations and seven other nations, you find the arguments of Mr Psycho more appealing.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tariq Ayyaz</seg>
     <seg id="7">Those who don't deserve such education shouldn't get it either.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The reflection of the pine in water never got to be green.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Britain never allowed the two to be united and always came up with a new Hindu-Muslim conflict which was looked after by Sir Syed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Psycho</seg>
     <seg id="3">How merciless is our nation? We are blind when writing in favor of ourselves and our party, but now when every historical intellectual is being blamed and critiqued, no one is saying a word.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We have succeeded a lot!</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="6">Some things are ignored, thinking that nothing can be done about them. Just like a donkey does not become a scholar if you en wreathe him with books.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Although the ongoing talks between Pakistan and India were interrupted after the Bombay attacks, Pakistan and India should continue these meetings.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If they talk about war, then both sides will suffer human loss.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India says that a Pakistani citizen is caught in Bombay attacks. He has written and sent a letter in Urdu to Pakistan. But earlier, when India caught this extremist, said that he is a smart engineer, but later they declared him to have studied only four grades. This is what has to be considered.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First of all, merry Christmas to Mr. Bhana and  all Christian friends of the forum.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Friends of the forum: Greetings Mr. Psycho, A. Raza, Sister Sana, Sister Shahida Akram and all.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Instead of the flames of fire, we want the flowers of peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">War itself is a problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Does war solve problems?</seg>
     <seg id="6">It will bless with fire and blood.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It will cause hunger and desperation.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Therefore, wise people,</seg>
     <seg id="9">it's better to avoid war,</seg>
     <seg id="10">in our own backyards.</seg>
     <seg id="11">its better that the glim keeps lightened</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Indian and American relations have deepened, and India knows, when the time comes, America will openly betray Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is that the old history of America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because in the case of an Indian attack, America's goals will also be fulfilled but the expenses will be India's.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan should clearly announce that it will not start a war, but if injury is caused, there will be no talks of peace or truce, and the war will not stop until India is completely destroyed or captured, even if it involves our own destruction.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is Islamic history.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Before the resolution, the message that had to be given by the public and the army was given.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The disproportionate diplomatic and military concessions that India sought as compensation for the Mumbai attacks made it seem more a victimizer than a victim. As a result, the world has now reduced their pressure on Pakistan relative to the initially harsh global response.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Both the satisfaction expressed by the United Nations and the praise of the leader of Interpol for Pakistani efforts, irregardless of India's objections, show the side effects of India's excessive diplomacy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There are no two opinions about this being a very beastly action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But the question is, when thousands of Taliban were attacking Pir Samiullah's town, where was the Pakistani Army, and what were they doing?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Should the army not held accountable for what they did there for one year?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Every day, how many Taliban die due to the firing of the thousands of mortar and canon shells?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I appeal to the ICI that they stop their guardianship of the Taliban, for Gods sake, and let us live peacefully in paradise like Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And they stop this fixed operation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The day is not far, when a resolution will be passed in the United Nations against army intervention in Pakistan, in the same way in which it was passed against Jama'athud-Da'wah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Riyaz Ahmad Farooqi</seg>
     <seg id="3">First of all, our radicalism and our protection of them, is sufficient alone to provide complete proof and permissibility for action against us. And the very day such a resolution is passed, there is all probability that, in the United Nations, no voice will be raised in our support.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Supposing the passing of such a resolution is delayed, some other strength will definitely leave our aid to ourself,, keeping the example of America in front of them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We do not know about the personality and works of Pir Samiullah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Perhaps he was not a revolutionist.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As the bodies of Comrade Che Guevara, Nawab Akbar Khan Bagti, Dr. Najibullah and thousands of other revolutionists were dishonored at the hands of the enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are alive even after being dead.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But here an international game is being played. Here ferocity and animosity is created to do the ruling.</seg>
     <seg id="6">So there is a reason created that if we are not here then these vandals and animals will come take over the government.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Activities of these so called Islam lovers, in the name of religion, is highly condemned.</seg>
     <seg id="2">America sees the torture of these extremists but instead of being sad for these faithless activities, it easily labels them as tribal culture.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The reason for these faithless activities is sometimes explained in the name of tribal culture and other times in the name of Islam. These activities cannot not be done by a person with a heart.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, people of our army are with these people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">That is because when they change destination, it takes time. But to catch them, forget about getting there on time, even when they are on the spot they escape.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are they so clever that they keep 50-70 people hostage and our army just watches it as spectators?</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are also men of God and so is our army.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is very clear that there is something fishy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Instead of promoting God's blessing and merciful nature, discussing various disastrous and lesson-gaining occurrences to create an air of fear and terror in the name of religion was being seen. Besides the event of hanging the dead body, their literature and books like "What Will Happen After Death" also create fear and terror.</seg>
     <seg id="2">These people are using this fear and terror as a shield for the purpose of obtaining world power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wiso!</seg>
     <seg id="4">You have scared the world with the fire of hell.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You, yourself, have become the reason for fear.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It comes as a surprise when it is said that this was not done by a Muslim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We are either unaware of our history or we choose to not know about it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who burned the closed door of the Prophet's daughter on the refusal of the oath after the Prophet passed away and who took her husband by the rope around his neck?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Did they come from abroad?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Was the attack on Medina by the the Army of Yazid and and the incident of Karbala the conspiracy of Jews and Pagans?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Without accepting the facts, neither motive can be removed nor can they be corrected.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC people, stop this dual policy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A better super hit title is:  The beating of Bush with shoes, right or wrong?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This should have been the topic.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Tahir Chowdhry, Japan</seg>
     <seg id="5">Be ashamed, the body of a person was taken out of the grave and hung on a pole because he spoke against the cruelty and you are more concerned about the Box Office.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The success of operation Sherdil and across the border the success of operation Lion Heart depends on the direction of the sympathies of the common folk.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pir Sahib is the victim of a conspiracy between American and Pakistani intelligence agencies.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the comments on this forum would be against the Taliban because intelligence agents have successfully infiltrated the Taliban ranks and they are carrying out actions that can change the perception of the people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I only want to ask, when this body was hanging for a whole day, what was the army doing? Are they only there for targeting the public? They even report something like this: "Bombing of Taliban residences, a shell falling on a house kills two children and their mother".</seg>
     <seg id="2">Did they not know about this mistake?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Or were they watching the show?</seg>
     <seg id="4">We fold our hands and request them to please, for God's sake, stop this game.</seg>
     <seg id="5">After all, there is a ruler above you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Whether the question asked by BBC is understandable or not, it is saddening to see the lack of perspective of the writer. For instance, no one asked what the army of 30,000 in Swat went there to do.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The bodies of the Taliban who help the army are left hanging on poles throughout the day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Whatever the green footed Pakistani government did with the Swat public, the media, including BBC did not do good by keeping the world ignorant about the reality.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Pakistani Army is putting up a drama.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Every child in Swat is saying that this is a bloody drama.</seg>
     <seg id="6">For God's sake, stop this drama.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These Talibans have tarnished the Muslim image.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If in the whole world true Muslims don't call these terrorists Muslims, then how come these elements are able to live in the lands of true Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Those who become shameless and won't do hard labor pick up guns and become the members of terrorist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Islam did not spread on the point of a sword or barrel of a gun.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Feel the shame.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no permission for this in any religion or family traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Including the BBC, all the media present their views on the Taliban or the tribal people in different ways.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But no one is aware of the factsor what the truth is. It is us-- the tribal people-- who know what's really going on.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In short, its a game in which the CIA, RAW, MOSAD and our own ISI are invloved. No one is a talib or a tribal. Who made these institutions? Warmongers--who are against Islam, Taliban, Madrassa's, Pushtoon people, tribes and tribal traditions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muslim heads hung from shame over this action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I salute the leader of MQM, Althaf Husain, and the leaderships of ANP and PPP, as they have spoken against this cancer, i.e. the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This cancer was given birth to by Zia-ul-Haqq. He has gone, but he has destroyed Pakistan as he went.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But I have hope that the present government will eradicate this cancer.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the Mumbai attacks, India had said that there was the hand of some Pakistani extremists behind the attack.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan refuted these claims and said that it would help India to investigate in every possible way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India said that they have given Pakistan a list of the suspected extremists wanted by India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now Pakistan says that the Jaish-e-Mohammad leader, who is included in the list, Moulana Mas'ood Azhar, is not under house arrest, and that the government of Pakistan has no information about him.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Previously, the President of Pakistan, Asif Ali Zardari, had rejected the idea that western intelligence agencies and the Indian government had provided Pakistan proof about the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">President Zardari said, regarding Ajmal Kasab, that it is not yet proven that he is Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="7">At that time, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh warned Pakistan that its relationship with India would not improve as long as they continued to harbor terrorism in their land.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Furthermore, in a recent development, the Indian cricket team canceled their tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should political events affect sports?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What do you see in the future of Indo-Pakistani relations?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Neither America nor India will break Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan will break itself.</seg>
     <seg id="3">With so much regionalism, factionism and infiltration in the country, what other outcome can you expect?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Time has shown that Jinnah did not benefit the Indian Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Yasmin, Chicago</seg>
     <seg id="6">Madam, if Jinnah's manner had improved, the sicknesses of regionalism, factionism and infiltration would not have spread in Pakistan, nor would the Indian Muslims have been treated in this way.</seg>
     <seg id="7">But it is our fault that we couldnt reproduce a leader of similar stature.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If we can't respect our leaders then</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There are many able-bodied people in this part of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">God knows when any sense will return to the people and when the blessing of a consensus in overall opinion will help this area become developed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In both countries, the Mullahs, Pundits, Taliban, Shiv Sena, and the RSS etc have been established to oppose the peace process.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Destructive forces don't want this area to develop and as a result these countries are manipulated like puppets.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can you imagine with the aid of consensus between Pakistan, India and China what position they would have in the world?</seg>
     <seg id="6">It is God's punishment that has positioned thieves, robbers and manipulators as leaders of this country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May God safe guard Pakistan from any harm, Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But sir, open your eyes and look around and you will see the current situation and ground realities revealing the extent to which the American have progressed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Moreover, the internal affairs don't seem to be good, as you can see the circumstances in NWFP, Balochistan and in Karachi, in Sindh.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In this situation the country needs such a leader who can unite us as one nation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">O Allah bestow your mercy upon us.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Account to my understanding, a final war is inevitable.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is enough of it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">nNw it should be do, or die.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This problem can not be solved through these acts of insincere dialogues.</seg>
     <seg id="5">and not through small scale terrorism in each other's country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">after all, Europe got settled after the final world war.</seg>
     <seg id="7">and if this world war had not taken place, then these countries, just like Pakistan and India, would have been clattering.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Almost all of our political parties agree on this: terrorists and denominational activities should be ended in this country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But our army rulers don't seem sincere in this matter. On one hand, America and Europe thinks we are with them in this war against terrorism.  But, on the other hand, we also help secretly help the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We have to think and choose our direction now because we can only choose one way. Thank you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no doubt that the majority of the members of Jamaat-ud-Dawa are also members of Lashker-e-Tayyaba, who joined  the party named Jamaat-ud-Dawa Pakistan after Lashker-e-Tayyaba was invalidated.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Although these members only did subsidiary activities, after India's great insistence The United Nations has invalidated the group.  The government of Pakistan is also  continuing the crack down against them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, it's better if Jihadi groups leave religious extremism and continue religious and subsidiary activities.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Terrorist groups in Pakistan, support professional criminals and the heads of those are Mullahs who call Pakistan the land of destruction and what not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And now they are doing everything to destroy Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In reality, they do not even deserve to be called human beings, let alone Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Without cleaning Pakistan of these evil doers, the country's existence will be in jeopardy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can we still afford to wonder whether we should ban these mutinous people or not?</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this world of callous leaders, there is no place for those whose work is only to kill.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This news breaks my heart to pieces.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What kind of world is this where it is hard to live for one who takes the name of one major pillar of Islam,  religion of Allah.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Non-Muslims can kill Muslims but when Muslims even try to take revenge, all our hypocrite leaders together with all the non-Muslim world treat people with the true and right pain of religion just like our great leader Hafiz Saeed is being treated today.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">India in impunity of Bombay attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan relations are bitter. The better relationship as a result of last few years between the two countries have been jolted greatly.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India has always held the military and non-military groups in Pakistan responsible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And putting the relationship back on track is being conditioned by operations against these groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Indian security departments have held Lashkher-e-Tayyaba responsible for the Bombay attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Because of this the name of Jamat Ul Dawa came up many times.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This was not the first time that terrorism caused intensely bad relations between two countries.</seg>
     <seg id="8">On December 2001, after attack on the Indian Parliament, these two neighbors came to the verge of war.</seg>
     <seg id="9">After this, sanctions were imposed against Luskaray Taiba and it was included on a list of terrorist organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="10">now on Jamat UL Dawa , about which security analyst said that this is new face of Laskaray Taiba, asking for sanctions.</seg>
     <seg id="11">What is your suggestion? Should this group be sanctioned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Does Pakistan need to take action against terrorist groups on its land?</seg>
     <seg id="13">does put sanction on Jamat Ul Dawa present India</seg>
     <seg id="14">Pak crisis could resolve and for real peace in between two countries how important is that to finished groups who have weapons?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The United Nations Security Council imposed sanctions against Jamat Ul Dawa in its last session. What evidence does the Security Council have for its haste?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Public Tranquility Council will always never show this much of expertness against Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This we say as Accuser is Weak and witness is Strong!</seg>
     <seg id="4">If you see India has make it self as a Disappointed Country</seg>
     <seg id="5">To the embarrassment of the Intelligence, Military and other Security Departments, a few terrorists have made them to dance for 72 hours and now India in its mortification is blaming Pakistan for this and trying to trick the whole world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If one non-Muslim is murdered, then there is a worldwide outcry. Why this double standard?</seg>
     <seg id="2">To my dearest country's one and only nonpolitical, religious, cultural organization -----------</seg>
     <seg id="3">Furqan Farooq, Faisalabad</seg>
     <seg id="4">Till the time Prophet PBUH, Saints and the Follower has given the respect to the Human beings, With Peace the Religion Islam was advertised a lot and was going on</seg>
     <seg id="5">Muslims have excelled in every field.</seg>
     <seg id="6">When this beautiful religion came to ordinary people, then divisions arose between Muslims and non Muslims and a new era of tumults and quarrel began. Previously the world was not aware of this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Do greet them sir, but at your own expense.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Don't do it only in response to the pressures of the America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If India has any complaints, then they should provide evidence to verify their claims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why don't they do so?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Why do they blame everything on us?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Extremist groups are also present in India, why don't they put sanctions on them?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are we the only terrorists in the world?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Who can India explain its actions in Kashmir?</seg>
     <seg id="9">and what of the actions of Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The truth is that we are the first Nuclear Islamic state in the world and it is causing all the hatred.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is in its last stage.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Kamran Hassan, ABU DHABI</seg>
     <seg id="3">Your talk touches the heart and circumstances also seems to be such</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now American magazines are very boldly printing the new map of Pakistan and all of these sanctions seem to be part of this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Americans are now not slowly but very swiftly tightening their grip over Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">We must remember that in these circumstances,if we as a nation do not display unity and solidarity and if Bangladesh can be created, then anything can happen.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The more terrorism is condemned the lesser it is , whether it is in a Hotel at Mumbai, in Marriott Hotel Islamabad or in Palestine.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Likewise irrespective of the origin of the terrorist, they should be eliminated, no matter these are Pakistanis or Indian or American or Israelite.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now the question remains why the whole world, including the Pakistani officials, is silent on the terrorist attacks that are conducted daily in Pakistan, resulting in the death of hundreds of people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Was the attack carried out on Marriott Hotel not committed by terrorists?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Then why?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Praise the worthy Interior Minister Rehman Malik by the grace of God, how brave has he become!</seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">Not only this, according to the BBC Minister Malik has also tried to negate this impression with full strength that all these imprisonments are being carried out on whose orders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Praise the lord!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Having this capability or not, that I don't want to say.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whose war are we Pakistanis fighting</seg>
     <seg id="3">and why? We have our own priorities which we shall protect with our full strength.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Nobody has an authority to interfere in any other country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Apparently colonial period does not seem to exist.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If people are expecting justice, then they should empower law enforcement agencies, respect democratic institutions and refrain from aiding dictators or any military personnel. Then the Third World country Pakistan can attain peace, and that would be unacceptable for the extremist groups.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is already in favor of the European Union and America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is despite the fact that the majority of groups in Pakistan are against this favor.</seg>
     <seg id="3">So this promotes more opposition.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And if America and its allied forces should leave Pakistan and believe in democracy, then the people will start supporting the soveriegnity by stopping their protests.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan is capable of deciding the issues by either dialogues or by taking up arms.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistani forces occupying Kashmir raided one of the camps of Lashkar-e-Tayyaba.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After the Mumbai attacks, there is pressure on Pakistan to increase the operation against extremist organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India claims that Lashkar-e-Tayyaba was involved in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
     <seg id="5">It is their claim that without a doubt, the extremists who carried out the Mumbai attacks used Pakistani land.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Meanwhile, officials in Peshawar claim that the lot of trucks which carry supplies to the united forces in Afghanistan was burned by unidentified armed people, because of which more than 50 trucks were destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the second attack in Peshawar on NATO and American supplies in the last 48 hours.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Meanwhile, Pakistan captured an established camp of the almost non-existent Lashkar-e-Taiba. Previously, lots of efforts were carried out to try to disarm groups all the way from Karachi to the tribal regions, which included giving compensation to those who returned their weapons and even assuring them that no action would be taken against them.</seg>
     <seg id="9">The situation is telling us that the efforts undertaken in the regime of General Ziyaul Haqq, after the previous Soviet Union's interference in Afghanistan to get rid of the armed groups that formed as a result of the resistance that started through American and Saudi funding, and to bring an environment similar to that before 1980 were not successful.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The question is what does Pakistan want to do?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Does Pakistan have the ability to do so?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Click here for details.</seg>
     <seg id="14">(Please note that since there is an increase in the number of comments, only those comments typed in Urdu will be published.)</seg>
     <seg id="15">Press alt+shift to select Urdu on screen.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I have only one question to ask of all humanitarian leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You murder their children and they bring garlands for you?   That's impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4">Based on the knowledge of east and west, is there any logic, reason or philosophy which allows the killing of innocent people?  Innocent people which include Namazi, laborers and poor service men in the revenge of American attacks, do not deserve to die.</seg>
     <seg id="5">If your answer is no, then you need to correct your point of view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">People were armed because there was a danger of Russia attacking Pakistan after Afghanistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now when the danger is that America can attack Pakistan form the channel of Afghanistan which was mentioned directly in the presidential campaign by the president himself. Then why should unarmed these people?</seg>
     <seg id="3">America and India will not have to face any public resistance after defeating Pakistan army.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Yes, if any of them are involved in terrorist activities, then only Pakistan should take action against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">But the sad fact of the matter is that leaders of Lashkar-e-Tayyaba declared India's accusations were correct, and that Pakistan was involved.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeeb Ur Rehman Psycho *Lahore*</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even if it is accepted that Lashkar-e-Tayyaba is involved, the blame cannot be placed on the Pakistani Government.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This raises another question of whether these terrorists did not have the aid of some government or non-government employee of India.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are these terrorists only born or prepared in Pakistan, and not prepared in India or other nations of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post63" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As far as Lashkar-e-Tayyaba is concerned, it has no involvement in the recent incidents.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It should be kept in mind that Hafiz Saeed was the first Jihadi leader who claimed that the actions of Taliban were a Fitna.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I believe without a doubt that all the actions of the Taliban were an integral part of the American scheme, therefore it is necessary to eradicate anyone and everyone who stands in the way of the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Despite the co-operation of the entire nation, launching an operation under the pressure of India shows the stature and non-existent leadership qualities of Zerdari and company</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The operations started with American and Saudi funding, and has to come to an end. To do so, it should be requested of them to wipe out this filth that is consistently polluting our society.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In their protest, they also claim that they ethically call Jihadi on America and Saudi for spreading dangerous weapons; however, in reality, the protesters are spreading their hate-inciting literature like a virus in our country, because of which our country has become a human slaughterhouse.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After facing the risk of attack from India, as the Pakistani Army announced that it would remove forces from the Afghan border and post them at the Indian border, the Taliban announced that it would handle the Afghan border, which caused America to stumble as well as pressure India not to attack Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This showed the strength of America in the region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India did not warn that they would attack, and nor do they have the courage to do so.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Taliban attacked and destroyed most of the remaining American supplies.</seg>
     <seg id="5">That proves that without the Pakistani Army and the Pakistani government, America is nothing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Karachi is the trade and financial center of Pakistan as well as the Dubai of the backward regions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Hundreds of thousands never return from here empty-handed, but ever since law and order in the western border regions was lost, everybody diverted their attention here.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now they want to kidnap this city.</seg>
     <seg id="4">For the first time, Pathans began to be called Pukhtons, and the people of a single town are made foreigners and are being made to fight, even though what is needed is unity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One solution to the problem is that the Urdu speakers learn Pashto, or the Pashto speakers learn Urdu, or maybe it's better for everybody to learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You must be thinking its a funny suggestion, but don't you think the cause of the conflict is also funny?</seg>
     <seg id="3">that the cause of the torture would be language?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir, in my childhood I actually gave the same suggestion many times to my friends, which included people from all religious and political groups, but people used to laugh at those suggestions.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At the time, these political and religious differences didn't surface, but they were boiling inside.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">its hard to understand that what is happening and why?</seg>
     <seg id="2">are these signs of the Judgment Day?</seg>
     <seg id="3">what are these innocent people being killed for?</seg>
     <seg id="4">the reason is in front of everyone. Those who want to break Pakistan into pieces are active and those who do all this belong to neither a religion nor a country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Be it Karachi or Mumbai, the houses were set on fire by its own residents.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Which ever government comes to power changes the name of important infrastructure projects like airports, major roads and building. Presently this is the case, and buildings, airports etc, have been renamed as Baynazeer.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Does Baynzeer understand what is going on with the people of Karachi and Pakistan?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">While the Mumbai attack was on peak, the initiative taken by RAW(Indian spy agency)to start sectarian violence was busted.  This event proves that in past, political figures on RAW's payroll have now given up the job.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Spilling of innocent blood of Pushto speaking people, and with India threatening many times, have awakened the Pakistani's from Karachi to Khyber.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All strict applause of anger from political, religious, sectarian and national bodies, is now teaching India the manners of diplomatic speech. They have provided American strategists a chance to think again.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Those responsible for the turmoil in Karachi, are Mutahida and Awami National Party ANP; where as the establishment is inclined towards one party and not neutral.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The establishment could have controlled the events in an hour but intentionally allowed to the event to escalate.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Police and rangers abstained from taking any action since they were under pressure from political parties.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The talks about a unity amongst political parties on the issue is limited to paper only. The party will have to forgo their own vested interests and work for the interests of a common man</seg>
     <seg id="5">Until there is pressure on the administration, these kinds of incidents will keep taking place.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To me, these people are the biggest terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Foreign powers are definitely involved in this, but no one knows who they are.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But, alas, if these incidents were in any city of NWFP, then what would the government have done? Since it's not in NWFP, the government seems to be helpless.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government should operate here, saving a large and very important city of the country from terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Otherwise, Pakistan will face a huge financial crisis.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The BBC Urdu is also not writing the truth under pressure.  Pakistani media's condition is already weak.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The whole truth is on the BBC.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There are two solutions to the problem: to teach Pushto to Urdo speakers or to teach everyone English.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You might think that this is odd, but don't you think the cause of the conflict is funny?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is language like that the reason for violence?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There was another incident of cruelty recorded in Karachi, the terror of which was felt by its citizens for a long time.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Wherever one could do something, he did everything. Reports in the media are 50% of what has happened here in four days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They stayed awake for the past four nights, and are still afraid.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Who evacuated hotels, killed cobblers peanut sellers.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Those who cause unrest on the highways and cut off the ears of the innocent are all not aware of the judgment of Allah, which they shall receive one day.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In your opinion, what are the reasons for this sudden disturbance?</seg>
     <seg id="2">(BBC)</seg>
     <seg id="3">When we look at the recent strikes at the heart of Bombay, we certainly do not have to dive to find the reasons for this disturbance in Karachi. But one simple and easy explanation is that this disturbance was the result of the subconscious spilling of blood.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is evident that if there is something wrong with the father, it is not unlikely that the son will also be out of control.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The blood of Liyaqath Ali Khan and many other brave hearts was also from there. I am writing this poem to get rid of Saiko's misunderstanding.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We will also repeat the traditions of the elders.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They gave their lives to build. we will give our lives to save.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Faizan Touseef Siddiqi.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is very sad that we are fighting each other at a time when the whole country is under attack.</seg>
     <seg id="6">I tell Mr. Siddiqi that if he checks Wikipedia.org for Liyaqath Ali Khan.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Then he will know that he was from a repectable Punjabi family in the Karnal region of Punjab district.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Because of his steps for immigrants, today the immigrant call him their own.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Every action has a reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">One can bear one's self, but...</seg>
     <seg id="3">The consequences of noises.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Many of us who live in large towns and cities have grown used to working in noise which comes from several different sources. There is the noise of moving trains, which is heard at almost all hours of the day,</seg>
     <seg id="5">and of the jet planes that fly over head and produce noise of even greater loudness and intensity.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Most of us have no time to think of noises on one type or another.</seg>
     <seg id="7">They become part of our daily lives.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">But there is something to be thought of: does noise affect our lives in some harmful ways?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Already there is evidence that it does so in several ways. It has been recognized for a long time</seg>
     <seg id="3">now that exposure to noise high intensity leads to loss of hearing. There have been cases of boiler-makers, for example, whose suffer from occupational deafness.</seg>
     <seg id="4">More recently it has also been found that people who are continuously exposed to other loud noises require protection of the ear.</seg>
     <seg id="5">If we live in industrial areas which are growing with every passing year, there is the deafening noise produced by the speakers in house or shops, radio sets in the neighborhood, school children at play or at chorus practice of arithmetical tables, and so on.</seg>
     <seg id="6">MQM is a coalation with the government. Muslim League(N) is a secret partnership with the government. The Muslim League(Q) is the party that passed the 17th amendment. Now, how it is possible that these parties are sincere in abolishing the 17th Amendment?</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the way to get ones name entered in the list of martyrs by just getting painted.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The Peoples Party is not in a hurry to end the seventeenth ammendment.</seg>
     <seg id="9">How can anyone think of getting his own hands cut?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The Seventeenth Ammendment cannot be abolished until Zardari is the President.</seg>
     <seg id="11">This was the opinion of the majority in one of our surveys and it is correct.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Zardari would not have opted to be the President if the seventeenth ammendment was to be abolished.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Now he is more powerful than President Musharraf. He is also  the chairman of Peoples Party.</seg>
     <seg id="14">The seventeenth ammendment is will not disappear until he is the president.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Political Parties will have to remove President Zardari first in order to abolish  the seventeenth ammendment.</seg>
     <seg id="16">This is not the will of MQM or of other parties.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In our family, most of the people are of the laborer type.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And in our childhood, when we used to see our uncles toil, we used to wish in our hearts that Allah would save us from labor that is hard on the body.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To save ourselves from this, we wrote a letter to the editor of the Amroz Daily, asking him what we could do after metric to save ourselves from having to toil.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The editor wrote in reply that we should become a doctor or engineer and take such and such subjects.</seg>
     <seg id="5">My focus was always on engineering; and, after metric, instead of Biology I took Technical Drawing.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But while entering the FSC, my elder brother forced me to do FSC in medicine and become a doctor.</seg>
     <seg id="7">I studied Biology for a month with great difficulty; and when I still could not understand anything, I took maths as a subject instead.</seg>
     <seg id="8">So the scare of having to work made me an engineer, and today I am in very good condition compared to many of my same aged relatives, for which I am always thanking Allah.</seg>
     <seg id="9">I remembered this when my two young sons and I were  trying to lift the carpet of my old house.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It has not even been half an hour since we started working, when the younger son said, "Dad, it looks as if I was not made for this job".</seg>
     <seg id="11">We said, "if that is true, then study a lot like us and free yourself from bodily pain".</seg>
     <seg id="12">The son said, "I am studying and will continue studying. But I cannot do this work".</seg>
     <seg id="13">Anyway, the three of us finished the work in three hours and returned.</seg>
     <seg id="14">My purpose is that if a person has set a goal, whatever the reason behind it, no one can stop him from achieving his goal.</seg>
     <seg id="15">But if you do not even know what you have to do, then Allah alone is your protector.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">They say that you should not speak bad about the dead but what can I do? Even after one year of Benazir's death, I can only see faults in her.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For personal interests, Benazir handed over the list of Sikhs who were fighting for independence to India. At the same time, they were crushing the Sikhs independence movement and also allowing India to transfer its complete attention to Pakistan, having taken care of the Punjab movement.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Russia wars in the regimes of Benazir and Nawaz Sherif have become a part of history, which pushed the country many years back.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir continued to speak ill about Kashmir and the atomic program throughout his exile.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Benazir Bhutto struck a deal with Musharraf, going against her London Treaty with Nawaz Sharif.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Benazir allowed her husband to openly earn money in her era, which is why he came to be known as Mr. Ten Percent.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In Benazir's era, her brother was killed, and his killer has still not been punished.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Despite being a woman, Benazir avoided fighting for women's rights.</seg>
     <seg id="9">In a way similar to how Benazir conducted politics over her father's dead body, her widower is now conducting politics over her dead body.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Benazir came to power twice, but has not been able to bring the people guilty of the political killing of her father to justice, let alone file a case against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It has been 37 years since East Pakistan was separated from us, and look at the height of insensitivity on the part of the public and the rulers, that no one ever mourned or expressed sorrow over their mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We should have been observing December 16 as a day of reflection and making plans to prevent the reoccurrence of such incidents.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We should have been sending greetings to the people of Bangladesh on this day and been trying to bring them closer to ourselves.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The ruler should have opened the Jamudur Rahman commission file and pondered over the causes of separation of West Pakistan, mentioned therein.</seg>
     <seg id="5">to help the people who are sick and in trouble in Bangladesh and for their safe return planning and for motivation gifts are sent to them.</seg>
     <seg id="6">we have no feeling, our neighbors die and we do not even know about it</seg>
     <seg id="7">we do not care about brothers and sisters because we are selfish.</seg>
     <seg id="8">big crisis get over and we became normal and return to our routines.</seg>
     <seg id="9">As eastern Germany and western Germany merged together i wished if East and West Pakistan get together.</seg>
     <seg id="10">we can be one again, if we scarifie for each other and get over with our selfishness.</seg>
     <seg id="11">This wish (dream) can not seem to come true in near Future.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Today in news it was said that Governor of Illinois is arrested for corruption.</seg>
     <seg id="2">to remove him from the office of Governor, State Congress is preparing to start trial against him as soon as possible. One of our friend who has keen eye on the current affairs of Pakistan proudly said that this is democracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In USA Every man is equal under Law.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And there is your country, whose president was made after he had the corruption charges dropped.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We felt our nerve of wit and said  "What if a governor was arrested in America?" In our Pakistan, our prime minister was arrested during the night and was then hanged. The other time was exiled.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tell me if anything like this has happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan awarded the guard of honor and bid farewell from the president's house, who broke the law of the country. Tell me if anything like this has happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="8">The Chief Justice of Pakistan was laid off in such a way that even after the nation's support, he has yet not reinstated. Tell me if anything like this has happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="9">In Pakistan, a fake degree holder was appointed as Health Minister, Tell me if anything like this has happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="10">After listening to this, the poor American could not stop laughing, and also accepted defeat.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In this picture, President Zardari is smiling even after being surrounded by Americans from all sides.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It seems from his smile</seg>
     <seg id="3">...that America is with his government. But, he is forgetting that last year the same people were with Parvez Musharaf.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This picture was passed on as if it was of some family.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Previously such a photo, one president with three American agents, has never been printed in newspapers before.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It seems as if America's work in Pakistan has increased and now more than one agent is needed to complete it, or that they did not trust the new slave as they trusted the first one.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is also possible that this was done by keeping in mind the notoriety of President Zardari breaking his promises.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If he was a smart ruler, at least he would not have shown his teeth in this photo, and he would have at least seemed ashamed of the neckband of slavery that he was sporting.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If the rules of democracy are implemented in this photo, then President Zardari is in the minority.</seg>
     <seg id="10">According to democracy, the majority are the rulers of the country, and the photo is speaking for itself who that is.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Paradisical Swat is also called the "Switzerland of Pakistan".</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to the government, tactics along with force, and discussions have been going on.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The use of force is not giving any benefit other than increasing the force of the Taliban and increasing the public favor for them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is required that the government finish the causes of this problem, rather than use force.</seg>
     <seg id="5">By finishing the causes, Fazlullah and the Taliban will be finished themselves.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The proposed Shariah bill of the ANP government will become a moderate solution to the problems in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Alongside the establishment of the Shariah, the government will also have to take care of economic problems.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">From General Musharraf's initial few steps, it looked as if the nation would be freed of useless politicians.  But the love for power changed all his plans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whatever expectations were, after joining the 'war of terror', he began to consider himself irremovable.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And whatever steps were expected were no more.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Just as Bush's term came to an end, he started to worry about the end of his own rule, and he struck a deal with thieves in the dark.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Even then, General Musharraf could have commanded the army, but the present government did not even know what was happening.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Whether in Bajod or Swat, the army cannot control terror.  Instead they bomb the 'enemy', i.e. the public. Apart from loss of life and money, if they are making the 'enemy' psychologically ill, then we are the enemies, aren't we?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The conditions in the  terrorist stricken area Swat, in the Frontier Province, are continuously deteriorating in spite of continuous Army action in the area.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the one side, the governments rights in the area is restricted to the extent of just getting the condemnation resolution passed from the National Assembly. On the other side, the effect of Taliban's unlawful radio is increasing everday in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the third side, the common folk consider it safe to listen to those who are in control of the area.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The security forces claimed to have killed many extremists during Gunship Helicopter attacks and Artillery Bombardment, but in spite of these killings the Taliban has not only gained strength, but according to estimate they have established their control over eighty percent of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The result is that on the one hand the government is not ready to accept its defeat and on the other, the Taliban has established its' hold.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And the poor citizens of Swat are stuck in between.</seg>
     <seg id="7">When a citizen of Swat was asked, "what kind of people are theTaliban?" The answer was  "Very good people, because they are the custodians of the religion and they are fighting a war against the enemies of the country."</seg>
     <seg id="8">When asked how is the Army,  the answer was that the Army is very good, since they protect the country and they fight with the enemies of the country.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Then it was asked, who are the enemies of religion and country, the answer was "the citizens"</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I am astonished, how the Pakistani Army will fight with the Indian Army, while it is unable to control a small group of Taliban's.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They could not track the illegally set up FM channel of the Taliban, which, I believe, was very easy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Still, the FM channel is spreading poison with all vigor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First the girls schools and now the boys schools are being destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Curfews are in place so that the Taliban can move around easily.</seg>
     <seg id="6">During curfew, eight trucks entered the outskirts of Mengorah and formed barriers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The question arises as to how they got there despite the curfew.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The army could kill Akbar Bugti in his house yet it salutes the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="9">To save the poor public from the grip of the Taliban and prove that the Army can defeat any enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">You say, blood is spilled in the world because of religion. Tell me, if there was no religion, would all this killing not take place?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are Punjabi, Pathan, White, Black, Mahsood and other tribes the result of religion?</seg>
     <seg id="3">No sir no way! Only religion teaches that there is no black and white. As well as no Punjabi and no immigrant. If it were not for religion then half of the world would have been destroyed in fights between the white and the black. While the rest of the people would have drowned in tribe-brotherhood hatred.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Actually only religion trains man's character and restricts him as he has not come here on his own will, but rather the Creator of all that exists sent him here, and he must live here according to His commands.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a Muslim I am completely convinced that Islam is a complete way of life and the true religion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After settling down in London, every morning I would first call my relatives and ask them how they were. Most of them had never called me to find out how I was doing. I then realized that they didn't like me calling them either, so I stopped calling them.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Living here in France for two years I also felt the same way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I do not know why people only expect us to call.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A resolution about Iraq passed in a few hours to send a "peace" force to Darfur was not a problem at all.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Immediately criticizing the Mumbai attacks and restricting suspected groups in a matter of a few hours.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In addition where there is a matter of death, we are still holding meetings about that.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Our upholders of world peace and life is still finishing over here.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is it true that everyone is waiting for their end?</seg>
     <seg id="6">No other victim should even think about using a dangerous weapon like a sling shot to fight for his rights.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Doesn't your heart ache when a father is running while holding his dead son's body?</seg>
     <seg id="8">If no, then you have no right to be called a human being.</seg>
     <seg id="9">You are a shame to the name of humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It was proven that this area was Israel's country for thousands of years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What should happen is that both the nations should live together happily with love, but since they are controlled by the west and Arab countries, peace cannot be formed without their consent.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even Iran wants to fight its proxy war here now.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even if operations in Israel are stopped for the time being, they will start again after some other incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The interest of BBC's country is subject to the bestowing of America and Israel. And this is why in the name of ""enlightenment"", they have come with a series of blogs based on ""darkness"" and a blind propaganda.</seg>
     <seg id="2">BBC is just using formality to gain sympathy which is their only purpose and wish!</seg>
     <seg id="3">Mr. Moderator has requested that he may publish the commentary, and by this humble soul,one can guess BBC still has some integrity left.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thank you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">No one knows about the author and the origin of this story, but the fact remains, in every era Draculas have fed on innocent blood.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Every era has seen war as well as bloodshed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Surprisingly, the twenty first century man, who considers himself very civilized, is silent over this murder, done publicly in the day light.</seg>
     <seg id="4">How can he not realize that whatever is happening is showing the ugliest face of humanity</seg>
     <seg id="5"></seg>
     <seg id="6">well wisher, Sajjad ul Hasnain, Hyderabad Dakan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At this time along with Dera Ghazi Khan, in whole country winter rains are going on.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Here is a poem for the season. Enjoy the rain with this poem.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These rains are also from you</seg>
     <seg id="4">Which when fell brings spring.</seg>
     <seg id="5">When it stops there is no movement</seg>
     <seg id="6">sometimes it came just like that, without a reason.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Sometimes it spreads day and night.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Sometimes loudly, sometimes silently.</seg>
     <seg id="9">These rains are also from you</seg>
     <seg id="10">in some remembrance some night</seg>
     <seg id="11">on some suppressed ashes</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sometimes we blew out the flames.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Sometimes we burnt ourselves.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Sometimes every drop is like pain.</seg>
     <seg id="15">And these rains are only because of you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All these leaders are going to run away with their briefcases in hand.  What do they care about what will happen to the country?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Let the population sell toothpaste or clean the bells of the Mandir with lemon peel.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And then our media is also corrupt, like our leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The only purpose of it is to get money out of the government.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And as far as the population goes, they can remain in the dark, because speaking out about the corruption would be foolish.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Yesterday, a strange incident took place.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All together police running here and there but not asking about illegal parking</seg>
     <seg id="3">The NYPD traffic police were also not in a mood to look at illegal parked cars.</seg>
     <seg id="4">it happened like this that a plane of US Air really became a plane and landed in Hudson river.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Until now it is just known this that ""Terrorists"" relation was with birds race Goose.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Yesterday was maybe New York's historic cold</seg>
     <seg id="7">Temperature normally do not drop to this degree.</seg>
     <seg id="8">My jaw is beginning to hurt after half an hour of strolling outside.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Imagine that what would have happened to those people who jumped from a plane into the river.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Happy news is that the people all stayed safe.</seg>
     <seg id="11">The sad news is that the ship of company sank in this financial crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="12">I reached New Jersey from west site e way and also saw that south bound is closed and still what have i done?</seg>
     <seg id="13">On the way back, I got caught in traffic.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Luckily, after my trip of an hour, I was able to find a road to 56th street exit.</seg>
     <seg id="15">I couldn't see the traffic lines for that exit.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Maki, My Pakistan: Same to you in reply of Eid Mubarak.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ammaar: Of course; With faith.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Shagufta: Same to you in reply of Eid Mubarak.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sara: I killed two chickens and cooked them to the best of my knowledge.</seg>
     <seg id="5">I didn't know any other way.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this farm, you have to prepare the meat yourself, including removing the chicken's skin.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Dot net could take time to become right.</seg>
     <seg id="8">What happened on the form?</seg>
     <seg id="9">This is a link.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Listen to the blog. To give back look to Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Deafer: wish you, you too Eid Mubarak.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Dear sir, use Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Ice will disappear.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We considered the Taliban group of Swat to be only against women's education.</seg>
     <seg id="2">To show this unease every day in any way caused the demolishing of the School and College of Women.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This thought was also wrong, as according to the news of CNN today, the holy day of Monday, the Taliban demolished a boy's school with dynamite.</seg>
     <seg id="4">shawat</seg>
     <seg id="5">kaiwan</seg>
     <seg id="6">aike</seg>
     <seg id="7">yaallam</seg>
     <seg id="8">taqat</seg>
     <seg id="9">maiyin</seg>
     <seg id="10"></seg>
     <seg id="11"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">Just a while before this, the wedding of a girl with a dog took place.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Look at the groom.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Humanity is still a rarity in the twenty first century.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the era of computers and its involvement is ever increasing in every sphere of life.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have many reservation over this increasing involvement of computers. For example, in financial matters,</seg>
     <seg id="3">where use of credit cards bring ease to life, it also gives better control to law enforcement agencies over your private life.</seg>
     <seg id="4">So now, only through your financial matters, like through your credit card, you can be located.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And in the future, when use of real currency will be reduced a great extent, its benefits will increase more and more.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Similarly, in the world of crimes, instead of playing with the dangers of robbing a bank, the credit card information is stolen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Similarly computers have become the source of friendship.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Social networking websites like Orket, Facebook and MySpace have the first accepting level.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But has it not occurred to you that as we obey these social networks as we are being away from the people in act.</seg>
     <seg id="10">So, this way you have seen your wanted people and their index in the matchmaking website.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Now can you spend your life with a person like you?</seg>
     <seg id="12">I cannot spend and for this the wife is also called half body.</seg>
     <seg id="13">That she fulfill my void.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I am probably not intelligent.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I considered true all the elder's advice.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And so I had assurance that my father knew the answer to every question in the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I was laughed at because of it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But only that seems to be true, which is possible.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It is very troubling, that the need to tell lies.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Even at this age, he was harmed by this.</seg>
     <seg id="8">That is why, I try to lie, as less as possible.</seg>
     <seg id="9">That, I do not falsely please others, that too in the name of Allah.</seg>
     <seg id="10">And that I say,'Insha Allah' (If God Wills), only when I am asking Allah to complete the work.</seg>
     <seg id="11">As for the intentions, only Allah knows best.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a despicable matter that rose due to distance from religion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to both, our religion and Pakistani law, young children should stay with their mothers.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Their expenses are to be borne by the father, and the father can meet his children.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Then, when they become mature, they live with whomever they want.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You are right. The actual problem is the misguiding relatives.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Feudalism has overshadowed our deeds.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Even here is thinking is prevailing that there will be more partners in father's property so it is resisted, although this act of the father is commendable should be imitated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Here, these bans upon relation-making have created many evils in society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The concept of remarriage of a divorce or a widow is getting rare.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Due to these unnecessary beliefs and traditions, the family system is facing disarray.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In our society, if a wife of a 50 or 55 years old man dies or a husband of wife passes away and they remarry, then why it is not appreciated?</seg>
     <seg id="2">There is a Pakistani uncle near us whose wife died a good 10 or 12 years ago, now after getting all his children married when he married a widow, his own children have gone against him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, this is the religious right, what do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Until we are alive we will never accept that any one else can take the place of my mother, is this kind of thought is a thought?  While we are alive, we will never accept that anyone else can take the place of my mother.  Is this a reasonable thought?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my view Sirs children has to think that, if after doing the Marriage of all the children, he him self has married to a widow women, so is that any thing wrong he has done?  In my opinion, Sir has done nothing wrong or not acceptable. He respectfully waited until all of his children were married before he himself married a widow woman.  The children should have no reason to resent or be unhappy about that.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In this way this widow women has also got some support and that uncle will also get some one to take care of the home (homemaker)  This marriage will allow the woman to have someone to care for her and to support her; while uncle will also have someone to care for him and to keep a good home for him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because that is for sure that his children got busy in there own personal life and they are not giving him time  His children have their own personal lives and their own marriages to with which they are concerned.  They certainly do not have time, nor are they making time, to care for their father.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Reason for this is unknowledgeable  I don't know why they have no time for him, but they do not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If tomorrow there wifes refuses to serve that old man then what will he do?  It's very possible that the wives of his children could refuse to serve him in the future; then how could he take care of himself and his home?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This result is because of Societies pressure</seg>
     <seg id="4">When People will laugh on this activity and on there Family then children will feel ashamed on second marriage of there father  If people laugh at this marriage and at their family, then the children will feel ashamed of their father and his second marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Actually they have to defend the situation stating there father has done this according to Islam view  Actually, they should defend this situation, stating that their father has done this according to the Islam view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is one of the curses on our society like we are totally into Venery in past 40-50 years  Sadly, this is one of the curses in our society. It might seem that we are totally into venery (pursuit of sexual pleasure) for the past 40-50 years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is acceptable for a wife that her husband does unlawful actions but even then she does not let him marry another woman.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If its in her power, she will not let him do that even after she dies.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Destroys her after life along with her husbands.And also lets spreading of the immorality in the society.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Nothing happens with the singing about Islam. We actually like what our traditions and cultures are.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For example, keeping girls from getting education and fear of love marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And about your question, when sir instead of bringing his wife home, goes to someone else's wife so the dependents just make a fuss for the show and stay quiet and satisfied. ( yeah, later the relatives of the wife get angry)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Indian subcontinent, we accepted Islam centuries ago but we could not let go of with the illiterate thinking and always thought of culture and tradition as more valuable than Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Considering man's 2nd marriage as ridiculous, divorce as denigration, divorced as untouchable, love marriage as dishonor and considering a man marrying an older women is dissimulation of the women is only the result of this way of thinking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And over all, by copying the western world, we are declaring the religious and veil as old fashioned.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Accepting Islam was easy, getting rid of this way of thinking is very hard.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Allahn give us courage and Daringness.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">it was not really difficult to write Urdu ever before.</seg>
     <seg id="8">decades gone to writes that little.</seg>
     <seg id="9">consider more to less.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Allah Hafiz.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Amir Taimoor Write on his book ""I am Tamioor"" that I have discovered secrets in my life that if any force commander in chief on the first raw so that force never loss.</seg>
     <seg id="2">but that circumstances different there.</seg>
     <seg id="3">it was said lay folk die for our self we die so martyr.</seg>
     <seg id="4">if some one die form Lay folk so killed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah bless and have mercy on you.</seg>
     <seg id="2">When I was coming back to the shop after Isha prayer tonight one man who was sitting in his car raised his hand and asked me to come.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I thought maybe this man has forgotten his way or maybe he wants to ask me something. I stopped and saw his whole family was in the car.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He asked if I can understand Arabic very well or if I couldn't. I said that there is no problem I understand very well. Then I said you tell me what is the matter.</seg>
     <seg id="5">He started saying I have come from Riyadh but someone in Medina picked my pocket, if you could please help me? I said forget about it, because this has happened to me earlier. In return I gave this man 20 riyals to pay for gas and to go back to Riyadh. In stead he started doing the same thing after moving forward a little.</seg>
     <seg id="6">I got really angry and when I told him so with threatening to call the cops on him, he vanished from there.</seg>
     <seg id="7">So now this is the condition of us Muslims. That even when we come to beg money we come with families riding in cars and manage daily to get at least 2 to 3000.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Although there is an evident saying of the Prophet (P.B.U.H) "That the hand above is better than the hand below" meaning the hand above is the giving hand the lower is the taking hand.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Allah have mercy on us and make us true Muslims ( Amen)</seg>
     <seg id="10">Wassalam</seg>
     <seg id="11">Javed Iqbal</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The wife of famous singer Adnan Sami, went to a police station in Bombay and accused him of torturing her.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The police station suggested that she contact the Court.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Adnan Sami's wife, Saba Guladari, submitted a plea against her husband claiming that he tortures her continuously.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He also treats her inhumanely.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now that this has exceeded her tolerance limit, a case should be recorded against Adnan Sami.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Police suggested that instead of recording a report, that she should contact the court because this matter is not under police control.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In your opinion, is the accusation of Adnan Sami's wife on him correct?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What if this accusation is an attempt of tarnishing the name of Adnan Sami?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Let us know of your comments regarding this matter.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Adam Saanghar, stamp.</seg>
     <seg id="2">as far as blames concern so any man can do on other.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There's nothing more important than respect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">what so ever relation of present wife and Adnan Samih , Adnan Samih leave his respected life and went India to earn money, now this popularity made hurdle for him.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is due to his own deed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Washington.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A high level American official said that president Obama made a strong policy against the Afghan president Hamid Karzai.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This new policy of America about Afghanistan focuses more importance on war instead of development.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Officials say what Hamid Karzai considers as a hurdle in Afghanistan to get American Aid, because corruption in the government, intoxication business get increased and Taliban forces get regathered.</seg>
     <seg id="5">American officials said that those people from American government who put pressure on Hamid Karzai to do more in which vice president Joe Biden and representative of Brack Obama for Afghanistan and Pakistan Richard Holbrooke included.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that this policy appeared after President Bush, who used to video conference with Hamid Karzai every two weeks, left. He used to stress upon the American role in rebuilding Afghanistan and its civilian institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Officials say that the Obama government would rather work with the State leaders than the central government.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The officials say that it will pressurize Karzai to step up the war against corruption.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Hamid Karzai is facing fresh elections this year and it is not yet clear whether Obama and his group will support Karzai for presidency or not.</seg>
     <seg id="10">This statement of the American officials is not a precursor for a change in the American policy towards Afghanistan...is it?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Is Hamid Karzai's rule coming to an end?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What is your opinion about this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In a series of three one day matches between Sri Lanka and Pakistan, Sri Lanka defeated Pakistan 2-1.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan had defeated Sri Lanka in the first match, but Sri Lanka was victorious in the remaining two matches.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the third one day match, the national cricket team's performance was very poor. In reply to Sri Lanka's 309 runs, it only managed to hit 75 runs in 23 overs before going all out. As such, it had to face a humiliating loss.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The result of the series shows the inconsistency of our cricket team's performance</seg>
     <seg id="5">Despite the home ground advantage and claims, National team is defeated. Can you give the reasons of this defeat?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Which department of the sport needs more attention from concerning authorities?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are you satisfied with team selection?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Which department is the major reason of the defeat: fielding, batting or bowling.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Kindly share your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Babar Hussain, it is sad that such custom of ignorance still exist in this modern age. These feudal target the poor and innocent people, who will believe that they are Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="2">If any tribal chief proved his innocence by walking on fire. why Government does not take action?</seg>
     <seg id="3">When will the judicial justice play its role?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370243-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Sri Lankan team has reached Pakistan to play one day series.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Besides the Indo-Pak sullenness, a visit by a foreign team to Pakistan is very pleasing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Upon reaching the Karachi airport, the Srilankan team was very warmly welcomed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Two one days between Pakistan and Srilanka in Karachi, whereas the third one day will be played in Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Both teams have there claims over bowling, batting and fielding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If the Srilankans are proud of their spinners, the Pakistanis trust their fast bowlers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Srilankan Captain Mahela Jayvardena has said that not a single player but the whole team from Pakistan is dangerous</seg>
     <seg id="8">Murli dharan and Mendis will be the trump cards whereas the Pakistan Captain says that it will be a tough competition.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Shoaib Malik has said that "We have played Murli dharan and we'll see Mendis as well. We have prepared a secret game plan and we shall implement that in the ground"</seg>
     <seg id="10">Will the Pak-Srilanka Series be really as interesting and exciting as they claim are?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Who will dominate the series between Pakistan and Srilanka?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Who will win the series?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Who will be the main of the series?</seg>
     <seg id="14">Let us know your recommendation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Gulfam wants his favorable speech and you are also to consider that it is our wish that you should write some truth. Do not make an interpretation, as Mukhurjee did. It is ordered to be said right in the open and it is equal to Jihad when Mukhurjee tries to get in the news by changing his speech.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Yousuf, Dubai</seg>
     <seg id="2">Those same people have been responsible for Kashmirs fighting for their freedom these last 60 years.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No one asks about that now that they have stuck with fundamentalism and fight for terrorism. They now start talking about a deal.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First they killed Muslims brutally, and now they are trying to resolve issues.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan has tried to understand their two-way policy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Asad Khan, London.</seg>
     <seg id="2">India is creating this situation to distract the world attention away from the Kashmir issue.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Pakistan has always shown the true face of India to the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now the British government has realized that the Indian government is maligning Pakistan for terrorism so that it can occupy Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They are unwilling to talk with Pakistan on this matter.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">British Foreign Minister, David Miliband, has said that by resolving the Kashmir issue it will end extremism. The the Pakistan government will be able to handle the border issues.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It should be noted that American President Obama has already expressed similar views on the Kashmir issue.</seg>
     <seg id="3">British Foreign Minister has said, while talking to media in Mumbai and also written in an essay, that the idea of war on terror is wrong. On the basis of threat to oneself, killing others was Bush's policy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">David Miliband has said that Pakistan should show leniency towards extremist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Due to insistence of major powers to resolve the Kashmir issue, India is now creating unrest in the region to distract the world from this issue.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The terrorist attack in Mumbai is also a part of this strategy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Does India want to the allegations of terrorism its escape goat to avoid peace talks?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Tell us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Usman Aftab</seg>
     <seg id="2">In my opinion many of the powerful nations do not want to bring harm to Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But they are thinking of plans to keep it on a leash because they know that Pakistan is a nuclear power.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They want to fuel a situation for a revolution.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Other nations are thinking that in cornering Pakistan they may face geo-political problems. They also want to aid Pakistan while accomplishing their own ulterior ends.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A Citizen, USA</seg>
     <seg id="2">Indians have been known to be snakes in the grass.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion they get cramps every now and then causes them to utter baseless threats.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Indian army chief, keep your mouth shut. Anyway, we are ready, or else we know to give you a solid answer.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">FM SADIQ</seg>
     <seg id="2">With the help of American wealth, Rasil Quium gave an ec speech, with which he blew the American's mind. This is wrong, but now the surprising thing is "attack and watch". Truth will be proved. Who's right?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israil attacked Hamas but there was no one to stop them, the Indian brother just watched the work done by Israil. He wanted to do something.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Prime Minster Syed Yousuf said that all the issues of America will be taken to the parliment and will be solved with each sentence kept in mind.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Remove the uniform and their public support.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All issues will be explained in the parliment.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Dr.Qadir has become famous with the help of the Prime Minster.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is there any hope in your sense against Maryeth? Does any part of the public support?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Did the lawyer play any role in this case?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you think of the Prime Minister's statement?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Let us know what you think.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American president, George W. Bush, affirms to the newly elected President Barack Obama in his outgoing press conference, that though hes made plenty of mistakes during his presidency, one must always remain true to what he feels is best for the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As President, I did whatever I felt was appropriate in accordance to the situation, American law, and Constitution by often allowing the American interest reign over my own acceptance.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Bush reiterates that there is still opposition that desire to attack the United States, and Barack Obama must make it his focus to ensure that these attacks do not occur.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He confesses that his failure to locate the weapons of mass destruction in Iraq was a huge disappointment for him, and even admits that the Iraqu mission to be his greatest mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The American President expressed his adieus at his final press conference and thanked the journalist and associates present at the conference.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you believe that Obama will not repeat the same mistakes that Bush made?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Was it too late for Bush to admit to his mistakes?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Will Obama follow Bush's advice?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Let us know your suggestions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Vice President of America, Dick Cheney, said that he want to see Osama Bin Laden dead or alive.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He said that Osama Bin Ladin hid himself in some mountainous area.  If Osama Bin Ladin is arrested either dead or alive his organization should be finished.</seg>
     <seg id="3">America is hopeful to arrest Osama Bin Ladin though the search for Osama continues.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Did Dick Cheney's wish to arrest Osama bin Ladin come true?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Let us know your suggestions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Shahid Afridi is a cricket player in Qaiud-e-Aazam.  At the end of first day match of Habib Bank, he fought with a spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="2">At UBL ground Shahif Afridi left the drawing room after finishing his match.  Many spectators gathered around him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">At one event, one spectator requested that Shahid take a picture with him by holding his hand out to him.  Shahid Afridi rejected him and said that they would take a picture tomorrow.  The spectator insisted that they take the picture then.  Shahid became angry and soon they began to fight.  It took many people to resolve this matter.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After that altercation, Shahid said that became a huge issue without any reason.  At the time of the confrontation he was late for prayer.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Anyway, Ill excuse myself from taking part in these old matters.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What would you say about the behavior of Shahid Afridi?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Do let us know your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian President Manmohan Singh has again accused Pakistan of hyping the talk of war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And he said that Pakistan uses terrorism as its state policy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">While speaking to the Chief Ministers, Manmohan Singh stated that terrorist elements were being housed in neighboring countries such as Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And he said that, during the Mumbai attacks, the terrorists used the sea route and managed to elude the coast guard.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian president stated that the Mumbai attacks were carried out by the Lashkar-e-Tayyebah.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He continued that the terrorists were using new techniques and advanced equipment and that the security on the line of control should also be increased so that infiltration of these things could be stopped.  He also stated that terrorism shall never be tolerated by the Indian government and that was their policy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In what light do you see these accusations made by the Indian President?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Is the internal chaos and separation movements of India not the show of India's anxiety?</seg>
     <seg id="9">On whose signals is India chosen to be in threatening attitude?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Let us know your opinion</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Zubeer Khan, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is very hurtful incident that Israel is publicly massacring the Palestinians, same situation is here in Kashmir but Security Council do not even bother about it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As many organizations who are in Palestine and Kashmir should continue their fight till freedom and by creating unity between themselves keep fighting every kind of aggression, one of these days their Martyr will bring result. By the will of Allah</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Israeli air attacks still continues in Gaza, since now several Palestinian men, women and children have been martyred.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Important political leader of Hamas Nazarian have been martyred with wife and kids.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The meeting of Security Council ended without any decision.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The condemning resolution presented by Libya and other Arab countries against Israel is facing American opposition in the meeting.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The civilian population of Palestine has been under attack by the Israeli Air force for many days.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The world showed a strong reaction over the Mumbai attacks but no one, including Great Britain and the US, is reacting to the violence in Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Why are the leading Muslim countries silent?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What would you say about the world's double standard?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Saeed, New York.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think the problem lies in the illiteracy of our nation. People do not know how their money is spent. The government is solving its problems by introducing new taxes. The power and Gas crisis will remain unsolved.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Everyone knows the real faces of the people's elected representatives.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The power crisis has become worse in Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand price of Gas has been increased by 18%. Due to the scarce availability of petrol, people are facing severe difficulties.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The business and industrial communities of Pakistan are violently protesting the power and gas crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The producers have given the ultimatum to close the factories.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Here in Karachi, the public is annoyed over the 8-10 hour load shedding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Production has become practically paralyzed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The government institutions are blaming each other to express their positions.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Are the talks of increasing the prices of electricity and gas not a joke against the nation?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Shouldn't more attention should be given to solving the problems?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Are the wheels of national development not seeming jammed to the government?</seg>
     <seg id="11">What immediate steps can you suggest to gain control over this crisis?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Please let us know your opinions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Imran Khokhar, Madina Munawwarah, I want to say that, as the people, the rulers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I am surprised that the people who called for a democratic government are being given such a hard time.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The unavailability of electricity, gas and petrol has become absolute torture.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is no control over government institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The law-and-order situation is getting worse every day. May Allah have mercy on this country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The New Year has started.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The previous year was a year of protests and political ups and downs, and will also be remembered as a time of terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We will also remember the removal of President Musharraf from power, the end of President Bush's eight-year regime, Bush having shoes thrown at him, the establishment of a democratic government in Pakistan, sudden calamities, the earthquake of Balochistan, and the terrible global financial crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now that the new year has arrived, how do you think it will go?</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you think the political and geographic scenarios will be like, and what wise policies do you think Obama will implement?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is there any hope of moving towards the eradication of terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Will the judicial crisis in Pakistan come to an end?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What direction will Indo-Pak relations take?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is there a chance of surgical strikes, or a full-fledged war?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What are your expectations for the New Year?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please provide your feedback.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370256-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The first anniversary of the death of Benazir Bhutto is being celebrated. She was martyred on December 27, 2007 after a  congregation at the Liaqat Bagh in Rawalpindi.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir is no longer among us. She was a statesman, politician and world famous personality and had a unique status in national politics.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One year has gone by but the mystery of her martyrdom has not yet been resolved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Her efforts in bringing democracy in Pakistan and forming government have not been in vain.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Today, Pakistan has a democratic government, and her former husband Asif Ali Zardari is holding the presidential seat.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you think of Benazir Bhutto's role in Pakistani politics?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Who is behind her death?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Recently, she has been acclaimed by the Human Rights Organization for her work in politics and democracy. What is your opinion about this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">President Bush after completing his 8 years tenure of the Government from white house he reached Presidential Camp Office Camp David so that white house can be decorated according to the wish of President Barack Obama  After completion of his eight years in office, President Bush</seg>
     <seg id="2">During Bush's eight-year hold of the presidency, America has witnessed a historical attack on World Trade Center, an attack on the Pentagon, and in the wake of war against terrorists which became to military invasion in Afghanistan and Iraq, dragging different countries into the war effort and using up resources have become memorable about these wars.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Due to this war, America is facing a historical economic crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Do you think this war resulted in benefit or loss for the world?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Was the policy of President Bush successful?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What is your opinion on President Bush's tenure?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Indian Government has stop Indian cricket team to visit Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="2">The India cricket team is scheduled to play three tests, five one-day and one twenty-twenty match on its Pakistan tour.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Vice President of the Indian Cricket Board, Mr. Ragiv Shukla, told Geo News that he has sought permission for the tour of Pakistan from the Indian government, but due to current tensions between the two countries the tour has been canceled.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Is the Indian Government's initiative not to allow the cricket team to visit Pakistan on political grounds justified? Can't sports be kept separate from politics?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is the Indian Government's decision counterproductive for cricket?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Despite security concerns, an English team visited India. Then why can't the Indian team continue its tour of Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion is this regard?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salman from Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">Those people who feel proud of visiting India</seg>
     <seg id="3">and direct or produce their videos in India should open their eyes to India's response.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I remember an interview of Adnan Sami in which he said that he is not a Pakistani national but a British subject.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan Sami should come back to Pakistan at the first opportunity, because he did not get honor over there either.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Farid Ahmad</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="3">After the Mumbai attacks, the mode of the Indians has changed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jagjeet Singh reacted by expressing hatred for Pakistan and Pakistanis.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It should be known that Adnan Sami has sung with Asha Bhonsle. How has he become helpless now? Adnan Sami should stay in India. There is no need for him to come here.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muhammad Shamshad Aalam,</seg>
     <seg id="2">I will only say this about Jagjeet Singh - that he too changes colors like a chameleon.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Pakistanis, open your eyes and see how much you are respected in India. Do not be dull minded.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the Mumbai incident, their hate-filled speech has increased. Now they are spreading poison about famous singer Adnan Sami.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">according to a foreign news agency, during his final visit to Iraq, when American president Bush along with Iraqi president Noori Almaliki were in a press conference in his office, the situation went ludicrous when an Iraqi journalist while addressing President Bush said ""You dog this is a farewell kiss""</seg>
     <seg id="2">after that the journalist removed his shoe and threw it towards Bush. president Bush expertly ducked before the shoe could hit and saved himself.</seg>
     <seg id="3">second shoe hit the American Flag.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Security personnel's dragged the journalist away from there.</seg>
     <seg id="5">at this point, president Bush said that he didn't know why he had done so , Shoe was of number 10, and he didn't had any problem.</seg>
     <seg id="6">do you think this reaction of the journalist wasn't an expression of deprecation or President bush from the Iraqi people?</seg>
     <seg id="7">what would you say on this incident?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The tension between Pakistan and India's relations after the terrorism in Mumbai got further intense when the fighter planes from the Indian Air force violated the Pakistani airspace in Lahore and Kashmir sectors.</seg>
     <seg id="2">as a result of retaliation from Pak Air force, the Indian planes were forced to go back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">sources say that both Indian planes were loaded with ammunition.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is the first incident of its nature in the present strained situation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan Air Force has affirmed it is absolutely ready to defend the country .</seg>
     <seg id="6">Federal Minister of Information Sherry Rehman has stated the Indian leaders have acknowledged the violation of Pakistani airspace, however this happened by mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan's military sources have declared thisa grave incident.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Do you think India really intends to launch an air raid on Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is India's claim true, about the violation of Pakistani airspace being a mistake, or is India trying to cover up an attempt made to analyze the capability of Pakistan Air Force?</seg>
     <seg id="10">This incident will cause an increase in tension between the two countries?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Share your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Benazir Bhutto was posthumously awarded the UN Human Rights prize, which was received by her son, Chairman of Peoples' Party Bilawal Bhutto Zardari.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This award was given to the former Prime Minister of Pakistan, slain Benazir Bhutto, in acknowledgment of her contribution towards human rights, in a function held during one of the meetings of the General Assembly in UN Headquarters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The 17th birthday of human rights was celebrated by United States.</seg>
     <seg id="4">On this event the personalities and institutes which are rewarded in the declare of human rights, from them except Nazir Bhutto American past president General Lotis Ramray Kalarak all the workin for human rights all over the world,</seg>
     <seg id="5">At the time, Pakistani ambassador Abdullah Hussain Taron and other Pakistani center ambassadors were also present in United States.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What will you say when past Prime Minister Baynazir receives this award?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Samir.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Shikago.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is true that it was determined, but we also remember how many non-criminals they murdered?  Upon it she has proud that Nasirullah Babur did a good deed today.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Bur she completely changed after it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But it is also true that she ignored the caniters of the party and chose his son for the representative of the People's Party.  How is it democratic?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Juma Noor,Karachi,It proved this Quranic saying that unbelievers help unbelievers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Until the metal of the axe has a grip attached to it, it cannot chop off the wings.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our leaders have an idea of this, and therefore they are using it to make secret plans.</seg>
     <seg id="4">God help our leaders.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The security council of the United Nations included the names of Hafiz Saeed and 3 other Pakistanis along with the Jamat Al Dawa and 5 other groups in the terrorists list.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Taliban and Al Qaeda sanctions committee of the United Nations gave the approval of including the names of the following individuals into the Terrorists list: Hafiz Muhammad Saeed of Jameetae Dawa, the Operations Chief of Lashkarae Tayyaba Hafeez Zaki ur Rehman, and the leader of Shoiaba Al Maliyat Haji Muhammad Ashraf.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Other than these, a Saudi individual Mehmood Ahmed Bazeek has also been included in the terrorist list.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Among these groups Jametae Dawa, Pasbane Kashmir, Al Rasheed Trust, and Al Akhtar Trust International are included.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The allied nations will instantly cease their accounts and funds, and have sanctions on travel and will be arrested.</seg>
     <seg id="6">They will face a formal trial.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are these sanctions under the influence of Indian propaganda?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Why does India have such claims about these agencies for the Mumbai blast without any proof?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Are the terrorism agencies not in India?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Do the UNO not have the knowledge of the blasts that occurred in India?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please provide us your suggestion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The festival of EID is the symbol for the happiest moment. While the followers of Allah sacrifice animals on EID Zuha for the remembrance of the sunnat carried out by Prophet Ibrahim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What ever may be the situation I.E., inflation, political, or environmental. The people either rich or poor perform EID's based on their capacity, and convey wishes to their friends and relatives with their ways.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We also provide a platform to you to convey your wishes to your loved ones in a simple way.</seg>
     <seg id="4">For EID you can convey in the form of a poem.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
     <seg id="2">Murtaza, Gillani, Karachi: Our ministers has to understand that the operation they are carrying are the people who respects us, even after many damages, also they love us.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>

