<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="mturk">
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Committee supports the French proposal</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A committee lead by chairman Mushahid Husain Syedby took place in the parliament house and proposed to the government to send a delegation with representatives of all political parties to send humanitarian aid to Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="3">After the meeting, speaking to representatives of the press, Mushahid Husain Syed said that the committee welcomed the proposal given by France, in which it was stated that Israel calls for an immediate ceasefire and allowing humanitarian work among the affected people of Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Calling the Israeli attacks on Palestine "a crime against humanity," he said that all countries should denounce these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mushahid Husain attacled the the double standards of the countries of the world and said,  "Why are those who speak against terrorism quiet about the Israeli attacks on Palestine?"</seg>
    <seg id="6">The chairman of the standing committee of external affairs in the senate also targeted the leaders of Muslim nation who were taking a quiet stance on the matter of Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said the committee expressed hope that the newly elected American President, Barack Obama, would speak to the Muslim nation within his first 100 days of his government, to bridge the gulf forming between America and the Muslim nation.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mushahid Husain Syed said that the gap formed between the Muslim nations and the west should be filled by taking not only sudden steps but also by solving long standing issues like Kashmir and Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The minister of foreign affairs, Malik Imad, told the committee that he was going to Saudi Arabia to attend the meeting of the foreign ministers of the governments of Islamic countries.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This sudden meeting was called as a result of Israeli attacks on Palestine. He said that he was aware of the Palestinian matter and at present, the government was in contact with the premiers of other countries.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The Minister of State for Foreign Affairs has said that the issue of Palestine should be resolved in accordance with the resolutions of the United Nations.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Two journalists from Arab countries also joined the conference, and they told about the latest situation in Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In Islamabad, students of the International University protested against the Israeli attacks on Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="14">The protesters were holding banners and placards, of which had anti-Israel slogans written on them.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Abstention from dieting in order to avoid Flu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This research from the American Scientists has come up after the experiments on rats.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It has been proven by experiments that rats put on diets with fewer calories were more prone to the Flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Research has proven the old myth  of fasting during fever wrong.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to scientists, one should eat a lot during fever.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The researchers from Michigan State University say that the rats that were dieting were not as able to resist the infection, and their chances of dying had increased.  Whereas rats on normal diets had better resistance against the Flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In many modern countries it has for sometime been fashionable to think that, by free education for all-whether rich or poor, clever or stupid- one can solve all the problems of the society.</seg>
    <seg id="8">But we can already see that free education for all is not enough; we find in such countries a far larger number of people with University degrees than there are jobs for them to fill.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Plan of Education Implemented in 1990.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Because of their degrees, they refuse to do what they think low work and in fact work with the hands is thought to be dirty and shameful in such countries.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The work of a completely uneducated farmer is far more important than that of a professor: we can live without education, but we die if we have no food. If no one cleaned our streets and took the rubbish away from our houses, we should get terrible diseases in our towns.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In fact, when we say that all of us must be educated to fit us for life, it means that we must be educated in such a way that, firstly, each of us can do whatever job is suited.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Education is not an end but a means to an end. In other words we do not educate children only for the purpose of educating them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">When men become organized in to very large groups, civilization develops.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It is possible to get freedom from hunger, thirsty, cold, heat and many diseases, so that each person can live a happier life than he could.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It means that we must be educated in such a way that, firstly, each of us can do whatever job is suited to his brain and ability, and secondly, that we can realize that all jobs are necessary to society and that it is very bad to be ashamed of ones work or to scorn someone else.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He said further that in May 1998, the atom bomb that Pakistan tested was made with care, and Pakistani scientists were completely trusted for it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">When Thomas Reed was asked if China supplied atomic technology to Pakistan, he replied that India is a mutual enemy of Pakistan and China.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said  evidence was also present that Dr. Abdul Qadir Khan had used the Chinese model. Later the Libyan documents confirmed this.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Another question was about mutual nuclear experiment. He replied that Anees Sonway openly performed a nuclear experiment in the desert of Nevada for Britain.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said Israel was predicted to have access to the results of this experiment.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Thomas Reeds was also asked if China was continuing nuclear proliferation.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On this Thomas Reeds said that China has been supplying raw material, instructions and the design to an Iranian nuclear facility in Asfahan.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Apart from this, China has also provided Iran with an enrichment plant in Kheeraj.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He said that China had been providing nuclear technology to Iran, Rome, Pakistan, Egypt, Libya and Yemen via North Korea.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">2008 the most successful year for Madonna.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This show was organized for Madonna's album 'Hard Candy' and it also included a Ukrainian gypsy band and Justin Timberlake's one or two songs.</seg>
    <seg id="3">An old racing car was also showed on the stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Celine Dion's show in the year 2008 was the second best show from the revenue point of view in which two hundred and thirty six million dollar's were made.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Canadian show 'Taking Chances' toured twenty four countries whereas Madonna toured only seventeen countries in her first tour in last eight years.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The director of  shows of both the singers was Jimmy King, who also organized the tour 'Reunion' or 'Spice Girls'.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Madonna has broken her own record in 2006</seg>
    <seg id="8">In 2006 in 'confession concerts' she made one hundred and ninety three million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Polestar has declared 'Bon Jovi' the third most successful singer who had made one hundred and seventy million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bruce Springsteen has made one hundred and sixty million dollars and he stands fourth, and Police stood fifth by making one hundred and twenty six million dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="11">According to a magazine in year 2008 very few people in North America had attended concerts and musical events and only those people participated who were willing to buy expensive tickets.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On the average, ticket prices increased by 8%; the most expensive Madonna ticket sold for $350.00.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Polester newspaper director, Gairi Bongiongi, said that despite the global economic recession, 2008 proved to be a good year for musicians.</seg>
    <seg id="14">It is anticipated that 2009 will be even better.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Taliban resists co-education</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Taliban members of the Hafiz Gul Bahadur group have distributed literature in  the area of North Wazeerastan Meeran Shah which contain threats governmental and civilian institutions which participate in co-education.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It was mentioned in the literature that if the co-educational institutions are not closed, action will be taken upon them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It was also mentioned that there would be restrictions on govt. help and the creation of student identification cards and women will be prevented from going to Nadra offices.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The announcement of the ban on women's identification cards was made by the Taliban at a time when, in North Wazeerastan, 200 women had submitted forms for Nadra identity cards for the Bay Nazir support program.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to the public that literature was read aloud in every mosque in North Wazeerastan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">However, it was mentioned in the letter that if the stop on non co-education or not.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the pamphlet, if after this announcement, a woman gets caught while out to get education or get an ID made, she and her family will be given serious punishment.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In the area of Bannu, the police say that a tunnel of gunpowder was blasted Sunday on Bannu Mir Insha Road. One pedestrian died and one was injured.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The injured were admitted to the Bannu civil hospital.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">More Dead Bodies Found in What Appear to be Target Killings</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Sunday morning, according to the police, two dead bodies were found in the areas of the main Mangora, Green Square, and Sohrab Khan square. The victims' heads were seperated from their bodies.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The deceased were said to have been related to Frontier Core and the police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">An eye witness said that a letter that contained a threat was found near the bodies. The letter claimed that whomever picks up the dead bodies before eleven in the morning would be responsible for his own death.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Locals report that the dead bodies lay in the market until eleven in the morning. Finally, security officials picked up both of the bodies and transported them to the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In the main city Mangora and surrounding areas, there has been a dangerous rise in target killing during the last few weeks.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In some of these target killings, local citizens, including women and security officials, have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to local sources, until now, more than thirty people were killed in such incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="9">No organization has accepted responsibility for these deaths yet.</seg>
    <seg id="10">On Saturday, the spokesperson for the local Taliban in Swat, Muslim Khan told BBC that among the bodies found on Friday, three belonged to his companions, among which the body of Dewli's Taliban commander Rafi'ullah was also included.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Muslim Khan said that Rafi'ullah was in the custody of the security forces for the last one and a half months.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He said that when the local Taliban kills anyone, first they send a notice to him, and on the other side a lot of confusion about such incidents occurring in Mengorah, is seen among the civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It is the statement of the local people, that heavy posting of security forces is found in Mengorah, but still, there is an increase on attacks on the civilians.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Benazir honored in a song by Bukhtawar</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A rap song (a type of new music), sung in the voice of Bukhtawar is now posted on YouTube.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this 5 minute song, photos and video clips of Benazir are shown.</seg>
    <seg id="4">18 year old Bukhtawar is a student of Edinburgh University.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He has a great Affection towards; Peotry and singing.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Said that, after the motivation from mother, he started singing peoms as a hobby.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He complemented her mother by words, he said "you was Beautiful and intelligent", and your work was there in a good way.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said you were shot dead on 27th december in your fore head, at the age of 54, She left 3 children alone.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The people are alone without you, and you are in the heart beat of every one.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Baqthawar Benazir Bhutto has the same position of benazir after 20 years, he was the 2nd Bhutto.</seg>
    <seg id="11">She was interested in the art of music from her childhood</seg>
    <seg id="12">He said that, "before his mother's return to home town, he was interested to meet the Grami Awarded Music Director Repref DD in America", but unabe to meet him.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The Sindi Newspaper has published translation of his poem, but his voice was heard with the help of Youtube for the first time.</seg>
    <seg id="14">The people around Benazir bhutto has realized the CD of his songs.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Farhatullah Babar, the spokesperson of PPP verified that a song presented on YouTube is sung and written by Bakhtawar .</seg>
    <seg id="16">He stated on the phone from Islamabad a tribute for a mourning daughter to her great mom. His statement was aired on a national television network.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar said that at the moment no plan was made by his party to distribute the CDs of Bakhtawar's song.</seg>
    <seg id="18">He stated that a fake account was made by Balawal Bhutto Zardari, a young chairman of his party, which later was  terminated.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ajmal Kasab is the Information Minister of Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Federal Minister for Information has verified via SMS to BBC that Amjal Kasab is a Pakistani citizen and further investigations are in process.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Earlier, Rehman Malik, advisor to the Prime Minister  denied the Pakistani citizenship of Kasab.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that NADRA's database does not contain any record of Ajmal.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It has not been established why the Government of Pakistan has changed its stance over the citizenship of Ajmal Kasab.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, according to the foreign office, the citizenship of Ajmal Kasab has been verified by the Interior Ministry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The BBC Urdu service and other media have alleged that Ajmal Qassab is from Farid Kot town of the Okara District in Punjab Province.</seg>
    <seg id="8">However, the government had been denying these claims.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It has not yet been established whether Ajmal Qassab is from Farid Kot or some other place.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Rockets fired from Lebanon bring bombardment in retaliation.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Israeli Army and Police officials have told media correspondents that 4 rockets were fired on Israeli territory from Lebanon, of which one fell into the town of Neharia in northern Israel, slightly injuring two people.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Israeli artillery has bombarded Lebanon in answer to the rockets fired from Lebanese territory.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It is not clear whether this attack was carried out by Hizbullah or the Palestinian groups active in Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Lebanese government says that it is also trying to determine who is behind these rocket attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">BBC correspondents have declared that this as a very dangerous development in the region's current situation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The BBC's editor for the Middle East, Jeremy Bowen, stated that because of these rocket attacks the danger of the war spreading has increased.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In the last few days, it was feared that the action going on in Gaza might spread to the Israeli border with Lebanon in the north.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Here, on the nights between Wednesday and Thursday, the Israeli army made 60 air attacks on the Gaza strip.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Israeli army, in these attacks, the police stations of Hamas, their tunnels, weapon stocks, rocket launching pads, and armed workers were targeted.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Apart from the air attacks, the Israeli army and the naval launching pad also bombarded Gaza all night.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Palestinian sources say that the air attacks have destroyed a mosque in Gaza city.</seg>
    <seg id="13">According to unconfirmed reports, the Israeli army tanks with air support from helicopters moved towards the region of Khan Younus.</seg>
    <seg id="14">In this war that has been going on for the last 12 days, about 700 people including a large number of women and children have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other side, 11 Israeli soldiers have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Israeli security forces have confirmed that a high defense agent, Amous Gilad, is going to Cairo to decide the conditions for ceasefire.</seg>
    <seg id="17">A delegation from Hamas is also going to Cairo to hold simultaneous dialog with the Egyptian diplomats.</seg>
    <seg id="18">beside that, leader of Palestinian Authority Mahmoud Abbas is reaching Cairo on friday.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">my heart is broken, return my kidney</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Richard Batistant told that he donated his kidney 24 years ago to his wife, Daniel to save her life.</seg>
    <seg id="3">according to news authority AFP, Dr. Batistan says that in favor of his kidney his wife has returned him a deception by loving someone else and now asking for a divorce</seg>
    <seg id="4">in an interview with regional newspaper Daily News, Dr. Batistan say that his wife's lover has drilled a hole in heart which still exists</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to lawyer of Dr. Richard Batistan, Dr. Richard is asking for the return of kidney but actually he is asking for the payment of his kidney.</seg>
    <seg id="6">according to his wife, she will deliver her opinion in few days in front of the judge</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">140 years ago, 9 kg Lobster was free</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">George the giant Lobster, was caught 2 weeks ago from the sea</seg>
    <seg id="3">the city's sea food company has bought this in 100 dollars</seg>
    <seg id="4">It also immediately started to use the pictures of the lobster for the sake of publicity.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, an animal preservation group called PETA demanded that they release the lobster. This led to it being released back into the sea.</seg>
    <seg id="6">George was captured from the sea in Canada and placed in the tank of the City Crab and Seafood Company for a period of ten days.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The age of the lobster can be estimated from its weight.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The manager of the restaurant, Keith Valenti, said that he did not want to harm the lobster and that he only kept him in the tank for the sake of pleasing his customers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Animal protection organization PETA leader Ingrid Newkirk said that they applaud the decision of the restaurant and say it serves as an example to those people who want to confine such intriguing animals to tiny tanks or boil them alive.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The search of a girl by mobile.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When officials came to know about Natalie Maltise, the police and firefighters of Athule, Massachusetts came alive.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The agents came to know about her exact location with the use of the GPS present in her mobile.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, with the use of Google Street View, it came to be known that she was in a hotel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">One week ago, Natalie's, Rose Maltise had taken Natalie away from the supervision of her legal parents.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Police Chief of Athule, Timothy Anderson, told BBC that she said that she will never return Natalie, and she left the state.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The police contacted Mrs. Maltise, but when she did not return Natalie, as promised, the police decided to trace Natalie using her mobile phone.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Since 2005, it is a rule in America that the mobile service providers must provide the location of 65% of the callers of more than 100 meters away and that of 95% of the callers of more than 300 meters away.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on Indian trip</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This is the second Indian visit for Hamid Karzai in the last 5 months.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is expected that, during this trip, he will speak to Prime Minister Manmohan Singh about the situation after the terrorist attacks in Mumbai.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this trip, he wants to express the feelings of Afghnistan and its public about the Mumbai attacks, and show its solidarity with India.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Apart from solidarity, Karzai will also discuss business during this trip.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is expected that the mutual help between the two countries, in eradicating extremism will be talked about.</seg>
    <seg id="7">During his last visit to India, Hamid Karzai said terrorism will not interfere with the relationship between India and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He also said that both India and Afghanistan will face the challenge of terrorism with mercilessness.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Strength and peace is beneficial for both countries and the entire world.</seg>
    <seg id="10">We understand this truth that both countries and the entire world can fight this curse only when united.</seg>
    <seg id="11"></seg>
    <seg id="12"></seg>
    <seg id="13"></seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2"></seg>
    <seg id="3"></seg>
    <seg id="4">Ajmal Qassab is under arrest and in police custody for the time being.  It is expected that police will launch a charge sheet against him before the 24th of January.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ajmal Qassab did not have a lawyer present for his defense.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Qassab appealed legal help in one written letter to the Pakistani government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">India gave evidence to Pakistan about the involvement of the Pakistani extremist in the Mumbai attack.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Pakistan accepted that Ajmal Qassab is a citizen of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to police, Ajmal Qassab's friend, Abu Al Ismail, ATS, Chief Hamunt Karkuray, and Police commissioner Ashoke Komantay expect to encounter Police inspector Vijay Salaskar include after killed police personal snatch scud car and runs away and than he arrested near form DB Marg Gargam Chupati.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Due to police action, Ismail Khan died, and police arrested Ajmal Qasam alive.</seg>
    <seg id="11">There is still no lawyer hired for Ajmal Qasab's case.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The one lawyer that was selected by government, Daneesh Muta, denied to accept the case on a moral basis.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Two lawyers took back there name after a protest by a political party and Contra-Remonstrance.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Legal committee formed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Tuesday in Islamabad he addressed a seminar on environmental changes. Afterward, he told the media that a meeting of the parliamentary party will be called to decide the formation of this committee.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that MQM had presented the bill to dissolve the 17th amendment. Others parties are planning to present their bills.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said, "to repeal the 17th amendment PPP, has sent a legal document to all political parties."</seg>
    <seg id="5">In response to a question, he said that the balance of powers between the PM and President would be decided by Parliament.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Prime Minister said that Parliament is sovereign to make decisions.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In response to another question, he said that Benazir and other political forces had also played a role in forcing Musharraf to step down as Army chief by convincing the international community.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that the Vice President of the United States, Joseph Biden, supports democracy in Pakistan. That is why he is awarded sitars imtiaz.</seg>
    <seg id="9">When asked about India's threat to cut off all relations with Pakistan, the PM said that this statement was given under  intense public pressure.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Protest against the removal of journalists</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Tuesday, the organization of journalists, RIUJ, held protests in front of the Islamabad Press Club of Journalists and Newspaper Workers against media owners and the government about the news channel and newspapers removing many of their employees.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking to the protesters, a senior member of Pakistan's biggest journalist organization, the Federal Union of Journalists,  C.R. Shamsi said, "The politicians who protested with us yesterday on the streets, today, have become rulers and are sitting in Parliament. Out of fear of a certain lobby of media owners, they are not doing anything for the rights of journalists."</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the newspaper owners who speak of human rights have made their offices houses of punishment and beggar camps, where despite their earnings of millions of Rupees per year, their workers are given meager wages, and by removing hundreds of said workers, they are killing them economically.</seg>
    <seg id="5">An example of this is before us, in the case of a worker for Channel 5, a private TV station in Lahore, who committed suicide after not receiving his salary for four months. Even today, due to being unfairly removed or not getting salaries for months, many workers are leading very difficult lives.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that there should be firm measures taken against the TV and newspaper owners, and the journalists should establish a protest camp in front of Parliament to fight for their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="7">C.R. Shamsi criticized the governor of Punjab, Salman Taseer, saying that employees were removed from the staff of his Urdu Newspaper 'Aaj Kal' without prior notice.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Whereas Junah Daily, Khabrein Daily, Channel 5, Burns Plus TV and Aaj TV have removed dozens of workers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Speaking to the protestors, the General Secretary of PUFJ said that today, throughout the country, journalist organizations will be observing a "black day" against the removal of journalists and newspaper workers, during which journalists will go to the Parliamentary session wearing black bands on their arms in an act of protest to get back their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Mazhar Abbas, they had receiver reports of 50% of Pakistani newspapers and TV channels in which the workers and journalists were being exploited, working without any agreement or contract.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that until now, more than 200 journalists and workers have been removed from newspapers and TV channels, and the current fear is that the owners will remove hundreds more in the present year while blaming it on the present financial crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas has said that the journalists' movement will continue unless the dismissed workers are allowed to return. Implementation of the seventh wage board responsible for determining the wages of employees of news papers and release of salaries of TV channels and newspaper employees' blocked since many months.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Eleven member cabinet has taken oath.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The new cabinet includes six ministers from the  anti-ex prime minister Sardar Atiq Ahmed Khan Muslim conference group, two from the Pakistani Peoples Party, two from the Peoples Muslim Conference and two from the Mutahida Qaumi Movement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The eleven member cabinet also includes a female member, who belongs to the anti-Atiq Muslim Conference group.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The ruling coalition has said that an expansion to the cabinet  will be made next week, and it is expected that a dozen more ministers will be added at that time. Earlier this month Sardar Atiq Khan was dismissed from the Prime Ministry through a vote of confidence and Sardar Yaqoob was elected as the new prime minister.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The ministers departments will be announced later on.</seg>
    <seg id="6">During the oath ceremony, the workers of the Pakistan Peoples Party raised slogans in favor of ex-prime minister Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Virus infects 3.5  million users.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The virus is known by the names Confecker, Down and Up and Kido. It was discovered for the first time in October 2008.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Despite Microsofts release of a patch to stop the virus, almost 3.5 million computer and memory sticks have been infected by it.</seg>
    <seg id="4">experts estimate that the number of affected computers are more than the suggested value.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In order to fix this poblem, users must use Microsoft's MS08067 patch.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Microsoft, this virus that has infected millions of computers, locates the services.exe file in windows and enter gets into its code.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Afterwards, this virus turns into a DLL file and locks itself into the System folder of windows.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It also create a name for this file as well.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Subsequently, it changes the registry details of the windows.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Once it is activated, this virus creates a problem that arises as an http server to change the restoration point of the system.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Next, it downloads the files from the maker's website.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to Microsoft, this virus has infected computers in different countries of the world.</seg>
    <seg id="13">This includes countries such as China, Brazil, Russia, India, America and Britain.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Great Advantages of a Statement</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">By his own nature as a man; this is my attack him, and death will certainly come to him sooner or later.</seg>
    <seg id="3">One man can become a doctor, knowing that others will grow food, makes clothes and build a house for him.</seg>
    <seg id="4">When men become organized into very large groups and civilization develops, it is possible to get away from hunger, thirst, cold, heat.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He can live happily with the others.</seg>
    <seg id="6">A man living absolutely alone in a desert or forest is free from other people; but he is not absolutely free.</seg>
    <seg id="7">His freedom is limited in several ways. Firstly, by the things around him such as wild animals or steep cliffs.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Secondly, by his own needs: he must have sleep, water, food and shelter from extreme heat or cold.</seg>
    <seg id="9">When men live together, on the one hand, each gets protection against wild animals easier and they can work together to get food and build shelters but each men has to give up some of his freedom.</seg>
    <seg id="10">I agree to respect the rights of others and in return they agree to respect mine.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In reply to a question, he said that the law enforcement agencies in India took 42 days to gather information about the guilty people in the Mumbai incident, so we hope that India, along with the global community will give Pakistan some time to verify this information.</seg>
    <seg id="12">They once again repeated the offer of the government to form a joint investigation team to research the Mumbai incident.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Let it be known, that a three member investigation team has been formed in the leadership of the Additional Director General of the FIA. The information about the Mumbai attacks given by India</seg>
    <seg id="14">to Pakistan, is being verified by this team.</seg>
    <seg id="15">The High Commissioner of Pakistan in India, Shahid Malik, met President Asif Ali Zardari, in which meeting the president made it clear that if any Pakistani group or individual is found guilty in the Mumbai attacks, action will be taken against them according to the country law, and no one would be handed over to India. This, when the Indian government is continuously pressuring Pakistan to hand over the guilty people to India.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Anything is possible in America'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mister Obama will take the oath on the 20th of January, to become America's 44th President.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Standing on the steps of the memorial built in the remembrance of the 16th American President, Abraham Lincoln, in Washington and giving a speech to the music concert,</seg>
    <seg id="4">mister Obama said that America is facing the most difficult challenges it has faced in many generations, and that he hopes that America can overcome those challenges.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Abraham Lincoln got rid of the tradition of slavery from India.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But at the same time Mr. Obama said that it will take time to solve problems that are facing the country and it is a tough road.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Nevertheless, I am hopeful that the dream of the founders of this country will live.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America, besides the wars of Iraq and Afghanistan, is fighting a great economic downfall.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Unusual steps are being taken for the ceremony of the oath taking.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Management thinks that 2 million people will attend this ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="11">America has a public holiday on Monday as on this same day the great leader of human rights Martin Luther King was assassinated.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Martin Luther King was black.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A tribute to Martin Luther King, The decision of doing work.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Martin Luther King was murdered in 1968.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barrack Obama paid tribute to Dr. Martin Luther King and told Americans to work together to fulfill the promises of this nation.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Preparations are under way for the new president's public inauguration ceremony to be held on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Nearly 2 million people are expected to attend this historic event.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On Monday, Barrack Obama began his day by visiting a medical center to meet with wounded American soldiers. After this he went to a shelter for homeless people and painted a wall there.</seg>
    <seg id="7">While talking to journalists the Obama said, "In the crisis that we are in, and the difficulties that our people are facing, we cant afford to sit idle."</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that Martin Luther King dedicated his life to serving the people.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Barrack Obama said, "today we are honoring the memories of him. This is not the day to just pause and think. It is the day to act."</seg>
    <seg id="10">Regarding the oath taking ceremony on Tuesday, Obama stated that it will have the same spirit as when many people gathered to hear the "I have a dream" speech of Martin Luther King, Jr. in 1963.</seg>
    <seg id="11">During that speech, Martin Luthar King said that a day will come when no discrimination will be made on the basis of one's skin color.</seg>
    <seg id="12">BBC's Matthew Price pointed out that it is a strange historical coincidence that Martin Luther King Day should fall on the day before the first black president of the U.S. will take his oath.</seg>
    <seg id="13">For many in the southern states, Barrack Obama's presidency will be a realization of Dr Luther King's dream.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Additional Politican has been freed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">10 days ago, an additional political agent was kidnapped by some unknown kidnappers in south Wazirisatan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Sources claim that the Mulla Nazir group of local Taliban is responsible for the kidnapping of the agent.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to local administration, the political agent, Aamir Latif was handed over to a scout camp by the tribal jirga.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It was not disclosed who was responsible for kidnapping of the political agent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, people of local tribes claim Mulla Nazir group of Taliban were responsible for kidnapping the Political agent.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Aamir Latif was kidnapped when he was traveling form wana to Tonk.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On the 11th of January 2009, the additional political agent Aamir Latif and his driver were kidnapped by 7 veiled gun men in the tribal area of South Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to govt. officials, kidnappers first disarmed the security guards of the political agents and then took him away from there.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Local administration, all the check posts in the area have been strengthened with more security forces. Travelers are being checked thoroughly. An economic sanction has been imposed on Wana for the last week.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the 8th of December, 2008, the Assistant Political Agent of North Waziristan was kidnapped while he went to celebrate the Eid vacation from Meer Ali to Banoo.A few days later, two people including District Officer Amanullah were killed by unidentified masked men.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A Britain hacker's victory in court.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A 42 year old England citizen admitted to hacking websites of the American army.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gary is suffering from Asperger syndrome. It must be known that patients suffering from Asperger syndrome have strong inclinations to do one certain thing.</seg>
    <seg id="4">His lawyers said that if he is handed over to America, it is possible that he would commit suicide.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, government advocates claim that there are very few threats to Gary's life.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Lord Justice Morse and Justice Simon said, while declaring the judgement said that Gary is given permission to ask a second chance from the Court of England.</seg>
    <seg id="7"></seg>
    <seg id="8">They further said that the Home Secretary did not study the matter.</seg>
    <seg id="9">However, the government advocates claimed that the Home Secretary had used his rights.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Gary never denied hacking the American army website.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Gary had hacked the American computer system in 2001 and 2002. Because of this the American government suffered a loss of $800,000.00.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Gary hacked 97 computers, including those of the American Navy and NASA.</seg>
    <seg id="13">However, Gary said he did not hack with any wrong intent. He said he was searching for information regarding extra- terrestrial creatures, which he believed that the American government had kept secret.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Gary's mother, Jane Sharp, said that she is happy with this decision.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Gary's lawyer said that this was a correct judgment.</seg>
    <seg id="16">This case was running since 2002, and finally a correct judgment was passed.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Two Hizb commanders dead.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The spokesperson of the Northern Command of the Indian Army posted in Jammu, Lieutenant Colonel Acharya, told BBC that, "According to a confirmed report, 24 National Rifles and Jammu police officers surrounded the parts of the Butty House Woods in Gandoh province of the Dodah district, in which the militants were supposed to be hiding.</seg>
    <seg id="3">They fired at the army and in the crossfire two armed extremists were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The spokesman said that one of the two killed extremists is district commander Zahoor-ud-din of prohibited Hizbul Mujahiddins, who was active for 12 years in the district and was an expert in gunpowder explosives.</seg>
    <seg id="5">His partner has been identified as Sajjad Hussain who, according to Army, was connected with extremists from last year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Acharia, the operation still continues in the mentioned jungle areas because, according to them, there is more possibility that there are more extremists there. Army says that two rifles were recovered in the first phase of the operation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Yesterday Provincial Head of police Kuldeep Kumar Khudda, while issuing statistics for the year 2008, established that this was the most peaceful year so far.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that there was no violence in the election of assembly, which was held in seven phases in November and December.</seg>
    <seg id="9">More than 1300 candidates participated in this election.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Be it known that Hizbul Mujahiddin has been active for the past eighteen years in Jammu-Kashimir.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On 12 July 2000, Hizb announced one sided cease fire for the first time.  After that there was talk between Government Hind(India) and Hizb Commanders.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Although cease fire ended in just fifteen days.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Afterwards, several elite commanders of Hizb-ul-Mujahddins were killed in different operations.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On Thursday, Pakistan's famous daily The News said regarding the extremist groups existing in the Pakistani-administered Kashmir, that Lashkare Taiba and Hizbul Mujahidin have decided to review the Kashmir policy.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Both organizations had a policy that the Kashmir dispute should be resolved through an armed resistance.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Dera Bugti: Blast Over the Gas Pipeline</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Police officials say that the 18 inch diameter pipeline going from Lui gas field to Peer Koh was blasted.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This pipeline goes towards the Sui plant.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Meanwhile, Sarbaz Baloch, presenting himself as a representative of the banned Baloch Republican army, has accepted the responsibility of the blast on behalf of his organization.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A fourth pipeline has been blasted in four days.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On Friday, an 18 inch diameter pipeline was blasted in Dera Allahyar, where repair work continued until Sunday morning.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Mushtaq Siddiqui, General Manager of Sui Southern Gas in Quetta, has said that supply from this pipeline will resume in the afternoon.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This pipeline reached Quetta through Sibbi.</seg>
    <seg id="9">There is a severe shortage of gas in Quetta, Ziarat and other surrounding areas for the past three days. On one hand, snowfall is continuing and temperature has fallen below the freezing point and on the other, hand heaters and stoves are out of gas.</seg>
    <seg id="10">In Dera Bugti city, there was a motorcycle blast on the mall road but the police claim that there was no loss of lives in this blast.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Jamaat Al-Dawa's Adminstrator</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The central headquarter of Jamaat Al dawa is in Muridkay, almost 25 Kilometers away from Lahore.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The center includes hospital, schools and student hostels.</seg>
    <seg id="4">As a law minister for Punjab, Rana Sanaullah has said that the posting of the administrator in Jammat al Dawa Center is to make sure that the social work being done over there is not affected.</seg>
    <seg id="5">the leader of Jamaat al Dawa Hafiz Saeed's son in law Khalid Waheed has told that for the supervision of the hospitals, schools and other welfare organizations a high government official has been appointed and according to him the number of police troops have also been increased.</seg>
    <seg id="6">the Security counsel of the United Nations have imposed sanctions on Jamaat al Dawa after which the Federal government of Pakistan have stared an operation across the country against Jamaat al Dawa and have put leaders including  the leader of the Jamaat Hafiz Saeed in House-Arrest.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Khaqan Babar belongs to the DMG or District Management Group.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Hafiz Khalid Waheed has told that on Sunday the Commissioner of Lahore Khusro Pervez Khan along with police and civil administration came to the Taiba Center and inspected its different parts. Khalid Waheed has disapproved the appointment of the administrator in the center of Jamaat al Dawa and said that due to the actions of the government, the number of patients in the hospitals and children in the schools of the center have already decreased.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Here, according to one press release of the council party, the council's prince Hafiz Saeed has written a letter to the United Nations General Secretary, Ban Ki Mon and to members of the committee. He asked to end the regularity made on the council by the peace convention.</seg>
    <seg id="10">In the letter it has said that the one sided decision of the peace convention on making the regularity on the council party was not fair and there is no connection of the council party with terrorism hence, they are busy in peace making work.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">On the Edhi Ghaza's Relief Mission</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">To enter in Ghaza after going through many procedures to gain permission, they finally reached Egypt starting from New York.</seg>
    <seg id="3">While in Cairo talking to the BBC's Urdu Service they had said that till now they haven't reached Ghaza because Egypt and Israel have created many hurdles.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that he had been here from eight days and until now, didn't get the permission to go to Ghaza.</seg>
    <seg id="5">I am still in Cairo and hope that tomorrow I will get permission to go to Ghaza.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said in detail "In the beginning I was given only a seven day visa to enter Ghaza and afterwards on my request, the governors of Pakistan had helped me and extended it to one month, but on one condition that I will only have a single entry to Ghaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that with him are his son and daughters and they want to do the relief work in Ghaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">I have come with some money.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Red Cross Egypt has been given a check of 100,000 dollars and 10,000 dollars in cash so it can send aid materials to Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Four new ministers added to the cabinet; totaling 63.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In four newly apponited federal ministers, two represent Mutahida Qaumi Movement(MQM) and two from the Jamiaiat-e-Uliyma Islam Fazal-ur-Rehman group.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Asif Ali Zardari took the oath from the new ministers.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In the oath taking ceremony, the Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani, and members of federal cabinet were present.</seg>
    <seg id="5">With the addition of four new ministers to the cabinet, the number of federal ministers, prime ministers and advisers have totaled to 63</seg>
    <seg id="6">MQM's representative ministers are Farooq Sattar and Babar Ghori, where as Jamiaiat-e-Uliyma Islam Fazal-ur-Rehman group is represented by ministers named Azam Suwati and Molana Ata-ur-Rehman .</seg>
    <seg id="7">Until now the ministries have not been finalized for these ministers.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Farooq Sattar is the convener of MQM, where as Babar Ghori is a senator. His term ends on March 10th</seg>
    <seg id="9">Azam Suwati is an independent candidate and was elected a senator and is one of the richest senators.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Moulana Ata-ur-Rahman is a member of the National Assembly and is also Moulana Fazal-ur-Rahman's younger brother.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Remember however, that four statesmen holding posts in important ministries are not members of the National Assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Note that the cabinet was expanded on 3rd November, 2008 with 22 new ministers and 18 national ministries added. So, at the time it was thought that the members of MQM would also be included but due to disagreements regarding the distribution of the ministries, MQM declined to be involved.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bolochistan, Blasted Pipeline</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police, the pipeline, which is 18 inches in diameter, connects different wells of Parekoh and meets the Suyi gas pipeline. It was blasted by unidentified men early in the morning.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In addition to this, yesterday well number 3 near Suyi was totally destroyed by a blast and also a gas pipeline near Dera-allayar was damaged due to a further explosion.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Militant organization Baloch republican army's spokeperson, Saryaz Baluch has accepted the responsibility of these blasts on behalf of his organization.</seg>
    <seg id="5">At the beginning of 2009, there was an increase in violent incidents in Baluchistan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">So far this month, several gas pipelines have been blasted.  Also, there has been an increase in the number of attacks on trains and against people from the Punjab region.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Even though the Prime Minister of Baluchistan, Nawab Aslam Rayisani, has expressed concern over such activities and ordered the police to exchange information with intelligence agencies, stopping such incidents has not yet been possible.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">819 billion dollars package for economic revival approved.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">All members of the Republican party voted against President Obama's plan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Members of the Republican party said that the economic plan is very expensive and will not prove effective.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In the members assembly, 240 votes were drawn in favor of this package, while 160 were drawn against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This economic revival plan will be presented next week in the Senate, where the ruling Democratic party has very little majority.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Concern is being expressed that great opposition from the Republican party may not make it easy for Senate approval.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After the economic revival plan was approved by the members assembly, Barrack Obama urged members to look past political differences, and work together on this plan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">President Obama said that this plan, which he was hopeful would become law by next month, will prove to create a peaceful atmosphere in the country, which will stimulate the American economy.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to this plan, working-class people will be relieved of 275 billion dollars worth of debt, and 540 billion dollars will be paid for roads, bridges, schools, unemployment allowance and research for new technology.</seg>
    <seg id="10">BBC writer Richard Luster in Washington has stated that Barrack Obama intended to introduce a new political culture by putting back the political disagreements but discussion this Economic Package has once again made political pillars sore.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Republican party members in the assembly declared the bill proposed by the government a waste of government money, and they said that this will not help in creating new jobs.</seg>
    <seg id="12">They insisted on the bill proposed by their party in which attention has been given to reduced taxes.</seg>
    <seg id="13">They said that through their package, less investment is required to create more chances of livelihood.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They said that instead of construction plans, reduced taxes can create more jobs instantly.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bitterness among Israeli president and Turkish Prime Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Rajab Tayyab Erdogan almost shouted at Israeli President and said that the blood of many people has been shed in Gaza. He felt sorrow watching that people can actually applaud this military action from Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Erdogan said that, "I think you are using such words to erase your guilt and that in a high voice. But you killed people and I am remembering those children who were killed near the shore."</seg>
    <seg id="4">Shamoon Parez said that Gaza's pain is not Israel, but that it is instead Hammas who has founded a dangerous dictatorship there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A correspondent of BBC from Davis said that nothing like this has been seen before in an international economic forum.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Although, Erdogan said later that he respects the Israeli president and also his age due to which he did not shout at him but what he was saying was miles away from truth.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Turkey is one of the few Islamic countries which have diplomatic relations with Israel, but for the last few years there has been tension between them.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The attacks were not planned in Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Speaking to Indian news channel NDTV, Wajid Shamsul Hasan, said that the report of the Pakistani investigations into the Mumbai blast will be prepared soon.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the attacks that took place in Mumbai last Novemeber, more than 170 people were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">India claims that extremist group Lashkar-e-Taiba is responsible for the attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">India also said that Pakistani "state factors" were responsible for the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Mumbai attacks affected relations between the two countries.</seg>
    <seg id="7">High commissioner Wajid Shamsul Hasan gave his first statement about the report of the Pakistani investigations, from which it becomes evident as to what is within the report.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wajid Shamsul Hasan said that as far as the investigation has deteremined, Pakistani land has not been used.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It must be some other place, not England.</seg>
    <seg id="10">These were the two places about which I was in doubt: Pakistan and Britain.</seg>
    <seg id="11">India and the global brotherhood has put considerable pressure on Pakistan to take action against the perpetrators of the Mumbai attacks. Pakistan says that it has arrested dozens of people during the action against groups which were clearly involved in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Wahid Shamsul Hasan said, "We are not trying to cover this up."</seg>
    <seg id="13">We believe in acting upon facts.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Our investigations will be accepted by the world.</seg>
    <seg id="15">We will try to satisfy India with the results [of the investigation].</seg>
    <seg id="16">Defending the delay in the Pakistani investigations, he said that to gather, understand and verify such matters takes time.</seg>
    <seg id="17">High Commissioner Wajid Shamsul Hasan said that India took 45 days to hand over its dossier.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Black person chosen as Republican leader as well.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the sixth round of elections of the Republican party, Michael Steele won, receiving 91 of 168 votes.</seg>
    <seg id="3">For the election in party the right candidate, Caton Dousin, has 70 votes, but the competitor, Jerman Duncon, is in second place running very close to him.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Micheal Steel is the number one candidate for the election of chairmain in Republican bari and he is on top among the other five candidates.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After the victory, Michael Steel is awarded by friends and word together, and he quoted that "Those who want to be with us come and those who want to interrupt should go away." Michael Steel is very much connected with his motherland.</seg>
    <seg id="6">They both know each other since they had stood in election for the seat in Sant.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But after the interference from Sant, he has been elected as chairman of Political conservant committee.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Now whatever the work of Republican Bari will be done, it all will be ordered and completed under the chairman of the party.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He has made promise that he will make victory to the party and those who walk together, he will try to add them to the party with new technique.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Proof of Lashkar-e-Toiba and Jaish-e-Mohammad in Jammu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">There is proof of the presense of terriosts in punch district of jammu.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to goverment sources, the police and intelligence department will start their searching operation there.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Meanwhile, a fight started in which 4 extremists, 2 tribunes and 1 policeman died.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to eyewitnesses, the fight continued until troops of Lashkar-e-Tayyaba and Jaish-e-Mohammad arrived. More soldiers have been sent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Chief Minister Umer Abdullah, appointed by conflate government, met with the Governor and told him about him being selected by his National Conference party.</seg>
    <seg id="7">National Conference's allied party Congress also informed the Governor about their support for Umer Abdullah.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Umer Abdullah will take the oath tomorrow as Chief Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In recent local elections, National Conference gained 28 seats to win. Those parties who supported separation opposed elections and boycotted it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Congress, who got 17 seats has agreed to make a combined government with National Conference.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Party members greeted Umer Abdullah with a warm welcome on his arrival today in Sri Nagar.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Umer Abdullah said he will play his role in patching up talks between Indian government and separation supporters. However, until the Indian elections and before the new government is elected, this will be difficult.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The European Union's role in Peace in the Middle East</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Looking it from the government's point of view, the efforts by the European Union to stop the war in the Middle East have been decisive.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to Brussels official position, the Shoarzan Berg group or Sarkozy's efforts are symbolic of the seriousness of the matter.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The European Commission's Spokeman, Amadeu Altafa, said that every effort is commendable and a unified message from the European Union can reach the warring sides.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In light of the government's statement all seems to be fine.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In reality the European Union is presenting a view of conflict amongst each other on this idea and that is very sad.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The European Union's President says the Czech Republic's role is already weak.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In addition to it, the internal turmoil has nullified the effect.</seg>
    <seg id="9">On the other hand, the French President's role seems to indicate he is still working as the president of the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This is despite the fact that France has expired its 6 month Presidential term.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Sarkozy wants to play a leader's role and he can, but he lacks the authorization.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The most funny situation is faced by the French foreign minister Bernard Kouchner.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He is part of a delegation which is headed by the foreign minister of Czech republic Schwarzenberg.</seg>
    <seg id="14">The problem is that both foreign ministers are issuing contradictory statements over the Middle East war.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Schwarzenberg says that Israel has the right of self defense whereas Kouchner says that this cannot be considered as a war for self defense. moreover Germany has sent its special ambassador to Middle East. Unless the European Union does not show unity based on common stance, it can not succeed on the diplomatic front.</seg>
    <seg id="16">The proof for this is,  Israeli behavior which does not care about the efforts for reconciliation from the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="17">this is a golden chance for the European Union to do something, since America; due to the policies of George W. Bush has already failed in the Middle East.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Financial Crisis: German industrialist billionaire commites Suicide</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Adolf Merckle, a resident of Sawabia in Southern Germany left a huge business group behind him.</seg>
    <seg id="3">but a short while ago, common German citizens did not know much about it.</seg>
    <seg id="4">when he had to negotiate with 30 banks who lent money to his industrial group, he became the topic of the headlines and he could foresee the murky future of the Merckle group.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Merkle group had to face a loss of a few hundred million Euros due to financial crisis after it bought shares in the German car manufacturing company, Volkswagen.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Financial institutions then refused to give it the new 700 and  one billion euro loan it needed immediately , so Merkle went into deep pressure.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Some time before that, the same bank was prepared to give it the immediate loan that it needed, but Adolf Merkel had gone from being a small producer, to having a yearly turnover of nearly 30 billion Euros, so he could not bear to lose his capitalistic power.</seg>
    <seg id="8">After the death of his father, Adolf Merkel took over his family business. He developed it quick, putting it on new lines.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He called his company Ratiopharm, which is a very successful and large pharmaceutical company in Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Until a while ago, the value of this business was between 5 and 6 billion Euros, and it still earns about 8.1 billion Euros a year.After the superb success of Ratiopharm,the  Merkel group started buying many other institutions which included construction supply manufacturing companies like Hydelburg Cement to car manufacturing companies like Kassbohrer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The number of employees of the Merkel group around the world is near 100,000 and its foundation company, the pharmaceutical Ratiopharm, always had special importance.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Adolf Merkel has said many times in his life: "It has been four generations since I started making medicine."</seg>
    <seg id="13">Now the management of this group is in the hands of my children and I hope that the management of this company will remain in my family for a few hundred years.</seg>
    <seg id="14">After the suicide of Adolf Merkel, banks have sanctioned 400 million Euros in floating loans for his group. But under the condition that VEM will have to sell Ratiopharm so that it could improve its financial conditions in the long term.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Therefore after Adolf Merkeley's demise the Merkeley Group which once existed came to an end.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">According to new statistics the crime rate among the immigrants in Germany if compared with other countries between 2004 and 2007 dropped from 22.9% to 21.4%.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2"></seg>
    <seg id="3"></seg>
    <seg id="4"></seg>
    <seg id="5">In the view of Joachim Herrmann the minister for home affairs of Baaveria it has been a positive change.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said: "It is to be noted that the number of aspirants seeking German citizenship has increased."</seg>
    <seg id="7">The statistics would have mentioned the fact that most of the persons indulging in the crimes are Germans.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Based on this a foreigner said "when statistics of crime was taken in his homeland in 2010 the above mentioned factors will be taken for consideration by Herrmann".</seg>
    <seg id="9">Mentions have been made in his letters about Humberg except Baaveria.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Christoph Ahlhaus, an internal affair's senator belong to CDU, said, ""When one does research in a scientific manner, then the results can not be predetermined. The results are based on the figures and numbers which are the outcome of the research.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Ahlhaus brought the attention towards an analysis report of 2006 prepared by a regional (provincial) office of Crime Prevention, in view of which it was calculated that in the crimes happening from bergdorf to hamburg, what is the percentage of foreigners involved.</seg>
    <seg id="12">From the results it was found out that the foreigners'</seg>
    <seg id="13">crime percentage is less compared to the overall crime rate of the whole province.</seg>
    <seg id="14">In contrast to this calculation, when in 2006 in Berlin, the teenage crime rates were analyzed, it was found that the teenagers witha foreign background was 7.44%</seg>
    <seg id="15">was 7.44 %</seg>
    <seg id="16">However certain political parties of Germany for example SPD, the environmentalist party The Greens, and the Left party Linkspartei (Die Linke), are against the idea of collecting information about whether certain German citizens are foreigners or not, at the same time as collecting facts about crimes and crime rates.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">We want the army to evacuate from Gaza soon : Olmert</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Ehud Olmert has insisted that the alliance of complete peace and no future war in return for evacuation of army is not unacceptable.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamas and Israel announced war this Sunday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Islamic militant organization, Hamas, has announced a cease fire for one week. Thay have asked the Israel Military to completely evacuate the Gaza Strip and to clear the check post completely.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On the other hand, Hamas' Leader Ismael Hani, says that in Gaza's War Isreals army got a victory because of the god.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He says that in Gaza's War, Israel was unable to fulfill his targets.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Before that in Egypt city Sharam-ul-Shiekh, on Sunday there was a meeting between European and Arab leader. They demanded that Israel evacuate the Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In the meeting it was decided that soon there will be World Conference on it.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In the meeting, German Chancellor Angelina Markel was also present.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The war between Israel and Hamas Militant which lasted for 3 weeks, killed almost 1300 Palestine, 10 soldiers and a total 13 Israelis.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the other side, Palestine President Mahmud Abbas urges to make a United Government in the Palestine area.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Al Qaidas' Video Message For Germany</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this 30 minute video, one man wearing black color turbine covering his face with a cloth and holding a gun, addresses the Government.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Abu Talha is introducing himself and speaking in German language.</seg>
    <seg id="4">There are Arabic sub-titles of this video message.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The logo of Al-Qaida  is on the side of the screen and the date written is October 2008.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In this message it is said to the German government that after deploying such a large number of troops in Afghanistan, this country is thinking that it will not be attacked. If it's not ingeniousness then what else?</seg>
    <seg id="7">Introducing himself as Abu Talha, this man however did not threaten to directly attack Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The number of German troops amongst the Allied NATO forces in Afghanistan is around 3500.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Last year the German parliament approved a bill to send one thousand more troops to Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This is the first message to Germany from Al-Qaida.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Having a critical eye on terrorism related issues, the famous expert Mikhail Luders says: "the recent suicide attack on the German embassy in Kabul is a proof of the fact that we should take it seriously in any case."</seg>
    <seg id="12">For the past few years Al-Qaida has been issuing video messages on the internet and there have been attacks after such messages.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The responsibility of the suicide bomb attack outside the German Embassy in Kabul has been accepted by the armed organization called the Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Most of the German magazines were associating these attacks with Al Qaeda.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They are targeting Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="16">The fundamentalist Muslims are seeing German Afghan policy as negative and discriminatory.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They are blaming Germany for keeping discriminatory policies, not only in Afghanistan, but in the Middle East also.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Because of this, they are considering Germany their target even more.</seg>
    <seg id="19">In the mean time, the German Government says that the German intelligence agencies already knew about this video before it came into the limelight.</seg>
    <seg id="20">The German Department for the Elimination of Crimes is busy in analyzing this video.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama has Taken Charge of the American Presidency</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">World has Developed Various Expectations for Obama</seg>
    <seg id="3">As Barak Obama is receiving Congratulation from all over the world for the presidency of United States of America; people are expecting more from him.</seg>
    <seg id="4">German Chancellor Angela Miracle expressed her confidence on the new president of the USA.</seg>
    <seg id="5">I am sure that Germany and the United State of America will cooperate with each other on the basis of friendship to solve common problems.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Russian Prime Minister Putin said that Obama is a serious and openhearted man and that is a good quality.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Previously he criticized Bush's policies.</seg>
    <seg id="8">But his administration is appreciated to be cooperative with China for constructive work. The new president of the USA will work for new military and strategic relation among both countries.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to German expert in politics, Govsi.</seg>
    <seg id="10">I am sure that Obama will put economical pressure on Beijing to put standard measure for the Chinese currency to collaborate with other currencies in market.</seg>
    <seg id="11">previous American administration made good relation with India.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Obama will further strengthen the relations but according to professor Christopher, Obama can't bring changes in one night.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In his message to Obama, Pope Benedict has stressed on peace and cooperation in the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Provincial elections in Iraq.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">These are the first elections since 2005 in this war-stricken country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">There are only 440 seats available in the provincial elections, but 14,400 candidate looking to fill those seats.</seg>
    <seg id="4">800,000 police and soldiers have been deployed in Iraq to keep peace during the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Iraqi borders were sealed on Friday to mitigate the effect of a terror attack occurring on election day.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Public transport was forbidden and part of the airport were closed as well.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Media reports indicate that the Iraqi children are playing football in the roads that are deserted due to the ban on traffic.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The security situation during recent elections will help in analyzing whether or not local security organizations will be able to keep the country under control after American withdrawal scheduled for 2011.  Political analysts are watching closely to see whether or not Iraqi people are ready to bring change through democratic elections.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Provincial elections are currently being held in Iraq with the help of the United Nations.  Approximately 800 international correspondents will be monitoring the elections.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Today, the Day of Aashura was celebrated throughout Iran in remembrance, respect and honor of the great sacrifice of the chief of all martyrs, Imam Hussain.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to Mehr news agency, all small and large cities, including the capital city of Tehran, witnessed the celebration of this day in respect to the chief of martyrs, Imam Husain, with great respect and honor. On this occasion, the believers gathered in great numbers in honorary gatherings and remembered the deaths of the Holy Prophet (PBUH) and his family members. Today, the whole country of Iran is mourning the great sacrifice of the martyrdom of the Prophet's grandson, Imam Hussain in the battlefield of Karbala. The believers are remembering this unmatched sacrifice and attending large honorary gatherings in his honor.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Retreat of Israeli soldiers from Ajleen province of Gaza: unmatched forbearance of Palestinian soldiers.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Urdu service of Mehr news agency, even on the 16th day of the fight between truth and falsehood in Gaza, there was beastly bombing by Israel on the city population of Gaza, by the use of air, land and naval attacks, in which 880 people have died so far.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Among the martyred are 275 innocent children, who have slept in the lap of death, smiling at the deception of the leaders of Arab countries and of so-called human rights organizations.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Today, the always ready to die, Mujahids of Ajeen province, have defeated the Israeli army, with the power of faith and martyrdom, and a show of amazing forbearance and steadfastness, tightening the collar of life, around the necks of the Zionist enemies.</seg>
    <seg id="5">If it were not for the deception of Egyptian president, Hasani (not) Mubarak, the brave and loyal Hamas Mujahids would have defeated Israel a long while ago, but apart from the Israeli siege, the Egyptians have also placed Palestinian Muslims under siege, which is the saddest story of Arab history.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Here, the Saudi Arabian and Jordanian governments are giving the Israeli government political and economic support, and are helping Israel by deceiving the helpless Muslims of Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barack Obama: America will use a new policy towards Iran.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report from Mehr news agency, the newly-elected president of America, Barack Obama, told ABC news channel, in an interview with them, that they would take a new approach towards the Iran dilemma.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama said that Iran would be a very big challenge for the American government.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that there is a dilemma with regard to Palestinian Islamic organizations Hamas and Hizbullah's support of Iran and Iran's nuclear enrichment program.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But he will not retain the policy of present American president George Bush with regards to Iran, but would adopt different policies for Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama said that he would make his actual goal completely clear, while stressing the hope for mutual respect and dialogue.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Barack Obama has mentioned in the past that no prerequisites will be set with regard to dialogue with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the interview, he expressed hope that his government would make quick policy decisions on Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Regarding the Middle East crisis, Obama said that he would form a special team.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It will start working on establishing peace in the Middle East from the 20th of January.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush, unable and disliked president Bush accepted his mistakes and crimes in his last press statement.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency related from Associated Press that the American president George Bush, in the last press conference of his term, accepted many of his mistakes and crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking during the press conference at the White House, President Bush said that though newly elected president Obama has good intentions, the biggest challenge facing him would be preventing possible attacks on America.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the completion of the Iraq mission and social security reforms were his mistakes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush said that whatever he did, he did it for the sake of protecting America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Upon being asked various questions about the Israeli inflictions on Gaza, President Bush said that Israel has the right to defend itself. According to him, Hamas does not have the right to defend itself and Hamas should not do anything to Israel, and like America, the whole world should choke the oppressed rather than the oppressor.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The incapable and despicable president of the United States said that Hamas should not be given weapons either, while America is providing Israel the world's most destructive weapons. Israel is using American weapons to massacre Palestinians and Bush also praised the Israel-supporting Arabs, calling them the friends of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Bush expressed shame at some of the crimes going on in the Abu Ghraib and Guantanamo prisons.</seg>
    <seg id="9">People are opining that cases should be filed against Bush for his war crimes, and that the organizations which manage to do this will have done a great service to humanity.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Iranian President Ahmedinejad expressed sorrow over the silence of the Arab leaders.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by Mehr News Agency, the Iranian President Mahmood Ahmadinejad criticized the Arab leaders' silence on the Israeli inhumanity and oppression on Gaza, expressing his sorrow.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmadinejad said, expressing surprise over the Arab countries and their leaders' silence over the beastly acts of Israel, that Israel is subjecting the Palestinian public to a holocaust. They are making the Palestinian children, women and civilians targets of their barbarianism, and the Arab leaders have not even given one statement.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The president Ahmade Nazad said that all Arab countries should unite against Israel and save the unjustly treated Muslims from evil and the unjust treatment of Irael.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The king of Saudi Arabia, Ahmade Nazad, should show his views on the killing of humanity by Israel in Ghaza.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to an expert news reportm President Mahmood Ahmade Zazad sent a message to the commander of Saudi Arabia, King Abdullah, that the silence of the Islamic king of Saudi Arabia about the killing of humanity by Israel in Ghaza (including killing innocent children and openly killing women) is encouraging the enemy of Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmade Nazad said in the message that they must really show their view and help the unjustly treated so as to remove the effort of Islamic enemies to cause disputes between Muslim Umma.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmade Nazad said in the message that you know that Israel has been killing humanity for 19 days and killing the innocent children openly and bombing houses, mosques, schools and hospitals and that non-Mulsims are killing openly and this is encouraged by Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Ahmade Nazad said to Abdullah that non-Muslim counties like Winrola and Bolive act against such doings of Israel and you should do this too.</seg>
    <seg id="6">President Ahmade Nazad said that there will be success for Falastini Muslims in Ghaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">And those unjustly treated will conquer over those doing unjust actions because it is the promise of Allah.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090116.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Goerge Bush is talking about the danger of terrorism on America.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">It is narrated by an expert German news reporter  that the American president George Bush said in his last speech to incoming Barak Obama that America is not safe from terrorism although is safer than it was seven years ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Bush said the terrorists are prepared to attack America and are waiting for the right moment and they have strong determination to attack. So America should not show any negligence for its national security.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The American President ignored the suffering of millions of Palestinian people and defended his aggressive and wrong policies. The American President said, America even today is the biggest country that supports freedom but the experts don't buy this idea and are of the opinion that this claim is not  realistic because not only America is not the flag bearer of freedom but also not a supporter of human rights. In fact America is the biggest terrorist country in the world that not only is supporting the barbaric Israeli Government but also directly involved with Israel in committing the crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Israel is committing massacre by slaughtering children, women and common people and America's President is praising him. This is the humanity and freedom the America that the world is witnessing in Gaza and other parts of the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Asama Hamadan in Philistine the dialog will continue to go on</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to news agency's report the spokesmen for Hamas in Labnon Asama Hamadan talking to French news agency said that Israel's one sided cease fire is against the United Nations initiative and until Israel is present in Gaza the cease fire is meaningless.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He further said that one sided cease fire was a failed attempt by the Israel to avoid a defeat. If Israel wanted sustainable peace then it would not only need to end the siege of Gaza but also accept the terms proposed by Hamas.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The representative of Hamas in Lebanon clarified further that if Israel proposed the one sided cease fire with the presence of Israeli troops in the belt of Gaza, Hamas will still continue to confront the Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In Beirut, attending a conference in solidarity with the Gaza people Asama Hamadan asked the European countries to discontinue diplomatic relations with Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The representative of Hamas said that with the increasing number of Martyrs and injured people in Gaza our resolve is getting even more stronger for our cause.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He emphasized on the Palestine people that they should be as a solid rock against the enemy and continue to resist strongly.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan: Taliban have killed 6 people in the Pakistani tribal region of north Waziristan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr news agency reports from Reuters that two Afghan civilians and four Pakistanis were killed after having been accused of being spies, by the Taliban, in the Pakistani tribal region of North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to reports the local people found four bullet ridden bodies in the Mir Ali province, at the Tahseel circle.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Two more bodies were found at central region Meeran Shah, which were disposed of in a market area.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Near the bodies were letters written in Urdu, in which it was claimed that these people were spies.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Two weeks ago, two Afghan natives were killed in the central region of North Waziristan, Meeran Shah, for having been spies.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In the last 12 days, 15 people were killed on the accusation of being spies for America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be known that within the last 6 years, more than 100 people were killed on the accusation of spying, in south and north Waziristan. Taliban is accused of being involved in such cases.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">It is expected that president Barack Obama will sign the order for closing down the most notorious Guatanamo Bay jail.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr news agency report sources to say that the American president will sign the order for closing down the most notorious Guatanamo Bay jail.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The newly elected American President has started to implement his election manifesto at the surface level.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Obama has asked to start planning for the exit of American army from Iraq. Today Obama will sign the executive order to seize Guantanamo Bay jail.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that after Obama's approval, Guantanamo Bay jail will be closed within a year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is expected that White House will review the investigative methods from suspected terrorists. Misbehavior with prisoners can also be banned.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Obama has started to implement his election manifesto on the very first day of his tenure. He has taken many steps to make the goverment transparent and functional.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Experts say that it is daunting task for Obama to restore the international image of the US. To obtain its lost credibility, America has to review its pro-Israel policies.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tony Blare Expressed Importance to Engage Hamas in Dialogue.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Former UK Prime Minister Says That Hamas' Participation is Must for Peace in Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to a local newspaper, Tony Blair is on a quest to find the right solution to bring peace in Middle East. He criticized the Bush Administration's attitude of negligence towards Hamas.  Western countries have realized the public and administrative power of Hamas. In past, Hamas was considered a terrorist organization, a terrorist organisation which is struggling for the freedom of its homeland while being immorally occupied by the Israel Government.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Baloch Businessmen Killed in Karachi.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Against the killing of the four traders of Baluchistan in Karachi, there was full strike on Thursday in Kwetta and other areas.</seg>
    <seg id="3">During this all the trading centers were kept closed and the traffic was less than normal.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The Union of Baluchistan Traders, the Pashtunkhuwah Public Party and the Islamic Ulema Committee has appealed for the strike, who have charged that the Karachi Police opened firing on these traders at the time when they were driving their car reaching near their cars showroom on Tarriq Road.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The leader of the Traders Union, Abdul Rahim Kakkar, asked to arrest the accused policemen of the incident and call an inquiry against them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Unfortunately, regarding the incident the role of the Karachi police was not recalled immediately.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The four traders who were killed belonged to the capital city Chaman.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the strike on behalf of the government security arrangements were made and the police were appointed to the main places of the whole city.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Israel Attack: Senior Commander of Hamas is Killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the Israel air strike, the senior commander of Hamas was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This was the second important personality of Hamas who was killed during the week long attacks of Israel on the lands of Ghaza.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The office bearer of Hamas has said that Abu Zakaria Al Jamal died on Saturday in the Al Shujahia street, located in the east of Gaza City.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In another air attack on Thursday, the scholar of Hamas Alam Nazar Rehan was also killed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Hamas expatriate leader living in Syria Khalid Mashal has shown his will to take revenge and warned Israel against ground attack.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Thousands of Israeli soldiers and tanks are located at Gaza Border and they are waiting for the orders to attack.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The Americans have appealed for the cease fire, but they have said that the decision whether to attack Gaza or not will be made by Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="9">President George Bush, in his weekly radio address has accused Hamas of increasing atrocities in order to aggravate the situation and termed it as Rocket Attacks on Israel as terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He has said that America is working for a cease fire but any one sided pact will not be acceptable.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Three Dead Bodies Recovered in North Waziristan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The officials of Pakistani security forces has said that the dead bodies three men have been recovered from the tribal area of North Waziristan</seg>
    <seg id="3">There is a doubt that Taliban has killed them by giving them death sentences.</seg>
    <seg id="4">These bodies were found near the capital city of north Waziristan, Meeran Shah, and such papers were found on them on which accusations of their spying for America were written.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officials say that perhaps one of these bodies belonged to the local person who was kidnapped last week.</seg>
    <seg id="6">They said that the two remaining bullet-ridden bodies belonged to Afghani citizens.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Israeli attacks continue for a tenth day, in Gaza.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Palestinian children were injured in Israeli missile attacks. All along the Gaza belt, the Israeli army is fighting against Hamas soldiers, while the Israeli air force is attacking suspected residences of the militant groups, for the tenth continuous day, in the region.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Israeli defense minister, Yahud Barak, said on Monday that the attacks will continue as long as the people of south Israel are not safe from Hamas rocket firing.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, despite Israeli attacks, the rocket firing from Hamas's side has continued, as a result of which four people died, including three civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hamas leader Mahmood Zuhr pressured his companions on Monday to destroy the Israeli army and target Israeli civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, Hamas leaders say that the organization is planning to send a delegation to Egypt, on Monday, to think over the new developments.</seg>
    <seg id="7">A wounded woman in Gaza. Medical sources say that over the last ten days, about 530 people have died, including the 11 people who died on Monday, of which 5 were children.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Israel has reported one soldier killed and 10 more injured in a ground attack.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Israel has stopped journalists from entering Gaza to do reporting on the military action.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Elected Vice President of America, Joseph Biden, has reached Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Foreign Minister welcomed the American Vice President.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The elected Vice President of America, along with his delegates, have reached Islamabad on Friday on a tour to Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Foreign Minister Shah Mehmood Qureshi, and higher officials of the American consulate, welcome them.</seg>
    <seg id="5">American senator Lindsy Graham is also accompanying Biden in his visit.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Press officer of the American embassy, Luo Fentern, told voice of America that the elected vice president will discuss different regional issues with Pakistani officials; but he restrained from giving more details.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Sources from Foreign Office say that apart from government officials, Joseph Biden will also meet the Chief of army staff; General Ashfaq Pervez Kiani.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is expected that apart from bilateral and global issuesl war on terror related issues will also be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Joseph Biden was awarded Hilal Imtiaz.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After arriving in Islamabad, Joe Biden met with President Asif Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In the meeting he was awarded with Hilal Imtiaz by President Zardari. He played an important role in building up friendly relations between America and Pakistan .</seg>
    <seg id="12">Joe Biden, head of the Foreign Relations Committee, along with Senator Richard Lugar introduced a bill indicating that the United States would increase defense to Pakistan to $5.7 billion in the next five years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">He played a major role in the impeachment of Perveiz Musharaf.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">yousaf raza and joeseph biden file photo. [not sure] but     possibly: Yousaf Raza and Joe Biden pose for a photo.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Prime Minister stated that the U.S. Vice President played an important role in  Perveiz musharafs impeachment to change the army chief's political stance. Joe Biden also had helped Pakistan in the restoration of democracy .</seg>
    <seg id="4">Yousaf Raza Gillani gave this statement while addressing the news reporters in the Karachi Shipyard.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He said  that Joe Biden is pro Pakistan or is in good relations with Pakistan . As the chairman of the foreign committee, he introduced a $15 billion aid bill for Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Once again we condemned the deadly missile attack by the American spy plane in Pakistani territory. The Prime Minister said that there is no treaty with America where they  were authorized in these kind of attacks.  According to the Prime Minister this is a matter of Pakistans integrity. How can we allow them to carry out these attacks  on our territory?</seg>
    <seg id="7">They also expressed the hope that after the new president came into power American policy would also be changed.</seg>
    <seg id="8">(File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="9">Yousuf Rza Gilani said that government get separated terrorist from ordinary tribes sucessfully but due to UAV missile air strike that made goverment effort worthless and it cause terrorist again enclose with tribes.</seg>
    <seg id="10">he said that International world accept Pakistan this averment.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Prime minister also said that if any trustful evidence given so Pakistani forces take action on there area by itself.</seg>
    <seg id="12">about Mumbai attack Pakistani prime minister resaid his averment that if India give evidence so according to that investigation would made and if some one found in this activity so take an action against him accourding to national law.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Reman Malik was on a tour of Britain. His reply to a question about his meeting with MQM leader Altaf Hussain was that he toured Britain by permission of the prime minister.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Queta, including DSP, four police men killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">File Photo.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On Siryab Road, the only main highway in Queta, an unknown shooter killed the DSP Deputy Superintendent of Police and four additional policemen.</seg>
    <seg id="4">On Wednesday morning 2 DSPS, a sub inspector, and two constables were  heading toward the police training center when they were attacked by unknown assailants, near a degree college on saryaab road. The attackers started shooting at their jeep for unknown reasons. Sub inspector, Marri, and Constables, Sibghat Ullah and Nasrullah, were killed instantly. One DSP, Hassan Ali, died right after reaching the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the hospital sources the other DSP, Ghulam Muhammad, who is severly injured, is in critical condition. He received bullet wounds on his head and neck.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After this incident police cordoned the entire area. As of now, no one has claimed the responsibility for the attack.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Death of another Indian software engineer in America.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In America another software engineer was killed by gun shots from unknown Assailants. He is from Andhra Pardash.</seg>
    <seg id="3">26 years old Akshay wishal who is from Sikandar Abad was killed 2 days ago by unknown assailants in the state of Arkansas. He died in the hospital, while getting medical treatment.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was a worker in Satyam computers and provided his services to Falcon Jet Airways.</seg>
    <seg id="5">During the last year 7 students from Andhra Pardash have been killed by the unsocial people.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Too many deaths has created a big concern for the families of thousand of those students, they are getting higher education or they are staying in America to look for a job.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It should be known in Andhra Pardash they prefer to go to America for higher education and for a better future.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In election,according to American councilate counting 100000 applications are received every year and from the the most are 40% from Uttar Pardaish.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Meanwhile, provincial govt. started the efforts to bring murdered to Hyderabad.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">America: Be Aware of Enemy Attack</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">President George Bush stressed in his last speech that America should be aware of enemy attack.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Bush said that the threat of danger for Americans exists from extremists and he relayed information that country enemies are waiting and are to attack.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The leaving president said that America must not stray from his safety.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush demonstrates these wants for coming president Obama, who will take the oath of President.</seg>
    <seg id="6">New elected President Barack Obama defined the importance of taking the oath for the democratic party.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that this function is a tradition which has a great relationship with the changing authorities from old President to coming.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Obama remembered that many people can not imagine that their leaders will leave leadership without a fight.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Shariff Brothers Meet with the Minister of Embassy and Ambassador</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">without anyone decisions, on Punjab, the biggest government, as well as Jamaat, Pakistan Muslim league Leader Nawaz Sharif and the Ambassodor Rahman Malick, has meet each other on sunday at Raiwindon, along with them the punjab chief minister Shahbaz Shariff also found.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Based on the local media, Rahman Malick brought some proposal from the Pakistan People Party.</seg>
    <seg id="4">After the meeting, Rahman Malick has not explained anything to the journalist. He just said that they might have a joined planned with all the political parties, and they will have  a discussion about the Mumbai attack briefing.</seg>
    <seg id="5">These are his words: till this what ever the things carried out we have got it.</seg>
    <seg id="6">This was carried out at Punjab. We dont have to forget. Instead, we have formed a team to complete this task but we need a big support from Punjab government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Rahman Malick said that the message can't be given to media daily. With the help of PML, the message is getting transferred. On other side the speaker of Pakistan Mislim league, Mr. Parvez Rashid did not blamed political matters and said only what Rahman Malick has said.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Came to know that, with the guidance of Pakistan muslim League, the meeting with Ambassador was in such situation that it is the hot news in political matters. Government of Punjab against 20 people who are having connection with the PML, The governer of Punjab declined the suggestion of PML during the conference. the governor of punjab has against the people who are having connection Pakistan people party is also</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama's Speech Supportive to Pakistan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani President Asif Ali Zardari has appreciated the presidential talk of Obama. He said that he will support the Muslim world. Pakistan will also support them to get both Pakistan and America benefited.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In a statement given on Wednesday, he said that "assurance of great ideologies and will of values from the American President is a hope of better future for the entire world".</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Zardari said that America, together with the international community, has  undoubtedly a great responsibility of finding new ways of peace, success and happiness in the 21st century.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After taking his oath on Tuesday, President Obama said in his opening speech that America wants a new development with the Muslim world which is based on mutual benefit and respect.</seg>
    <seg id="6">They made people of developing countries believe that America will work together with them so that there can be strong social development and a decline in poverty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Obama Assigns Richard Hall Brook as Special Representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Former ambassador of the UN Richard Hall Brook has been appointed as a Special Representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hall Brook played a very important role in the peace treaty between Bosnia and Herzegovina.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said he is ready to advise President Obama on the matters of Pakistan and Afghanistan's relations.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He added that this work is not easy.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that both countries have an extremely different history.</seg>
    <seg id="7">George Mitchell, who has been selected for the Middle East, will try to revive the Arab-Israeli dialogue.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mitchell is an ex-minister and played an important role in establishing peace in Northern Ireland.</seg>
    <seg id="9">While talking at the State Department today, he said that the situation in the Middle East is very vulnerable, complicated and dangerous.</seg>
    <seg id="10">But despite this, America will not step back from efforts for peace over there.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghanistan: Voters' registration in danger.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Election commission of Afghanistan: due to concerns over security, it is delaying voter registration in some areas in the south.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In southern Afghanistan, voter registration had to be started this week for the upcoming presidential election.</seg>
    <seg id="4">But the commission was told that, unless the security situation improves, voters in few areas of the Hilmand province will be unable to get registered.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In those parts of the south, repression has increased from last year, where the rebel Talibans have increased attacks on Afghans and international forces.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Meanwhile, Afghans and international forces have said that during the night, between Wednesday and Thursday, they had killed at least 28 militants during fights across Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">NATO states that its armies had killed 22 soldiers in land and air strikes in the western province of Khost, near the Pakistani border.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Previously, the Afghan Defense Ministry had stated that the Afghan army had killed eight rebels and injured two in the same province.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is not clear whether the Afghani representatives are speaking about the same incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090123.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Two missile attacks in Waziristan, at least 18 killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistan Intelligence officials have said that at least 18 people were killed in two doubtful American missile attacks in North Waziristan .</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the Waziristani officials, unmanned planes dropped three missiles on a house in the northern Mir province, killing ten people.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to local officials, five of the dead were non-national soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This region is considered the center of the Taliban and Al-Qaidah soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="6">A few hours after this incident, a missile attack was performed in south Waziristan as well, in which at least eight people died.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Despite the objections of the Pakistani government, about 30 missile attacks occurred in Pakistan since the middle of last year.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The present attacks were the first since President Barack Obama took office.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The Bush government had been avoiding acknowledging the attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="10">On Friday, suspected American spy planes dropped three missiles in the tribal region of North Waziristan. Five deaths have been reported.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The dead could not be identified.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to initial reports the missile attacks were on a house in the locality of Mir Ali.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It should be noted that these are the first missile attacks on the tribal regions of Pakistan since Barack Obama became president.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Sarhad state officials reject demand to restrict girls' education.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In Sarhad state, officials have rejected the Taliban's warning to restrict girls education, saying that this announcement is against both law and Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On Sunday, the education minister of Sarhad state, Sardar Husain Babar, added that the government will never allow such efforts to succeed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the extremists are attempting to deprive our region's children of education.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He said, "Secretly, these people try to demolish schools and threaten girls."</seg>
    <seg id="6">Talking about the terror and fear, he said that the government is fully aware of this and that no force can stop the spread of education in the land of Pakhtoons.</seg>
    <seg id="7">On January 15, the Taliban, under the command of Mulana Fazal-ul-allah, demanded the closing of schools for girls; otherwise they would be demolished.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Despite the military operation in Swat, more than 150 educational institutes have been burnt or destroyed by the extremists.</seg>
    <seg id="9">As a result of the destruction of these educational institutes, thousands of children have lost the means to seek knowledge.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tight security measures on the Republic day of India.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Indians will celebrate their 60th Republic day on Monday. Tight security arrangements have been made for the occasion.  Thousands of soldiers have been deployed in all parts of the country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On the Republic day of India, a grand parade is held and  fighter jets and military apparatus are exhibited.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to officials,  air guns and 'sharp shooters' have been deployed to strengthen the security arrangements. Police will monitor the routes used for the Parade. The American President congratulated India on this occasion.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He also sent good wishes to Indian PM Man Mohn Singh, who is recovering from heart surgery.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Indian police have claimed that two Pakistani combatants were killed after a fight near the outskirts of New Delhi.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Local authorities have stated that the police confiscated 47 rifles, grenades and some documents from the combatants that showed proof they were Pakistani combatants.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Authorities are also investigating if the two were members of the outlawed Laskhar-e-Tayyaba Party, which was involved in the Bombay attacks in November of last year.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Research Shows Tea May Be An Effective Cure Of Chest Cancer</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">New Research Indicates Drinking 3 Cups Of Tea Daily May Be An Effective Deterrent Of Chest Cancer</seg>
    <seg id="3">Tea Drinking Reduces The Risk Of Chest Cancer In Women Over 50 By 33%</seg>
    <seg id="4">Research At The Moffitt Cancer Center In Florida, U.S.A. Shows Tea Deters Chest Cancer In Women Over 50</seg>
    <seg id="5">Chest Cancer Is Reduced by 33% In Those Who Drink At Least Three Cups Of Tea Everyday</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is also told in the research that it does not help older women even if they drink three or more cups of tea daily.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Specialists think that this is because of the presence of such components in tea that are more effective against such types of cancer tumors, which usually targets women under 50 years of age.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Research was done on 5000 women who had treatment done for Chest Cancer at Moffitt  Cancer Center founded in city Tampa of State of Florida.    The Moffitt Cancer Center founded in Tampa, Florida, conducted research on 5000 women treated for breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Their ages are between 20 and 74 years.    The ages ranged from 20 to 74 years.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Specialists compared their medical records and lifestyle to those women who are free from chest cancer.    Medical records and lifestyles were compared between the women who had been treated for breast cancer, and those women who were cancer-free.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Specialists also came to know that tea had its prominent effect on one of the kinds of cancer, Lobes, and it was reduced by 66%.    Specialists discovered that cancer of the Lobes was reduced by 66 per cent when tea was consumed.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Every 10th chest cancer patient has this kind of cancer.    One in every ten cancer patients suffers from this type of cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="13">This type of chest cancer is dangerous because it is deep inside and usually diagnosed when it has spread alot.    Because this type of cancer is deep-seated it is dangerous, and usually is detected after it has become wide-spread.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Specialists say that having at least three cups of tea every day can readily reduce the chances of chest cancer in women of lesser age.    Specialists recommend consuming at least three cups of tea a day, which greatly reduces the chance of getting breast cancer for younger women.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They say that incorporating tea as a regular drink in your daily routine helps create immunity against the cancer.    In order to increase immunity to this type of cancer, it is suggested that tea be consumed as a routine part of a daily diet regimen.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Almost 40,000 women are diagnosed with chest cancer in Britain.    In Britain, nearly 40,000 women have been diagnosed with breast cancer.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">War in Afghanistan is the greatest army challenge facing America- Gates.    GATES CLAIMS AFGHAN WAR IS GREATEST CHALLENGE FACING AMERICA'S ARMY.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">American defense minister Robert Gates has said that the war in Afghanistan is the biggest military challenge faced by America.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gates will give a briefing today to the Senate and Parliament over the strategies of the Obama regime on Afghanistan and Iraq wars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Gates told the Armed Services committee of the Senate that fight is not the only solution to the Afghanistan issue. He added that in order to secure several areas, sufficient number of troops is not there, and the Talibans take advantage of that to carry out their activities.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">why reduce exercise with the age?</seg>
     <seg id="2">new research</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="3">Exercise at any age is good for health.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It energizes your heart, reduces the cholesterol level, helps in keeping the weight low, helps in preventing diabetes and slows down the process of Alzheimer's or dementia.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Unfortunately the ability to exercise reduces in many people with the age.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Experts say that exercise keep our body and brain active however age can affect it.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the American Medical Association, several health related problems can arise by not doing exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Dr. Patricia Palecca, of Mayo Clinic Minnesota, says that an increase in age is a major cause of inability to exercise and lack of bodily activity.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Dr. Patricia teaches medicine at Mayo Clinic.</seg>
    <seg id="10">She lead a study of how heart related diseases and the ability to exercise is related to old age.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The team of doctors used high frequency sound waves to measure the working of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The pumping of the blood by the heart - its contraction and relaxation - was studied.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The experts focused on the left part of the heart which is the main part for pumping blood.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They learned that as people grew older there was an increase in faults in the relaxation of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Dr. Patricia says that as age increases the faults in the relaxation of the heart begin to appear and this affects the ability to exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Dr. Garwin Cain was also a part of this study.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He says that they were surprised to see that there is a definite effect of this and that this clearly proves how deep of a relationship there is between the decrease of exercise and the relaxation of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Sometimes blood pressure can cause faults in the working of the heart and can become a cause of heart disease.</seg>
    <seg id="19">If the doctor and the patient work together on the faults of the heart they can achieve the benefits of exercise, despite the increase in age.</seg>
    <seg id="20">A detailed report of this has been published in the magazine of the American Medical Association.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">There are no chances of an immediate war with Pakistan: Indian Army Chief.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The chief of the Indian Army, General Deepak Kapoor, has stated that there is no chance of immediate war with Pakistan. However, to serve the country and protect its interests, they are always ready.</seg>
    <seg id="3">General Kapoor has made the accusation that despite ascertainments and the international pressure on Pakistan due to the Mumbai attacks, the terrorists structure is not only the same in Pakistan, but it is also active.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said this in an interview to journalists in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Indian Army Chief was on a one day trip to the Kashmir valley to inspect the situation of the overall security, which is under New Delhi's management, and to check the preparations of the armed forces at the border.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He was asked about the Mumbai attacks and his reaction to the media reports which state that Pakistan refuted the proof presented by India.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He stated, "The matters of peace and war are decided by the political leadership."</seg>
    <seg id="8">Talking about the presence of the skeleton of terrorism on the land of Pakistan,he said allegedly, that India would fight against such people who are ready to destroy peace and weaken India.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He said that there are around 7 to 800 fighters presented on the land of Indian Kashmir from which almost 50% were foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="10">General Deepak Kapoor said that only with the betterment in the weather, the efforts of encroachment between Pakistan and Kashmir under its government could be increased,  although India has increased security on the boarders.</seg>
    <seg id="11">They have refused to the possibility of reduction in the number of army soldiers in Indian Kashmir by stating that one can not compromise over the country's security.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May God answer the world's prayers and may Barrack Obama be beneficial for the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Though there is not much hope, but we shall see how the relationship between America and Pakistan , effected by this change, are in our favor.</seg>
     <seg id="3">That is what Mr. Barrack Obama will give to the world in the name of Martin Luther King's dreams.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The oath taking of Obama as the president of America, whose part of the name is also Hussain, is where historically important in all the ways, is also a great challenge for the history.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Not only for himself but also for those who supported him with all their hearts.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This challenge will also be for the white majority as it is not easy for them to accept that a colored man is ruling over them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Those here in South Asia, especially the Muslims, who have hopes about him, should remember that he was elected the president of America, and Obama should remember that the president of America is actually the president of the world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A little while back, a person whose real brothers were brought to America from their own countries, wearing the neckband of slavery, and whose blood and sweat watered the roots of the strongest country of the new era, today are representative of that very same targeted lineage that will be called the 44th President.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have many expectations from this man.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is necessary for those who admire him that they do not make unrealistic expectations about him.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If Obama is even successful in somewhat reducing the hate that is spread on lineage and religion-based lines, it will be a victory for his admirers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What effect will this change have on South Asia, and what considerable change can be expected in American policy in this regards?</seg>
     <seg id="2">How will these changes affect Pakistani-American relations?</seg>
     <seg id="3">?</seg>
     <seg id="4">My Sir, whether it be Obama or someone else, the type of policies with regards to the whole world, is decided by the multi-billion, influential, strong Jewish lobby.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As for Pakistan, with regards to the recent Mumbai blasts, the injurious actions taken by India, Israel and America have been seen by the whole world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even after the creation on Pakistan, the governance of Swat was in the hands of its own King who even had his own army and law.</seg>
     <seg id="2">With the help of an agreement, they transferred the administration of Swat to the Pakistan government.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But it's disheartening to know that our government treated Swat in the same way a step mother would treat another person's child.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the end of the governance of the King there were no more schools founded in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The areas of development were not given any notice.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Currently the number of girls acquiring education is far less than that of previous years.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Taliban are continuing their attacks on educational institutions in the NWFP.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Swat has suffered the highest number of schools destroyed and the majority of them have been girls schools.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Not just that-the Taliban have also announced a ban on education for girls.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thousands of students are being deprived of their rightful education.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What are your views about stopping girls' education and how it affects the the goals Taliban want to achieve?</seg>
     <seg id="6">The big question people are asking is, Why has the government failed to stop these illegal activities so far?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What actions do you think the government should take to stop these illegal activities.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The question should be that what ISI and Pakistani Agencies will work on solutions to the Taliban illegal activities.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Because the people of Swat believe that the game Army is corrupt and is there to serve the Taliban and not to kill or capture them. Otherwise how can five schools be bombed in a single night and all the bombings occur during the hours of Curfew. How come such atrocities such as; people being beheaded and people being hanged in the center of a crossroad during the hours of Curfew?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When the writ of the government is not being carried out and enforced, how can the government succeed in stopping these illegal activities?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now brings about the question why would have an armed force; armed with modern weapons, technologies and intelligence system that does not give the government the upper hand over the enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The only answer is that there is an alternate force and corruption within the government that prevents the capture or killing of Taliban insurgents.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The resulting discussion is that the Taliban with their wrong steps are making it easier for the imperialists to push Western Democracy on the people of Afghanistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fifteen years before the war was continued in Afghanistan the Russians were driven out of the country using arms and tactics from the West.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The ISI used to control the Taliban when there was opposition from the Northern Alliance, which was supported by Russia, India, and Iran.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Then, suddenly, the situation changed and the Taliban's works came to light.</seg>
     <seg id="4">ISI also got an offer of dollars from America, so the previous friend became an enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now the situation has changed, but the war is still going on and the countries supporting them in Pakistan are still Russia, India, and Iran.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Until man realizes what is wrong and what is right, he continues to make mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For instance, when a thief goes to steal something, if he realizes at that time that stealing is wrong, that it is a curse and it will bring punishment, and he fears Allah, then that person will not steal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Similarly, as long as Israel does not realize that it is doing wrong, and spilling the blood of the innocent, it will receive punishment for that and will continue to play with the blood of the innocent people in Gaza.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Greetings.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The question is whether or not war, armed resistance, and terrorism are the solution to problems?</seg>
     <seg id="3">If not, then what is the magic recipe that will bring out a solution to the problems?</seg>
     <seg id="4">This war is not right. It is destructive and increase our problems rather than solve it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Palestine, Afghanistan, Iraq should adopt these models in order to get their Independence, much like how Nelson Mandela freed his beloved country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">to fight more for socially and ethically, rather than with arms.</seg>
     <seg id="7">kashmiri's participation in election shows that they have accepted his point.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Israeli attacks have gone on for 3 weeks and the death toll have reached 1000.</seg>
     <seg id="2">world diplomacy efforts have not resulted in cease fire until now.</seg>
     <seg id="3">an according to a survey , after the dec. 27 attacks, 90,000 Palestine left their homes and moved to a safer place.</seg>
     <seg id="4">on the other hand, NGOs has accused Israel for not taking care of Palestinian children and added that these children will have serious phsycological and emotional problems.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What have you to say??</seg>
     <seg id="6">what do you think should to be done?</seg>
     <seg id="7">How is permanent peace possible in Gaza?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Click here for details.</seg>
     <seg id="9">(Please note that due to the increase of the number of comments, only the reviews typed in Urdu will be published.)</seg>
     <seg id="10">In order to select Urdu, press Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Taliban should be given a chance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">basit, Peshawar</seg>
     <seg id="3">Please wakeup! If the Taliban start doing the real Jihad, who will be responsible for killing innocent people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Who will burn down the girl's schools?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Who will do kidnapping for ransom.  If the ransom is not paid, who will blame people of being American agents and hang them on the towers?</seg>
     <seg id="6">These Taliban have brought created more damage to Islam that no nation or religion has ever created.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pashtoon Rore</seg>
     <seg id="8">Kohat, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If the whole Muslim world just give a joint threat to attack Israel, you will see  how upset its father, America, will be.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Immediately, not only talks on ceasefire, but ceasefire will really happen as well.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But what can be done? Where should our Muslim leaders bring the courage from?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Someone tell Ahmed Nayad to take the first step, as he is very popular for his bravery at the BBC forums.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The responsibility of peace and human rights not only lies on Arabs and the Muslim world but its an  obligation of the whole world to raise their voice against tyranny.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This unfortunate incident is Bush's worst sin so far.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Just like in Pakistan and India, before June 30th or the end of the fiscal year, the government institutions were looted. The American regime, just before its end, have given a green signal to Israel to do what ever it wants.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">America says that effort will be made for ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, the United Nation is passing one resolution over another but both have done practically nothing. This means that the United Nations is also working  to crush the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the Islamic Countries should cancel their membership in United Nations and they should lay the foundation of their own international organization.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Many examples are in front of us where only promises and resolutions of America and the United Nations came forward and only the Muslims suffered.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What is the advantage of these actions when BBC does not have to print anything?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now where have the principles of journalism been buried when the unrequired blood, especially of the Muslims, starts flowing and the ghost of unbiased reporting starts riding over the BBC?</seg>
     <seg id="3">It otherwise portrays itself as a flag bearer of righteousness.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Saying something from their side is a far away thing when they do not even want comments.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is from the Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The difference between you and the Jews is that they call themselves Jews and martyr the Muslims and people like you live among Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">[syja786]</seg>
     <seg id="3">Long time since, in the forums of BBC, a specific cult has been targeted sometimes in suicide attacks and sometimes in terrorism happening in India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Extremism is the favorite word for those anti-Islamic comments.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But by viewing the above comment, you can easily differentiate who is the actual extremist, in which almost a Fatwa of blasphemy has been pronounced for writing against Iran.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When will our Muslims understand that Dajjal cannot be fought with the help of sword?</seg>
     <seg id="2">After watching Israel's bombings on unarmed people, what would one's tear-filled heart do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the actual blame should go to terrorism and violence, which we state as Jihad and ruin the beautiful name of Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Since the majority of Palestinians have already accepted the existence of Israel, does it make sense for Hamas to fire rockets on Israel or do suicide attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Behavior from both side lacks humanity.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The character played by America and United Nations again showed us their support for the cruelties of Israel.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah grant us, the Muslims, a way to re-unite. Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And the real terrorists should be given the noble prize for this painful movement against terrorism.  After all, they are doing the real work.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise, is this large scale terrorism possible without the support of some big feudal presence? And everyone knows who these controllers are.</seg>
     <seg id="4">So in this situation, in common terms, it is called DADAGEERI, which means: do whatever you can.</seg>
     <seg id="5">That it even hits you hard on the head and does not even let you cry.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Medicines for the injured and coffins for the dead are being supplied by the Arab leaders and asked that</seg>
     <seg id="2">Should the Israeli attacks take place?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is the actual problem: that the leaders of Muslim countries, including the Saudi crown prince, are deluded. They neither have an army nor any plan for defense and just by providing aid, they think they have fulfilled their responsibilities.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They should take immediate measures against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="5">for example, stopping the supplies of petrol to European countries and America but alas they</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salam to all brothers and sisters!</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think at this hard time, advising Hammas to stop struggling in the name of peace, would be unjustified. With thousands of widows and millions of orphans, and it would be similar to prove them wrong.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If Israel and its followers are at peak of cruelty, then soon a revolution to stop all this is going to show up. This is the law of nature. America and Isreal's steps are bringing suicide bombers.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They can can not understand. They are blind in a trance of power.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Abu Abdullah, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now Hammas and Israel should become friends to stop blood shed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Muhammad Sarfaraz, Paris, France.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Very rightly said.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Assuming Hammas is 100% right and by fighting against malice it gets higher place in the eyes of God, even then, at least, they should realize if by good deeds, peace in others home is shattered, then that act is no longer a good deed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Those who claim to love God, His Prophet(P.B.U.H) and their religion,then to love humanity is part of their belief.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Consequently, after muslims confiscation of everybody on earth is Allah's order.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najibur Rehman Psycho, *Lahore* [P@KI@N]</seg>
     <seg id="3">There are no orders to destroy them, but they are invited to come to Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">However, Jihad has ordered against those who have conspiracies against their religion.</seg>
     <seg id="5">These people should be fought, unless they stop the conspiracies. Although, this doesn't mean that one should wear a jacket and blast himself at a gathering.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">For all my brothers, the only end to the killer of innocent children is destruction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I have asked my friends about the Israelis who did not have a place to shelter in past, about how they become so strong today and how about why they don't listen to any one? He stated that this is because the Jews are united.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There are no Shea's and Sunnis. They are just Jews and they have developed everything in every field.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In contrast, what is the condition of 55 Islamic countries?</seg>
     <seg id="5">These countries are behind in every field and they have become so helpless that the enemies are killing them to the point that they are just waiting for their death.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is essential that all Muslim countries unite and prepare a strategy against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Feroz Magsi, Jhang, Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">And there is no better strategy than to recognize Israel, learn through modern education the means of progress, and let the world live in peace and harmony.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Muslims have plenty of land and resources as well.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The need is for proper usage.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This first most disappointing factor is that Hamas and Alfateh could not unite.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Great leaders like Yasir Arafat and Sheikh Yasin were killed in an organized manner in order to weaken this brave nation which is doing Jihad for the Aqsa Mosque.  This was impossible without removing Yasin and Arafat.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The world is witnessing how Palestine has been scattered  after the death of these two leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And it's noticing how the Jewish lobby gradually kept strengthening its grip.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In 1974 a Pakistani prime minister was so trusted by the world that for the first time in history he managed to gather all the Muslim leaders under one roof with a hundred percent attendance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today, on his 81st birthday, the whole nation promises the very difficult task of seeking unity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Will the incomplete mission of forming a joint Islamic nation will be advanced while still removing the differences between the Muslims?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a Jinn, which has been inside Palestine for half a century.</seg>
     <seg id="2">That Jinn has many different opinions.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Often this Jinn calls itself bad names from one of its other mouths to divert the attention and reduce the pressure put on it by other governments.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is another mouth of this Jinn which is causing the unrest in Iraq, Afghanistan, Iran and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This Jinn fears Islam the most because it knows that whenever it is removed, only Islam, Mulsims, and the complete religion of Islam in its followers can remove it, as history proves that Islam has brought many Abu Jahls into practice.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The series of bombings of Gaza by Israeli war planes and missile strikes has been going on since the 27th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="2">More than three hundred Israeli citizens have died so far in these attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now, after the air strikes, Israeli tanks have reached the Gaza border in preparation for a land offensive.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Security Council of the United Nations, through an agreed  resolution passed in an emergency meeting, have demanded that Israeli and Palestinian authorities stop extremist activities immediately.</seg>
     <seg id="5">However, the Israeli authorities say that they will continue the operation in Gaza until they make sure that the rocket attacks on Israel have stopped.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In your opinion, is this claim of Israel true, that it's doing all this for defending the sovereignty of Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is the community playing its role in such situation?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Does this aggression have an indirect relation to the coming elections in Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Can any improvement be expected in the situation in the Middle East after the succession of the newly elected American President Barak Obama?</seg>
     <seg id="10">(Kindly note, that due to the increase in number of reviews, only those typed in Urdu will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="11">For this press Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard to select Urdu.)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Palestine will forever remain a sacred place for Muslims and its protection is a must for us.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We should also remember that it is also our Qibla e Awwal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel and India have to vanish one day since these countries are made to be broken. God will surely torment these disbelievers. Sajid Sadiq, Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="4">"When has a lonely night passed merely by weeping? When has misfortune departed by praying only?" (Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
     <seg id="5">"When has a lonely night passed merely by weeping? When has misfortune departed by praying only?" (Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The BBC makes it a point to dig out and publish such accounts.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After all, they have to maintain the illusion of neutrality.</seg>
     <seg id="3">By the way, BBC news is factual, but an essential factor is the tone in which the news is delivered.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Which news to be made prominent and which news to be considered as insignificant.</seg>
     <seg id="5">etc. etc.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="7">Now even the electronic media and printed media of Pakistan, specifically a few Urdu newspapers and columnists, are not behind anybody else in exhibiting this skill-- who, while giving coverage of the increasing extremism and terrorism, and while writing about it, hide facts about the grudge mafia.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It has been said that the United Nations seemingly supports human rights and peace but actually the Muslims are being subjected to extreme levels of cruelty and brutality. And what we hear from the United Nations is that Hamas should stop the attacks. How long will this hypocrisy carry on?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why there is so much atrocity committed on Muslims. If people like Americans are backing up the Jews then Allah Almighty had said that this nation will live a shabby life and this nation can never live a right life. So, Americans, if you have courage then stop supporting them and see then what their fate is.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">So-called writers and murderers in name of peace should understand that peace in the world can only be obtained through justice not through genocide.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If any nations perish through genocide and results of choice can be obtained then after actions of Hitler, existence of Jews and their uprising was impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As poet says.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Atrocity is atrocity, it vanishes when it rises.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Blood is blood, clots when drop.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now who will tell whom what is terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Is this comes in terrorism, why? because own pain is only felt.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Other people are not humans or blood of Muslims is so cheap or color of these innocents' blood was not red?</seg>
     <seg id="4">And now why there is no condolence message coming from anywhere?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I saw the terror act of Mumbai attacks as my own house was set on fire. It is painful to see the sufferings of humanity.   if such sufferings can not be seen by others. May the Muslims think collectively.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Dead bodies on the roads, helpless and wounded people stained with their own blood. How it should be condamned; words are too poor to express this condemnation.</seg>
     <seg id="2">My heart is crying over the miseries and helplessness of Muslims. On one hand People are being killed in India and on the other hand, without any solid proof, whole world is pressing Pakistan to do more or we will do it ourselves.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the other side Israel is killing Muslims. The silence of the world is intolerable.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It may be delayed but God will surely do the justice to end the dominance of falsehood.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A threat to Israel's security in the presence of United States, no way! it is a joke.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In Israel, such tactics are used by ruling party to achieve public support.Historically no president was powerful enough to change American policies.Barrack Obama is no exception. Forces of Exploitation are similar in their character; whether they are black or white.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In this forum discussion, it is clear that every body is mourning the death of Benazir but she is not forgiven for her political mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is debatable whether Benazir died for democracy or for the lust of Power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If Democracy was her motto then why did not she come before American clearance and deal? Whey did she leave democracy under the control of Musharraf's dictatorship for 10 years?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir did not come to Pakistan when the public needed her. Unfortunately, she came at a time when her acquittal from her cases and her supremacy was promised.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When each and every historic personality is being accused, there is no one to say anything about this.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="3">Few things are ignored thinking that nothing can be done about them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Another reader.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir, probably you should not only study Pakistan's history but that of 4 friends and 7 other countries. Maybe you would agree with Psycho's point of view.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tariq Ayaz</seg>
     <seg id="7">"Those who don't have a good nature can't be corrected through training."</seg>
     <seg id="8">Living green in the water made the reflection of the wheat plant look like a cypress.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Britain never let them unite and established the Hindu-Muslim conflict which was later on brought up by Sir Syed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">psycho</seg>
     <seg id="3">How brutal is our nation?  Not only we are blind while writing odes on ourselves and our parties, but now we are picking, accusing and criticizing every historical scholar and no body is there to say any thing about it.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Enough of development that we have made.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="6">Few things are ignored just by thinking that nothing can be done with them. Just like a donkey can not become a scholar by just loading books onto it.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Because of the Mumbai attacks, there has been a setback in the dialog between Pakistan and India.  However, Pakistan and India should continue these dialogs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If we talk of war then it will bring loss of life on both sides.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India says that the man caught in the Mumbai attacks is a Pakistani citizen and he has written a letter to Pakistan in Urdu.  On the other hand, when India initially apprehended this extremist, they said he is a great engineer.  Shortly afterwards he was declared as a 4th grader; point to be noted.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First of all Merry Christmas to Mr. Bhana and to all the Christian brothers of the forum.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Greeting to all friends of the Forum: Mr. Psycho, A. Raza, Sister Sana, Sister Shahida and Mr. Akram.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We want flowers of peace rather in the flame of war.</seg>
     <seg id="4">War is, itself, a problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What solution will the war give?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Today, will give Fire and blood.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Tomorrow, will give hunger and necessity.</seg>
     <seg id="8">For this wise people,</seg>
     <seg id="9">it is better that war keeps postponing.</seg>
     <seg id="10">In your and our garden.</seg>
     <seg id="11">It is better that candle keeps lit.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The relationship of India and America have become deep and India knows that when the time comes America will openly deceive Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is the old history of America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">However, America will gain its aims in the Indian attack and the India will bear all the costs.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan should announce clearly that they will not attack first, but if the first attack comes from India then there will be no peace until India will be abolished and occupied andd there will be on one to  care for all our killing.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is the Islamic history</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">.  Before this approval, Pakistani public and force spoke for what they wanted.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Indian efforts of receiving extra-ordinary ambassador and force benefits in fulfilling Mambai attacks are making It clever party mare than impress so after the first world hard opposite action decreased on Pakistan by the world.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The display to the United States and increasing status of the president of Interpol's peace of mind at Pakistani efforts by avoiding unnecessary noise of India is the side effect of the extra ambassador of India.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There are no two sayings about this dishonest action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But the question is where was the Pakistani force and what was doing when thousands Talibans attacked at the village of Pir Same-u-Llah?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Should the contentedness of force not be in action that what they did was for their country.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Every day thousands of missiles and bombs has been detonated. How many Taliban citizens has been killed?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I am Requesting of ISI, for God's sake: leave the Guardianship of Taliban and let us live with peace and happiness in our Heaven.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And stop this fake Operation</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In National Unity the day is not too far away when in Pakistan the military affirmative will be passed as it has been passed against jamiat-ul-dawa</seg>
     <seg id="2">Riyaz Ahmed Farooqui.</seg>
     <seg id="3">First our lovers of intemperance and their supporters are continuously collecting the evidence for legal action.  Any day affirmation comes through then there are many possibilities that in this National Unity there will be no one to speak up to voice support for us.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If supposing there is any delay for Affirmative to pass then we can keep an example of America in the forefront so that any one of  power will join us to walk with us.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We dont have the consciousness and knowledge of Peer Sami ul llah his personality and his adventures- and what work he was busy in,</seg>
     <seg id="2">probably he was not a revolutionary.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As Kamri Dach Gaveera, Nawab Akbar Khan Bagti, Dr Najeeb ul llah and thousands of Revolutionarys Dead bodies has been disgraced by enemyhands</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are still in command after death.</seg>
     <seg id="5">There is an international game being played over here. They rule by scaring the public about beastliness and terror.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Would it be permissible for them to say that if we are not there, beasts and wild people will come and capture the government?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Such actions in the name of religion of the so-called Islam lovers is extremely disagreeable.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The supporters of these fundamentalists can see the oppression of America, but instead of being sorry about such beastly actions, they give it the name of tribal traditions and avoid it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Any person with a heart can never accept these beastly actions, done sometimes in the name of tribal traditions, while others are done in the name of Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I think our army has joint these people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">When these people move around, some time will have to be taken. Catching them will only take so much time. But even if they were there, forget about that spot because they escape from there.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are these people so brave that they take 50 or 70 people hostage and our army watches like an audience with hand on hand?</seg>
     <seg id="4">They, as well as the army, are also servants of Allah.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is clear that something is sinister.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Ziya-ul-Haqq's dictatorship, instead of presenting the Noble and Merciful characters of God, an atmosphere of anti-religion was created by the use of many types of narrations of punishments apart from the incident of the body hanging. Even the literature and books like, 'What will happen when we die?' created fear and terror.</seg>
     <seg id="2">These people are only using this fear as a tool or a weapon to gain worldly pleasures and honor.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Preachers!</seg>
     <seg id="4">As you have preached against the fire of Hell</seg>
     <seg id="5">that you have yourself become the face of fear.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is surprising when it is said that this can not be a work of a Muslim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We are either unaware of our own history or we ignore it for some reason.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Upon the death of the Prophet and refusing to pledge allegiance, who burnt the Messenger's daughter's door and pulled her husband out with a rope around his neck?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Did they come from somewhere outside?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Was the strike on Madeena and Great Karbala the work of Hindus and Jews?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Without the submission of the truth nor the movement was away neither the check.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC people close quadrant policy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The title for this incident: "Was it legal or illegal to hit Bush with the shoes?"</seg>
     <seg id="3">It was meant to be.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Tahir Choudry, Japan</seg>
     <seg id="5">Friend, have some shame that a human being was taken from the grave and hung on a pole just because he raised his voice against the wrongdoing and you are only concerned about the box office title.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">For the victory of the operation Sherdil and on the other side of the border the victorious invasion of the operation lion heart is dependable that on whose favor is the opinion of normal people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Peer Sahib was the target of this conspiracy led by American and Pakistan agencies.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the criticism is now going to be directed against the Taaliban because undercover people have infiltrated the Taaliban very successfully and they are taking steps to encourage normal people to change their opinions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I only have one thing to ask - what were the police doing when that dead body was just hanging there the whole day? Are they in this country to kill normal civilians like these two children and their mother, who are dead thanks to Taliban bombing people's houses?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Were they not know about that chowk?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Or they were seeing an action film?</seg>
     <seg id="4">We say stop these stupid games, for Allah's sake.</seg>
     <seg id="5">At last there is a commander upon you also.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A question raised from BBS if it is not reasonable but alas on the sow thinking of writers,.for example it was asked from any person that for what purpose the force went Swaaat containing 30000 persons.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The dead bodies of the helpers of force fighting with the Taliban remained hanging on poles all day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What did the Pakistani Force do to help the people of Swat? How did the media or the BBC or the world knowing about this do anything to help? It was not good.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Pakistani Force is just making things up to sound worse.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Every child of Swaat is saying that this is a bloodbath.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Please stop this drama, for god's sake.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Taliban has destroyed the name of Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If the pure Muslims of whole world tell them: as a Muslim, they wont get any place to live for the terror.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Those that are not interested in working and not interested in living peaceful life take guns and join those people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Islam has not come under the pressure of guns or swords.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Shame on you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no reason for this in any religion or in any family.</seg>
     <seg id="2">BBC, along with other media, has gathered information about the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the reality is not even known to anyone. That is the real situation. We only know because we are tribal.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Bssically, it is a game in which CIA, RAW, MOSAD, and our ISI, are involved. There is no one in from the Taliban or from tribal. Terror was created from the above agencies, who are insulting the Taliban, Islam, Madarsa's, Pestos, and Tribals</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Because of this action Muslims had their heads down with shyness.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I salute MQM Leader Altaf Hussain, ANP and PPP leaders who are against this cancer it means united talks against Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This cancer created by Ziaulhaq, he left the government but, also desires to destroy Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I am hopeful that a large number of the Pakistani leadership will work together to end this cancer within the nations government.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">India after Mumbai the attack said that the attack was the work of Pakistani extremists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan denies the blames and said it will give all possible assistance to India in interrogation.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India said that it will provide list to Pakistan officials that contains the names of the suspects linked to the extremist group believed to be responsible for the attacks in India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan said that Jaish Muhammad Leader, Mulana Masood Azhar has gone into hiding and they did not have any information about him.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Before this list was given to Pakistan, the Pakistani president Asif Ali Zardari did not want to receive information from western secret agencies and Indian government concerning evidence linking Pakistan to the  Mumbai attack.</seg>
     <seg id="6">President Zardari stated that no evidence proves that Ajmal Qasaab is a Pakistani National.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Meanwhile, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has warned Pakistan that its relation with India can not improve unless its land is being used for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In a recent development, the Indian cricket team has cancelled its tour to Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should these political events affect sports?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What do you see as the future of Pakistan and India relations?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Neither America will break Pakistan nor India.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan will be broken by Pakistanis themselves.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This to be expected because of the widespread practices of provincialism, sectarianism, and Mullaism.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Proof that  Jinnah also did not treat the Muslims of India so well has been evident over a period of time.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Yasmin, Chicago.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Madam, If  Mr. Jinnah's vision had been realized, neither the cancer of provincialism, sectarianism, and Mullaism would have  spread in Pakistan nor would the Muslims in India have displayed such behavior.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It's our fault that we could not bring up a leader of his stature.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If we can not care for our heroes, then</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">this region has great capabilities.</seg>
     <seg id="2">God knows when we'll understand and the region will progress with the blessing of unity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In both countries, enemies of peace like Mullas, Pandits, Taliban, Shiv sena, RSS have been raised.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The evil powers don't want this region to progress, therefore these countries are controlled like puppets.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can you imagine what status this region of Pakistan, India and China will have in the world?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Pakistan is under persecution from God that these thieves, bandits and criminals have been imposed as leaders of the nation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah protect our country from any harm, Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But sir, open your eyes to see the surrounding situation and reality on the ground, and you will figure out how far American forces have penetrated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Other than that National matter are not looking good as well, circumstances in Sarhad, Balochistan, Karachi in Sindh are in front of you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In this situation, the country needs a leader who can unite us as a single Nation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">O Allah, have mercy on us.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, there is no way other than a last war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Too much has happened.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now this affair has to win or lose.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This problem will not be solved with hypocrisy and deceit.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And neither with small big terrorism in each other countries.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Even Europe rested after fighting the last great war.</seg>
     <seg id="7">And if this great war had not happened, then they  would be chattering like Pakistan and India.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Almost all our political parties agree that terrorism and factionalism should be stopped.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But our military leadership does not seem to be sincere in these regards. On the one hand, America and Europe are ascertained that we are with them in their war against terrorism, and on the other hand we secretly help the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We should think and fix our direction and choose only one side.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no doubt that the majority of the workers of Jama'athud Da'wah are the previous members of Lashkar-e-Taiba who joined the group called Jama'athud Da'wah Pakistan after Lashkar-e-Taiba was rendered inexistent.</seg>
     <seg id="2">However, after that, the members gave preference to social work.  Even now Jama'athud Da'wah was rendered inexistent by the United Nations due to the pressure applied by India and the crackdown being enforced by the Pakistani government.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I believe that if Jihadi groups leave religious fundamentalism and take up social efforts that would be better.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The present terrorist groups that bring up criminals in the name of Jihad, and the elders of these Mullas, are the same people who used to call Pakistan 'Palidistan', and other derogatory terms.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now they are not leaving any stone unturned in the quest to destroy Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These people are not even fit to be called human beings, let alone 'Muslims'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Without cleaning Pakistan of these mischief mongers, the national security will remain at risk.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can we still think about whether or not to put a ban on these trouble makers?</seg>
     <seg id="6">There is no place on earth for extremist Mullahs whose only work is to cause killings.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This news tore my heart.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What kind of world is this? In which it has become difficult for those who even take the name of one of the important parts of the religion of Allah, Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Non-Muslims can kill Muslims, but if a Muslim even tries to extract revenge, along with the whole non-Muslim world, even the hypocrite leaders join and treat those who have sincere religious feeling in the manner our great leaders are treating Hafiz Saeed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the Mumbai attacks, Indo-</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pak relationships turned sour, the proximity between the two countries forming after many years, has suffered a severe setback for the first time.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India has always claimed that militant and non-militant groups which are active in Pakistan were responsible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">For the relationships to return to normal; taking action against these countries is being made a prerequisite.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whereas Indian security agencies have accused Lashkar-e-Taiba of being directly responsible for the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The name of Jama'athud Da'wah also comes up many times in this regard.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is not the first time that relationships between the two countries have become strained due to some terrorist activity that took place in India.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In December 2001, after the attack on the parliament, the two neighbors were prepared to go to war.</seg>
     <seg id="9">After that, Lashkar-e-Taiba was banned and it was included in the list of terrorist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Now, it is being demanded that Jama'athud Da'wah, which according to security reports, is just a new form of Lashkar-e-Taiba, also be banned.</seg>
     <seg id="11">In your opinion, should this group be banned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Should Pakistan take decisive action against the active fundamentalist groups within its boundaries?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Can putting a ban on Jama'athud Da'wah help the present Indo-</seg>
     <seg id="14">Pak crisis to subside, and how important is it for permanent peace between the two countries that armed groups be dismantled?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Security Council of the United Nations has passed the ban on Jama'athud Da'wah. However, what proof did the Security Council have on which to base such urgency?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Does the Security Council always show this type of urgency dealing with the Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is what they call a slow complainant and a fast witness.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If you think about it, even India has become an unsuccessful state.</seg>
     <seg id="5">whose intelligence, army and security institutes failed, and were brought to their knees by a few terrorists for three days. And India wants to put the blame for its inability on Pakistan, to fool the whole world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When one disbeliever dies, there is an uproar the whole world over. Why these double standards?</seg>
     <seg id="2">To a non political, religious and social organisation of our dear country---</seg>
     <seg id="3">Furqan Farooq, Faisalabad</seg>
     <seg id="4">As long as our Prophet (PBUH), the Awliya Kiram and the Sufis continued to teach people the lesson of love and respect, the religion of Islam would spread and prosper with peace.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Muslims have also advanced in every field.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But when Mullahism rose in popularity in the religion, the people were divided into Muslims and Kafirs, and new avenues of mischief were opened, which were not known to the world previously.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salam: Please do it with pleasure but act on your own.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Do not do it under American pressure.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If India is aggrieved, it should provide the evidence.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why doesn't it give it?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And why does it accuse us of everything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">There are extremist groups and organizations in India as well. Why don't they put sanctions on them?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are we the only terrorist in the world?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What India is doing in Kashmir, what is that?</seg>
     <seg id="9">What Israel is doing, what is that?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The truth is, we are the first nuclear Muslim state. Why is this the main issue?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is now in last steps.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Kamran Hasan, Abu Dhabe</seg>
     <seg id="3">Your talk is near to the heart and situations are also like it.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now the printed new map of Pakistan is shown in American newspapers and the round of punctuation is also a sign of it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">America is gripping more on Pakistan slowly day by day.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this situation if we did not show union as a nation then there is possible another part as Bangla daish.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To show disatbleness of errorism is less where will be it in Mambae Hotal, Meriat hotal in Islamabad and in Falastin.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Like this terorrists should be punished where they will where from Pakistan, India, America or Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now the question is this that terorriss attacks on Pakistan and many bodies died by their attacks that what is the reason of scielence of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Was the attack on Mariat hotal not by terorrists?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Then why?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Hats off to the Home Advisor, Mr. Rahman Malik. Masha Allah, has become so brave and courageous.</seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">According to BBC, Mr. Malik has vehemently denied the accusation that the arrests of terrorists were being done at the 'request of others'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Brother, Subhanallah!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Whether the ability is there or not, or whether it should be said that it is not needed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We, i.e. Pakistan, are fighting somebody else's war.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And where are our own interests which we are trying so hard to save?</seg>
     <seg id="4">No one has the right to interfere in any country's affairs.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This does not seem to be the era of new populations.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If people expect justice or demand that an external united court be established to respect democratic institutions, and not help any dictator or military regime, there could be peace in the Third World, including Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As such, Pakistan is always following the goals set by Europe and America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This happens, despite the opposition of a majority of the Pakistani population.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And this causes more opposing feelings.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If they trust America and the United republics, then let them leave the style of new populations, and let them work on those lines, upholding the sovereignty of the state.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan has the ability to arm and disarm.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Pakistan Occupied Kashmir, security forces captured a camp of practically non-existent Lashkar-e-Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Since the Mumbai attacks, pressure is increasing on Pakistan to act against the extremist organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India's accusation is that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
     <seg id="5">He said that the extremists whom attacked Mambae used Pakistani earth.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Meanwhile, Pashawar military officials report that unknown miltary personnel fired upon UN military trucks, destroying approximately 50 trucks.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is the second attack on NATO and America.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Meanwhile, Pakistan made the show of disactive party Lashkar-e-Taiba and before this was tried to make miltary persons unmiltary and miltary wepons were changed with money and cartainly no any action without it.</seg>
     <seg id="9">The situations told that in the past period of President ZiaulHaq  the efforts of Pakistan to end of miltary parties in the result of enterance of Soviat Union in Afghanistan and the resistance by America funding did not succeed.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The question is, is this what Pakistan really wants to do?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Are Pakistan really capable of this?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Click here for details.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Please note that only messages in Urdu will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="15">For this, press alt+shift on keyboard and select urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I ask only one question from the flag holders of humanity.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If you kill their children and they bring necklace for you, this is impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4">And question from you that from islamic studies to western eastern studies, say any logic, argument and philosophy give permission to kill innocent civilians including praying men, laborers and poor workers of different occupations, in revenge of American attack?</seg>
     <seg id="5">If answer is in no then you have an instant need of correcting your point of view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">People were armed, at that time their was a danger that Russia will turn toward Pakistan after Afghanistan, therefore people were armed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now when there is danger that America will overrun Pakistan through passage of Afghanistan of which American president had said out in his election campaign then why should we unarm these people?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Only because America or India army don't have to face any civil resistance after defeating Pakistani army?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Yes, if anyone of them is involved in any destructive actions then Pakistan should act against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">But this is more, that government against Lashkar-e-Taiba proves correct by India that Pakistan is involve in that.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeeb Ul Rehman Saico, *Lahore*.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If except that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved than its still wrong to blame the Pakistani government.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And one question also arises that do these terrorist's have or get support of any Government or Indian government's insiders?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are terrorist's only born and made in Pakistan and not made in India and rest of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post63" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As far as Lashkar-e-Taiba is concerned they are not involved in this recent terror.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This recalls that Hafiz Saeed was the first person who called Taliban acts as 'Fitnah'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is my firm belief that the Taliban acts were a part of American projects so that every person or group are cleaned out from the way who challenge the Taliban in any manner.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even support by the whole nation, to take action against the Lashkar-e-Taiba due to Indian pressure indicates Zardini's frustration and buttering nature.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Americans said to end this campagin which started from Saudi's funding. Ask them now to clean this dirt as well, which make our society polluted.</seg>
     <seg id="2">One should also protest against them that according to ethics, America and Saudi Arabia distributed dangerous weapons and named Jihadis, but in reality spread the virus of hateful literature and culture due to which slaughter houses were opened in our country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the threat of attack from India, the announcement of the Pakistani Army that they will divert their attention to India by removing the army from Afghanistan, and the announcement of Taliban that they will take care of the Afghan border, America stumbled badly and tried its best to convince India that she should attack Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This shattered the confidence of Americans in the area.</seg>
     <seg id="3">However, India did not make such threats, nor had they any plans to.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The rest was taken care of by either attacks from the Taliban or American military posts.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Thus it was proven that without the support of Pakistan and its army, America can do nothing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Karachi is Pakistan's business and economic center and Dubai of the less privileged areas.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Hundreds of thousands do not return empty handed from here. But since the law was enforced on the western borders, Karachi has taken all the attention.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now they are looking to occupy this city.</seg>
     <seg id="4">For the first time Pathans are called Pashtoons. They are made to fight by making them strangers to each other. What they need is to be united.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One possible solution to the problem is this that either Urdu speakers learn Pashto or Pashto speakers learn Urdu.  What is better is that they all learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You will surely think this a ridiculous suggestion. Do you think that reason of this conflict is not ridiculous?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The reason of violence is language?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir, I gave this suggestion  in childhood. In reality, to my friends in which there were people according to classification from every religion and dialect but friends used to laugh on my talks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At that time the condition of Jinn, of hatred, of dialectal, and religious was not alive and strong but it was brewing internally.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I do not understand what and why is this happening?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are these the very same signs of Last day?</seg>
     <seg id="3">For what crime are innocent and guiltless being killed?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The reasons are in front of everyone who wants to divide Pakistan in pieces.  Thos that are active here and who do this have religion and nor country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whether it is Karachi or Bombay, our homes are burnt with their own lamps (we have destroyed our homes ourselves.)</seg>
     <seg id="6">When the government comes, they just change names of the places to build a name for themselves. Just like these days airports, roads, buildings are all named Benazir.</seg>
     <seg id="7">What has happened in Karachi, is this what Benazir means?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When Bombay attacks were at their peak, the failure of efforts of the RA to initiate turmoil in Karachi proves this that in the past political elements working on the payroll of RA have now resigned from their posts.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Unjustified killing of Pashto speaking hard workers and Indian threats have awakened sleeping Pakistanis from Karachi to Khyber.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Where reactions full of patriotism of all political, religious, lingual and national parties have taught diplomatic manners to India, at the same time they have also given American planners one more chance to think.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">MQM and ANP are responsible for the turmoil in Karachi and management is showing self interest.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Management can control the situation in one hour but it is being given wind on purpose.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Pressure of political parties on police and rangers keep them from doing the operation.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Talk of getting united are only limited to statements, political parties should let go of their self interests and work for the interest of a common man.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As long as there is political pressure on the government, more incidents will take place. May Allah save Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I believe these people are the biggest terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And there are definitely some foreign forces at work here, but I do not know whose.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And the sad thing is that if such a situation was prevalent in any border town, the government would take care of that place. But since this is far from the border, the government looks helpless.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government should set up an operation here in order to save a big and important town from terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Otherwise Pakistan will face a huge financial crisis.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even BBC Urdu is not writing the truth out of fear, and as for the local media, it is even more afraid.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The whole truth is available on BBC English.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One solution to the problem is that either the Urdu-speaking people learn Pushtun or the Pushtun-speaking people learn Urdu; even better, both could learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You might think this is a funny proposal, but isn't the reason for the clashes funny?</seg>
     <seg id="5">that the cause of extremism could be language?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">They spilled blood in Karachi and the story that each citizen was fearing for a long time was finally written.</seg>
     <seg id="2">No one left any stone unturned, and the reports that surfaced in the media was 50% of what actually happened here in four days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I stayed up the last three nights, and I am still afraid.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The people who killed the cobblers and peanut sellers who evacuated the hotel (this is a fragment)</seg>
     <seg id="5">The people who looted the super highway and cut the ears of innocent people are all unaware of Allah's punishment which can catch them anytime.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What do you think are the reasons for this sudden violence?</seg>
     <seg id="2">(BBC)</seg>
     <seg id="3">Keeping the heart rendering Mumbai attacks in view and driving to search for a cause for the violence in Karachi is not at all needed, rather the quite straightforward reason for this violence is the subconscious change in 'blood'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is obvious that if someone mistreats the father, it is no surprise if the son becomes out of control.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Liaquat Ali Khan and many other freedom fighters belong to that. He was writing a poem to remove Mr. Saiko's misunderstanding.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We will again establish the old traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We gave lives for it and we are going to protect it by giving our lives.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Faizan Tausif Siddiqui</seg>
     <seg id="5">It's very sad that the whole country is at stake and we are still fighting each other</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mr. Siddiqui, in Wikipedia</seg>
     <seg id="7">We got to know that Liaquat Ali Khan was related to the province of Punjab, in the area of Karnal and belongs to a Punjabi family.</seg>
     <seg id="8">For his effort of refugees, today refugees consider him as there own.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">For every action there is a reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You can tolerate till your own bust.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I'jaz A'wan</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sir, before you get a large number of people with proposals, I shall tell you that the open signs of this mischief is also found on the walls of Karachi in the form of posters and wall chalking.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We have been bearing both types of mischief.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mischief mongers did not leave Pakistan or the founder of Pakistan. They did not have to face any reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Contrary to that, they are pecking at the chest of Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There used to be one Muslim League.  They made the rough version of the 18th amendment and handed it over to the People's Party.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Before that, MQM and Muslim League had already handed in rough versions of the 18th amendment to the national assembly and senate.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It still seems that the copy of the 18th amendment is a political trickery, and no one is sincere about accepting that amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is why no fuss was made in the assembly or on the floor of senate over this amendment and the parliament was not forced into accepting the amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It looks as if the parties just wanted to get the thing off their backs by submitting the rough versions so that tomorrow they may say that we submitted our versions of the amendment, but the government speaker did not take action.</seg>
     <seg id="6">How is it possible that MQM coalition partner of the government, Muslim League N an underhand ally of the government and Muslim league Q the party to approve the seventeenth amendment be sincere enough to approve the disapproved amendment?</seg>
     <seg id="7">It's just like writing your name amongst Shaheeds by just putting color on yourself.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The People's Party is not in a hurry to dismiss the seventeenth amendment anyways.</seg>
     <seg id="9">What would one think of getting his own hands cut?</seg>
     <seg id="10">As long as Zardari is the president, the seventeenth amendment is not going to be canceled.</seg>
     <seg id="11">This is the opinion of the majority in our survey takers and so is deemed to be the truth.</seg>
     <seg id="12">If the seventeenth amendment had been canceled then Zardari would never had become the president.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Now he is even more powerful than President Musharaf because along with being the president he is also the chairman of the People's party.</seg>
     <seg id="14">As long as he is the president, the seventeenth amendment will remain intact.</seg>
     <seg id="15">In order to cancel the seventeenth amendment, the political parties will first have to dismiss President Zardari from the presidency.</seg>
     <seg id="16">Neither MQM nor other parties want this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Most of the elders from our family belonged to the labor community.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In our childhood, when we used to see our uncles doing labor work, we used to pray to Allah to save us from this hard work.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To avoid this, we wrote a letter to the editor of the daily Amroz and asked him what we should we do after matriculation so that we don't have to do labor work.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The editor wrote in reply that we should select certain subjects and become doctors or engineers.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Right from beginning, my trend was towards engineering. I had selected technical drawing instead of Biology as well.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But at the time of admission in F.Sc. my elder brother forced me to become a doctor after doing F.Sc. in medical.</seg>
     <seg id="7">I studied biology for a month and then took math as an alternate subject when nothing worked out.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The fear of labor work made me an engineer and now I am in a better position than other in my family, for which I am always thankful to God.</seg>
     <seg id="9">I remembered that when my two sons and I were trying to remove the carpets from our old house.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It was only half an hour since he started working that the little boy said, "Daddy, I am not born to do this".</seg>
     <seg id="11">I said that if this is true, then study a lot like us and get rid of the physical labor.</seg>
     <seg id="12">The son said, "I am studying and I will get through it, but it is the work that I cannot do".</seg>
     <seg id="13">We did that work in three hours and came back home.</seg>
     <seg id="14">The point of this story is that if a person picks his destiny, whatever is the reason behind it, no one can stop him from achieving that destiny.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Here if you do not know what you have to do then may God help you!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is said that you should not say bad things about the dead, but what shall we do? We see only bad things in Benazir, even on the anniversary of her first death.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir, for her selfish purpose, crushed the independence movement of the Sikhs after giving the list of the names of those who were fighting for freedom. On the other hand, she gave India the chance to keep its full attention on Kashmir after helping to suppress the Punjab movement.</seg>
     <seg id="3">A tug-of-war between Benazir and Nawaz Sharif rule is part of the history and has pushed the country back many years.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir continued to give negative comments on Kashmir and the nuclear program after being exiled.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Baenazir violated the pact with Nawaz Shareef in London by making a deal with General Musharaf</seg>
     <seg id="6">Because of Baenazir's open hand policy towards family members in earning money during her rule, he became known as Mr. Ten Percent.</seg>
     <seg id="7">During Baenazir's rule, her brother got murdered, and even today his murderers are still at large.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Though a woman herself, Baebnazir did not fight for women's rights.</seg>
     <seg id="9">The way in which Baenazir did politics on her fathers dead body, in the same way her followers are doing politics on the dead bodies of her family.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Baenazir got to be a leader twice and in that time punishing her fathers murders at one side she didn't even file charges against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Sadly, no leaders condemn the day that began the 37 years of separation of eastern Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We should have mourned this 16th of September as a black day and taken steps to prevent similar tragic incidences from occurring in the future.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On this day, we should have sent the Bangali's letters of consolation and tried to reconcile with them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now we must examine the reasons why eastern Pakistan was separated.</seg>
     <seg id="5">He planned on bringing back the people of Bihar, who were stuck in Bangladesh, and he would send them gifts to keep their spirits up.</seg>
     <seg id="6">We have become so insensitive in our neighborhood, that if someone dies, we are not even aware of it.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We do not care for our brothers and sisters because we have become selfish.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If a huge calamity passes by, we forget about it and by the next day we carry on with our normal life.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If only East and West Pakistan could become one again, like East and West Germany had done.</seg>
     <seg id="10">If we sacrifice a little for each other and leave our selfishness behind us, we can again become one.</seg>
     <seg id="11">It doesn't look as if this dream will be fulfilled in the near future.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Today, it was announced in the news, that the governor of Illinois, in The United States, was caught on corruption charges.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He would soon be brought up on charges and forced to resign his position.  My American friend, who had knowledge of the political system in The U.S. And in Pakistan seemed embarrassed by this example of democracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In America, no one is above the law, not even government officials.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and there is your country, Pakistan, whose president has been elected after his corruption charges were dropped.</seg>
     <seg id="5">My sense of humor spoke, and I said "What's wrong if a governor got arrested in America - in Pakistan, we arrested the Prime Minister overnight and hanged him once, and another time we exiled one."</seg>
     <seg id="6">tell me when it happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan sent off the criminal with a guard of honor from the presidency. Tell me, when did such a thing happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="8">In Pakistan, the Chief Justice was suspended in such a way that besides the public support he is unable to be restored so far, did this ever happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="9">A holder of a falsified degree was made the Minster of Health in Pakistan, did this ever happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="10">after hearing all this, the American went down laughing and then conceded defeat.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">in this picture, President Zardari is smiling despite being surrounded by Americans on all four sides.</seg>
     <seg id="2">it looks from his smile</seg>
     <seg id="3">He thinks that America is supporting his government, but he forgot that a year ago they supported Pervez Musharaf.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The picture looks like a picture of Family.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Before this no picture, as such, has been published in which the President is with 3 American authorities.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It looks like America's work has been increased in Pakistan and one or more Authorities are working on it or they might not believe that person as compared to the first one.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It might be possible that they have planned this also, keeping in mind the nature of President Zardari's promise fulfillment.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If he was an intelligent politician then he would not be smiling in this picture and his face would show some embarassment.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If the Principle of Democracy is applied to this picture then President Zardari is in the minority.</seg>
     <seg id="10">According to Democracy, the majority makes the rules for the nation and that is who is shown in the picture.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Heaven like Swat of Pakistan is also known as Switzerland.</seg>
     <seg id="2">till now, according to Government Policy, cross talks are also going along with the power use</seg>
     <seg id="3">but power use is resulting in increase power of Taliban and increasing sympathy for Taliban among people beside that it is not providing any benefits</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government must, instead of using the power, eliminate the causes of the issue.</seg>
     <seg id="5">by eliminating the causes, Fazlullah and Taliban will automatically disperse.</seg>
     <seg id="6">the Sharia bill proposed by ANP will, to a great extent, become the solution of the problems of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="7">But besides implementation of the Sharia, the government will have to give more attention to the economical issues.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At the beginning of General Musharaf rise, it looked like the nation had rid itself of the incompetent politicians, but the lust for power changed all his plans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">all the hopes were from the participation in the "War of terror", he had started considering himself immortal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">those steps which were expected, all broke-off.</seg>
     <seg id="4">as soon as Bush's era came close to an end he started worrying about the end of his rule and in that bewilderment, made a deal with the thieves.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Even then General Musharaf could control the Army but never know what wass happening to the present government.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Either its Bajor or Swat, the army does not control terror but bombs the ""Enemy"" public; along with loss of lives and wealth if you make the enemy a mentally sick, then aren't we the Enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Despite the military operation in Swat, a war-torn area of NWFP, things are getting worse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On one hand the writ of GOVT is limited to a resolution of condemnation passed by National assembly while on other hand the influence of Taliban's FM channel is increasing in swat.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The common citizen has no choice but to obey the rule of power.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In swat security forces have used lethal weapons and have claimed to kill many extremists. But despite these causalities, Taliban's Power is rising. They are controlling nearly 80% area of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Result: GOVT is not accepting its failure and Talibans are getting stronger</seg>
     <seg id="6">The poor citizen is the only looser.</seg>
     <seg id="7">""how are the Talibans"" asked by someone in Swat. It is answered as ""They are very good; they are fighting the war against the enemies of God""</seg>
     <seg id="8">Then asked about the army. Answer was ""very good, it is fighting against the enemies of our country""</seg>
     <seg id="9">Who are the enemies of religion and country? ""The poor citizens"", it was answered.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I am greatly astonished, how the Army of Pakistan will fight against Indian Army. It has failed to  control a small group of Talibans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They are unable to track the illegal FM radio channel of Taliban. I think that can easily be tracked.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This FM radio is strongly propagating the agenda of hatred and terror.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the girls' school, now they are demolishing the schools for boys.</seg>
     <seg id="5">curfew is imposed to facilitate the taliban's movement</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tonight during curfew, they have made new bunkers in the nearby areas of Mangora.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Question arises, how did they reach there during curfew?</seg>
     <seg id="8">If Army can kill Akbar bugti in a cave, why taliban can't be targeted?</seg>
     <seg id="9">For God's sake, Army should take actions to free the helpless people of Swat from the brutal occupation of Taliban. This will improve the image of Pakistan Army.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">He has said that religion is the reason of bloodshed; kindly tell me if it would be a peaceful world without any concept of religion?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Does religion divide us on ethnic , linguistic and regional basis?</seg>
     <seg id="3">No Sir, religion is what teaches that no one is black or white, punjabi or muhajir otherwise if religion was not present, then half world would have vanished in the war between white and black and other half fighting over the status and sect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Actually, religion gives moral teachings to man. And binds him that he is not here on his own choice but the creator of the universe has sent him here. And he should spend his life according to his teachings.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a muslim, I have total faith that Islam is complete way of life and a true religion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After living in London, for many years I used to ask wellness of my family over the phone every morning. Although most of them did not even call once to find out how we were. Then I realized that they do not even like our phone calls so we stopped calling.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Living here in France for the past two years, I have also felt the same thing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Do not know why people expect us to call.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A resolution passed about Iraq few hours back, Darfar has absolutely no problem in sending the peace army.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Bombay attacks were condemned, in no time banning dubious groups is only a matter of a few hours.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And where death is dancing, we are consenting.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Oh caretakers of international peace, life is finishing here!</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is the wait really going on for it to finish?</seg>
     <seg id="6">So that some oppressed person would not even be able to think about using some weapon of mass destruction, like ill will, to obtain their right?</seg>
     <seg id="7">When a father is running around holding the corpse of his son, even then a small wave of sorrow does not arise from any part of your heart.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If not, you have no right to be called a human.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Rather you are a black spot on the name of humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">OK, this was proved that this area was also the home of the Israelis for thousands of years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ideally, these two tribes should have lived happily together with love and affection, but since their strings are in the hands of the western and Arab countries, peace is not possible without their will.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rather, now even Iran wants to fight a proxy war from here.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even if Israeli action has stopped for a while, it will start again after some incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The interest of the owner of BBC is associated with serving America and Israel, and this is why in the name of 'enlightenment' it has come out with a series of Zionist favoring blogs, and is doing biased and blind propaganda.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What the BBC doing is just a formality. Their primary objective is to generate sympathy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I would like to request of the moderator that the commentary of the applicant be published to show that the BBC still have some respect for facts.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thanks.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I don't know how this story began, but one is sure that the Dracula of every age is thirsty for human blood.</seg>
     <seg id="2">There were wars and bloodshed in every era of history.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is strange that people of the 21st century, who claim to be more civilized, do not show any concern over open bloodshed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">How does he not feel that what is happening in the world around him is the distorted/evil aspect of humanity.</seg>
     <seg id="5"></seg>
     <seg id="6">well wisher, Sajjad ul Hasan, Hayderabad dakan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At the moment, in Dera Ghazikhan and in other parts of the country, it is raining.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Here is a poem according to the weather. Enjoy the weather along with this poem.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These rains are with your presence.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If it rains, it's spring.</seg>
     <seg id="5">If it stays, then it's peace.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Sometimes it comes without a reason.</seg>
     <seg id="7">At times it spreads over day and night.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Sometimes very noisy and sometimes very quiet.</seg>
     <seg id="9">These rains are with your presence.</seg>
     <seg id="10">In a memory, at night.</seg>
     <seg id="11">To buried ash.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sometimes it was such, that the wind put it out.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Sometimes it burnt itself.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Sometimes each drop seemed sorrowful.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Even the rains are from you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All these rulers are going to run away carrying a suitcase. What is it to them, whether the country lasts or not?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whether the public sells or takes lemon peels, and scrubs the temple bells with them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">For one, our media is also corrupted, like our leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It's goal is only to extract money from the government, and nothing else.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As for the public, they are ignorant. To speak about them is the biggest ignorance.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Yesterday afternoon, something surprising happened.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All the police are running around, but they do not check illegal parking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Also, New York City traffic police did not bother with illegally parked vehicles.</seg>
     <seg id="4">A U.S. Air Force plane was forced to land in the Hudson River.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Till today only this much is known: The ""terrorist" was actually a flock of geese.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It was historical cold spell yesterday in New York.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Normally, the temperature never drops this low.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The pain started in my own jaw after walking outside for 30 minutes.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Imagine the horrendous condition of those people who jumped from the plane into the icy river.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The reason for their happiness is that all of them were safe.</seg>
     <seg id="11">The reason for concern is that the company was in financial crisis when the plane went down in the water.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Seeing all those sites, I reached the New Jersey side from the  West Side Highway. There I found the South Bond closed. What should I do?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Coming back I got wedged on the busy street.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Thank the Lord! After an hour of hurry, a way was opened to me. I found myself at the 56th Street exit.</seg>
     <seg id="15">I had not come across the exit first, nor the long lines.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Mekki: My Pakistan..! Good greetings. Eid Mubarak to you.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Umar: Of course, Faithful.!</seg>
     <seg id="3">Shugfath: Good greetings..! Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sarah: I have had two chickens. It's a sacrifice. Janzeb will tell you how it was.</seg>
     <seg id="5">There was no other option. Otherwise, I would have to go to the farm</seg>
     <seg id="6">and prepare the meat, skin it  too.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Basim.Net might take some to repair.</seg>
     <seg id="8">What happened on the forum?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Linko</seg>
     <seg id="10">In order to work with Listen to Blog, see it in Fire Fox.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Duffer: Same to you. Eid greetings to you.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sir please use Fire Fox.</seg>
     <seg id="13">The snow will vanish.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We unnecessarily kept thinking of these Taliban of Swat as indelicate, but who were only unhappy over women's education.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They kept expressing their grief by demolishing a womens schools and college somewhere every day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But just like other ideas, this idea did not also come true. According to this report by CNN, today on the sacred day of Monday, this Taliban gang of Swat have blasted a boy's school.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In Swat,the Taliban closed down the school.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The schools of girls were closed down first, as in the case of the famous English school Ladies First and I do not see why the people did not consider the Taliban free of crimes.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It is also known that it is wrong that the Taliban are only against the education of girls.</seg>
     <seg id="7">not this but it is wonderful that they are against total education.</seg>
     <seg id="8">These freedom fighters are gifted with more power and the Devil</seg>
     <seg id="9">which is commanding us and has helped to abolish it.</seg>
     <seg id="10"></seg>
     <seg id="11"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">Sometime before this a girl was married to a dog.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now that is a groom that we have to see!</seg>
     <seg id="5">A decline in traditional morales has become increasingly evident during the 21'st century.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">An age of computer technology.  Where computers continue to become greater parts of everyday life.</seg>
     <seg id="2">There are reservations among some.  People who feel our growing dependence upon computers for computer technology.  Especially in the areas of finiance and monatory areas.  Is a hazardous precident.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Credit cards, debit cards, and other forms of ecommerce have gone a long way towards streamlinging modern life.  However this convience does have a price tag all it's own.  Their use trades away the anomiyity of old fashioned paper currency.  Giving modern law agencies unprecendented and easy access to civilian finiancial records.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The simple act of using a credit card.  Leaves a paper trail that any agency or curious individual can easily follow.  Detailing your daily life.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As use of hard currency continues to diminsh.  More and more people will naturally shift towards the use of credit cards and other ecommerce devices.  Even those who previously chose not to.</seg>
     <seg id="6">This trend has also encouraged crime to shift in similar directions.  Criminals would now rather steal your card, with all the power and personal information attached.  Then rob a banks vault.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Similarly computer has provided means for  friendship or networking.    Computers have also provided a new method for fostering friendship as well as building social networks.  Unlike anything that has come before.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Social Networking sites like Orkut, Facebook and MySspace comes are first tier compared according to popularity.</seg>
     <seg id="9">However, don't you feel psychologically that the more we are accustoming ourselves to social networks, the more we are physically getting away from people.</seg>
     <seg id="10">For example, match making websites that match your choices to other peoples' choices to find similarities and you get a list of matches.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Now can you spend your life with a person exactly like you ?</seg>
     <seg id="12">I can't and that's why we can't compromise a life partner who is half or partly similar to you.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Whatever I lack can be compensated by the partner.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I guess I got a lesser part of intelligence.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Since childhood, whenever an elder said anything to me, that was the truth according to me.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is why I believe dad has the answer to every question in the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">People used to make a lot of jokes about me on this.</seg>
     <seg id="5">the only thing that look truth is which can be done in real.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It's frustrating,that they feel it is necessary to lie.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Because of this, he also suffered at this age.</seg>
     <seg id="8">it is always my wish to tell the truth to the best of my knowledge.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Don't tell lies, especially in the name of God.</seg>
     <seg id="10">and say Inshallah only when the prayers is only for the God that he will accomplish it</seg>
     <seg id="11">God Knows all about your will.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is the only complication due to the distance from the religion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to our religion and the law of Pakistan, a minor should stay with their mother.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Their expenses are the responsibility the father when the father can meet them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Then when the kids mature, they can live with anyone they want.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You have spoken truly about the misunderstandings relatives sometimes create.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Our behavior is controlled by feudal thinking</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ever here this way of thinking is working that new co-sharers will be born in father's property and this is where the opposition is shown. Otherwise their father's this behavior is worth praise and pursuance.</seg>
     <seg id="3">With reference to relationships, these forced affiliations have created evil in our society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Marriage to a divorced person or a widow is becoming less acceptable.</seg>
     <seg id="5">These absurd beliefs and baseless traditions are the reason for many family breakups.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In our society, if wife of a 50-55 year old man or husband of a woman goes to the next world and he marries again, why is he not respected?</seg>
     <seg id="2">We have a Pakistani uncle living close to us. His wife passed away around 10-12 years ago. Now after all his children got married, he married a widow. All his kids have turned against him because of it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my point of view, it is their religious right, what do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="4">""To take place of our mother in the being of our mother"" what kind of thinking?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">According to my thinking, his sons should think about what he done wrong when he married the widow after the marriage of children?</seg>
     <seg id="2">The widow got a helper and he got a person to manage his home.</seg>
     <seg id="3">His sons and daughters engaged in each of their lives and would not care for him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The reason is lack of knowledge.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If their wifes denied to serve him tomorrow, then what will he do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is the result of the stress of society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When the people laughed at the family's actions, the sons denied the second marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We should justify such situation as their father's doing was according to Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is a curse in our society that we are caught in from 40 to 50 years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The feeling of a wife is that her husband can do lots of bad things whatever it may be, but he doesnot has the marry again</seg>
     <seg id="3">If she has the potency, she will try, even after her death.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Along with her husband, she also losing the life after death, and she is one for the evils things in the environment</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Saying Islam, Islam from the mouth does not do any thing, we like the thing which are there in rituals</seg>
     <seg id="2">like, demotivation for the girls education, and love marriage, etc.,</seg>
     <seg id="3">now your Question is, if the big brother rather bringing the widow to his home, he might have went to her home itself, then there will no querrals from his children, (they quarrel may be in the widows children)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We embraced Islam even before the separation of Hindustan and Pakistan, but we have not came out of such evil thinking and this ritual are a more important than islam</seg>
     <seg id="2">The second marriage of a man is bad, divorce is known to be bad. The divorced woman is untouchablesion, the marriage of a man with a elder woman is said to be the evil plan of the woman. the above things are of such evil thinkings</seg>
     <seg id="3">and we think that if we wont follow modernism, we considered to a old thinking man</seg>
     <seg id="4">Embracing Islam is easy, but to come out from such evil thinking is somewhat impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Allah bless us with the ability and courage to do this task.  Allah blessed us with the ability and courage to do this task.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Ameen.   Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It was never that difficult to write Urdu.  It has never been difficult to write Urdu.</seg>
     <seg id="8">It took century's to write this little.  It has taken a century to write this ...</seg>
     <seg id="9">Think of this less as a lot.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Good Bye. goodbye</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Ameer Taimur in his book, I am a Taimur, wrote : "I found the secret in in my lifetime that if the commander of any army is present on the front line then that army will never be defeated."</seg>
     <seg id="2">But here the things are altogether different.    Things here are different.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They say the population is by default for getting killed for us.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If anyone dies from the population, it is considered Murder.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May the peace and blessings of the Almighty be upon you.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As I was coming back to my shop after the Isha prayer tonight, a man sitting in his car called and waved to me.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I thought that this man had probably lost his way or had a question, so I stopped.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He asked me if I spoke Arabic, and I said, "Yes.  How can I help you?"</seg>
     <seg id="5">He told me that he had come from Riyadh to Medina and someone had picked his pocket.  He asked if I could help, but I said no and gave him 12 riyals to help him reach Riyadh.  After traveling a little further, he began doing the same.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Angrily, I cursed at him and threatened to call the police, so he ran away.</seg>
     <seg id="7">this is the situation of Muslims now that even for begging we ride our cars along with our families and make at least 2 to 3 thousand a day.</seg>
     <seg id="8">However there is a clear Hadith (SAAW) that the upper hand is better than the lower hand since the lower hand is the begging one and the upper hand is the giving one.</seg>
     <seg id="9">May Allah bless us and make us true Muslims (Amen)</seg>
     <seg id="10">Wassalam</seg>
     <seg id="11">Javed Iqbal</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The wife of famous singer Adnan Sami approached a Police Station in Mumbai; accusing him of torture.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Police Station advised her to approach the court.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Saba Galadari, the wife of Adnan Sami, gave an application against her husband that Adnan Sami continuously tortures her.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He is also administering in human behavior against her.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now this thing has gone out of her tolerance, therefore, a case may be registered against Adnan Sami.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The police  station has advised her to approach the court instead of registering  the case, on the plea that the case is not within the valid jurisdiction of the police station.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Do you think that the accusation on Adnan Sami by his wife is correct?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Can this accusation be an attempt of India to defame Adnan Sami?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Inform us about your opinion on the Subject.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Adam Sanghar, Mehr.</seg>
     <seg id="2">as far as allegations are concerned, anyone can post it on someone else.  As far as allegations are concerned, anyone can make accusations about someone else.</seg>
     <seg id="3">nothing comes before prestige.  Nothing comes before prestige,</seg>
     <seg id="4">however may be the relations between Adnan Sami and his present wife, he left his respectful life and went to India to make money and now this fame has caught him badly.  however, Adnan Sami's actions of leaving a respectful life to live in India with his present wife reflect badly on him.</seg>
     <seg id="5">this is a consequence of his own deeds.  This is a result of his own actions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Washington...</seg>
     <seg id="2">top American officials say that president Obama will take strict stance over Afghan president Hamid Karzai.  Top American officials say that president Obama will take a strick stand against Afghan president Hamid Karsai.</seg>
     <seg id="3">in the new American policy over Afghanistan, there is more emphasis on war than development.  The new American policy on Afghanistan puts more emphasis on war than development.</seg>
     <seg id="4">officials say that Hamid Karzai is considered to be a hurdle in achievement of American goals Since in his government, there is corruption, drugs business has increased and Taliban are regaining their power.  Officials say that Hamid Karzai is considered a hurdle in the achievement of American goals.  His government is considered to be corrupted by the drug trade and increase in Taliban power.</seg>
     <seg id="5">American officials say that people, who are putting more pressure on Hamid Karzai to do more, include vice president Joe Biden and President Obama's representative for Afhanistan and Pakistan Richard Holbrooke.  American officials, including Vice-president Joe Biden and President Obama's representative for Afghanistan and Pakistan Richard Holbrooke are putting pressure on Hamid Karzai.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that the strategy came forward after President Bush left. He participated in video conferences with Hamid Karzay every two weeks. Those conferences emphasized America's role in reconstructing Afghanistan and it's cities.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The American officer says that the Central administration under Obama will work with local leaders; for a change.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The officer says stress will be given in the fight against corruption joining hands with the Karzay administration.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Hamid Karzay is going to face a new election and it is still not clear whether Obama and his friends will support Karzay's candidature for Presidency.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Can we predict whether the declaration of the American Officer will effect a policy change in the Afgan affairs?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Whether Hamid Karzay's rule is coming to an end.</seg>
     <seg id="12">What do you think about it?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">SriLanka beat Pakistan in the three day international cricket match series for 2-1.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In the first one day match Pakistan defeated SriLanka, however SriLanka won the remaining two matches.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the third day match the performance of the national team was too awesome. The team chasing a target of 309 runs of SriLanka was able score only 75 in 23 overs.The national team should thus have learned a lesson from this defeat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">From the results of the series, it becomes evident that the performance of the national cricket team is not consistent.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Despite home field advantage and all claims, the national team suffered defeat. What do you think are the reasons?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Which aspects of the game should experts focus on?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are you satisfied with the selection of the team?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Which part do you place the responsibility of the loss on, fielding, batting or bowling?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Let us know your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Babar Husain, Jeddah. It is very sad that even in today's modern age, such ignorant traditions are prevalent. If the landlord or the property owner targets innocent people with his harsh dictatorship, who will call them Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Let any big shot walk on these burning coals. Why does the government allow them to do that?</seg>
     <seg id="3">When will legal justice come into play?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370243-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Sri Lankan cricket team has reached Pakistan, to play the one day international series.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The foreign team is still coming to Pakistan despite tensions with India.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The SriLankan team was given a warm welcome at their airport arrival.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Two matches between Pakistan and Srilanka will be at Karachi and Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Both teams are confident in their bowling, batting and fielding skills.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Srilankan is proud of Spiner; Pakistani believes in their fast bowler.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Srilankan Captain Mahela Jaywardena said that no one player on the Pakistan team is dangerous -- the entire team is.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The Pakistan captain said the competition will be tough, while the Srilankans claim that Murlidharan and Mendas will be their trump card.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Shoaib Malik said they have played Murlidharn and Mendas, and will develop a secret game plan to be unveiled on the ground.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Will the Pak-Sri series be entertaining and thrilling?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Which team has a better chance of winning the Pakistan versus Srilanka series?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Who will win the series?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Which man will win the series?</seg>
     <seg id="14">Tell us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Gulfam, London, Publish statements that are of liking, you give preference to those too, it is our wish that even you write some truth, do not entangle the statement like Mukher Jee because it is commanded to say truth in front of tyrant and it is equal to Crusade (Jihad). What to say of Mukher Jee, change the statement between news and try to weep.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Javed Mailk Yousaf, Dubai</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is all these people's doing that Kashmiris have been fighting a war of independence for the past sixty years.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, no one  asked, now that they are caught in a war of extremism and terrorism so they have started talking about peace and settlement.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First they generally massacred Muslims, and now they are perplexedly settling the matters.</seg>
     <seg id="5">At any rate, Pakistan has to understand their duplicitous policies.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Asad Khan London</seg>
     <seg id="2">India creates such situations that world concentration on Kashmir has turned back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But Pakistan has always shown India  its real face to the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now the British government also understands that India made a bad image of Pakistan in the name of terrorism to turn back eyes on Kashmir occupation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">and are frustrated to talk this matter over with Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">British Foreign minister David Milliband said that by resolving Kashmir issue terrorism will be reduced and the government of Pakistan can handle new challenges impressively on its border.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Its clear that before that newly elected American president Barack Obama will alsogive his thoughts in a similarmanner.</seg>
     <seg id="3">British foreign minster said while talking with media and w roteon one essay that though of fight against terrorism is wrong for challenge of danger for its own safety killed people is the policy of Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="4">David Milliband said that Pakistan did not show a soft consideration for terrorist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Due to pressure from big powers to resolve conflict of Kashmir, is India trying to create intense environment in this region to turn back concentration from this problem?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is Mumbai terrorism is a part of this conspiracy?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Does India want to use terrorism as a means to avoid dialogue?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Let us know your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Usman Aftab</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think it is the big countries, That want to harm Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In fact They are thinking of means to control Pakistan; They know Pakistan is an atomic power.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They want to create an environment for revolution.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Foreign countries are thinking that if Pakistan is cornered, It will pose more political and geographical problems. They want to help Pakistan and want to achieve their vested interests.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A citizen of the USA.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It has always been a Hindu tradition; walking stick in arm and name of Ram on lips.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I think from sometimes, there is an anxiety and to relieve that, Pakistan is blamed or associated with some negative event.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are ready in all ways.  The Indian Chief of Army should keep his mouth shut or else.  We know how to give mouth breaking answers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Faheem Siddiqi</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ras al Khaima.  This conversation is going on due to American mischief. America's mind was already spoiled, but now India is also becoming like that. Let them attack, and they will see the reality as to who is in how deep waters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel is attacking Hamas, but no one has the courage to stop it. Watching Israel, India also wants to do that.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Prime Minister, Syed Raza Yusuf Geelani, said that the newly elected American vice president, Joe Biden played an important role in removing the ex-president Musharraf's uniform and replacing it with a lame democracy.  This is why the Pakistani government has honored him with a special star.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The credit for removing the uniform and replacing the democracy should not go to any political party. The Parliament is not a rubber stamp.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All decisions will be made in the parliament.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Prime Minister said that Qadeer's door was closed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In your opinion, do the public protests against Mina Marriot not mean anything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Has the lawyers movement not played any role?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you want say about about the words of the Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Please give us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The President of America, George W. Bush, said to Barack Obama that he in his position made many mistakes and that if Obama wants to correct them, he can.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As a president, and based on the situation and rules and regulations of America, I have taken steps to work only for the benefit of America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">He said that the enemies of America are planning today to attack America. To stop this this is the biggest challenge for Barack Obama.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He said that being unable to find the weapons of mass destruction in Iraq was a problem, and he felt that saying he won the battle in Iraq was his biggest mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In the last conference given at the White House, he said, "This is my last press conference, and I thank all those who have attended."</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you think Obama will repeat the same mistakes that Bush made?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Was Bush too late in accepting the mistakes he made?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Will Obama work to change the people's opinion of Bush?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Inform me of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The step president of America said that he wants to see Usama alive or dead.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He said that Usama bin Ladan is in a difficult place and is he useless whether is is arrested alive or dead, but that his organization should be killed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">America aimes to arrest Usama bin Ladan and they are searching for him.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The arrest of Usama is the completion of heart want of Dak Chene.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Inform me of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Like Shahid Aafridi all rounder cricketers quarled with a visiter after the end of IA and Habib bank in Qaid-e-Azam.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In UBL ground Shahid Afride after match playing when came from drying room then many wanters gathered.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Once a fan asked to take a picture with him and when he declined Afride brushed him off and the crowd moved on.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Afterward, Afride said an issue is being made for no reason, but I was praying.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Nevertheless, I shall apologize to that spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What would you say about this behavior of Shahid Afridi?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Tell us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian prime minister Manmohan Singh has once again accused Pakistan of provoking a war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan is using terrorism as a state policy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">while addressing a Chief Ministers conference in New Delhi, Manmohan Singh said that the terrorist elements are backed by neighboring countries, especially Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Because the terrorists of the Mumbai attacks used the Pelagic route they were safe from the Indian Coast Guard.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian prime minister said that the attacks in November were carried out by Lashkare Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He added that the terrorists are using modern techniques and the latest communication systems, that we have to be more vigilant over the border where in the intrusion took place, and that our policy is that terrorism will not be spared in any case.</seg>
     <seg id="7">How do you see this allegation from the Indian prime minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Does the internal political war, and individualism show that India is in trouble?</seg>
     <seg id="9">On what basis is India warning others?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Please give us your suggestions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Zubair Khan, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is the most dangerous situation where Isreal kills Palestinians, on the other hand the same in Kashmir also, it was not noted by any peace councils, and not even responding for this</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Associations in Kashmir and Palestian, ther have to fight for their freedom, and they to be united and strrugle to all dangerous situations. definitely one day their struggle will give you a good result. Insha Allah</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">on Ghazwa, they air force of Isreals are attacking on palestain, today also. till this more than lakhs people are died.</seg>
     <seg id="2">An important member of HAMAS, Nazariyan, was killed along with his family.</seg>
     <seg id="3">the other side the functions of  peace councils got closed, without any conclusion</seg>
     <seg id="4">The conference was conducted against Israel by Libya and other gulf countries. A report on the conference was submitted to America.</seg>
     <seg id="5">For the last few days there have been bombings by Israeli planes on the Palestinian civilian population.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The whole world cried out about the Mumbai issue, but the Israeli attacks do not seem to matter to anyone including America and Britain.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Why are the important Islamic countries quiet?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What can say about this double standard of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Saeed, New York</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think that most of our people are ignorant. They do not know where their money is going. The government fixes taxes and likes to fulfill its duties. The electricity and gas crisis will not be like this.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because everyone knows the role of those selected by the people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The electricity and gas crisis across Pakistan has taken a serious position.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other side, there was an increase of an average of 18% in gas rates, while the unavailability of petrol in some cities has become a cause of great difficulty for the public.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Among the manufacturing and business circles, there are strong protests and severe protests against the long power cut and gas crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Industrialist have given an ultimatum before closing the factories.</seg>
     <seg id="5">There is growing anxiety among those dwelling in  Karachi because of the eight to ten hours of electricity load shedding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Industrial activities have almost paralyzed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Government departments are playing a blame game on each other.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Isn't under these circumstance the proposals for increasing electricity and gas tariff a joke with the people?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Why is attention not being given in resolving the issues?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Can the government see the failing of the country's economy?</seg>
     <seg id="11">To counter these problems for the short term, what suggestions do you have?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Please inform us about your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Imran Khokar from Madina Munawara Saudi Arabia, I want to say the way the people are, they get similar leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I'm surprised that the government carrying slogan of public service, is hurting them alone.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The scarcity of electricity, gas, and petroleum has become a threat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government has no control over the institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The law and order situation is deteriorating every day, may Allah have mercy on this country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The new year has began.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Last year was the year of outbreaks and political ups and downs. It will also be remembered in reference to terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Stepping down of President Musharf and the end of the eight years rule of president Bush, throwing of shoes on Bush and formation of democratic government in Pakistan, calamities, earthquake in Baluchistan, global financial slump and monopoly.</seg>
     <seg id="4">With the new year arriving, how do you foresee it?</seg>
     <seg id="5">In your opinion, what will be the result of the political or geographical situation. What will be Obama's strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is there hope for a development towards eliminating terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="7">When will the judicial crisis of Pakistan be finished?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What shape will the Pakistan and India relationship become?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is there a chance of a surgical strike or full scale war?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What expectations do you have for the new year?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Tell us about your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370256-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The first anniversary of Benazir Bhutto is being celebrated.  She was martyred in an election rally at Liaquat Garden Rawalpindi on 27 December 2007.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today Benazir is not with us,she was a seasoned politician and a person of international repute,she had a unique status in the country's politics.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The mystery of her killing still has not been solved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Her efforts to establish government and Democracy in the country have not been wasted.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Today, a Democratic government has been established in Pakistan and Bhutto's husband, Asif Ali Zardari, is holding the office of the President of the State.</seg>
     <seg id="6">How do you see Shaheed Benazir's role in Pakistan's politics?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Who can be behind her martyrdom?</seg>
     <seg id="8">she was recently awarded with the global award for human rights. what would you like to say about her political and democratic services.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">after ruling America for 8 years, president Bush has departed from the White House and shifted to the president camp office in Camp David so that the White House can be renovated according to the new president Barrack Obama's likings.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During Bush's eight years rule, the historical attacks and destruction of the World Trade Center, attack on Pentagon and then in the name of war against terror, attacking Afghanistan and Iraq and involving forces from other countries into the war and use of American resources in it have become memorable examples of his time.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Due to this war, America itself faced the worst ever economical and financial crisis in history.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What do you think the world achieved and lost through this war?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Were the policies of Bush successful?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What is your opinion on president Bush's rule?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian government has stopped the Indian cricket team from visiting Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Indian cricket team was supposed to play three tests, five one-day matches and one 20-20, during the tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rajiv Shekhla, the Vice President of the Indian Cricket Board, in an interview with Jeev News said that the board had asked the government for permission to go on the Pakistan tour, but due to the difficult situation in the two countries, the tour was not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Is the Indian government's decision to cancel the trip in view of the present political situation a proper step? Should sports be separated from politics?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is the Indian government's decision harmful for cricket?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Despite the fact that security conditions in India are bad, England's cricket team is continuing its tour. Therefore, why can't the Indian team make the tour of Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion on this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salman, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">Those people who are proud about going to India</seg>
     <seg id="3">and who make their films and videos over there, should now have their eyes opened as to how much the people of India respect them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I remember an interview of Adnan Sami, in which he said that he is not Pakistani, rather, his citizenship is of England.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan Sami should return to Pakistan the first chance he gets because he was not respected elsewhere.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fareed Ahmed</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="3">India's attitude has changed after the Bombay Attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jagjit Singh has showed his reaction in the way that he hates Pakistan and Pakistanis.</seg>
     <seg id="5">One should know that Adnan Sami has sung with Asha Bhonsley. How is he a bad singer now? Adnan Sami Should stay in India, there is no need to come here.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muhammad Shamshaad Alam</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi, at the advice of Jagjit Singh, said that he changes color like a chameleon.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who gives statements in relation to the circumstances? Pakistanis! Open your eyes to how much value you are given in India. Understand their mentality.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the Bombay incident, their hateful statements have increased. The same people are now saying evil things against the famous singer Adnan Sami.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">According to foreign news agencies, in the farewell trip of American President George Bush, during a press conference with the Prime Minister Nur-al-Maliki in his office, the situation became hilarious when an Iraqi journalist called Bush and said "Dog, this is a farewell kiss".</seg>
     <seg id="2">After this, the journalist took his shoe off and threw it at Bush. President Bush ducked with expertise and saved himself from getting hit by the shoe.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The second shoe hit the American flag.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Security agents pulled this journalist away from the president.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On this occasion, President Bush said that he did not know why he did that. The shoe was a size ten. The president was not very upset by the incident.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In your opinion, does this action of the journalist show the anger of the Iraqi public against President Bush?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you think about this incident?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the Mumbai terror incidents, the tension in Indo-Pak relations escalated to an even more grave extent when Indian Air Force war planes violated Pakistani air space in the Lahore and Kashmir sectors.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Due to the reaction of the Pakistani Air Force, the Indian planes were forced to go back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">According to sources, both Indian planes were full of weapons and ammunition.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the first of its kind incident in the current tensed situation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan Air Force says that it is ready to defend the country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Information Minister Sherry Rahman says that Indian officials have accepted that aerial boundaries have been crossed, although this happened by mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan military sources have declared this incident felonious.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In your opinion, does India really have an intention of an air strike on Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is this statement of India correct that this violation was a mistake or this was to find out the ability of the Pakistan Air Force?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Is this incident not going to aggravate the current estrangement among the two countries?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please inform us with your comments.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Respected martyr Benazir Bhutto was given the International Award for Human Rights after her death, which was received by her son and chairperson of the People's Party Bilawal Bhutto Zardari.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During a session of the General Assembly in the United Nations headquarters, the former prime minister of Pakistan, martyr Benazir Bhutto, was presented with this award for acknowledgment of her efforts for human rights in a ceremony.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The 60th anniversary of the passing of the human rights resolution by the United Nations was celebrated on the 10th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Among those people and institutes being recognized for their human rights work, apart from Benazir Bhutto, were former American Attorney General, Louis Ramsey Clark and Human Rights Watch, an organisation that works around the world for human rights.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On this occasion, the Pakistani Ambassador to the United Nations, Abdullah Husain Harun, and other senior embassy agents were present.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you say about the former martyr Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto receiving this award?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Samir</seg>
     <seg id="2">Chicago</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is true that she was martyred, but we also remember how many innocent people she killed in Karachi, she was proud that Nasirullah Babar did well.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But, later she changed totally.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is also true that she ignored the senior members of her party and made her son the representative of Peoples Party. What kind of democracy is that?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Jami Noor, Karachi, This news proves that disbelievers will only help disbelievers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But until the iron ax is not fitted with a wooden handle, it cannot cut a wing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our rulers are just like this, that they are adopting secretive ways. This is why calamities are befalling the country.</seg>
     <seg id="4">May Allah guide our rulers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Security Council panel of the United Nations have included the name of Hafiz Sa'eed as well as two other Pakistani citizens and the name of Jama'athud Da'wah as well as four other organisations into the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Pakistanis whose names were included in the terrorist list by the Al-Qaidah and Taliban Sanctions Committee of the Security Council included Jama'athud Da'ah chief, Hafiz Mohammad Saeed, practically non-existent organisation Lashkar-e-Taiba Operation Chief, Zakiur Rahman Lakhwi and Financial Chief Haji Mohammad Ashraf.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Apart from this, a saudi national, Mahmood Ahmad Bazek was also included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Among the organisations were Jama'athud Da'wah, Pasban Kashmir, ArRasheed trust, and Al-Akhtar trust International.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The member countries will immediately freeze all the assets of these individuals and organisations, they will be restricted from traveling and will be under arrest.</seg>
     <seg id="6">They will have to face cases.</seg>
     <seg id="7">These regulations are not as a result of Indian influence, are they?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Why is India accusing these organizations of being responsible for the Mumbai Attacks without any proof?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Doesn't India have any local terrorist groups?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Aren't the world organizations aware of the persecution of minorities in India?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Share your opinion with us.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Eid is a festival of happiness and serenity, and on Eid-ul-Azha, the muslims sacrifice a domestic animal to commemorate the sacrifice of Prophet Ibrahim A.S. (Prophet Abraham).</seg>
     <seg id="2">In these troubled times, when the inflation is at its peak and the government is highly unstable; everybody, poor or rich, prepares for Eid and wishes loved ones a Happy Eid in their own different way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We are also giving you an oppurtunity to wish your loved ones eid greetings through our blog, in the form of short messages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You can also send Eid wishes in the form of short Eid poems.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-Murtaza Gilani</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi says, "Our leaders should understand that the people they are targetting by their military operations are the ones who are actually the true patriots, who are enduring all types of cruelty but continue to love Pakistan more than their own lives."</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>

