<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="mturk">
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">France's Suggestion Appreciatable.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When committee's meeting was set up in the parliament house the chairman Mushahid Hussain syeed of the commity in his presence the   suggestion was given to the government,not only with the help of donating thinks but also  with all the political group to send to the parliment of Paliestien.</seg>
    <seg id="3">After the meeting while talking to one of the members, Mushahid hussain sayeed stood by the side of France's  suggestion. Which it is said that the Israial's should stop the war immediatly, besides all this the people who are in the cave should be permitted to do some work.</seg>
    <seg id="4">On behalf of Israel the attack on Palistine was declared as a crime on humanity, they said that all the countries should help.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mushahid Hussain said that all the countries give their opinion on terrorism, but on the attack of Israel or Paliestine they were all quiet.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The chairman of the committee said the Paliestien's matter of Saddam's brother Tanfeed was made a target.</seg>
    <seg id="7">They said that the commitee said that America's President Barack Obama will speak to the muslim people to erase the misunderstanding between muslim people and America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mushahid Hussain Sayeed said that the arising misunderstanding between muslim and western people will be seen and decided. The Kashmir and Paliestine problem will be solved.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Malik imdad khan the ex minister said to the committee that he will be attending the confrence of the Islamic countries which is held in Saudi Arabia.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The meeting on Israel's attack on Palestine and the other country is trying to be resolved.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The prime minister of external affairs said that the issue of Falastin should be solved according to the planning of The United States.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Two generalists belonging Arab countries also attended the meeting and told about the fresh situation of Falastin.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Here the students of International University in Islamabad held a strike against Islaean attacks on Falastin.</seg>
    <seg id="14">The strikers held banners and pads containing slogans against Israel.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Abstain from eating less in order to escape from flu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This research of American scientists was published after many experiments on mice.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The experiments proved that mice who consumed less calories had less defense against the flu.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The research disproved the old wives tale that eating less is useful in preventing the fever.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Eat and drink more when you have a fever according to scientists.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is the saying of the researchers of Michigan State University that the low eater mouses had the low defending power against infection and their death chances decreased although the more eaters mouses had the high power against flue virus.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Professor Elizabeth Gardner said that those who are dieting are not only likely to contract the flu, but also take longer to recover.</seg>
    <seg id="8">She also said that those who have taken flu vaccines should also avoid dieting for a few months during the winter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">First nuclear test was done in 1990.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Thomas Reid, who worked in the Leur National Laboratory as a weapon designer wrote this book with the help of Los Alamos National Laboratory's former Technical Intelligence Director, Danny Staleman.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this book, called 'Nuclear Express', details the political history of the bomb and its spread. Both the authors claim that whichever country made an atom bomb, they either stole the nuclear secrets from another country or they got help from a nuclear power.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Thomas Reid said in an interview with US News that China tested Pakistan's first atom bomb in 1990. This was during the term of the Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Thomas Reid said that, due to many factors, he is certain that China tested Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Among the factors are the design of the bomb and the information he gathered from Chinese scientists.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He further added this was the reason that Pakistan was able to respond to India's Nuclear test with a nuclear test in just 2 weeks and 3 days.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Thomas Reid reminded us that in 1961 Russia suddenly performed a nuclear test. The response to which America took 17 days to preform a test.  This was despite having this bomb for a long time.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He added that the atom bomb that was tested on May 19th 1998 by Pakistan was made very carefully, and that Pakistani scientists had complete faith in it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">When Thomas Reid was asked whether China had provided nuclear technology to Pakistan, he said India was the common enemy of both China and Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that there was proof available that Dr. Abdul Qadeer Khan used the Chinese design.  Later, documents were received from Libya which also verified this fact.</seg>
    <seg id="12">When asked whether joint nuclear testing was common, he said that America had openly performed nuclear tests for England in the deserts of Nevada in 1990.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said that he also believes that Israel has access to the results of this testing.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Thomas Reid was also asked about China's nuclear distribution program which is ongoing.</seg>
    <seg id="15">In answer, Thomas Reid said that China has been providing raw material, guidance and design for the nuclear setup in Esfahan, Iran since 1991.</seg>
    <seg id="16">In conjunction with this, China provided Iran with the nuclear enrichment plant in Kheraj.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He said that China has been providing Iran, Syria, Pakistan, Egypt, and Libya with nuclear technology through North Korea.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">2008 was excellent for the media.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The business man travels throughout his normal day when he discovers a flaw in his work, and fixes it and goes about his day.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The male student walks along the long road.</seg>
    <seg id="4">the puppy and the children play non-stop until their mother calls them all in.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The business man travels throughout his normal day when he discovers a flaw in his work, and fixes it and goes about his day.</seg>
    <seg id="6">the puppy and the children play non-stop until their mother calls them all in.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The male student walks along the long road.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The business man travels throughout his normal day when he discovers a flaw in his work, and fixes it and goes about his day.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The male student walks along the long road.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The puppy and the children play non-stop until their mother calls them all in.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The business man travels throughout his normal day when he discovers a flaw in his work, and fixes it and goes about his day.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In America, there was an average increase of 8% in the price of one ticket. In Madonna's show, the most expensive ticket sold was $350.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Pollstar magazine editor Gary Bongiovanni said that given the economic environment, 2008 was a good year for musicians.</seg>
    <seg id="14">He predicted that 2009 would be a good year for Springsteen and U2, whose albums were to be released this year.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ban on Joint Education: Taliban</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The local Taliban of the Hafiz Gul Bahadur faction (the chief province), Miran Shah and other provinces of North Waziristan have distributed a pamphlet in which government and semi-government institutes in which boys and girl are given joint education were warned.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The pamphlet stated that if the joint educational institutes were not closed by the 5th of January, action will be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The pamphlet said that making identification cards for women, either for government aid or for other educational reasons would be forbidden, and that women would be disallowed from going to identification offices in all provinces.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This announcement was made at a time when about 200 women had already submitted their forms in North Waziristan for identification cards in the identification offices for the sake of the Benazir Income Support Program.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to locals, the pamphlets were read out over the loudspeakers of all mosques in North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">However, the letter did not state whether or not there would be a ban on separate girls' educational institutions.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to this pamphlet if any women goes to school or any government office to get education or make the Identity car then there would be strict punishment for her and her family when she is caught.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Apart from this the Police have also reported that on Sunday, in the District of Banu, Meeran Shah Road there was a nuclear Blast at the tunnel, as a result of which a  passenger was killed and one man is injured</seg>
    <seg id="10">The injured was admitted to the Banu Soul Hospital.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Target Cling- "More dead bodies are discovered"</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police two dead bodies were discovered on Sunday, from the areas of Green Chowk and Saharab Khan Chowk (Mingora).The heads of these bodies were separated at their necks.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The information about the killed are being told through the Front-air corp. and police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The investigation team has reported that a letter was found near the killed bodies warning that whoever attended or shifted these killed bodies before the morning at 11 a.m. will be responsible for his destruction.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The local people of that area have stated that no dead bodies were touched until 11am in the morning. Later we security guards lifted these bodies and shifted to the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The head place Mingora and the nearby places of this area have been experiencing a lot of new dangerous incidents during the Target Cling, from the past few weeks. There is an increase in these incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It has been shown that among the killed there included the local area people, women and security guards.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to local sources, more than thirty people have been killed to date by these kind of incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="9">so far, no organization have taken responsibility for these killings.</seg>
    <seg id="10">the spokesman of the local Taliban in Swat Muslim Khan told us this Saturday that the dead bodies found last Friday included those of his fellows. It also included the dead body of the Taliban commander, Deolai Rafiullah</seg>
    <seg id="11">Muslim Khan said that Rafiullah was under custody of the security forces for one and half month.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He had said that the local Taliban sent notices before killing anybody.     On the other hand, the citizens of Mengora are worried about these incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="13">according to the local people, a large number of security forces have been deployed in Mengora,  but despite all these, attacks on the citizens are still increasing.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A Tribute to Benazir from Bakhtawar.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A rap song (a modern style of music) in Bakhtawar's voice is posted on youtube.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is 5 minutes long song contains pictures and video- clips of Benazir.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Eighteen years old Bakhtawar is a student at the Edinburgh University.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Poetry and singing greatly interest her.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Singing became a hobby for her after the encouragement she received from her mother.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Paying tribute to her mother, she said she was a beautiful and intelligent lady who did everything with style.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On December 27th her mother was shot in the temple and died at the age of 54 leaving behind three children.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The whole nation misses her and she is still in everyone's heart.</seg>
    <seg id="10">20 year old Bilawal is the eldest of Benazir's children with Bakhtawar being the next oldest.</seg>
    <seg id="11">She has had an interest in music from her earliest days.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Before her mother's return to the country she told a journalist friend that she would like to meet the Grammy award winning music director and rapper Puff DD but the meeting could not take place.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Bakhtawar's voice is being heard for the first time through You Tube and her poetry is being published by some Sindhi newspapers as well.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Some workers and followers of Benazir Bhutto have started preparing CDs of Bakhtawar's rap song.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other hand, Pakistan Peoples Party spokesperson, Farhatullah Babar, confirmed that the song and voice present on YouTube is that of Bukhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="16">He said on the phone from Islamabad that this was the honoring of a brave mother by a sad daughter, which even started to play on Pakistan's government TV network.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar said that the party had no present plan to distribute CD's of her song.</seg>
    <seg id="18">He said that, a few months ago, a fake page belonging to their party's young chairman, Bilawal Bhutto Zardari, was created on Facebook and that this was later removed.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani and is the Minister for Media.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The joint minister of media and publishing, Sherry Rehman, told BBC Urdu in an SMS message, that he could confirm Ajmal Qasab's citizenship as a Pakistani but that more investigations were going on.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Before this, the internal advisor to the Prime Minister, Rahman Malik, had denied his Pakistani citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the record keeping offices do not have any record of him.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Regarding this new standpoint, it could not be ascertained why the Pakistani government changed their stand.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, according to the Foreign Ministry, the confirmation of Ajmal Qasab's citizenship was done by the Home Ministry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Before the BBC Urdu service and some other news papers and TV channels showed Ajamal Qasab belongs to Okara's district Faridcoat village of province Punjab.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The government kept denying it.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is still not clear that either Ajmal Qasaab belongs to Faridcort or some other area.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Rockets fired from Lebanon, Lebanon fires back!</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Israels soldier and police personnel told news agencies representative that there were four rockets fired from Lebanon to Israel in which one landed on North district of Nahriya resulting in two people receiving minor injuries.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In reply, Israeli tanks bombarded on Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It is not clear that this attack was made by Hezbollah or either behind that there is a hand of Palestinian activists group in Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Lebanon's government said that they are also trying to discover who is behind that rockets attack.</seg>
    <seg id="6">BBC analyst considered that this is a very dangerous turn of an intense situation in this region at the present time.</seg>
    <seg id="7">BBC correspondent for the middle east Jeremy Boin stated according to him this rocket attack gives more danger to a separate war.</seg>
    <seg id="8">A threat is being expressed for the last few days that what if the current proceedings in Gaza spread to the borders of Israel along with Lebanon in the North.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Here, during the night between Wednesday and Thursday, Israel's air force performed 7 aerial attacks on the Gaza strip.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the Israeli army, the police stations in Hammas, tunnels, stock of weapons, rocket firing points, and weapon workers of Hammas were made targets during these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Besides the aerial attacks, the Israeli army and marine artillery men continued bombing on Gaza through out the night.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to the Palestine sources, a mosque was destroyed in one of the aerial attacks in the city of Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="13">According to unverified sources,Israeli army tanks, which were supported by helicopters, moved towards the area of Khan Yunus.</seg>
    <seg id="14">In the fight going on for the last 12 days,almost 700 Palestinians have died including women and children in a large number.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Although on the other hand, 11 men of the Israeli army were also killed.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Israeli security forces have confirmed that high defense official Amoos Gilad is going to Qahir to discuss the conditions of the cease fire.</seg>
    <seg id="17">One delegation from Hammas is also about to leave for Qahir to talk to the ambassadors of Egypt.</seg>
    <seg id="18">With this, the director of Falastin authority abbas Mahmood is also reaching Qahira at Friday.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">My heart has been broken, return my kidney.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Doctor Richard Batista told that he donated his kidney to his wife,8 years ago,in order to save her life.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the saying of news reporter institute A.F., the wife of Doctor Richard Batista gave the reward for that donation, and then deceived him and made out with another person and got divorce.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Doctor Richard Batista told in an interview to a national news Daily News, that the lover of his wife made a hole in his heart and that is still in his heart.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the statement of Doctor Richard Batista, he is asking for his kidney back, and in fact he wants to return the money for that kidney.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to his wife, she will give her testimony in the front of a judge after some days.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Nine k.g. lobster freed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Jar j The Joint: The lobster was caught from a sea before two weeks.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The company of sea food purchased it in 100 dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">They started taking photos of lobsters for their marketing campaign.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Working for All Animal Protection Organization, PETA demanded the release of the lobster, which resulted in their being released into the sea.</seg>
    <seg id="6">George was caught in the sea near Canada from where he spent ten days at City Crab and Seafood Company.</seg>
    <seg id="7">A lobster's age can be calculated according to his weight.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Restaurant Manager Keth Walnti says that his intention was not to harm but to simply place the lobster in the tank so people could take interest.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Wallay Ingrid Newkrk, a member of Animal Protection Organization PETA, says that the restaurant's decision is appreciated and is an example for those who wish to keep this precious animal in to tank or to cook them in water.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Cell Phone Helped to Find Baby</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When authorities learned of the disappearance of Nitali Maltis, Massachusetts city Police officer and Agarbijhon jumped to action.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Authorities found the exact location of the baby with the help of the GPS system installed in her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="4">They utilized Google Street View to help and locate the baby, she was in Hotel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A week ago Natalie's grandmother Rose Maltois Natalie took her from her legal parents' custody.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Ethol's police chief Timothy Anderson told BBC that she said she would never give Natalie back and then she left the state.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Police contacted Miss Maltois but when as per promise she did not send Natalie back, the Police decided to search for Natalie through her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Since 2005, there is a regulation in America that the cellular companies will provide location for 67 percent people in a range of 100 meters and 95 percent callers in a range of 300 meters.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on a visit to India.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This is Hamid Karzai's second Indian tour in last five months.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is expected that during his meeting with Prime minister Manmohan Singh, he will discuss after effects of the terrorist attacks in Mumbai.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this visit, he wants to express the feeling of his people and solidarity with India over the Mumbai terrorists attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">During Karzai's visit, besides extremism, bilateral trade will also be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Discussion on bilateral cooperation to counter extremism between both countries is also expected.</seg>
    <seg id="7">During his last visit to India, president Hamid Karzai said that terrorism will not be interfere with the relations between India and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He also said that both India and Afghanistan are facing challenges of terrorism and merciless killings.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Peace and stability in both countries would be very beneficial for the whole world.</seg>
    <seg id="10">We understand the reality that both countries, and the whole world can only join hands to face this curse of terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="11"></seg>
    <seg id="12"></seg>
    <seg id="13"></seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2"></seg>
    <seg id="3"></seg>
    <seg id="4">Ajmal Qasab is now in police custody, and it is hoped that the police will file charges against him before January 24th.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ajmal Qasab does not have a lawyer to defend him.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In a letter written to the Pakistani government, Qasab asked for legal aid.</seg>
    <seg id="7">India has given Pakistan proof of the involvement of Pakistani extremists in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Pakistan has accepted that Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani civilian.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the police file, Ajmal Qasab and his partner Abu Ismail killed 6 police officers including ATS chief Hemant Karkare, Additional Police Commissioner Ashok Kamte and Encounter Specialist Police Inspector Vijay Salaskar, after which they fled with their squad car, which was later recovered near DB Marg, Gurgam Choupati.</seg>
    <seg id="10">During police action, Ismail Khan died and the police captured Ajmal alive.</seg>
    <seg id="11">No lawyer has been appointed yet, to follow Ajmal's case.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The lawyer chosen by the government, from the legal aid cell, Dinesh Mota, refused to accept the case on moral reasons.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Two other lawyers pulled out their names after protests and opposition by a political group.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Constitutional Amendment; Committee to be formed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After addressing a seminar on environment change; he told media representatives, that for this sake, the parliamentary meeting will take place in which a committee will be formed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that until now, to complete the 17th amendment, the constitutional amendment bill was presented by the Joint National Movement to the National Assembly; whereas other political parties have also presented their constitutional bills in this regard to the parliament.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the Pakistan Peoples Party has also sent all the political parties a rough version of the 17th amendment and the committee would analyze their version.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In answer to a question, he said that the parliament would decide the balance of power between the President and the Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Prime Minister said that the Parliament has the complete right to take any decision.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In answer to another question, he said that in getting the former President retired General Pervez Musharraf to leave his post, apart from the role of political partiesl the former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Pakistan Peoples Party, Benazir Bhutto also played an important role, By forcing the global brotherhood to remove the uniform of President Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that the elected Vice President of America, Joe Biden, was a supporter of Pakistan and democracy, and that the president honored him in return for his services with the Pakistani Crescent.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Replying to a question about the Indian governments warning of breaking all ties with Pakistan, after the Mumbai incident, the Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Geelani said that the leaders are under extreme pressure from the public; which is why they issue such statements.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Protest against the removal of journalists.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Many print and electronic media journalists held protest demonstration under the backing of RIUJ against the downsizing in different media organizations. They were shouting slogans against media owners and government</seg>
    <seg id="3">CR Shamsi, a senior member of RIUJ, addressed the gathering. He said the same politicians who were protesting on roads with us, now are ruling this country. They have not had enough courage to take actions against some power media owners.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the owners of media groups talked about human rights, but they are exploiting the poor journalists by killing them financially.</seg>
    <seg id="5">One example of the exploitation is the suicide of a reporter on a Lahore based Private TV channel. He had not been paid his salary for four months. The media workers are living hand to mouth under the constant stress of downsizing and under payment.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He supported a decisive action against media owners, proposing that a camp should be installed before the National assembly to show anger and protest.</seg>
    <seg id="7">CR Shamsi criticized Salman Taseer and claimed that the Goverment's newspaper aaj Kaal is firing its employees without any prior notice.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Daily Jinnah, Daily Khabrain, Channel 5, Business Plus and Aaj news have fired dozens of their employees.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Mazhar Abbas, General Secretary RIUJ, also addressed the group. He said that all journalists associations are observing black day today to protest against forced abdications of journalists. He said that journalists will cover the Parliaments session with black strips to protest.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Mazhar Abbas said that fifty percent of Pakistan television channels and newspapers are exploiting media workers. Journalists are working there without any formal agreement</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that more than two hundred journalists and media workers are being fired from TV channels and newspapers. More workers can be fired by using economic crisis as a possible reason.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas said that movement of journalists will remain active until restoration of dismissed employees, implementation of 7th wage board and payment of pending salaries to employees of newspapers and TV channels.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The 11 cabinet members too their oath.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The new cabinet consists of Farward's block of former PM Sardar Attique's Muslim conference, 2 members of PPP, 2 members of People's Muslim League and one member of MQM.</seg>
    <seg id="3">A female member is also a part of the cabinet. She belongs to the forward block of Muslim conference.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the Ruling Alliance, the cabinet will be enhanced during next week. Twelve more ministers will be included in the cabinet. Earlier this month Sardar Attique Khan lost his position due to the of vote of no confidence. He was replaced by Sardar yaqoob kKhan.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The department of The Ministers will be announced later.</seg>
    <seg id="6">During the oath taking ceremony, PPP workers raised slogans of support to Benazir Bhutto the former Prime Minister of Pakistan.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Three and a half million users were infected by a virus.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Conficker was first identified in October 2008. He is also named as Downup, Downadup and Kido</seg>
    <seg id="3">A patch is offered by Microsoft to remove this virus, still almost three and a half computers and memory sticks are effected by this problem.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Experts say that the number of computers affected could be quite large.</seg>
    <seg id="5">To get rid of this, dealers need to use Microsoft's MS08-067 patch.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Microsoft reports that the virus which, has affected thousands of computers, searches for the Windows file 'services.exe' and injects its code into it.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Then, this virus becomes a DLL type of file in the Windows system folder.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This virus also changes the name of the file.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It then changes the Windows registration details.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After this virus has infected the machine, it creates problems; a connection appears as an HTTP server as well as changes the restore point of the machine.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It then downloads files from the hackers' websites.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Microsoft claims that this virus has affected computers worldwide.</seg>
    <seg id="13">China, Brazil, Russia, India, America and England are just some of those countries.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Asking for urgent report on Indian information.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Monday, after meeting in ministry of foreign affairs, while talking to the media representative, he said that information given from India</seg>
    <seg id="3">to help investigate this matter.</seg>
    <seg id="4">They said Pakistan is an independent country and does investigate information provided by India and from any other country.</seg>
    <seg id="5">They will not accept any dictation.</seg>
    <seg id="6">They also said they are collecting other information in addition to getting information from India.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Adviser of foreign minter said that organization who controls law and order arrested 124 member of blacklist organization for the risk of peace threat.</seg>
    <seg id="8">And if  some evidence is found against them they will take action and innocents will be freed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He replies no one prison can send to India and take an action against them as according to Pakistani Law.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said takes an action against them as on F.I.A law.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that Indian law enforcement agencies have collected information about people involved in the Mumbai attacks, and the world community, including India, will give Pakistan some time to investigate this information.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He reiterated this offer from the government that a joint investigation team be formed to investigate the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It should be clear that a three-member team from India investigating the Mumbai attacks team is led by an additional director general.</seg>
    <seg id="14">investigating on informations provided to Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Pakistani high commissioner in India Shahid Malik has met President Asif Ali Zardari, and it was decided that if any person or group from Pakistan is found to have been involved in the Mumbai attacks, they will be dealt with in accordance with national laws and no one will be handed over to India. However, Indian leadership is putting pressure on Pakistan to extradite the people involved in the incident to India.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Any thing is possible in America'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mr. Obama will take oath as the 44th president of America on January 20.</seg>
    <seg id="3">While standing on the stairs of the building built in memory of 16th American president Abraham Lincoln, they addressing a musical concert</seg>
    <seg id="4">Mr. Obama said that America is facing the most bitter challenge in many generations, and he is hopeful that America will resolve it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Abraham Lincoln put an end to slavery in America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But along with that Mr. Obama also stated that solving the problems faced by the country would take time and that the path would be a very difficult one.</seg>
    <seg id="7">"But despite this Im hopeful that the vision of the founders of this nation will stay alive."</seg>
    <seg id="8">Besides being involved in the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, America is in the grip of a severe economic crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Extraordinary preparations are on the way for the oath taking ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Observers believe that around two million people will attend the ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Tuesday is a national holiday because on that day the great American visionary, Martin Luther King, Jr., was assassinated.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Martin Luther King was an African American.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Commitment to Work Promised in Honor of Martin Luther King, Jr.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. was killed in the year 1968.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama paid his respects to Dr. King and told his fellow Americans to work together to achieve what was promised to this country.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In Washington there are preparations going on for the oath ceremony that is going to take place on Tuesday. The preparations include preparation for the big public meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that nearly twenty Lakh people will gather in Washington for the first time in the American history, to see this American oath leadership ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama has started Monday by his visit to the TB center in the North America. In in the later part of the day he visited the injured American soldiers. After this he went to visit the house of those who were homeless and painted something on the wall.</seg>
    <seg id="7">While talking to the correspondents Barack Obama has said that - "the problems and troubles in which we are bounded and people who are homeless and troubled by the present circumstances require us to take actions to come out of these problems".</seg>
    <seg id="8">He has also said that Martin Luther King Jr. had spent most of his life by serving the nation and its people.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Barack Obama was also saying that when we are respecting the memories of Martin Luther King Jr. that we should not just stand in his respect but instead adopt his sayings in practice.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He has said that the Tuesday's function in which thousands of people gathered to hear the dream of Martin Luther King Jr. People heard my speech which who were also gathered to hear the same dream in the year 1970.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Martin Luther King Jr. has also said in the same function that "that day would come when people would take inspiration from his color."</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to the BBC's reporter Mathew Pres in the history of the Martin Luther King Jr. celebrations, the President has come for the oath taking ceremony 24 hours before.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The leadership of Obama in the various southern states of America would prove to be the implementation of the dream of Martin Luther King Jr.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Was the Additional Political Agent.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Additional Political Agent was kidnapped by the unknown masked men during the first ten days from Southern Wazeerastan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Sources said that the member was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer Group's local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="4">On the basis of the local organization on Tuesday at nearly four o'clock in the evening the Additional Political Agent of Wazeerastan Aamir Lateef had reached the Wana Scout Camp by a tribal group.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But they didn't say that who kidnapped the Additional Political Agent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Therefore local people say that the local Taaliban had kidnapped the Political Agent.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Aamir Lateef was kidnapped at that time when he was going to Tank from Wana Camp.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On the eleventh of January 2009, in the tribal locality of Karkandra, seven armed masked men had kidnapped the Additional Political Agent Aamir Lateef along with his driver.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Official members say that the kidnappers first unarmed the security available in the cars and then made the Additional Political Agent to sit in another car and took him away.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the Local Organization, after the kidnap of the Additional Political Agent, security forces blockaded all the check posts of the Southern Wasziristan, and the tribal area and every passerby was checked thoroughly and from about a week the officials had ordered economical restrictions on Wana.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the eighth  of December 2008, Northern Wazeerastan's Assistant Political Agent Asmattullah was kidnapped, and at that time when he was traveling from Meer Ali to Banu on Eid Vacation.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">British Hacker's win in the court.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Forty Two years old British citizen had confessed that he had hacked the American Army's website.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gerry is patient of Esperanza Syndrome. It is clear that Esperanza Syndrome patient does only one type of work.</seg>
    <seg id="4">His advocates say that if he was submitted to America then they fear that maybe he will try to commit suicide.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Therefore the government's advocates say that on the basis of Gerry's health condition the possibility is very low.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Lord justice Morris K. and Mister justice Simon had declared that Gerry has the permission to apply for the appeal in the British court.</seg>
    <seg id="7"></seg>
    <seg id="8">They also said that on this situation even the Secretarial Department didn't take any interest.</seg>
    <seg id="9">But the Government's advocates said that the secretarial department had used their options.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Gerry never denied the hacking of an American military website.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In 2001, Gerry hacked into two American systems, resulting  in a loss of 0.8 million dollars to the American government.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Gerry has hacked 97 computers, including the American Navy and NASA.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Gerry has said that his intentions were not wrong. He was only looking for the information related to aliens, which he thinks that American government has kept secret.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Gerry's father, Janes Sharp, is happy with the decision.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Gerry's lawyer has said that the verdict is correct.</seg>
    <seg id="16">This case is under proceeding since 2002 and finally the decision has been made.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Kashmir: Two Hizb Commanders Killed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Lieutenant Kernel Achari, Indian solider of East Frontier, is posted in Jammu and has said to BBC that 24 Rachtri rifles and Jammu Kashmir policeman has covered the area of Gindo Destrict in DoDuk where militants were hiding.</seg>
    <seg id="3">They fired at the military and in return, fired two militants who were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The spokesperson said that among the two killed extremists was the district commander of the 12 year banned organization, Hizbul Mujahideen, which is active in the region, Zuhoorud Deen Khande, who was an expert at gunpowder blasts.</seg>
    <seg id="5">His companion was identified as Sajjad Husain who joined the extremists last year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Acharya, operations are still continuing in the mentioned jungle region, and there is the possibility of more extremists being present there. Two Kalashnikov rifles were also recovered during the first stage of the operation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Yesterday, state police chief, Kuldeep Kumar Khudda released the stats for 2008, saying that this was the most peaceful year so far.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that no violence was reported in the seven stage assembly elections that took place in November and December.</seg>
    <seg id="9">More than 1350 contestants took part in these elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It should be known that Hizbul Mujahideen is active in Jammu and Kashmir for the last 18 years.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Hizb called a one sided ceasefire for the first time in July 2000, after which the Indian government and Hizb commanders held dialogs.</seg>
    <seg id="12">However, the ceasefire came to an end within 15 days.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Since then, many Hizbul Mujahideen commanders were killed in operations.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On Thursday in Pakistan's reputed daily newspaper "The News", an article was written about the residing terrorist groups in Pakistani Kashmir saying that Lashker-e-Tayyaba and Hizb-ul-Mujahideen has made a decision considering the Kashmir policy.</seg>
    <seg id="15">It should be made clear that the policy of both groups until now was that the Kashmir problem can be solved by the armed opposition.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Dera Bugti: Blast on the gas pipe line.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police officials, the 18 inch Qatar pipe line from Loti gas field was destroyed in a bomb blast on Monday.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This pipe line goes towards the Sui plant.</seg>
    <seg id="4">A man named Sarbaz Baloch heralding himself as a representative of his invalidate party "Baloch republican army" has accepted the responsibility for this attack on behalf of the aforementioned party.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In four days, this is the fourth gas pipe line was destroyed in a bomb blast.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On Friday, in Dera Allah Yar, another 18 inch Qatar pipe line was destroyed whose maintenance was continued until Sunday morning.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The general manager Mushtaq Siddiqui of the Sui Southern Gas company in Quetta said that gas supply through this pipeline would begin after noon.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This pipeline comes to Quetta through Sibbi.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In Quetta, Ziyarath, and other far off regions, there has been an acute shortage of gas for the last three days. On the one hand, it is continuously snowing and the temperature has fallen below the freezing point, and, on the other hand, the heaters and stoves have gone cold.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Apart from this, in Derahbagti town, there was a motorcycle blast in the market; but according to the police, there was no loss of life in the blast.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Administrator for Jamaa'athud Da'wah</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The central headquarters of Jamaa'athud Da'wah is in Taibah, about 25  kilometers from Karachi.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This center includes a hospital, a school, and a hostel for students.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The law minister of Punjab, Rana Sanaullah Khan, says that supervisors were appointed in the center of Jamaa'athud Da'wah, so that the work of social institutes there goes on unaffected.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Khalid Waleed, son in law of the Jamaa'athud Da'wah chief, Hafiz Saeed, a high ranking government officer, Khaqan Babar, was appointed as the administrator for the supervision of the hospital, school, and other social institutes based in the center, while according to him, the posting of police at the center was also increased.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Security Council has passed a ban on Jamaa'athud Da'wah, after which the Pakistani government has started taking action against Jamaa'athud Da'wah across the country, and has put the chief of the Jamaa'ath, Hafiz Saeed, along with other leaders under house arrest. The appointment of the administrator in the Taibah center by the Punjab government was also a part of the action being taken against Jamaa'athud Da'wah by the joint government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Khaqan Babar belongs to the DMG, i.e. District Management Group.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Hafiz Khalid Waleed said that the Commissioner of Lahore division, Khusroe Pervez Khan, along with police and the civil government, came on Sunday and inspected the Taibah center. Khalid Waleed spoke badly about the appointment of an administrator by the government in Jamaa'athud Da'wah, and he said that the number of patients in the hospital and children in the school had already dropped due to government actions.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Here, according to a press release by Jamat-ud-Dawa, the party's chief Hafiz Saeed has written a letter to the General Secretary of the United Nations, Ban Ki Mon, and Committee for Taliban, requesting to cancel the restrictions on the party made by the Security Council.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It says in the letter that the one-sided decision of the Security Council on banning Jamat-ud-Dawa is unfair. And Jamat-ud-Dawa has no relation with terrorism but is busy with the activities of charity.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Edhi on the aid mission of Gaza.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After going through many steps of receiving permission required to enter Gaza, he has only been successful in reaching Egypt from New York.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said while talking to BBC Urdu service from Qahira that he has still not reached Gaza because Egypt and Israel have created many obstacles.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that it has been 8 days since I am here but I still have not received the permission to enter Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I am currently in Qahira and hopefully will get permission to go to Gaza."</seg>
    <seg id="6">He explained: "First I was given only a 7-day visa to go to Gaza and later on my insisting, Pakistani officials helped me and had it extended for one month but on this condition: that I will go to Gaza only once and that it is a single entry."</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that he has his son and daughters with him and they want to do charity work in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">I have brought some money.</seg>
    <seg id="9">$100,000 Cheque has been given to Egypt Red-Cross and $10,000 total cash is also being donated for aid supply to Ghaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Four more minister added to the cabinet which now totals 64 Ministers.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Among the new Federal Ministers, two Members are from Mutihida Qaumi Moment and two are from Jamiat Ulmai Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The newly elected Ministers took the Oath from President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During the Oath Ceremony, also present were Federation Cabinet members: Prime Minister Yuosaf Raza Gillani.</seg>
    <seg id="5">With four New Federal Ministers the total strength of Cabinet incliding  Ministers, Federal Ministers and Advisors reached a total of 63.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Farooq Sattar and Babar Ghuari are two ministers from MQM while Azam Swati and Mulana Atta  Rehman are from Jamiat e Ulami Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The department of Ministries were not announced till today.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Faroo Sattar is a Convener and Babar Ghauri is a Senator from MQM their terms are ending on the 10th of March.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Azam Swati is Selected as Independent Senator. He is considered to be richest Senator.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Member of the National Assembly, Molana Ata-ur-Rehman is the younger brother of Molana Fazal-ur-Rehman</seg>
    <seg id="11">It should be noted that four important advisers are not members of National Assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It should be noted that on November 3, 2008, 22 new ministers and 18 state ministers were added in the cabinet. At that time, it was thought that MQM would be added to the cabinet, however, due to disagreements over division of ministries, MQA was not included.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Baluchistan, Pipe Line Destroyed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to Police, an 18 inch diameter pipe line which serviced different wells in Pee Koh, was destroyed in the morning by an unidentified party.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Yesterday a third well in Sui was also completely destroyed, and a gas pipe line was damaged near Dera Illa Yar.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Sirbaz Khan, who is the representative of the disbanded organization Baloch Republican Army, has claimed responsibility for the attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Violent incidents have increased in Balochistan since the start of 2009.</seg>
    <seg id="6">This month, dozens of gas pipe lines have been destroyed and the attacks have increased on trains and people from Punjab.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Although Chief Minister Balochistan Nawab Aslam Raeesaani has expressed his concerns and ordered police to exchange information with secret agencies, it has still been impossible to stop these incidents.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">$819 Billion dollar economic package approved.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">No Republican member voted in support of President Obama's  plan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to Republicans, this economic package will not prove to be a failure</seg>
    <seg id="4">In the House, this economic package is passed at a 244-188 vote.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This package will be presented to the Senate next week. In the senate, the democrats are in a slight majority.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Because of the strong criticism from republicans approval of this package will not be easy.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Obama has asked the congress to support this economic package by putting aside their political bias.</seg>
    <seg id="8">ThePresident is very optimistic about his economic plan, which may become a law next month. The President hopes this economic plan will be useful for the American economy and trade.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to this economic plan, a large amount has been dedicated to the general public and business community. $540 billion dollars will be spent on communication, education and modern technology.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Richard Listern, A BBC correspondent in Washington D.C, Obama came in to power with the motto to introduce new political culture. Current debate on the economic package has increased political bitterness.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Republican members of the senate called the proposed bill a waste of government money, and said that it will not help in creating new employment opportunities.</seg>
    <seg id="12">They instead stressed the bill passed by their own party, in which more importance was given to tax cuts.</seg>
    <seg id="13">They said that more employment opportunities could be formed with less capital through their bill.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They said that compared to constructive plans, more employment opportunities could be formed through tax cuts.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bitterness between Israeli President and Turkish Prime Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Nearly screaming, Recep Tayyip Erdogan told the Israeli president that the blood of many humans were spilled in Gaza, and it saddened him to see that people could watch this armed killing from Israel and clap in agreement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Erdogan said that ""I believe that you are using such words to publicly ease your guilty conscience.  But you killed those people, and I will not forget those children who were killed near the shore.""</seg>
    <seg id="4">Simon said that Gaza's calamity is not due to Israel, but rather Hamas, who have established a dangerous dictatorship over there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A BBC journalist from Davos said that he had never seen such a scene in an global economic forum before.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, Erdogan later stated that he respected the aged Israeli president, falsely claiming that he was not yelling at him.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Turkey is one of the few Muslim countries which has a diplomatic relationship with Israel, but displeasure has been materializing between the two recently.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Attack not planned by Pakistan'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When talking to ND TV, an Indian channel, Wajid Shamsul Hassan stated that the Pakistani investigation report on Mumbai attack would be executed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">When the attack occurred in Mumbai last November, more than 120 people were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">India accused the extremist outfit, Lashkar e Twaiba, of being behind the attack.</seg>
    <seg id="5">India also said that the 'political factors' in Pakistan influenced the incident.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Mumbai attack has badly affected the relationship between the two countries.</seg>
    <seg id="7">When talking about the Pakistan investigation report on the incident, the high commissioner, Wajid Shamsul Hassan, has given out hints about the whereabouts of the report.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wajid Shamsul Hassan said that in the light of investigation made so far, it is understood that Pak land had not been used for organizing the attack.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It might have been some other land; definitely, not Britain too.</seg>
    <seg id="10">these are the two places (Pakistan and Britain) about which I was worried.</seg>
    <seg id="11">India and the international community have created a lot of pressure on Pakistan to take actions against the culprits of the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Wajid Shamsul Haq said: we are not trying to cover it up.</seg>
    <seg id="13">we believe in taking action based on facts.</seg>
    <seg id="14">the world will accept our investigations.</seg>
    <seg id="15">we will try to satisfy India over the results (of the investigation)</seg>
    <seg id="16">while defending the delay in the investigation in Pakistan he said that it takes time to collect, understand and check these kind of information.</seg>
    <seg id="17">The High Commissioner Wajid Shamsul Haq said that it took 45 days for India to present its dossier.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A black man elected as the republican leader too.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">in the sixth round of elections in the Republican party, Michael Steel has won and received 91 votes out of 168.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Katon Dawson, the candidate for Chairman who was opposing Steele received 77 votes. Ex-chairman Duncan withdrew from the competition in the second stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Newspaper writers say that among the five candidates for the chairmanship of the Republican Party, Michael Steele was considered the most moderate leader.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After winning, Michael Steele said in his speech, 'We are going to tell our friends and foes together, that you can join with us, but whoever wants to spoil this, they should be ready to be separated from us'. Michael Steele is from Maryland where he was the Deputy Governor.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He rose to fame in 2006, when he ran for a Senate seat.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But after losing in the race for the senate seat, he became the chairman of the Political Conservative Committee of the Republican party.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Now, after being selected the chairman of the party, the country wide projects will be under his supervision.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In the election he promised that he would take the party in a new direction, and that he would use new techniques to join old-fashioned supporters with the party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Indian Claim of the Presence of Lashkar-e-Taiba and Jaysh-e-Mohammad in Jammu</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">There are reports of militants in the Ponch province of Jammu.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to government sources, the police and the army upon receiving secret reports, have surrounded the region and have started searching it.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this, a fight started in which four militants, two soldiers, and one policeman were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the sources, fights were going on until the last news. And in this area, militants associated with Lashker-e-Tayyaba and Josh-e-Muhammad are present, for which more army has been sent to fight them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">During this, chief minister, nominated by the involved officials, Omer Abdullah met with the governor and he directly gave the news of the selection of the Assembly leader from his party national conference.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Congress, the ally of the National conference also informed the governor of the advocacy of Omar Abdullah.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Omar Abdullah will take oath as the chief minister of teh sate.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Remember, national conference became the biggest party by gaining 28 seats in the assembly of 87 members in the current state elections. Keep in mind that separatist parties boycotted the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Congress, which secured 17 seats, accepted to form a coailition government with the national conference.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Today party workers welcomed Omar Abdullah with great fanfare on his arrival in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On this occasion, Omar Abdullah says that he will play his role in making the talks possible between Indian government and separatists. Although, this is not possible until the elections in India and formation of the new government.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Role of EU for Peace in the Middle east.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">From the official point of view, the role of the European Union is decisive in the peace efforts to stop the war in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to Brussels' official stance, the efforts of Schwarzenberg delegation or Sarkozy were equally helpful in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The European Union's spokesman, Amadeu Altafaj, has said that every such effort is appreciated which is helpful in sending the European Union's message to the opponents of the war.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It seems alright as far as the official statement is concerned.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In reality, the European Union is portraying a very disappointing picture of the internal tensions.</seg>
    <seg id="7">As the head of the Union, the Czech Republic's role is even weaker than before.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Also, the internal issues have made it helpless.</seg>
    <seg id="9">On the other hand, the French President, Sarkozy, is behaving as if he is still the President of the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="10">France has completed its presidential tenure of six months.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Sarkozy wants to play a leading role, and he is capable of it, but he does not have the permission to do so.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The most comedic situation is for the Ambassdor of France Mr. Bernard Kouchner.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Mr. Bernard Kouchner is also involved in this, with guidance from the Ambassador of Czech Republic, Mr. Schwarzenberg.</seg>
    <seg id="14">This is not their only difference of  opinion, they may have to face a battle with the western world</seg>
    <seg id="15">they said that for the defence the Isreal they might has to face the war, even though it doesn't appear like that,  on the other side Germany also posted a person towards the east side. till Europeoan Union come to an conclusion, they wont win the battle</seg>
    <seg id="16">This is the proof of Isreal, which doesn't provide any response to the European Countries.</seg>
    <seg id="17">This is the best time for the European Union to perform, because America has failed in the western side. by the law of Goerge W bush</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Capitalism Revolution: Death of German millionare.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the south of Germany, a place by the name of Subia. Adolf Miracle has left big business people behind him.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Some time ago the german people didn't know him.</seg>
    <seg id="4">After which business people found it difficult to raise funds from 30 banks.  Then  he(name) was in the headline of a newspaper: this is a reflection of a bad future for the mircle group.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The aim of advertising is always to sell the product or let the people know the various facilities made available to them either at the market or at their doorstep.</seg>
    <seg id="6">When a product is being advertised we are able to gather more information such as its name, price, benefits and availability.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But sometime the drafted messages tends to be fictional, owing to either exaggeration or to false claims made by the advertiser. Viewed objectively, the advertising message must act as a salesperson and do its best to convince the consumer of the merits of the product.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The words used in advertisements are typical of a salespersons' language and this is how he would like to convince his prospective buyer, should they come face-to-face.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The name of this advertisement is Ratiopharm. The words used by the salesperson definitely praise the product or service that is available.</seg>
    <seg id="10">More often, they are colorful and catchy words as they persuade the customer to respond favorably and force him to purchase the product. Unless cosmetics and other like Kassbohrer products are heavily promoted, they will languish unsold on the shelves of stores for a long time.</seg>
    <seg id="11">So, advertising always puts forward the best points of the product. Advertisement can be educational, entertaining, informative, handy and surely interesting.</seg>
    <seg id="12">At times, however, they tend to be boring, irritating, incredible and embarrassing.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Another category of advertisements tends to brag so as to tempt the buyers.</seg>
    <seg id="14">But whatever it may be, advertisements have a two-fold purpose to serve. They have a message to convey and they attempt to evoke a desirable response in the buyer. As a result 400 VEM product become popular ones and the demand increases.</seg>
    <seg id="15">this way Merchlay group will stay as it used to be after the death of Adolph Merchley</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The crime rate among the immigrants in Germany.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to latest statistics the crime rate among immigrants from 2004 till 2007 is 22%.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Decline from 9 to 0.21%</seg>
    <seg id="4">has reached 4%</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Interior minister Joachim Herrmann of province Bavaria this is a superficial positive change.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said ""this should be noted that the number of outsiders seeking immigration of Germany is increasing""</seg>
    <seg id="7">Hence, this should also be stated in statistics that the criminal is a German citizen but his background is non-immigrant.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that his province will also consider this while collecting statistics</seg>
    <seg id="9">A part from Bavaria the same is being planned in Hamburg.</seg>
    <seg id="10">A senator for foreign affairs from CDU, Christoph Ahlhaus, has said: "When research is done in a scientific manner, man can not pre-decide its results but it is based on the facts and figures that come out as a result of the research."</seg>
    <seg id="11">Ahlhaus diverted attention to a research report from the anti-crime provincial office which was prepared in 2006 and according to this report in Bergdorf, a part of Hamburg, it was discovered that out of all crimes happening there is a percentage that have the involvement of foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="12">results showed that the foreigners here have</seg>
    <seg id="13">Tthe crime rate was less as compared to crime all over the province.</seg>
    <seg id="14">By contrast, when a survey was done in 2006 on crimes in youth in Berlin, it was determined that young people having foreign background had a percentage of 44%.</seg>
    <seg id="15">was 7 percent</seg>
    <seg id="16">However, other political parties of Germany for example, SPD, Environmentalists organization Greens, and leftist organization Linkspartei,were against this proposal that while collecting facts and figures regarding crimes, this should also be inquired which German citizens have foreign backgrounds.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">We want quick evacuation of troops from Gaza: Olmert</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Ehud Olmert has stressed that for complete evacuation of the army, a future and permanent ceasefire agreement is inevitable.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamas and Israel declared ceasefire on Sunday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Islamic militant group Hamas has announced a one week war break, and that the Israeli army should evacuate the Gaza strip within that week and to stop their guarding of the strip.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On the other side, Hamas leader Ismail Junaih said that Israel has received victory in the Gaza war from God.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Ismail Junaih also said that Israel was unsuccessful in achieving their goals in the Gaza war.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Before that on Sunday in Sharm-el-Shaikh located in Egypt, the leaders of Arab and European countries had a meeting in which there was a call for immediate evacuation of Israeli army from Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It was decided in the meeting that soon an international aid conference for Gaza would be held.</seg>
    <seg id="9">German Chancellor Angela Merchel was also present in the mentioned meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="10">At least 1,300 Palestinians including 10 soldiers and 13 Israelis were killed in the three week long war being fought between the Israeli and Hamas soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the other side the Palestinian President Mahmood Abbas stressed upon an international rule in the Palestinian regions.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Al-Qaida's video message to Germany</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this thirty minute video a man wearing a black turban covering his face and with a gun in his hand addressed the German government.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking in a German, the same man introduced himself as the "Father of Talha."</seg>
    <seg id="4">Arabic subtitles The video contains Arabic subtitles.</seg>
    <seg id="5">There is a log of Al-Qaeda on the side of the screen and video has the date of October 2008.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In this message, it is said to the German Government that is the country expressing their belief that they will not be attacked on after assigning army in a great number in Afghanistan. If this is not innocence, what is it?</seg>
    <seg id="7">The "Father of Talha" threatened an attack on Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Currently there are nearly 3500 German soldiers in Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Last year, in October, the German Parliament approved sending and additional 1000 soldiers to Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This is the first message Al-Qaeda has sent to Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Mikhael Luders, a monitor of terrorist related activities, says about the message, "The suicide bombing outside German consulate recently has proved that we should take it seriously in every condition."</seg>
    <seg id="12">Over the last few years, Al-Qaeda has distributed messages over the internet with attacks following.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The responsibility for the terrorist attack outside the German Embassy at the weekend was taken by the militant group, the Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Most German papers and analysts are linking this attack with the message of Al Qaeda.</seg>
    <seg id="15">"They are targeting Germany."</seg>
    <seg id="16">Muslim hard liners see the Germans Afghan policy as negative and questionable.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They blame the German government of adopting biased policies not just towards Afghanistan, but also the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="18">And for this reason that they are increasingly seeing Germany as an enemy.</seg>
    <seg id="19">The German Government stated that even before the video came out publically the German undercover agencies knew about it.</seg>
    <seg id="20">The German federal anti-crime organization was occupied in investigating the contents of the video.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama took office as the President of the United States of America.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this crisis, the American people and the rest of the world have different expectations of Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">As Barack Obama is receiving greetings from all over the world on becoming the president of America, the expectations from him are also rising.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this reference, the German Chancellor Angela Merckle has expressed confidence in the American president.</seg>
    <seg id="5">I am sure that based on the friendship between the Federal Republic of Germany and the United States of America, we can resolve all the issues faced.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Russian prime minister Viladimir Putin has said that Obama appears to a serious and open hearted man and that this is really good news.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The policies of former American president George W. Bush have been facing criticism.</seg>
    <seg id="8">However, his regime is appreciated for promoting China to play a more constructive role internationally. Whereas, China has said about the new American president will have to work for stronger military relations between both countries.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Active in the German city of Bochum, Chinese political expert Kusuay Wu says:</seg>
    <seg id="10">"In this reference, I am sure that in coming weeks and months, Obama and his team of economists will put immense pressure on China to have a more flexible and competitive to market exchange rate for the Chinese currency".</seg>
    <seg id="11">The former American regime has also improved its relations with India.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On the issue of how far Obama can take these relations, Christopher Raj, Professor of American Studies in New Delhi says, "now we have come closer in strategic partnership, however, Obama can not bring an overnight change".</seg>
    <seg id="13">Pope Benedict's message to President Obama stressed the need to create an environment of peace and mutual help in the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">State Elections In Israel</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This is the first important election in this war-torn country since 2005.</seg>
    <seg id="3">More than 14,400 people entered the race for 440 seats in the state elections.</seg>
    <seg id="4">To maintain peace and safety during the elections, 800,000 police and soldiers were posted in Iraq.</seg>
    <seg id="5">All Iraqi borders were sealed one day in advance fearing that a random bomb blast or terrorist attack might occur on this important day, especially Friday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Also, airports were closed and restrictions were placed on public transportation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to reports, due to the restrictions on public transportation, there was no traffic on Baghdad roads and children were spotted playing football there.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the present Iraqi elections, security arrangements will reveal whether the local security agencies will be able to control the country after the return of American forces in 2011. Political analysts also are using this as a test to see how far the public is willing to go to bring about democratic change.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The state elections are being overseen by the United Nations and nearly 800 international supervisors.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Today Ashoora Day is celebrated all over Iran with high reverence and piety and with the remembrance of the leader of martyrs, Imam Hazrat Husaian.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Mahar news agency, in all small and big cities including Tehran, the capital of Iran, people mourned the sacrifice of Hazrat Imam Husain (peace be upon him), the leader of martyrs.  Huge crowds attended the mourning processions and meetings. Due respects and condolence were given to the Ahlu Baith (the Prophet's-- PBUH--inheritors). The whole of Iran observed with great sorrow and lamentation the supreme martyrdom in the Karbala battleground of the Prophet's grandson, Imam Hazrat Husain (PBUH). The true believers cherished the memory of the unique sacrifice of Hazrat Imam Husain in Karbala. Large crowds attended the condolence meetings and processions.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Israeli Troops' Retreat from Gaza Corridor and a Stern Defense Put up by Palestine Fighters.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to Mahar news reports of Urdu service, even on the 16th day of the battle between good and evil, the Israeli troops showered bombs on the city dwellers. 880 people have so far been martyred in the land-sky-sea attack of the Israeli troops, and 3700 Palestinians have been severely injured.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The martyrs include 275 innocent children. They embraced death smiling at the faces of deceitful Arab leaders and the organizations pretending to be working for international human rights.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The Israeli troops were forced to leave Ujain in Gaza today because of the strong resistance of the masked Palestine soldiers. They exhibited magnificent defense with the help of their strong faith and desire for sacrifice. They engaged in a do or die battle against the Zionist enemies.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But for the treacherous stand of the Egyptian President Husni Mubarak, the brave and solid fighters of Hamas would have thrown the Israeli troops into the pit of shameful defeat. Unfortunately, the Egyptian Muslims also kept the Palestinians under siege along with the Israeli troops. It is the most tragic incident in the history of Arabia.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It can be seen that Saudi Arabia and the Udar government extends political as well as financial assistance to Israel. Similarly, they join hands with Israel to deceive the Musalmans of Gaza who are put in unending miseries.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barak Obama and America weave new evil strategies against Iran.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Mahar news agency, the elected President of America, Barak Obama, while talking to the ABC news channel, said that new and modern strategies would be adopted in dealing with the Iran affairs.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Bark Obama said that Iran will be the big challenge for American Government.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Bark Obama said he is concerned about Iran helping Falastini Islamic organizations Hammas and Hizbullah as well as the Iranic item program.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He will not continue Presidnt Bush's foreign policy, and will instead start a peaceful relationship with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Bark Obama said that he will stress on talking and respecting showing his real aim.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Bark Obama had said that there will be no conditions to talk with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In an interview he said that the management will work on this new Iran policy rapidly.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Bark Obama said he will create a committee to solve the problem of middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="10">That will start work after January 20 for the peace of middle East.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The president Jarj Bush declared his mistakes and crimes in his last speech.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The expert News agency said about the Associate Press that American president Bush declared his mistakes and crimes in last press conference.</seg>
    <seg id="3">During his press conference at the White ,President Bush offered his best wishes to newly elected President Obama and said that the biggest challenge would be to protect America from every possible attack.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the completion of Iraq mission and improvements in social security were his mistakes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush said that he did everything for the protection of America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In response to several questions asked about Israeli aggression in Gaza, President Bush replied that Israel has the right to protect herself but Hamas does not and Hamas should not attack Israel and like America the whole world should strangle the oppressed instead of the oppressor.</seg>
    <seg id="7">America's most incompetent and ineligible president said that Hamas should not be provided arms however America is giving the most devastating weapons to Israel who are using these weapons in the genocide of Palestinians. Also criticized pro Israeli Arabs and declared them friends of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Bush was embarrassed about the crimes committed in Abu Garib and Guantanamo bay prisons.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Experts say that Bush should be put on trial for war crimes and the organizations who will do this will do great benefit to mankind.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Iranian President Ahmedi Nizad regretted the silence of Arab countries.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to all news agencies Iranian president Doctor Ahmedi Nizad has strongly criticized silence of Arab leaders on the Israeli aggression and oppression.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmedi Nizad is shocked on the silence of Arab countries and their leaders on the Israeli aggression on Gaza and said that Israel is doing Holocaust of Palestinians, terrorizing Palestinian children, women and ordinary citizens.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmede Nejad has called upon all the Arab countries to unite against Israel and to save the oppressed Muslims of Gaza from Israel's harm and tyranny.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ahmade Nejad: "Saudi King should clarify his stance on the  genocide being done in Gaza by Israel."</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the report by MAHAR/MEHR news agency, President Ahmede Nejad in his message to the Saudi King Malik Abdullah declared that the King's silence on the human genocide in Gaza and on the murder of innocent women and children is encouraging the enemies of Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmede Nejad has said in his message: "You should show your true stance on Gaza and declare support for the oppressed so that the enemy's attempts to plant disagreements in the Islamic block will fail."</seg>
    <seg id="4">In his message, President Ahmede Nejad said "You know that for the last 19 days Israel has been bent upon human genocide, murdering innocent children, and subjecting homes, mosques, schools and hospitals to barbaric bombing. The Zonist Regime is brutally murdering the unarmed Muslims in Gaza. In situations like these, silence on the part of leaders like you is only encouraging Israel."</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Ahmede Nejad has told Malik Abdullah that even non- Muslim countries like Venezuela and Bolivia have taken concrete steps against Israel and that he is expected to take better steps.</seg>
    <seg id="6">President Ahmede Nejad told the Palestinians that success will be at their feet in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The oppressed will win over the oppressors and that's Allah's promise.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090116.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush: "Terrorism is still a threat to USA."</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The US President, while addressing his successor Barak Obama and the nation in his farewell speech, said that the US is safer than it was seven years ago but the threat of terrorism still looms over USA. (MEHER/MAHAR news agency, with reference from the German news agency)</seg>
    <seg id="3">Bush said that because enemy terrorists are waiting patiently to attack America and have a strong determination to do so, America should never be unaware about its security.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The American president ignored the pain and suffering of the hundreds of thousands of Palestinians in Gaza and defended his policies, saying that America is still the biggest supporter of Gaza's independence. However, commentators do not accept the reality of the unpopular president's remarks, as America is neither a supporter of freedom, nor a supporter of human rights, but rather is the most mischievous country in the world. Not only does it support a blood thirsty country like Israel, but it is also directly involved in its crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Israelis openly kill woman, children and other civilians. Despite this, the American president is congratulating them. This is the American humanity and freedom which the world is seeing in Gaza and other places.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Usama Hamdan: Presence of army in Palestine continues</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by Mehr News Agency, Usamah Hamdan,  the Hamas leader in Lebanon, told French News Agency during an interview that a one-sided ceasefire from the Israeli side is against the comprehensive international efforts for a ceasefire. He said that as long as Israel is present in Gaza, a one-sided ceasefire is meaningless.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamadan said that the one sided ceasefire was an unsuccessful effort of Israel to escape defeat. He said that if Israel wants long term peace, it will have to accept Hamas's conditions as well as end this siege.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He made it clear that if Israel tries a one-sided ceasefire with its army remaining in the Gaza belt, there will be resistance.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Addressing a one-way conference from Beirut, Usamah Hamdan called for European nations to break ties with Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Hamas leader said that the increasing numbers of the martyred and injured will only increase our determination.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He also told the Palestinian public to stay firmly rooted and resist the enemy like a boulder.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Taliban Killed 6 in Pakistan's Tribal Area North of Wazirastan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Meher Reporting Agency copied references from Rueters that the Taliban killed 2 Afghans and 4 Pakistanis over accusation of espionage in Pakistan's tribal area of north Wazirastan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to reports, on Tuesday morning locals found four dead bodies from Tehsil Chowk in Tehsil Mir Ali, who were shot dead.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, two of the dead bodies that were found in capital Miranshah were thrown in the market of a Bazaar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Letters written in Urdu have also been found near the dead bodies in which it is claimed that the dead were involved in espionage.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Also, two weeks earlier, in Miranshah, the capital of north Wazirastan, two Afghanis were killed over accusations of espionage.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Over last twelve days, fifteen people have been killed over charges of espionage for America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be noted that during last six years, more than a hundred people have been killed in South and North Wazirastan on accusations of espionage. Taliban members are accused of being involved in these murder cases.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama Expected to Undersign Closure Orders of the Infamous Guantanamo Bay Prison.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr Reporting Aagency has copied through sources that state that today the American president will sign the orders of the closure of the infamous Guantanamo bay prison.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The new American president, Barack Husain Obama, started working on his campaign promises at the surface level.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this regard, President Obama called for making a plan for recalling the army from Iraq, while the American president will sign an order today to close the notorious Guantanamo Bay prison.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that President Barack Obama will probably sign the order today by which the Guantanamo prison will be closed within one year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Apart from this, the White House is expected to revise suspected terrorism investigation methods and ban ill treatment of prisoners during interrogation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President Barack Obama started to fulfill his election campaign promises from his first day in office, and first of all started by taking steps toward making the actions and workings of the government transparent.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Experts say that the American president has started making efforts to save the declining image of America throughout the world, but that would be difficult, because as long as it will keep supporting the blood thirsty Israeli government, it can not be expected to do anything good. Therefore if America wants to save its image, it will have to stop its support of Israel and have to disassociate itself from Israel's crimes.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tony Blair stresses the need to include Islamic organization Hamas in the talks.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr news agency quoted from British newspaper The Times that former Prime Minister Tony Blair stressed the need to include Hamas in the talks to bring about peace in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the newspaper, Tony Blair said that it is important that a path be found for bringing Hamas into the Middle East peace process. Blair criticized the Bush administration for speaking only to Mahmood Abbas and ignoring Hamas. It should be clear that the western countries have realized the democratic and organizational powers of Hamas and are calling for bringing them into the talks, whereas previously they used to consider it a terrorist organization. A terrorist organization which is trying to defend its country and struggling to save its own house from the clutches of others. Whose house and country have been in the hand of the occupying Israeli government for 60 years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Murder of Balochistan merchants in Karachi, Complete strike in Quetta</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Due to the death of four merchants from Balochistan in Karachi a complete strike was in effect on Thursday against it in Quetta and some other places.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this period all business centers remained closed, as well as traffic was also less than normal.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The protesting strike was called by the 'Anjuman Tajiran Balochistan' (Balochistan Trade Union), Pushtunkhwah Milli Awami Party and the Jamiat-e-Ulama-e-Islam. They accused the Karachi police for open fire at these merchants, when they were going to their vehicle showroom on Tariq road.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The president of the Anjuman Tajiran, Abdur Raheem Kakad demanded that police agents at fault should be arrested and action should be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, the stand of the Karachi police about this incident was not immediately clear.</seg>
    <seg id="7">All four of the dead merchants were from the border city of Chaman.</seg>
    <seg id="8">A large amount of security was provided by the government during the strike and police officers were posted throughout the city at important locations.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A senior commander of Hamas was killed in Israeli attack.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In an air attack by Israel, a senior Hamas commander was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Second death of an important Hamas figure, in the week long Israeli attacks on the Gaza belt.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Hamas officeholders said that Abu Zakariyya AlJamaal was killed in Shujaaiyah palace in the east of Gaza city, on Saturday.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In another air attack by Israel, on Thursday, Aalam Nazar Ra'iyan was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Hamas's evacuated leader, who stays in Syria, Khalid Mushil has promised to take revenge and warned Israel of launching a land attack on Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Thousands of Israeli tanks and soldiers are posted at the Gaza border, and they are waiting for orders to attack.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America has called for a ceasefire, but said that it is up to Israel, whether to attack Gaza or not.</seg>
    <seg id="9">American President, George Bush said on his weekly speech on radio, that Hamas was escalating the situation, and he said that their attacks on Israel amounted to terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that America would work for a ceasefire, but any one sided settlement would not be acceptable.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bodies found in North Waziristan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani Security officials said that the bodies of three people were found in the tribal regions of North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is suspected that Taliban gave them the death penalty and killed them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Two dead bodies were discovered in Miran shah with letters. They were accused of spying for the US.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officials said that one dead body might be a local person who was kidnapped last week.</seg>
    <seg id="6">They disclosed that the other two dead bodies were Afghan citizens.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tenth day of Israel attack on Ghaza.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Philistine child that was wounded by Israel missile attack.  Israeli army is fighting against the armed men of Hamas in Ghaza. Israeli air force is striking against the shelters of Philistine fighters.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Israeli defense minister said that the operation will remain until South Israel is made safe from the rocket attacks of Hamas.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, Hamas is firing rocket despite the Israeli attacks. Four casualties have been reported, three of them are civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mehmood Zafar, a Hamas leader asked his soldiers to "crush" Israeli soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to a hamas official, Hamas is planning to send a envoy to Egypt to discuss the latest situation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">A wounded woman in ghaza. According to medical staff during last 10 days nearly 530 people have lost their lives.  Eleven civilians, including five young children were killed on Monday.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Israel has reported the death of one soldier and the injury of 30 others in land attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Israel has stopped other national journalists from entering Gaza, and investigating military action.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Elected American Vice President, Joseph Biden reaches Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The foreign minister received the elected American Vice President.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The elected American Vice President, Joseph Biden reached Islamabad on Friday, along with his group, for his tour of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The foreign minister, Shah Mahmood Qureishi and the high ambassadors of the American Embassy received him.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ameican senator Lindsy Graham is also with Biden on this trip.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Press Officer of the American Embassy, Lou Fintor told the Voice of America that the newly elected President, would talk to the Pakistani government about various regional issues during his tour. However, he avoided giving more detail.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to sources in the Office of the External Ministry, Joseph Biden would meet with various officeholders in the government, as well as with Army Chief Ashfaq Pervez Kiyani.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is expected that apart from important bilateral and global issues, matters related to the war against terrorism will also be discussed in these meetings.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Joseph Biden was awarded the Pakistan Crescent.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After reaching Islamabad, Joseph Biden met President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="11">During their meeting, in recognition of his efforts to increase ties between Pakistan and America, the President awarded him with the Pakistan Crescent.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It should be clear that Joseph Biden as the chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee of the American Senate had introduced a bill--- along with Senator Richard Logger--in which it was proposed that during the next five years there would be a tripling in the amount of military aid given to Pakistan, making it 15.7 billion dollars.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Joe Biden played an important role in removing Musharraf, according to Prime Minister Geelani.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Yusuf Riza Geelani and Joe Biden (File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Prime Minister, Yusuf Riza Geelani, said that the newly elected American Vice President played an important role in removing former President Pervez Musharraf from the position of Army Chief, and that Joe Biden helped Democracy in Pakistan considerably.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Yusuf Raza Geelani gave this statement, speaking to journalists in the Karachi shipyard.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He said that Joseph Biden was a Pro-Pakistan leader and as chairman of the committee for foreign relations of the American Senate, he passed a bill for aiding Pakistan with 15 Billion dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="6">About the missile attacks by American spy planes within Pakistani boundaries, the Pakistani Prime Minister once more denied them by saying that there is no agreement with the American government about allowing such attacks as, according to him, it was a matter of Pakistani sovereignty.  Hence, by no means could they give permission for such attacks within their territory.</seg>
    <seg id="7">They have also shown hope that after the change in leadership of the American government there will be changes in American policy.</seg>
    <seg id="8">(File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="9">Yousef Raza Geelani said that the government had removed terrorism from the general tribes successfully.  But the missile attacks from spy air craft had been a disaster to the governments efforts,  and the terrorists are once again included within the tribal areas.</seg>
    <seg id="10">They said that the United Nations accepts the situation with Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The Vice President said that if anyone from the tribes provides information then the Pakistan Forces themselves will investigate in their areas.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In responce to the attacks in Mumbai, the Vice President Yousef Raza Geelani repeated his opinion that if India provides information and witness then they will investigate, and anyone involved will be prosecuted according to the national law.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In answer to a question, the Vice President said that Rahman Malik went to London with his permission.  Rahman Malik toured Britain and met with his MQM leader Altaaf Hussain.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Qwetta was among the four DSP police members killed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">File photo</seg>
    <seg id="3">Four police members were killed on Qwettta's most imporant rorad, the Shah Rah Saryab Road when unknown persons fired upon them and the Deputy Superintendent of Police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Wednesday morning in a Jeep two DSP, one sub inspector and two constables were on their way to the police training center. On Sariab Road near a college, an unknown rider on a motorcycle attacked the police Jeep and fired continuously. Sub Inspector Mehdi and Constable Sibgat ul llah and Nasr ul Ilah died on the scene but one DSP, Hasan Ali, died after reaching the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The hospital said that the second DSP, Ghulam Mohammed, is in very serious condition as he is severely injured and he was shot in his head and neck.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After this incident, police besieged the area. Until now no one has accepted responsibility for the attack.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">In America one more Indian Software Engineer has been murdered</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In America an unknown person has killed a software engineer from Andhra Pradesh.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Two days before, an unknown person shot Akshya Vishal, who is 26 years old and from Andhra Pradesh. He died while being treated at the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was an employee of Satyam Computers and in America he was working with Falcon Jet Airways.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Last year seven students from Andhra Pradesh were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The students who were in America have been murdered, causing family and friends of those residing in America to be concerned.</seg>
    <seg id="7">They prefer America to Andhra Pradesh for higher education and a better future.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the statistics of the American Consulate in Chennai, 100,000 American visa applications are received from India. Of these the majority, i.e. 40%, are from Andra Pardes.</seg>
    <seg id="9">During this time, the provincial government began trying to bring the dead body of the deceased to Hyderabad.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Bush states America should stay alert for enemy attacks.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In his last weekly speech on the radio President Bush has insisted America be on the alert for enemy attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Bush has that even today America's biggest threat is another attack from the terrorists. He has warned that enemies of the country are waiting patiently and are ready to attack again.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The retiring president has said that America should always be on the alert regarding its safety.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush has also expressed best wishes for the next President, Barrack Obama, who will take his oath of office on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">During his radio speech last Saturday, newly elected President Barrack Obama shed light on the historical importance of his presidential oath taking ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that this ceremony is a tradition in which the peaceful transfer of power from one leader to another is further evidence of the greatness of America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mr. Obama reminded his audience that there are many people in the world who can not even imagine their leaders retiring from their positions without violence and the shedding of blood.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Meeting between sharifs and interior minister. Political and security affairs discussed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In Raiwind, a meeting was held between the interior minister Rehman Malik and Nawaz Sharif, head of PMLN (the largest opposition party in the center and the ruling party in Punjab). The CM, Shehbaz Sharif, was also present in the meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to local media, Rehman Malik has brought a message from the top of the PPP leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, Rehman Malik did not give any details to the press. He told the media that national affairs were discussed during the meeting and that he briefed the PMLN leadership about the situation after the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words, "He briefed about all the steps taken."</seg>
    <seg id="6">One should not forget that the most lethal terrorism occurred in Punjab, where PMLN is the ruling party, and my established team needs the cooperation of the government there.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to Rehman Malik, the media is not briefed but messages are exchanged with the leadership on daily basis. Pervaiz Rashid Mir, the representative of PMLN, was very cautious to disclose anything. He said, "Rehman Malik has told what is required to be told."</seg>
    <seg id="8">This meeting was held when the political temperature is on the rise in Punjab. The major cause of this rise is the joint conference of Governor of Punjab, Salman Taseer, and more than 20 Nazims of PMLQ. The policies of the Punjab government came under criticism during this press conference. PMLN has rejected the allegations and has criticized the governor's participation in the press conference.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama's speech is good news for Pakistan, Zardari</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The president of Pakistan welcomed Obama's speech and said that the American intent to have a respectful and balanced relationship with the Muslim world is good news for Pakistan and its people.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In a statement given on Wednesday, he said that the high ideals and values which the American President has promised to uphold gives people all over the world hope of a new life.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to his statement, President Zardari said that the responsibility of joining the global brotherhood and searching for roads to peace, development, and prosperity in the 21st century falls, no doubt, on the shoulders of America.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On Tuesday, after taking his oath, President Obama stated clearly in his opening speech that America wants a new approach towards the Muslim world, one that is based on mutual interests and mutual respect.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He ascertained that America will work alongside the people in under-developed nations to help them grow and advance and to reduce poverty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Obama Appoints Special Afghan/Pakistan Representative</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Former United Nations Ambassador Richard Holbrooke was appointed Special Representative to Afghanistan and Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Holbrooke played an important role in bringing peace to Bosnia and Herzegovina.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Holbrooke said that he was ready to counsel President Obama on matters relating to Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He also added that this would not be easy.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the histories of both countries were extremely different.</seg>
    <seg id="7">George Mitchell was chosen for the Middle East, who will try to breathe life into Arab-Israeli peace talks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mitchell is an ex-senator and he has played a role in establishing peace in Ireland.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Speaking at the State Department today, Mitchell said that the Middle East situation is unstable, confusing and dangerous.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Nevertheless, America will not step back on efforts to establish peace over there.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghanistan: Voter registration in danger.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Afghanistan Election Commission has said that due to safety concerns, it is delaying the voter registration in some of the southern regions.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The voter registration for the upcoming presidential elections had started this week in South Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">But the commission has declared that as long as the security conditions do not improve, the voters in some parts of Halmand state will not be able to register themselves.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Extremism has been on the rise in those regions of the south, where Taliban rebels have increased attacks on Afghani and international governments.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Meanwhile, the Afghani army and international armies are claiming that during the night between Wednesday and Thursday, during small skirmishes, they killed at least 28 soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="7">NATO claims their army has destroyed 22 fighters during air and land attacks on Eastern province Khost near the Pakistan border.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Before the attacks, the Afghan Ministry of Defense stated that in the same province, the Afghan army killed 8 rebels and injured two.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is not clear whether Afghan officials and Nato were discussing the same incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090123.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Two missile attacks in Waziristan left at least 18 people dead.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Pakistan Authority has said that at least 18 were found  dead in the two ambiguous American missile attacks in North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to officials, an American jet fired three missiles near a house in the area Mir Ali of North Waziristan, killing ten.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to local officials, there were five foreign fighters among the dead.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This area is considered to be the central hideout of the Taliban and Alqaida's fighters.</seg>
    <seg id="6">A few hours later, southern Waziristan was also attacked with a missile, which left at least eight dead.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Apart from the disagreement of the Pakistani government over the course of six months, there have been almost 30 additional missile attacks in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">These attacks did not come until after U.S. president Barack Obama came into control.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Bush management has abstained from accepting or rejecting these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Friday, found in the tribal areas of Pakistan Wazeerastan, three Mezayles were placed into custody as suspects by Americans.  Five men have been reported dead.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The dead persons have not been named yet.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to reports, these Mezile attacks occured at a house in the Meer Ali area.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It should be considered that this was the first attack after Barack Obama became president.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The province Sarhad's government refused to comment on the question regarding the ban on girls' education.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Province Sarhad rejected the threat by Taliban soldiers in Swat, stating that this announcement is against the law and against Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The prime minister of education in province Sarhad, Sardar Hussain Babur, stated that the government will not allow these efforts.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He states that the extremists want that the children in our areas left free from education.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words: ""These people try to secretly blow up schools and frighten the boys and girls""</seg>
    <seg id="6">Talking about the environment of fear and insecurity, he said that the local government knows well and wants it to be known that no force can stop the spread of education in the land of the Pukhtons.</seg>
    <seg id="7">One day ago, the Taliban soldiers, led by Moulana Fazlullah, had demanded that girls be banned from studying in the Swat's educational institutions beginning on the 15th of January.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Despite the military activity going on in Swat during the last one and a half years, about 150 educational institutions were destroyed by the militants by the use of explosives and arson.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Due to the destruction of these educational institutions, thousands of girls and boys were deprived of an education.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Strict security arrangements in India on Republic Day.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The 60th Republic Day is being celebrated in India on Monday. On this occasion, strict security measures are being taken and thousands of soldiers were posted throughout the country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On the occasion of Republic Day, during the army parade in New Delhi, weapons, planes and other military equipment is displayed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Officials are saying that the security arrangements include anti aircraft missiles and sharpshooters and that police will be deployed to watch the roads of the parade. American President Barack Obama congratulated India on the occasion.</seg>
    <seg id="5">And he also wished Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, who had undergone a heart operation on Saturday, a speedy recovery.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Yesterday Indian police allegedly killed two suspected Pakistani fighters near New Delhi after an encounter.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to local government, police recovered AK-47 rifles, grenades, and documents from both persons indicating that they were likely from Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Police are also investigating whether these two individuals belonged to the banned organization 'Lashkar-e-Taiba' which was involved in last November's Mumbai attacks.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tea: A potential cure for breast cancer?</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to new research, drinking three cups of tea every day</seg>
    <seg id="3">reduced the chances of breast cancer by more than one third  in women less than 50 years old.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In research conducted by the Moffitt Cancer Center in Florida in the United States, it has been found that women less than 50 years old that have the breast cancer oncogene</seg>
    <seg id="5">reduced their chances of breast cancer by 37 percent among those who drank three cups of tea a day.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The research indicated that older women did not get any benefit from drinking three or more cups of tea a day.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The researchers think that the tea contains polyphenols that are effective against the type of oncogene in the breast cancer that affects women younger than 50.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In Moffitt Cancer Center, in the city of Tampa, Florida state, a research was conducted on over 5000 women, who had undergone treatment for breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Their ages were between 20 and 74 years.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Experts compared their medical records and lifestyles with women who were safe from breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The experts also found out that on a specific type of cancer called lobular cancer, the drinking of tea has shown clear effects, and has decreased its occurrence by 66 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="12">A tenth of every breast cancer patient suffers this type of cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="13">This type of cancer is more dangerous because it is deeper and is usually only known after it spreads quite a bit.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Experts say that regular tea consumption, at least three cups a day, can drastically reduce the occurrence of breast cancer in young women.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They say that making tea a regular beverage taken on a daily basis and included in ones daily activities causes the suitable defense required against cancer in the body.</seg>
    <seg id="16">In Britain, every year, approximately 40,000 women are diagnosed with breast cancer.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The biggest military challenge facing the American war in Afghanistan is gas.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">American Defence Minister Robert Gates says that the biggest Military challenge for America is the war in Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Today, Gates is giving a briefing to the American Senate and the representatives of Congress on the Obama Administration policies on Afghanistan and Iraq wars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Gates told the Armed Services Senate Committee that war is not the only solution to Afghan problems. He also said that in order to make many areas secure, Army Personnel will not be available. The Taliban are taking advantage of this.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Why Do We Exercise Less As We Get Older?</seg>
     <seg id="2">New Research</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="3">Exercise is Good For Your Health, No Matter How Old You Are!</seg>
    <seg id="4">This keeps the heart healthy, reducing the level of cholesterol, and keeping weight low. It also helps in the reduction of sugar and reducing Alzheimers so the speed of dementia will decrease.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Unfortunately, in many older people, the capability to carry out exercise is low.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The specialists say that, with exercise, our body and brain remain active. Age can have an effect.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The American Medical Association says that Many health problems can occur if exercise is not carried out.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Dr. Patrisha Pae Leka of the Meo Clinic in Mani Sotta says that the reason for the addition in the age is from inability of exercise and less functionality in the body.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Dr. Patrisha is a medical professor in the Meo Clinic.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It was Dr. Patrisha who performed the research on heart-related illnesses in the elderly and the the benefits of exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="11">A team of doctors used a sonogram to test the functions of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Using the sonogram, they studied the integrity of the blood pump in the heart as well as the heart's palpitations.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The experts had given full attention to the left side of the heart, which is the more important half that pumps the blood through the body.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They came to know that as people get older, the heart is forced to work more to aid respiration.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Dr. Patrisha says that as people age, the heart's job in assisting respiration becomes harder, and the effect becomes more obvious with the inclusion of exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Dr. Garven Ken also participated in this research.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They say that we were surprised to see that this thing is effected necessarily and with this it has been clear that bad exercise functionality has an affect on the heart's respiration work.</seg>
    <seg id="18">High blood pressure can cause cardiovascular diseases and certain dysfunctions.</seg>
    <seg id="19">If doctor and patient cooperate with each other then exercise can be beneficial even in old age.</seg>
    <seg id="20">A detailed report has been published in the Journal of the  American Medical Association.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Indian Army Chief Declares Peace with Pakistan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Indian Army chief, Gen. Depak Kapoor said,"There is a fat chance of war with Pakistan. However, we are ready to protect our national interests at any cost".</seg>
    <seg id="3">General Kapoor feels that despite international pressure, terrorist networks still exist and are active on Pakistani soil.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was talking with journalists in Sri Nagar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Indian Army Chief is on a one day visit to Kashmir Valley to observe the  activities of Armed forces at the boundaries.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He was asked to comment about Pakistan's rejection of Indian evidence about Mumbai Attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Gen. Kapoor said that political leadership is responsible for dealing with issues relevant to peace or war.</seg>
    <seg id="8">There are many types of common riots and protests in Pakistan.  He also reported there would be a tremendous battle between India and Pakistan.  Pakistan has aimed to weaken the Indian Army.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He has also reported there are 700-800 army troups in Kashmir, of which apporximately half are not citizens.</seg>
    <seg id="10">General Deepak Kapoor has reported there is some improvement in the K.I.K.'s atmosphere. He has also said he has increased efforts in the battle on Pakistan Dependent Kashmir. Therefore, we have increased the number of Army camps on the Indian borders.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He has also reported that he has increased the number of army troups in Indian Dependent Kashmir. He has clearly notice from their actions that there cannot be any compromise with regard to the protection of the country.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Oh God, please accept our prayers.  Please prove Barack Obama to be good for this world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is evident from the present situation that there is a slim chance of getting a positive response.  Still, we will wait and see to what extent the Pakistan-American relationship changes and what benefit it can be to us.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What inspiration does Presdient Barack Obama give to this world compared to the inspiration and aims of Martin Luther King, Jr.?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Obama, whose name is partially Hussein, is going to take the Oath as an American Leader.  He is going to be a protector of the country and of it's history.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This will be a test not only of their community, but also for all those who have supported him with their heart and soul.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This extreme test will will occur on white paper.  It is not easy to write sincerely that he will rule the country with justice on blue paper.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here, South Asia, especially Muslims who have expectations from them, should remember that he has been elected as the president of America. And Obama should remember that the American president is actually the president of the entire world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After a moment, a man whose brothers and sisters from his generation were brought to America from their countries as slaves and whose sweat and blood have strengthened the roots of the most powerful country of the new era, today a representative of this racially discrete nation will be called the 40th president of this very America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have expectations from this one man.</seg>
     <seg id="3">People who love him, have to have unreal expectations from him.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If Obama succeeds to an extent in reducing the hatred among races and religion in the world, so this will be a victory for people who support him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What will be its effect on South Asia, and can a meaningful change be expected in the American policy regarding this matter?</seg>
     <seg id="2">How will this change affect the relationship between America and Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4">Dear, whether it is Obama or someone else, the decision of the policy of the entire world is done by the Jewish lobby of  billionaires, influencing powerful people.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And as far as Pakistan is concerned, after the series of recent Bombay blasts, the offensive reaction of India, America and Israel is obvious to everyone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the creation of Pakistan, the administration of Swat remained with the Ruler of Swat that had a regular Army and Law.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He handed over administration of Swat to Pakistan under a  pact.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is a matter of sorrow that our government treated Swat like a step-mother.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There was no increase in the number of schools after the end of the government by the ruler of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">No interest was taken in the building and development works.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The girls who are getting educations today are much fewer than those who used to get educated in the previous era.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Frontier Province there is a continuous targeting of educational institutions by the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Most of the schools that have been destroyed in district Swat are the girl's schools.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is not just that, but the Taliban has imposed a ban on girl's education.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thousands of male and female students have been deprived from getting education.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you think the goal of the Taliban is by wanting to end the education of women?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Why can the Government not stop these unlawful acts?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What efforts to you think the Government should make?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The question is what benefit is there for ISI and Pakstani agencies?</seg>
     <seg id="2">The people of Swat understand the "game" being played by the military in supporting the Taliban instead of killing them, evidenced by the fact that in Karfuo, 5 schools were blown up and people were killed and hung by the road.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When there is no authority of government left, then how can the government stop unlawful acts?</seg>
     <seg id="2">The question now arises, with all their advances in technology, destructive weapons and an effective network of spies, how is is the Taliban still have not garnered control?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The answer is that some unknown power has a hand in events.  That is why their weapon supply never stopped and they aren't ever arrested.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The conclusion is that the Taliban and their deeds are making it easier for World Powers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The war in Afghanistan has been ongoing for the past 15 years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">ISI was controlling Taliban while it's opponent, the North Coalition, was supported by Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Suddenly, the situation changed and the Taliban began to act.</seg>
     <seg id="4">ISI was also offered American fundsing, so past friends became enemies.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now,the war continues, but Iran, India and Russia are still helping Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Human will keep making mistakes until a feeling of what is right and wrong emerges.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For example, a thief will still steal until he believes stealing is a curse and there is punishment for it; until he fears from God, then that Human will steal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Likewise, unless Israel inderstand it is wrong for it to drain the blood of innocents, and that there will be  punishment for this, it will keep playing Holi with the innocent blood of Gaza.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Respects!</seg>
     <seg id="2">Question whether the war, armed movement, and terrorism are solutions to problems.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If not, then what are the specific actions that will provide solutions to these problems?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The truth is that war does not solve the problem, but instead makes it more difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Palistine, Afghanistan and Iraq should the adopt the methods used by Nelson Madela in South Africa to achieve success in their methods.</seg>
     <seg id="6">That mean there should be behaver and politics efforts in more then force.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The participation of the public in the Kashmir election suggests that they accepted this view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is the third week of Israel's attacks on Gaza, and the dead total about 1000.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The war could not be stopped with the efforts of ambassadors until this time.</seg>
     <seg id="3">An estimated 9000 Palistinians have left their homes for safer places since the attacks began in December.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Charitable organizations blame Israel for failing to care for the mental and emotional problems caused to Palistinian children.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is this the way it should be?</seg>
     <seg id="7">How is long term peace possible in Gaza?</seg>
     <seg id="8">For details, click here.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Kindly note that due to the increase in comments, only Urdu written suggestions will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="10">While pressing Alt+Shift, select Urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Give a chance to the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Basit, Peshawar.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wake up! If the Taliban will perform a real Jihad, then who will sacrifice innocent people?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Who burned down the girl's school?</seg>
     <seg id="5">If kidnap for ransom, or not getting ransom so who will hang people on the pole by called them American spy?</seg>
     <seg id="6">The Taliban has done more damage to Islam than any other nation or religio.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pashtoon roar</seg>
     <seg id="8">Kohat, Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If all of the Muslim world would attack Israel, or simply issue a threat to do so, then they would see how painful it would be for America, the Godfather of Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Then, a true cease-fire would be observed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But what should we do about the cowardice of the Muslim rulers?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Someone should ask Ahmadi Nejad to become the first to attack, as he is well-known for his bravery.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The struggle for peace and human rights is not the sole responsibility of Arabs or the Muslim world. It is the duty of the whole world to raise their voices against cruelty.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This sad incident is the worst crime committed by Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In India and Pakistan, the financial corruption becomes greater at the end of the fiscal year, while the Bush administration has permitted Israel to do what she wants.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">On one hand, America demands the cease-fire.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, the United Nations is passing resolution after resolution, but action-wise, has done nothing. There is only one meaning of this, and that is that the even the United Nations is openly in favor of destroying the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All Muslim countries should immediately end their membership in the United Nations, and should establish their own global organization.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We have many examples of where only promises and resolutions of America and the United Nations are seen, but the harm is only done to the Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What is the use of these vain efforts if BBC does not want to publish anything?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Where have all the rules of journalism been buried? When blood, specifically of Muslims, is spilled, the monster of unbiasedness gets onto BBC's back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It considers itself the standard bearer of truth.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Forget about breaking something on its own, the height of heartlessness is that it does not even publish comments from Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Forget about breaking something on its own, the height of heartlessness is that it does not even publish comments from Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The only difference between you and the Jews is that they call themselves Jews and martyr the Muslims, and the likes of you stay among Muslims, and call yourselves Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">[syja786]</seg>
     <seg id="3">For a long time on BBC forums, suicide bombing and other types of terrorism in India was used to target a certain sect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The favorite word of these Anti-Islamic discussions was Extremism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You can get a very good idea regarding who might be an extremist from the above discussion because writing against Iran was almost considered blasphemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When will our muslims understand that the Anti-Christ can not be fought with swords.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Looking at unarmed people in the bombing of Israel, what shall one do other than crying?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The basic fault of this turmoil and massacre is that by naming Jihad results in to blackening the beautiful face of Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When majority of Palestinians accepted the existence of Israel, why did Hammas need to fire those rockets on Israel and make suicide attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">The attitude of both sides is against humanity.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Once again, the role of the UN and the USA was seen as favoritism towards the injustice of Israel.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah give the muslim nation the understanding of becoming  united. Amen!</seg>
     <seg id="2">As a matter of fact, think about giving the Noble Prize to the terrorists for carrying out these painful terrorist activities. In the campaign against terrorism, eventually the actual work is being done by them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise, is it possible to carry out terrorist activity on such a massive scale without the assistance of chiefs and without every one knowing who is pulling their strings.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Such a situation can be termed as high handedness, "Do what ever you can".</seg>
     <seg id="5">The strong men first, it beats over the head but do not let one cry.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Arab rulers are giving medicines for the injured, funeral clothings for the dead and money and they are asking</seg>
     <seg id="2">Should the Israelis continue the attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The actual problem is that the rulers of Islamic countries including Saudi Arabia are dreaming undutifully while asleep. Neither do they have an army nor do they have any defence plans, they just think that by providing aid they have done their duty.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They should immediately take practical steps against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Like cutting off the oil supply to European countries and America instead of feeling sorry for them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Regards to all brothers and sisters.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think asking Hamas to give up their struggle for the sake of peace is unfair to millions of widows and orphans. It is the same as failing to them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If the Pharaoh-ism of US and Israel is on the rise then Moses will come to counter them because every Pharaoh has a Moses.  The American and Israelis actions are producing suicide bombers among Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The ability to think and understand has abandoned them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Abu Abdullah, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now Hamas and Israel should cease fire to stop bloodshed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Mohammad Sarfraz, Paris, France</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rightly said.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Suppose Hamas is on the right path and struggling against cruelty for the sake of God's will: they should know that an act of goodness does not remain good if it harms others.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Love for humanity is the precondition for earning God's and his prophet's love.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It seems God has asked to annihilate all those who are other than Muslim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeeb-ur-Rahman Psycho *Lahore* [Pakian]</seg>
     <seg id="3">No! It is not decreed to annihilate, but it is decreed to invite people to Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">People who have conspiracies against the religion are decreed to do Jihad against them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">One should fight with them until they finish their conspiracies, but this certainly does not mean that they can wear a jacket and blow up in a crowd.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Brothers, the consequence of a murder of children is disaster.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It's a request to my friends that yesterday Israelis did not have a roof over their heads and today they are so strong that they do not listen to anyone because all Jews are one.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They do not have Shiite nor Sunni, all are just Jews, and they have succeeded in every field and made everything.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Opposite to this, what is the condition of 55 Islamic Countries?</seg>
     <seg id="5">By lagging in every field now the condition is that they are so helpless that enemies are killing them and they are waiting for their death.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The point is that all Muslim countries should get together and should make a plan against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Feroz Magsi, Jhang, Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">And there is no better action plan than this, to accept Israel and to learn modern science and developmental ways from it, and allow the world to live in peace and serenity.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Muslims have a lot of land and resources.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The need is for proper utilisation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First, the part that hurts the most is there could not be unity between Hamas and Al-Fath.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Great leaders like Yasir Arafat and Sheikh Yasin were systematically killed to weaken the nation. The only region which is still fighting for Masjid Aqsa, and this was not possible as long as Yasin and Arafat were in the way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The world is watching how Palestine is getting scattered, second by second, after the death of these two leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Jewish lobby is increasing its reach, second by second.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In 1974, Pakistan had a Prime Minister of such global credentials that for the first time in the history of the country, he gathered all the Muslims leaders, with a 100% attendance, under a single roof.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today on his 81st birth anniversary, is it a very difficult task for the people to pledge to keep unity, not only within their ranks,</seg>
     <seg id="3">While eradicating the differences between other Muslims, the formation of an Islamic common wealth will be carried forward.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is a monster that has gripped Palestine for half a century.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This monster has many faces.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Many times, this monster criticizes itself from its own different mouth to divert the pressure and attention of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Its other mouths are eating humans in Iraq, Afghanistan, Iran and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This monster is most unhappy with Islam, because it knows that whenever it will be kicked out it will be through Islam. Muslims and the perfect religion of practical Islam, have put giants like Abu Jehl on the right path.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Bombing from Israeli fighter planes on Gaza has continued  since the 27th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="2">More than three hundred Palestinians have been killed in these attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="3">After the Arial attacks, Israeli tanks and armed vehicles have reached the Gaza border with complete preparation for a ground attack.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Through a unanimous resolution in an emergency meeting of the security council, the United Nations has demanded Israel and the Palestinian authorities to ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="5">However, Israeli officials claim that they will continue their action in Gaza until they are convinced that Israel will be safe from rocket attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In your opinion, is the statement by Israel, that this is an Israeli struggle for safety, acceptable?</seg>
     <seg id="7">In this situation, is the global brotherhood doing its job?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Can this inhumane action have a direct relation with the upcoming elections in Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Can there be any expectation of improvement in the Middle East situation, after the newly elected president Barack Obama takes office?</seg>
     <seg id="10">(Please note that due to an increase in the number of comments, only comments typed in Urdu will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="11">For this, hit Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard and select Urdu.)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Palestine is a holy land for the Muslims, all over the world, and protecting it is a necessary duty for us.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We should also remember that it was our first Qiblah.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And Israel, America and India have to disappear one day, as they are made only to be destroyed, and Allah will definitely destroy the disbelievers. Sajid Sadiq, Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="4">""when the night of loneliness can be passed by tearing down</seg>
     <seg id="5">when an affliction can be avoided with only prayers"" (Nawabzadah Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC publishes these kind of comments after deep search.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A neutral impression is to be maintained.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Although the news from BBC is usually correct, the real thing is the style of the news.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is sometimes difficult to decide what should be highlighted and what news should be given less importance.</seg>
     <seg id="5">etc. etc.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="7">In the Pakistani electronic and print media, some Urdu newspapers and columnists are no more behind anyone, and cheat in the coverage of the increasing extremism and terrorism or in the "grudge of Muavia" written on them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">has said that the United Nations which apparently talks of Human rights and peace, but when it comes to grimness and coercion over Muslims the only words coming out of its mouth are that Hamas should stop the attacks. how long this hypocrisy will continue.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why is so much oppression being done on the Muslims? If people such as Americans do not stop supporting the Jews, then Allah has declared that they will live the life of a disgraced people, and such people can never lead a proper life. So if the Americans have courage, let them stop their support, and then see what kind of life they will have.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The just people of the world and those that kill people in the name of peace should understand that peace will only be prevalent through administering justice, and not by being unjust and killing people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If any tribe could be erased by killing their people, and if the required results could be obtained from the killings, then after Hitler's steps, not only the presence but the rise that the Jews are enjoying today, could not have been possible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These are the words of a poet.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Oppression is oppression, the more it's done the more it is erased.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Blood is blood, the more it falls, the more it gathers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now who can tell who did terroristic acts?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Is all of this not included in terrorism? Why then does everybody worry only about their own pain?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are others not human? Or is it that the blood of Muslims has become so cheap? Was the blood of this many innocents not red?</seg>
     <seg id="4">And why is there no one to send a message of mourning from anywhere?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I saw Bombay blasts operation like this fire was in my own house. Can not see the sorrow of mankind. And can anyone not see this sorrow? Alas if Muslims would think as one.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I see dead bodies on the road, helpless injured and innocent faces soaked in blood. How shall we condemn? I can not find words!</seg>
     <seg id="2">I feel like crying over the helplessness of the Muslims. On one side people are being killed in India so the rest of the world comes over to Pakistan without any proof and asks to perform operations that we will do it ourselves!</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the other side, Israel is killing generations of Muslims in front of everyone and the world is silent. This is unbearable!</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is delay but not ever in the house of God. Only then will this darkness shed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the presence of America, danger to the integrity of Israel is a joke.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Considering elections, the rulers should these activities for people's support. There is no doubt in this, especially when countries like Israel exist. Rest talking about Barrack Obama, then history is the witness that no American leader has gone against the policy. Regime, whether black or white, is a regime.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The debate going on in the forum makes it clear that every one is sad on Benazir's death. As a politician, one can not ignore her mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This talk requires debate on whether Benazir gave her life for democracy or for power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If democracy was so dear, then  why was it left in 10 year dictatorship of Musharaf until American clearance and the deal?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir did not come to Pakistan when people affected by dictatorship needed her. Unfortunately she came to Pakistan when she was assured by the government that she will be freed from trails.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no one remaining to say about the criticism and accusations of a historical personality.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="3">Somethings should be ignored because nothing can be done about them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">One more reader</seg>
     <seg id="5">Ladies and gentlemen probably you will understand My ideas because you have not only read history of Pakistan  but you have also read about Sir in four friendly countries and seven others.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tariq Ayaz</seg>
     <seg id="7">Neither had the nature that can be improved with education</seg>
     <seg id="8">Remained green in water</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">England did not let them come closer which created Hindu-Muslim conflict that was pampered by Sir Syed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Psycho</seg>
     <seg id="3">How bloody is our Nation and in our parties excitement while writing the Epode they will be blind but now every historic people is trying to pinpoint an accusation and criticize the judious, but on this there is no one is tell any thing</seg>
     <seg id="4">We have achieved lot of success.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="6">Few things can be avoided by thinking that nothing can be done. For this in the same  as if we put books on a donkey. He will not become a professor.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the attack on Mumbai, a problem got created between Pakistan and India in there regular activities but still India and Pakistan have to continue there regular activities</seg>
     <seg id="2">If we talk about War, then at the both end there will be a loss of human beings.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India is saying that the person who got arrested at the time of Mumbai attack is a Pakistan citizen and he has written a letter in Urdu and sent to Pakistan. But at the other end India has first said after arresting him that he is a big Engineer but after that they have proved that he is just 4th standard Pass, point to be observed</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First of all, to Mr bhana and all western friends of this forum, a happy Christmas.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Colleagues of the forum: Mr psycho, a raza, sister Sana, sister Shahedah Akram and to all Adaab (salaam, greeting)</seg>
     <seg id="3">We do not want the flames of war, we want the flowers of peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">War in itself is a problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What problems can war solve?</seg>
     <seg id="6">It will give fire and blood today.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It will give hunger and need tomorrow.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Therefore, O intelligent people,</seg>
     <seg id="9">If war keeps getting postponed, it's better.</seg>
     <seg id="10">In your and our porch,</seg>
     <seg id="11">If the candle keeps burning, it's better.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Indo-American relations have now gotten quite deep, and India knows with certainty, that America will openly betray Pakistan when the time comes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is also the old history of America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the case of the Indian attack, America would get its' goals and the expense would be on India as well.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan should make a clear statement that we shall not attack first but if we are invaded then there will be no peace, reconciliation or ceasefire until India is completely destroyed or occupied, even if we ourselves get destroyed in doing so.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is the Islamic history.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even before this resolution, the Pakistani public and army had given the message that they wanted to give.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Indian efforts for achieving diplomatic and military benefits as a ransom for the Mumbai attacks are making it more clever than effective and that is why in contrast to the initial strict reaction, the world community has relaxed its' pressure now.</seg>
     <seg id="3">While ignoring India's unnecessary bobbery, the satisfaction of the United Nations and the appreciation from the Interpol chief over Pakistan's efforts is a "Side Effect" of India's overwhelming diplomacy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There are no two opinions over this that it is a heinous act.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But the question is that when thousands of Taliban attacked the house of Pir Samiullah, where and what was the Pakistani army doing at that time?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Should the army not be accountable for what they have done over the past year?</seg>
     <seg id="4">How many Taliban are killed by thousands of shells fired by mortars and cannons everyday?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I appeal to the I.S.I, that for God's sake, stop monitoring the Taliban and let us live in peace in our heavenly hometown Sawat.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And stop this phony operation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The day is not far when a resolution about Pakistan's military intervention will be passed by United Nations, just like the bill which was passed against Jamat-ud-Dawah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Riaz Ahmad Farooqi</seg>
     <seg id="3">The extremists of our country and their supporters themselves are constantly providing all evidences and justifications required for instigation of action against them, and God forbid, the day when such a resolution is passed, in all likelihood, not a single voice would be raised in United Nations, in our favor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And supposing there is a delay in the enactment of this resolution, then considering the example of America, a superpower will come forward to take over on its own resources.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We are not aware and familiar with the character and achievements of Pir Sami-ullah and what his activities were.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Maybe he was not a revolutionist.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Like the dead bodies of Comrade Che Guevara, Nawab Akbar Khan Bugti, Doctor Najeebullah and thousands of other revolutionists have been subjected to dishonor at the hands of the enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are immortal even after they die.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But there is a international game being played here in which the public is ruled by fear through barbarism and ferociousness.</seg>
     <seg id="6">So that license can be created that if we are not here than these ferocious and barbaric will clutch the government.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These acts of so called Islamic activists in the name of religion is without limit worthy of condemnation.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The supporters of extremists can see the injustice of America, but instead of expressing grieve on those dishonest acts they clearly shun them by giving them the name of tribal traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Sometimes by cloaking in tribal traditions, sometimes in the name of Islam, no pious man can give reason for such dishonest acts.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my view, our Army is associated with theses people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">When these people move from a place, it takes so much time that they can be caught.  There should be time for that, but it's a stretch that they get there on time, even if they are there, they are long gone.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are they so merciless that they kidnap fifty seventy men?  And our Army stands by like a spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are servants of Allah and so is our Army.</seg>
     <seg id="5">There is something wrong at the bottom.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malaiat, in the period of the dictator of the time Zia-u-Lhaq, did not show good characteristics of sympathies of Allah, but there is various tortures in the name of religion and more in his writing: "What will be done after death."</seg>
     <seg id="2">And such persons use this fear as a way to get the world's respect.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Speakers                                                                                                                                                              ""preachers""</seg>
     <seg id="4">You frightened the world with the fire of Hell.</seg>
     <seg id="5">That you became the image of fright.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Upon it wondered that when it is said that it cannot be a Muslim action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We ourselves do not know this history or cover it for any purpose.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
     <seg id="5">Was the attack of Yazid's forces on Medina not the act of Christians and the Jews?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Motives cannot be diminished and correcion cannot be made without accepting reality.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">O' BBC please stop this dual-headed policy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">better than this topic the super hit title: Shoe-ing of Bush fair or unfair?</seg>
     <seg id="3">'should have been</seg>
     <seg id="4">Tahir Choudhry, Japan</seg>
     <seg id="5">A human was pulled out of his grave and hanged over a pole just because he raised his voice against oppression, and you are concerned about the topic of the box office?  Please show some modesty.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the success of Operation Sherdil and Operation Lion Heart across the border depends on who is in the favor of public opinion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is an act of American and Pakistani agencies and Peer.  Sahab is a victim of this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now that secret agens have successfully joined the Taliban and they are doign what the can to change public opinion, all discussions on this forum will now be anti Taliban.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I would like to ask only this. What were the soldiers doing when the corpse was kept hanging throughout a day? were they sitting there to aim only the common people? It is said that Taliban hideouts were bombed and a woman and two kids were killed when a house was attacked.    I would like to ask this: what were the soldiers doing when they allowed a corpse to hang throughout the day?  It is said that two Taliban hideouts were bombed.  A woman and two children were also killed when a home was attacked.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why? Didn't they come to know about this great tragedy?    Why?  Didn't they already know about this great tragedy?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Were they leisurely having fun, or not?    Were they leisurely having fun or not?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Let us fold our hands to you in a request. For God's sake, stop this game.    Let us sincerely make a request: for God's sake, stop this game.</seg>
     <seg id="5">After all, there is a ruler who watches over all of us.    This sounds good.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Though the question raised from the B.B.C. is substandard, it could only be felt pity at the poor quality of the writers. For instance, nobody asked this. What were the 3000 soldiers camping at Swat doing ?    Though the questions raised from the B.B.C. are substandard, one could only feel pity at the poor quality of the writers. For instance, nobody asked this: what were the 3000 soldiers camping at Swat doing ?</seg>
     <seg id="2">The helpers of the army were hanging on poles the dead bodies of those who fought Taliban.    The helpers of the army were hanging the dead bodies of those who fought the Taliban on poles.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The cheating done to the commoners by the Pakistani soldiers is done, but, it is not right that the medias including B.B.C. has concealed the fact from the world.    The Pakistani soldiers have already cheated the common people, and what is done is done, but it is not right that the media (including the BBC) has concealed this fact from the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Pak soldiers are playing drama.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Every child in Swat whispers that it is a bloody drama.    This sounds good.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Stop this drama for goodness sake!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These Taliban members have destroyed the image of Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If the real Muslims don't accept the Taliban as Muslims then they become refugees in their own places.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The ones who are shameless and don't do hard work and labor take arms in their hands and join their group.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Islam doesn't spread through swords and guns.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Have shame.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It's baseless and has no roots in any religion or in family customs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All media including the BBC show different views on Taliban and tribals.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In fact, nobody knows the actual situation except us, because we are the natives.</seg>
     <seg id="4">(  sorry was pretty hard to translate)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This move has shamed all Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I salute Altaf Hussain of the MQM and the leadership of the ANP and PPP, who speak out against this cancer that is the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This cancer is a product of the late Zia-ul-Haq, who managed to destroy Pakistan before he died.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But I am hopeful that the current leadership will remove this cancer.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the Mumbai incident, India said that extremists were behind the attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan, rejecting the accusations, said that it will help India's investigation in every way possible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India said that it has submitted a "wanted list" of 20 suspected extremists to Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan has said that the list includes Jaish-e-Muhammad's Molana Azhar Masood, who is not in custody and about whom the government of Pakistan has no information.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Before that the president of Pakistan Asif Ali Zardari rejected the view that western spy agencies and the Indian government had provided evidence related to the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">President Zardari has said that it has not been proven that Ajmal Kasab is Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="7">During this, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh warned Pakistan that the its relations with India are not going to improve if its land continues to be used for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="8">And in the latest development, the Indian cricket team has cancelled their tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should sports be affected due to these political events?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What future to you see for the India-Pakistan relationship?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Neither America nor India could break Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan could only be broken by the Pakistanis themselves.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What do you expect after such regionalism, communalism. and vandalism?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even Jinnah, too, did not do good for the Muslims of India. Time has proved this.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Yasmin, Chicago</seg>
     <seg id="6">Madam, if we had kept working on the vision of Jinnah, the cancer of Communalism, Regionalism and Vandalism would not have spread in Pakistan. And also the Muslims of India would not have been treated this way.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is our mistake of not producing a leader of his caliber.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If only we could pay respect to our heroes.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This region has great potential.</seg>
     <seg id="2">God knows when this region will learn its lesson. Its unity will bring prosperity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Both countries have extremist forces, such as the Taliban and Shiv Sena. These extremist forces are the enemies of the peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The imperial powers do not want peace and stability in this region. They are controlling these countries like puppets.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can you imagine the potential international influence of Pakistan, China, and India if they were to be united?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Pakistan is under the occupation of corrupt and opportunist leadership.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May God protect our country, Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Being Pakistanis, we should not neglect the ground threats. American forces have been deployed near our Afghan borders.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Besides this, the situation in the country doesnt seem to be stable, like in the NWFP, Baluchistan and Sindh, and the problems in Karachi are also evident.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In this atmosphere, we need a leader that can unite the people of this country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">O God please show us some mercy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I believe we have no other option but to go to war one last time.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Enough is enough.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It's now or never.</seg>
     <seg id="4">These fraudulent dialogues and pointless meetings are not the solution to the problems.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Neither is committing small scale terrorist acts in each others territories.</seg>
     <seg id="6">After all, it was only after waging the Second World War that Europe managed to sort its problems out.</seg>
     <seg id="7">And if it wasn't for this World War then they'd still be arguing and nagging each other over small things.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Almost all of our political parties are unified in the idea that terrorism and sectarian violence shall be eradicated from the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">However, our own military leadership does not seem to be sincere in this assertion. On one side, Europe and America are assured that the military is sincere in achieving a terror-free state, but on the other hand, the military aids the Taliban covertly.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now we have to think, define our path, and select one path to focus on. Thank you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no doubt that the elements of Jamat-ud-dawa include a majority which belongs to Lashkar-e-Taiba, a banned organization which is now established and operating with a new name: Jamat-ud-dawa Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">However, after more focus was diverted towards humanitarian activities on India's strong request, the United Nations has also banned it. The government of Pakistan has also implemented a crackdown on this organization.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, if these Jihadi groups leave religious extremism and focus on religion and humanitarian assistance, then it is much better.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The terrorist organizations present in Pakistan which have used the name of Jihad to recruit and nurture professional killers and criminals and their molana's are the same people who called Pakistan "Plaeedistan", meaning unclean land. These are the people who use bad names for Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now they are trying their best to destroy Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In reality, they don't even get close deserving the term Muslim. In fact, they deserve to be called animals or barbarians.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan's security will be at risk until these extremists are eradicated from Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Should we still believe that the innocent people will be charged with rules and regulation?</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this furious world the job is war, their work is only to kill.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">With this news my heart is broken.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What type of world is this in which it is very difficult to follow the preachings of Allah's Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Non-Muslim can kill Muslims, but when Muslims try to take revenge then all non-Muslims along with the whole world think that Islamic preaching is done with Hafiz Sayeed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">India is very upset about the attack on Mumbai.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Citizens of Pakistan have created the misunderstanding between the two countries and in the coming days the situation will worsen.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India always blames Pakistan's terrorist group.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The upcoming problems on the Taluk have been stopped.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian security centers have blamed Lashkar-e-tayab for the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this case, the name of Jamat-ud-Dawa has come to the forefront many times.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the first time that relationship between both the countries has worsened due to terrorist activity in India.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In December 2001, after the attacks on the Indian Parliament, these two neighbors were on the brink of war.</seg>
     <seg id="9">After that, in 2002 Lashker-e-Tayyaba was banned and included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Now it is about Jamat-ud-Dawa, which Security analysts say that is in reality a new face of Lashker-e-Tayyaba. Restrictions on the party are being requested.</seg>
     <seg id="11">In your opinion, should this group be banned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Should Pakistan conduct decisive operations against extreme activists on its land?</seg>
     <seg id="13">By banning Jamat-ud-Dawa, can  the current Pak-India crisis be brought to a close?</seg>
     <seg id="14">And how important is it to close down the armed groups to keep constant peace between both countries?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Security Council of the United Nations has banned Jamat-ud-Dawa. After all, what proof does the Security Council have to decide this so quickly?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Will the Peace Council ever show any alertness against the Muslims any time?</seg>
     <seg id="3">For this it is said that when the accuser is lazy the witness is active.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If see; India itself has become one useless realm.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whose intelligence, army and other security officials have become useless, who for 72 hours has danced the dance of mole with terrorists and India is cheating the world by blaming Pakistan over its uselessness.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If one disbeliever dies then the whole world knows about it- why is this double accuracy?</seg>
     <seg id="2">To the dear nation of one nonpolitical, religious, farming organization</seg>
     <seg id="3">Farqaan Farooq, Faisalabad</seg>
     <seg id="4">Until our Prophet(Peace be upon Him), great ancestors, and Sufism give the human beings the love and respect. The religion of Islam was more vast growing and ripening from peace and sparkle.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Muslims also got promoted in every field.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But when this beautiful Religion rose to the hands of distillation then within the human beings began the difference of religious and disbeliever and the new gateways of pride and prejudice began to open by which the world was unknown before.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salute, sir! Salute happily, but get your work done on your own.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Do not do it because of American pressure.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Let India show it is having difficulties.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why does it not give?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And why do they accuse us of everything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Even in India, there are fundamentalist groups and organisations.  Why aren't they restricted?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are we the only terrorists in the whole world?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What is India doing in Kashmir?</seg>
     <seg id="9">What is Israel doing?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The truth is that we are the first Islamic Nuclear State. Is this what the fight is about?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is on the verge of breaking up.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Kamranhassan, ABU DHABI</seg>
     <seg id="3">You are right, and circumstances are supporting your argument.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now even American magazines are publishing new maps of Pakistan. These sanctions are the part of greater game plan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Gradually, the USA is making its grip on Pakistan stronger.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this situation, if we don't become a united nation, then the history of Bangladesh's creation will be repeated.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Terrorists' attacks should be condemned, whether these are committed in Mumbai, Islamabad, or Philistine.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Terrorists should be uprooted without any discrimination with regard to nationality.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The question arises as to why Pakistan and other world  powers remain silent about the terrorist attacks in Pakistan that killed hundreds of innocent people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Was the attack on the Marriott not an act of terror?</seg>
     <seg id="5">then why-</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">hail to the Interior Advisor Rehman Malik, how brave and bold has he become.</seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">not only this, but according to BBC Mr. Malik has denied this impression with intensity that the arresting of the terrorists have been carried out under 'someones's pressure'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">wow, all praise to the Almighty!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">whether having the ability or not or to say that I don't want.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We, Pakistanis are fighting whose war.</seg>
     <seg id="3">and why we have our own interests, which we shall do our best to protect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">No one has a right to interfere anyone's national affairs.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The colonial system is apparently not there.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If people are sure to have justice or Allies support the importance of free judiciary and give respect to democratic institutes and dont support the dictatorial governments; peace can be achieved in third world countries including Pakistan. But this is not acceptable for allies</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is always in line with European and American interests.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan is forced to do so, even though a majority of its population opposes it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This enhances the opposite or anti sentiments.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If America and its allies believe in democracy, they should give up their colonial behavior and leave this region.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan has the ability to arm or disarm.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Security forces searched a camp of Lashar-i-tayba in Pakistan that was  administered Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After the Mumbai attacks, increased pressure is being put on Pakistan to take actions against extreme outfits.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India blames that Lashar-i-tayba had role in the Mumbai Attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
     <seg id="5">He believed the terrorists involved in the Mumbai Attacks were from Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Meanwhile, the officials in Peshawar stated that more than fifty trucks have been burned by some unknown armed personnel. These trucks were going to Afghanistan with goods for NATO forces.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This was the second attack on American supplies during the last forty-eight hours.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Meanwhile, Pakistani police cracked down on a camp of Lashkar i Taiba, a banned organization. Already many efforts have been made to disarm the extremists. Even money and indemnity were offered.</seg>
     <seg id="9">It is clear from the circumstances that efforts remain unsuccessful to dislodge the armed groups funded by Americans and Saudis during the Afghan war. It means efforts to restore pre-80's Pakistan are fruitless.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The question arises whether Pakistan wants to do so?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Does Pakistan have an ability to do this?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What is your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="13">For details please click here.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Note: due to higher numbers, only comments typed in Urdu will be published</seg>
     <seg id="15">For this, click Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard and select Urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I have only one question for the standard-bearers of the world-</seg>
     <seg id="2">If you kill their children, will they come to praise you? It is impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4">And I ask you, does any science, from the Islamic sciences to the sciences of the East and the West, any logic or philosophy, anywhere, give the permission to kill the innocent public, including worshipers, laborers, and poor workers, in revenge for the American attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">If your answer is in the negative, then you really need to examine your point of view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The people were armed when there was the fear that Russia would head towards Pakistan after finishing in Afghanistan, and that is why they were supplied arms.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, when there is the fear that America will capture Pakistan via Afghanistan,as the American president  mentioned in his presidential address, why should we disarm them now?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Only so that after defeating the American or Indian army, it does not have to face any resistance from the public?</seg>
     <seg id="4">If any of them are guilty of being involved in any destructive work, Pakistan can take action against them alone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is sad that the fact that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved, proves India's claim that Pakistan is guilty in this.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeebur Rahman Syco, Lahore</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even if we accept that Lashkar-e-Taiba is guilty, it's still not correct to blame the Pakistani government.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Another question is that were these terrorists supported by an Indian governmental or non-governmental agent?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are terrorists only born or trained in Pakistan, and not any other country in the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post63" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As for Lashkar-e-Taiba, the present terrorism is in no way connected to it.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It must be remembered that Hafiz Saeed is the first 'Jehadi leader' who called the Taliban actions 'mischief'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I'm sure that the Taliban effect is a inseparable result of American plans, and hence every person who can stand in the way of the Taliban must be removed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Despite the support of the whole nation, the fact that Zardari and co. took action against the Lashkar is a clear sign of their frigid and kiss-up nature.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To stop the project that is running on Saudi-American funding, they must be requested themselves to regather the filth that has polluted our society.</seg>
     <seg id="2">we will protest against them about the ethical way America and Saudia has distributed Dangerous weapons and so called Jihad but actually they have distributed hatred literature and cultural virus which has created a human slaughter houses.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">after the threat from India to attack Pakistan, Pakistan Military announces that he will pull his forces from Afghan border and put it towards India. Taliban also announces that they will take care of the Afghan border which resulted in a chaos In America and he Forced India not to do war with Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In this Letter all the musket of American Power was exposed</seg>
     <seg id="3">in contrast India has never threatened nor it has the power to attack</seg>
     <seg id="4">the remaining damage is done by the Taliban by attacking the American convoy</seg>
     <seg id="5">this proved that without Pakistan Military and Government Of Pakistan support, America is Nothing</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Karachi, Pakistan's Main Business and Finance City which is Dubai of all the rural areas</seg>
     <seg id="2">Million never returned from here with empty hands, but when western areas law and order situation is worsen all attention is directed towards Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="3">now they want to hijack this city</seg>
     <seg id="4">for the first time Pathans are called by Pakhtuns,which is making city's people as stranger and fighting among each other, but to be united is necessity of time</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One solution to this problem is that either the Urdu speaking people learn Pushtun or the Pushtun speaking people learn Urdu, or better yet, both learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You might think that this is a funny proposal, but does the cause of the conflict not seem funny?</seg>
     <seg id="3">That the cause of extremism be language?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir, I actually shared this proposal many times in my childhood with my friends, which included people from all religious and linguistic groups, but these people used to laugh at me.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At that time, the religious and linguistic hate, which was not as lively and strong as they are today, were still developing within.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I can never understand what is happening and why.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are these the signs of the Day of Judgement?</seg>
     <seg id="3">For what crime are innocent people being killed?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The reasons are in front of everybody. Those who want to break up Pakistan are the active ones, and those who do such things, have neither religion, nor country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whether it be Karachi or Mumbai, the house was burnt by the houses own lanterns</seg>
     <seg id="6">Whichever government comes, it only changes the names of the places and starts working for fame, just like how nowadays, the airports, roads and buildings are all Benazir.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Does Benazir mean that is what is happening to the public of Karachi and Pakistan?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At the height of the Mumbai attacks, efforts to cause mischief on linguistic and racial lines in Karachi failed, which is proof that those politicians working on racial parole have resigned from their jobs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The taking of the lives of innocent Pushtu speaking laborers, and the Indian warnings have awakened the sleeping Pakistani feelings from Karachi to Khyber.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The identical country loving reaction of all the political, religious, linguistic and national parties has not only taught India the manners of diplomacy, but it has also given the American policy makers a chance to think again.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The responsible parties for the worsening situation in Karachi are the United and the ANP. The government is taking sides.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The government can control the situation in one hour, but it is purposely allowing it to grow.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The police and rangers are avoiding action because of the pressure on them by the political parties.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The talk of uniting is only restricted to speeches. The political parties should leave their interests and work for the interest of the common man.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Situations like this will continue to occur until political pressure is applied consistently on the management. Allah keep Pakistan safe.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, they are the biggest terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Of course there are external forces at work here, but no one knows who they are.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Saddest of all is that had this situation occurred somewhere in Sarhad, the government would not have acted as it has; but when not in Sarhad, the government is completely helpless.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government should intervene here and save one of the country's largest and most important cities.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Otherwise, Pakistan will face massive economic setbacks.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even BBC Urdu is too scared to write the truth, although the state of the Pakistani media is even worse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The complete truth is available on BBC English.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One solution to this problem would be for Urdu speakers to learn Pashto or vice versa, or better yet for everyone to learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You might consider this suggestion ridiculous but isn't the reason for the conflict also ridiculous?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Language may be the reason for persecution.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Another story of murder, long dreaded by all the citizens has finally been published in Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The criminals seize any opportunity to commit a crime. The media are only telling 50% of what actually happened here in 4 days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Citizens have spent three sleepless nights. Clearly the fear is still present.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Those who make the people evacuate hotels, those who kill the shoe-makers and the peanut-sellers.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Those who rob and kill at the Super Highway, and cut off the ears of innocent citizens are ignorant of the wrath of Allah which will eventually entrap them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In your opinion, what is the cause of this sudden turmoil?</seg>
     <seg id="2">(B.B.C)</seg>
     <seg id="3">In light of the gruesome bloodshed event in Mumbai, we do not need to delve deep into the matter to find the cause of the disorder in Karachi. It seems that the turmoil is due to an unconscious trade of blood.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Obviously if someone infuriates the father, it would not be surprising for the son to react violently.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The blood of the loyalists of Liaqat Ali Khan also belonged to the same place. To eliminate Mr. Psycho's misunderstanding I am writing this verse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We will also repeat our elders' traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We made it by sacrificing lives and will save it by doing the same.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Faizan Tauseef Siddiqui</seg>
     <seg id="5">it is very disappointing that whole country is at stake and we are fighting with each other.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mr. Siddiqui, I request if wikipedia.</seg>
     <seg id="7">See Liaqat Ali Khan and you will will find out that he belonged to a noble Punjabi family from Karnal in Punjab.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Due to his steps for the migrants, today the migrants consider him as one of them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is always a reaction to every action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">One can afford on oneself but.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Ejaz Aiwan</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sir, before you gather a huge crowd very quickly, I should tell you that you are finding the graffiti of real gangsters these days on the walls of Karachi in the form of wall chalking and posters.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We have been tolerating both kinds of actions.</seg>
     <seg id="6">These thugs did not even forgive Pakistan and the founder of Pakistan. They did not face any reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="7">On the contrary, we are writing our hearts on the chest of Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One Muslim League Q was left, and even they made a draft of the 18th amendment and gave it to the People's Party.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Before this, MQM and Muslim League Q made and submitted a draft of the 18th amendment to the National Assembly and the Senate.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Until now it seems that drafts of the 18th amendment are a political trick and no one is sincere in getting this amendment approved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the reason why no one has made a fuss in the assembly or senate floor in favor of this amendment, nor has anyone forced the assembly to approve this change.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It seems like after submitting the drafts of the 18th amendment, these parties have done their part. That is, they will be able to say tomorrow that they submitted the draft and the government speaker did not take any action.</seg>
     <seg id="6">MQM the government, Muslim League N in the opposition and Muslim League Q was the party who passed 17th amendment so how is it possible that these parties will be sincere in finishing the 17th amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is called getting credit for nothing.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The People's party is not in a hurry about finishing the 17th Amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="9">How can someone think of cutting their own hands?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The 17th Amendment will not be canceled until Zardari is the President.</seg>
     <seg id="11">This was the opinion of the majority in our survey.</seg>
     <seg id="12">If the 17th Amendment was discarded then Zardari would have never become the president.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Now he is even more powerful than President Parvez Musharaf, because being the president also makes him the chairman of the People's Party.</seg>
     <seg id="14">The 17th Amendment will not be valid until he is the president.</seg>
     <seg id="15">In order to finish the 17th amendment, the political parties will have to wait until Zardari leaves the office of president.</seg>
     <seg id="16">Neither MQM nor other parties want this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Most of the elders in our family belonged to the working class.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During our childhood when our uncles did their work, we prayed to Allah to protect us from physical labor.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To avoid this we wrote to the editor of monthly Amroz to ask him what to do after matriculation so that we would not have to do physical labor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In reply, the Editor wrote that we should become a Doctor or Engineer and study these courses.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We were inclined towards engineering and in matriculation we studied Technical drawing instead of Biology.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But at the time of admissions in FSc, our older brother forced us to study medical in FSc.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We had hardly studied biology for a month before we started studying math.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In order to avoid physical labor, we became engineers and we are in a better position than many friends in our family. We thank Allah for it.</seg>
     <seg id="9">We remembered this when with out 2 young sons we were trying to lift carpets of old hour.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It hasn't even been half an hour while we were working that the small son said, "Daddy it seems that I am not born for this job".</seg>
     <seg id="11">We said, "If so, study well like us and build up your body".</seg>
     <seg id="12">The son started saying, "I am studying already and will study more but this work is not done by me".</seg>
     <seg id="13">Anyhow, us three managed to complete the work within three hours and returned home.</seg>
     <seg id="14">The meaning of the saying is that if a man decides on one destiny then whatever comes afterward will not stop him to accomplish his destination.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Yes, and if you don't really know what you have to do then Allah is the only protector for you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is a saying that never say bad things for a dead. At the first death anniversary of Benazeer we only see bad in her.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazeer, for her own benefit, forwarded to India the Sikhs' army who were to fight the war of independent. On one side the independent movement of the Sikhs was collapsed and on the other side, they gave a chance for India to concentrate on Kashmir after pushing down the Punjab movement.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Distraction from the leadership of Benazeer and Nawaz Sharif have pushed the country to many years backwards.</seg>
     <seg id="4">During exile, Benazeer continued on keeping the series beneficiary information of Kashmir and Atomic Program.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Benazir violated the London agreement with Nawaz Sharif and made a deal with General Musharaf.</seg>
     <seg id="6">During the rule of Benazir, she gave her husband the freedom to make as much money as possible, which is why he is known as Mr. Ten Percent.</seg>
     <seg id="7">During Benazirs' rule, her brother was killed, but the murderers are still safe from any punishment.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Besides being a woman herself, Benazir avoided fighting for womens' rights.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Just like Benazir took over politics upon the death of her father, her widower has taken over politics at her death.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Benazir came into power twice, but she could not punish or register a case against  the culprits that murdered her father.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It has been 37 years since East Pakistan has been separated from us, but due to the extreme senselessness of our people and leaders we have never celebrated the mourning day.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Instead, we should have celebrated December 16th as Didactic Day and take measures so that this kind of incident doesn't take place again.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On this day we send greetings to the people of Bangladesh as we try to bring them closer to us again.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The rulers should reopen the Hamudur Rehman commission reports and discuss the reasons for the separation of East Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">There was once a plan in place to make bring back the Bahari's who were stuck in Bangladesh and send them aid to assist them and raise their moral.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But now there lacks compassion and initiative to continue acts of kindness and good will. We have become so concentrated on our own lives, we unaware of deaths of our neighbors.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We do not care about our friends, relatives and countrymen because, we have become selfish and self-centered.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Even if a massive natural disaster occurs, we are too busy in our daily routines to take notice or show any care for those in need from one day to the next.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Only if we could find a way to re-unite East and West Pakistan and both states could be together as one; just as East and West Germany were brought back together in the 1980s.</seg>
     <seg id="10">We can be a sovereign state of one again if each state sacrifices for the better of unity by relinquishing their selfish ways.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But this thought and hope of many does not seem to be possible in the near future.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When it was announced in the news today that the Governor of the American State Illinois was arrested for alleged corruption and misuse of his political powers</seg>
     <seg id="2">and the State Congress started actions to remove him from his position as governor immediately, we have American politician who has close ties to the circumstances of Pakistan, boastfully claimed to our government and nation that this is what we the United States calls democracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In America, even the politicians and the elite people can not break the law and get away with no consequences.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And the other is your country, Pakistan, where even the president was chosen after the corruption charges against him were dropped.</seg>
     <seg id="5">My vein of loyalty throbbed and I said what is the big deal if a governor was arrested in America? In Pakistan, once the prime minister was arrested and hanged overnight, and another time sent into exile.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tell me, when did this happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="7">In Pakistan, those who broke the law were sent out of the presidential palace with a guard of honor. Tell me when this happened in America.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The chief justice of Pakistan was removed in such a manner that, despite having public support, he could not be replaced until now. Has this happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="9">In Pakistan, a fake-degree holder was made the minister of health. Did this happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Hearing this, the American laughed until he was tired and conceded defeat.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In this picture, President Zardari is smiling, despite being surrounded on all four sides by Americans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It seems from his smile that he thinks that America is with his government.</seg>
     <seg id="3">He is forgetting that one year ago, they were with Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thus psychotherapy gained popularity.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whether there is madness in method, or method in madness, there is certainly a method in dealing with madness.</seg>
     <seg id="6">That said, mental health care has come a long way from merely addressing dementia, to dealing with problems such as stress, depression, anxiety and relationship problems.</seg>
     <seg id="7">When she finished her MA in counseling psychology from Columbia university.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The center offers support services for depression, anxiety, stress, learning problems, and personality deficiencies.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Material problems and workplace issues.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It also offers employee assistance programs for corporates.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There are enough opportunities in the fields of counseling and psychotherapy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Traditionally both roles were played by psychiatrists, who not only counseled patients.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Research has revealed that there are conditions which can be cured without medication.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Instead of using power, the government should be finding out the real sources of this problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Fazalullah and Taliban will dissolve into nothingness if the root causes are terminated.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The Shariat bill suggested by the ANP administration will, to a great extent, bring a solution for the problems in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="7">But, in addition to the observance of the Shariat law, the administration will take care of the well being of the people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The actions of General Musharaf led us to believe that we had been freed from the unqualified politicians of the land but, his ambition for more power changed everything.</seg>
     <seg id="2">How many expectations were there! He lost all hopes in "War and Terror".</seg>
     <seg id="3">Hopes of taking actions were lost.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It seemed that he understood that the end of his reign was imminent along with the end of Bush administration. As a result, thieves were recruited to power centers.</seg>
     <seg id="5">General Musharaf was in a position to control the army ,but the present administration does not know any of this was occurring.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The army could not put down the terror in Baajodoh and Swat. The commoners are subjected to "bombardments and enmity" i.e, resulting in great loss of lives and property. It also puts them into psychological disorder.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Swat, the strongly affected part of Sarhad state, despite the continuity of military action for over one year, the situation is still going from bad to worse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On one side, the government is only reiterating the passing of a reproachful resolution in the national assembly. On the other side, the Taliban's illegal radio FM channel is having much more influence in the region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the third side, the common man considers it safest to listen to the one who actually has control over the region.</seg>
     <seg id="4">During the action of the security forces, there were claims of destroying the fundamentalists by the bombing of gun ship helicopters and cannon houses, but despite these destructions, the Taliban only became more powerful, and according to an estimation, their control over Swat increased that much more.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a result, on the one hand the government is not ready to accept defeat, and on the other hand the Taliban is getting stronger.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Who are stuck in between? The poor civilians.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is said in Swat, that someone asked what kind of people the Taliban were, so he got the answer, 'They are very good, as they are protectors of the religion and they fight against the enemies of Allah and the religion'.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Then he asked how the army was, so he got the answer, 'They are very good, as they are the protectors of the country and they fight against the enemies of the country'.</seg>
     <seg id="9">He then asked who the enemies of the religion and the country were, so he got the answer, 'We civilians'.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I am wondering how the Pakistani Army will fight the Indian Army, when they couldn't control a small faction of the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They couldn't track down Taliban's illegally operated FM channel which in my opinion is very easy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the mean while still the FM was spreading hatred in full swing.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the girls school's now it's the boys school's that are being destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Curfew is imposed so that tablibans can move around easily.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tonight eight trucks entered the suburbs of Mingora during curfew and created bunkers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The question is that how could they reach there destination during curfew?</seg>
     <seg id="8">The army could kill Akbar Bugti in his house and salute the  Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="9">For God sake someone tells this Army to protect helpless people of Sawat from Taliban and prove that Pakistan army can overcome any enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">He says that most of the blood is spilt in the name of religion. Tell me if religion was not then blood wouldn't have spilt?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Punjabi, Pathan, White, Black, Mehsood and other tribes are these the products of religion?</seg>
     <seg id="3">No not at all. The religion teaches that there is no white nor black, there is no Punjabi nor immigrant. If there was no religion then people would have destroyed each other and other things in the battle of black and white.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The religion only teaches the man how to be disciplined and mannered. Religion only shows the man that he has not come by himself instead he has been created by the Supreme Power God and He has sent you in this world to lead a life as per His orders.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Being a Muslim I am very sure that Islam is a complete religion and moreover it is a true religion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even after the time I acquired the luxuries in London, I continued to call up my relatives every morning to find out about their good and bad events. Even though my relatives never bothered to call me ever in my life, I still  continued to do so. But when I felt that my relatives didn't even like my calling them, I stopped making calls to them.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Even I have felt the same here since I have spent two years in France.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Why the people keep expecting only from us to make a phone call to them in Patna?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Regarding Iraq, within a few hours there would be an Army sent for the "peace" in Darfar. This is not a problem for them.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The post action after the Mumbai Blasts and the security in the areas are a matter of few hours.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There are discussions and opinions on the matter where there are more risk to death in the areas of Mumbai through any sources.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Hey you, the Protectors and leaders of the peaceful world, life is being ended here only in the discussions.</seg>
     <seg id="5">is it really being waited to diminish.</seg>
     <seg id="6">so that no could again even think about using a weapon of mass destruction like the stonebow to gain his own rights.  (this is a fragment, we don't have a topic...why or who?  what was the action?)</seg>
     <seg id="7">when a father is running, carrying his beloved son's dead body, even then, your hearts don't pinch you with pain?</seg>
     <seg id="8">If not then, you don't even deserve to be called human being.</seg>
     <seg id="9">You become a black mottle over the name of humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">So at least it has been proven that this region has also been a homeland for Jews for centuries.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ideally these two nations should have lived in harmony, but  their strings are in Western and Arab hands. So without their own will, peace can not prevail in this region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And even now Iran wants to fight its proxy war from here.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even if the Israeli operation stops temporarily, Tension is so high it will start again any moment after any incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC's own country has its interests related to America and Israel and this is why while taking cover of enlightened moderation, it has started a series of blogs on Jewism and this creates biased propaganda.</seg>
     <seg id="2">BBC is only completing a formality, and its goal and intent is to gather well wishes.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I request the moderator to publish this comment of Fidwi, so it be known that at least a little bit of affinity towards truth is still remaining in BBC</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thank You.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I don't know who wrote this story or how this story came to being, but one thing is for sure, in every age, Dracula's have been drinking the blood of innocent people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In every age, wars have been fought and blood has been spilled.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the surprising thing is that this 21st century man, who considers himself civilized, is quiet over this ruthless open massacre.</seg>
     <seg id="4">How could I not feel that whatever is happening is presenting a very ugly picture of mankind.</seg>
     <seg id="5"></seg>
     <seg id="6">Well wisher, Sajjad Alhasnain, Hyderabad, Deccan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At this time, including Derah Gahzi Khan, summer showers are taking place throughout the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A poem on climate is presented to you. May you enjoy the sweet rain when you read this poem.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It rains just because of you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Whatever rains is the spring.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whatever comes to a standstill is tranquility.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Sometimes it comes for no reason.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Often it spreads wide in the night hours.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Sometimes quite noisily, often silently,</seg>
     <seg id="9">It rains.. but just because of you.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Whichever cherished memory, whichever night,</seg>
     <seg id="11">A suppressed music!</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sometimes, he put it out.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Sometimes, he lit himself up.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Sometimes, every drop carries sorrow.</seg>
     <seg id="15">These rains are quite like you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All of these leaders are about to ruin a sensitive case because they do not care if the country survives.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The people should be selling their possessions or wiping the temples clean with lemon peels.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our leaders and the media are both corrupt.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Its sole purpose is to extract money from the government.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And the people are oblivious of this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">An odd incident took place yesterday at noon.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Police are running here and there, but don't ask about illegal parking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What's more, NYPD traffic was not able to look at illegally parked vehicles.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Something like this happened, when a plane of US Air really became a ship and landed in the Hudson river.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Until now, we only thought that terrorists are of the descendants of geese.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Yesterday was perhaps historically cold in New York.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The temperature does not fall this much.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Even my jaw started hurting from my half an hour walk outside.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Imagine how the people who jumped from the plane into the river would have felt.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It is a matter of luck that all people were safe.</seg>
     <seg id="11">And it was sad that the company's plane sunk during this financial crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="12">I went by West Side Highway to New Jersey, watching all this, and I saw that Southbound was blocked, but what did I do?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Yes, I got stuck in the same rush on the way back.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Thankfully, in my one hour trip, the way had opened just a bit, so I was able to get onto the 56th street exit.</seg>
     <seg id="15">I had not taken the previous two exits, seeing the lines of traffic there.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Makki, My Pakistan: Well, congratulations. Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ammar: Of course, believing women</seg>
     <seg id="3">Shaguftah: Well, congratulations. Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sarah: I have slaughtered two chickens. How I did it, Jahanzeb has already mentioned.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Besides this, there is no other way.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At this farm, one has to process his own meat, including removing the skin.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Bossom: It may take some time for the dot net to get fixed</seg>
     <seg id="8">What happened on the forum?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Linko.</seg>
     <seg id="10">To fight with the "Listen to the blog", use Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Duffer: Khair Mubarak! Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sir please use Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="13">It will snow till it disappears.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">For no reason had we thought that the Taliban group from Sawat was non religious, who were only against women education.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They were expressing this irritation by demolishing schools and colleges for women every day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But like majority of the ideas, this was not proven right also. According to this news of CNN, on the lucky day of Monday, a group of Taliban demolished a Boys school with gunpowder.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Taliban has destroyed a boys school in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The girls schools were already destroyed, acting according to the famous English saying "Ladies First".  I do not know why people are still bent on calling the Taliban uncultured and barbaric.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Another thing that becomes clear from this is that the accusation of the Taliban being against girls education is not true.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Rather, they are against education altogether.</seg>
     <seg id="8">May Allah give these Mujahideen more power, and the evil government less.</seg>
     <seg id="9">May He help them in uprooting the evil government.</seg>
     <seg id="10"></seg>
     <seg id="11"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">Some days go, a girl's marriage with a dog become fresh.</seg>
     <seg id="4">see that now</seg>
     <seg id="5">Humanity is rare in 21st century.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the age of the computer. The computer occupies a place in every walk of life.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have objections over interference of computer as its role in financial matters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Although credit card users have facility but their personal life is under more control of law enforcement agencies.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now much of a person's financial matters can easily be tracked by using credit card records.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In the future, when usage of currency will become less frequent, the computer's importance will increase.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In the crime world risk is not as often taken to rob banks. Now credit card information is stolen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In addition, friends are also made through computers.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Social networking sites, like Orkut, Facebook and Myspace are accepted by many now.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But do you not think that the more we are following these social networking sites, the we interact with people in real life?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Similar problems can arise when using the match making websites, where your desires are matched with others desires and you are shown a list of the people who match with you.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Can you lead a life with a person who is just like you?</seg>
     <seg id="12">I can not. That is why a spouse is called the better half.</seg>
     <seg id="13">He/she will help eliminate my faults.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Perhaps I have achieved some small degree of wisdom.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I used to believe everything my elders said.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the same way, I thought that my father knew the answer to every question on earth.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I used to get laughed at a lot for this.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But only that saying seemed true, which is possible.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mad?  Why not just tell the truth?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Bore did not understand this saying inspite of his age.</seg>
     <seg id="8">So I am trying to tell the truth about this as much as is possible.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Do not misguide someone by lieing and then attaching Allah's name in order to appear honest.</seg>
     <seg id="10">And, Allah willing, say only when there is a prayer to Allah that work is completed.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Allah knows the true intentions of someone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a disgusting problem which is created because of a distance from religion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to law of both Pakistan and our religion, minor children should stay with their mother.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Their expenses should be paid by their father and the father should be able to meet with the children.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When the child becomes of age, he or she can stay with whomever they will.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You rightly mentioned the actual problem is that of the relatives who mislead.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Possessiveness is present in all of our actions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Because of this, there will be new shareholders in the father's property born, and they will go against him. Otherwise his fathers action is commendable.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These restrictions have caused social evils, even in our marriages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The concept of the marriage of a divorced woman or a widow has become obscure.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is these wasteful ideologies and baseless traditions that have made the family structure a mess.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In our society, if the wife of a 50-55 year old man or the husband of such a wife passes away, why are they not looked at in a nice manner?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Near us, there is a Pakistani uncle, whose wife passed away 10-12 years ago. Now, after marrying off all his children, he has married a widow, so even his children have gone against him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I believe this is his legitimate right. What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="4">What type of mentality is the "'while we are there, no one can take our mother's place" kind of mentality?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I believe that this person's children should have thought what's wrong if he married a widow after he married off all his children?</seg>
     <seg id="2">This widow also got support and the uncle also got someone to look after the house.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As the children would get busy in their own worlds and would not be able to give time to him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The reason for this is ignorance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Tomorrow, if their wives refuse to look after them when they are old, what will they do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is a result of the force of society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When people begin to make fun of such a family for doing something like that, children start to feel ashamed of their father's second marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Though they should face the environment and say that their father's action is in perfect accordance with Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is the curse of our society we are facing for the last 40-50 years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A wife can accept her husband going around having illicit relations, but she can't stand him having a second wife.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If possible, stop him from doing so, even after you die.</seg>
     <seg id="4">She destroys her husband and her own hereafter, and becomes a cause for spreading filthiness in society.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Islam doesn't mean anything; In reality, we like only our culture and traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For instance keeping girls from gaining an education and the fear of marrying ones choice.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As for your question about the old man going to the widows house, instead of bringing the widow to his house so the children could make some fuss and then become quiet and relax, (though the stomach of the widows children would hurt).</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Indo Pak subcontinent, Islam was accepted centuries ago, but it could not yet leave its ignorant mentality and has always kept culture and tradition above Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Thinking of a man's second marriage as an innovation, divorce as a clinical rest, divorced woman as untouchable, love marriage as a mark on honor and a man marrying a woman elder to him as a deception on the part of the wife, is all a part of this mentality.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What's more, in mimicry of the western countries, we have started to consider piety and veil as old fashioned.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Accepting Islam is easy, but leaving this mentality is very tough.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Allah grant us all spirit and courage for this.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Writing Urdu was never so difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Centuries passed with such little writing.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Know that little is much.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Allah Hafiz</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Ameer Taimoor in his book "I am Taimoor" writes, "I found this secret in my life that if the leader of any army is in the front line then that army will never lose."</seg>
     <seg id="2">But that's not the situation here.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They say that common people are there to die for us and they die as martyrs.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But when the common man dies it's murder.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As Salaamu Alaikum wa Rahmatullahi wa Barakatuhu (greeting).</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today, I was returning to my shop after Isha prayers, when a man sitting in a car at the circle raised his hand and diverted my attention towards him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I thought this man might have lost his way, or he might want to ask something of me, so I stopped, and saw that his whole family was sitting in the car.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He asked whether I could understand Arabic well or not. I said, no problem, tell me what you want.</seg>
     <seg id="5">He started to say that, "I have come from Riyadh, to Madinah, but someone has pick-pocketed me, so please help me out." I asked him to excuse me, as such an incident had taken place with me previously; I had given someone 20 Riyals to buy petrol to reach Riyadh, but he went a little ahead and started to ask somebody else.</seg>
     <seg id="6">I got rather upset and began to berate him, and warned him that I would call the military, at which point he got very frightened.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Now the situation has become that we Muslims come in cars with our families to beg all day, and gain at least two or three thousand illegally.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Whereas there is a clear Hadith of the Prophet (SAWS) that says that the upper hand is better than the lower hand; the lower hand being the begging hand and the upper hand being the giving one.</seg>
     <seg id="9">May Allah have mercy on us and make us true Muslims. (Amen, Amen.)</seg>
     <seg id="10">Was Salam</seg>
     <seg id="11">Jawed Iqbal</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The wife of the famous singer, Adnan Sami, went to a police station in Mumbai. She accused him of torturing her.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The police station advised her to contact a court.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Adnan Sami's wife Saba Giladari gave a complaint against her husband saying that he continuously tortured her.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He treats her in a non-human manner.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now it has become difficult for her to bear. This is why she has filed a case against him.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The police, instead of filing a case, told her to contact a court. They said that this matter was not one in which the police could control.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In your opinion, is the accusation of the wife of Adnan Sami proper?</seg>
     <seg id="8">This is not an Indian effort to disgrace Adnan Sami, is it?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Let us know your opinion on this issue.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Adam, Sanghad, Mehr</seg>
     <seg id="2">As far as accusations go, one person can accuse the other.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To get enraged for the sake honor is not sensible. One must show constrain and think of non-violent means if Honor has been compromised.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Whatever be the case between Adnan Sami and his present wife, he had left his everyday life and went to India, hoping to earn more money and better provide for his family. Now that he has become famous.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The event the have unfolded are the results of his own actions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Washington...</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many nations' ambassadors to America say that President Obama will take a strong stand against Afghan President Hamid Karzai, pushing for him to address corruption in the Afghan government.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In America's new policy for Afghanistan, instead of development and re-building, the war effort has been given more importance.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The envoys say that Hamid Karzai is being considered a barrier in the achievement of the overall American goals in Afghanistan. Corruption in the government is out of control and unchecked. Corrupt government officials have become middlemen and the Taliban are once more gathering strength in many regions of the country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The American envoys say that officials in the American government are stressing upon Hamid Karzai to do something more concerning the corruption in his government. The main voices being heard are Vice President Joseph Biden and President Obama's representative to Afghanistan and Pakistan, Richard Hallbrooke.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that this good administration was noticed after the President Bush left, who used to have a video conference with Hamid Karzai after every 2 weeks and used to emphasize on the role of America in Afghanistan and the development of its city departments.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Officials say that the Obama administration will work with the state leaders as an extension of the main government.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Officials say that they plan to join Hamid Karzai in the fight against corruption.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Hamid Karzai faces new elections this year, and it is not clear as of yet whether Obama and his companions will favor his presidency or not.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Does this statement of American officials mean a change of relations between America and Afghanistan?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Is the reign of Hamid Karzai coming to an end?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What are your thoughts in this matter?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In a series of three one-day matches between Pakistan and Sri Lanka, Sri Lanka defeated Pakistan 2-1.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan defeated Sri Lanka in the first one-day match, although Sri Lanka won in the next two matches.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the third one-day match, the national team's performance was very poor. They won out in only 75 runs in 23 overs against the 309 runs made by Sri Lanka. The national team should have learned a lesson from this defeat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The result of the series proves that the National team has no consistency in its performance.</seg>
     <seg id="5">besides the home ground and all claims, the national team was defeated, what are the reasons of this in your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Which facets of the game should be addressed most by the authorities?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are you satisfied with the selections for the team?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Which department would you hold responsible for the defeat- the fielding, batting or bowling department?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Please provide your feedback.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Babar Hussain, Judah, it is very disappointing that even today these kinds of heathenish traditions continue to occur. These feudal lords target innocent people using their authority, who would call them Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="2">A Sardar, himself should walk over these embers. Why doesn't the present government act against them?</seg>
     <seg id="3">When will the judicial justice be of use?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370243-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Shrilanken cricket team has arrived Karachi to play One Day internationals.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Despite tensions between India and Pakistan, it is good to see a foreign team visiting Pakistan once again.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On their arrival at Karachi airport, the Sri Lankan team was given a warm welcome.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There will be two one-day matches in Karachi between Pakistan and Sri Lanka and one in Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Both sides have made strong claims regarding their bowling, batting and fielding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">While the Sri Lankans are proud of their spinners, Pakistan has its fast bowlers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The Sri Lankan captain, Mahela Jayawardene, has said that no one player of the Pakistan team can be singled out as a threat, because the whole team is dangerous.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Muralitharan and Mendis are said to be trump cards, and the Pakistani captain has said the competition will be tough.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Shoaib Malik said they've already played Muralitharan and now they'll get to face Mendis as well. He added that they have a secret game plan which they'll reveal on the pitch.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Will the contest be as exciting as the Pakistanis and Sri Lankans predict?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Who will gain the upper hand when the series between Pakistan and Sri Lanka actually gets underway?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Who will win the series?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Who will be the man of the series?</seg>
     <seg id="14">Give your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Gulpham, London, publishes his own views and you also prefer these views. I wish you would also write some truth, and not change your words like Mukherjee, because the order is to speak the truth in front of a tyrant king, and this is equivalent to Jihad. What should be said of Mukherjee, he tries to change his statements and stay in the news.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Yusuf, Dubai.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Kashmiri people have been fighting for independence for the last 60 years.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, no one asked, and they are now stuck in their war of extremism and terrorism, so they start talking about making up.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First they openly killed the Muslims, now they are trying to set things right.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Anyway, Pakistan will have to understand their double edged policies.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Asad Khan, London.</seg>
     <seg id="2">India is creating a situation so that the world's attention can be diverted from Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Pakistan has always shown the real face of India to the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now the British Government is also understanding that the Indians are taking cover from their corrpution over Kashmir by blaming Pakistan of terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They hesitate to talk to Pakistan over this issue.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">British foreign minister David Milliband has said that by resolving the issue of Kashmir it will bring an end to extremism, and the government of Pakistan will effectively handle the threats rising on the borders.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It should be clear that the newly elected American president Obama has also expressed similar views over the Kashmir dispute.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The British foreign minister talked to the media in Mumbai and has written an article about the idea of the war against terror is wrong; killing people just for the threats to one self was the policy of president Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="4">David Milliband has said that Pakistan shouldn't be lenient with the extremist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Due to the stress over the need for resolution of the Kashmir dispute from the major powers, India is trying to divert the attention from this issue by creating unrest in the region.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Isn't the terrorism in Mumbai a part of this strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is India using terrorism as a base to escape from comprehensive dialog?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Let us know of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Usman Aftab,</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think the big powers do not want to harm Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rather it wants to keep it in check, and hence is thinking of taking certain steps. They know that Pakistan is a nuclear state.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They want to bring about some kind of revolution here.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Foreign countries are only thinking that if they corner Pakistan, they would face some political and geographic problems. They want to help Pakistan, but also want to be successful in their goal.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A citizen, USA.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It has always been a Hindu tradition, that in the side is a knife, and on the mouth is Ram.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I think that they get stomach aches over small issues and begin to warn Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are ready. The Indian Army chief should keep his mouth shut.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">F.M. siddique</seg>
     <seg id="2">Political statements are coming under the mischievous support of America. America is crazy and now Indians are following the same pattern. If India has the courage to attack, it should to know the reality.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel is attacking Hamas and no one has the courage to stop Israel. Following Israel, Indian also wants to have some adventure.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Prime Minister said that Biden played a great role in shedding Musharraf's uniform and restoring the democracy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">No political party can get the credit of uniform shedding and the restoration of democracy. Parliament is not a rubber stamp.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All decisions will be made in Parliament.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Prime Minister said that Dr. Qadir's chapter had closed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">If public protest against dictatorship has no significance to you?.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If lawyers movement did not play any role?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Where are you going to do the Prime Minister's statement</seg>
     <seg id="8">Please give us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American President George W Bush, in his last Press conference, advised newly elected President Barack Obama that he made many mistakes in his tenure, and Barack Obama should do what he thinks is right.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I, the President, and according with the constitution of USA and law i did the developments, put forward American interest on my own popularity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">He said that America's enemies are still planning to attack America, and the biggest challenge for Barack Obama is to prevent these attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">he said, being unable to find the weapons of mass destruction in Iraq was his biggest dissapointment and announced the mission completed in Iraq was his big mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In last press conference from white house American president has said that this is my last press conference i thank u all news reporter and my colleague who attended this conference</seg>
     <seg id="6">do you think Obama will not do that mistake which bush did?</seg>
     <seg id="7">don't you think bush was late in accepting his mistakes?</seg>
     <seg id="8">will Obama be able to follow the advice of Bush?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Give us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American Vice President Dick Cheney said, "I want to see Osama Bin Laden alive or dead."</seg>
     <seg id="2">He said that Osama Bin Laden is hiding in some hard to reach area and is of no use to his organization, and if Osama Bin Laden is arrested alive or dead then his organization must be destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">America intends to arrest Osama and the search for Osama is on.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Will Dick Cheney's goal to arrest Osama be accomplished?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Give us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the completion of Quaid Azam Trophy match between PIA and Habib Bank, the all-rounder cricketer Shahid Affridi had a altercation with one fan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">When Shahid Affridi came out of the drawing room after playing the match on the UBL ground, a large number of fans gathered around him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In one instance, a fan held his hand and asked to take a photo with him, after which Shahid Affridi removed his hand from the fan's and said that he can take the photo tomorrow. After further insistence from the fan, Affridi became angry and slapped him. An altercation then began between Affridi and the fan, though the crowd seemed to dismiss the matter there.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Shahid Affridi later said that he had been in a hurry to attend the prayer.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Any way, I beg pardon for this drama.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you say about Shahid Afridi's actions?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Let us know about your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Manmohan Singh once again accused Pakistan of creating a war-like atmosphere.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan is using terrorism as a policy of state.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Speaking to a meeting of the cabinet of ministers, Manmohan Singh said that terrorist factions are being supported by neighboring countries, especially Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And that the terrorists who attacked Mumbai used the sea way and remained safe from the coastal guard.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian Prime Minister said that the Mumbai attacks of November were carried out by Lashkar-e-Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that the terrorists were using new techniques and modern communication systems. We will have to step up the forces at the line of control as well, from where there is infiltration. He said that terrorism will not be accepted in any form, and this is our policy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you think about this accusation of the Indian Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Do the internally opposed and separatist movements of India show the disturbed situation n India?</seg>
     <seg id="9">On whose orders is India taking this warning stance?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Give us your views.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Zubair Khan, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is a sad calamity that Israeli is massacring the Palestinians and the same situation is prevalent in Kashmir, but there is no effect on the Security Council.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the organisations present in Palestine and Kashmir should keep their war going until they gain independence, and they should form unity among themselves and keep facing any type of harm, and one day or the other their martyrdom will give fruit, God Willing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The air attacks by Israel on Gaza are continuing, just the same. By now, hundreds of Palestinian men, women and children have been martyred.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Important Hamas leader Nazariyan was killed along with his wife and children.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Here the Security Council meeting concluded without any decision.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The meeting saw American opposition to the derogatory resolutions passed against Israel by Libya and other Arab countries.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Israel's jet planes have been bombarding the residential areas of Palestine for last many days.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Every country around the world began to protest against the Mumbai attacks but can't anyone see this brutality including America and Britain?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Why are the major Muslim countries quiet?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What is your opinion on these double standards of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Saeed, New York.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In my opinion, the basic fact is that most of our people are uneducated and they don't even know where their money is actually going. Government is interested in doing its job properly by applying and collecting taxes. Shortfalls of electricity and gas will continue in the same manner.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because everyone knows about the character of those who have been elected by our own nation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Shortages of electricity and gas all over Pakistan has become a critical state.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand the gas tariff has been raised to 8% whereas in some cities, due to the non-availability of petrol, the difficulties and miseries of the masses are increasing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Due to the long load shedding of electricity and gas crisis in Pakistan's industrial and business sector, there is a severe reaction. Riots and violent protests are taking place.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Industry leaders gave an ultimatum to stop the mills.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Here, there is still an outlandish situation in the cities: for example, there are blackouts in Karachi from 8 to 10 hours.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The industrial became aproximatly hand less and feet less.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Government leaders are pointing fingers at each other, blaming one another instead of fixing the problems.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Talks with other nation have increase the prices of electric and gas in not a jok.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Why didn't they pay attention and try to solve these problems?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The government is not working to improve the situation.</seg>
     <seg id="11">What are your suggestions to fix these problems?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Please give me your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the loss of Imram, that as there are people as there are commonders.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I wonder if those who shout slogans for an administration of the public create a nuisance to the public.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is torture not to get jelly, petroleum and gas.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Government departments have lost control.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Law and order has been degenerated. May Allah show his mercy  on this country of ours.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A new year has begun.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Last year was a year of political turmoil and chaos. The year will be remembered for terrorism too.</seg>
     <seg id="3">President Musharaf's stepping down from power, the end of President Bush's eight years' reign, the slinging of chappals to Bush, the rethroning of democracy in Pakistan,the unexpected disasters, the earthquake in Baloochistan, the financial melt down all over the world,the depression in the market.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The new year has set in. How do you feel now at the new year's arrival?</seg>
     <seg id="5">In your opinion, What colour will the political and geographical situations in the country take? What tricks will Obama adopt?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is it possible to predict an end to the threatening terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Will the judicial crisis in Pakistan come to an end?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What turn will the Indo-Pak relations take?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is there any chance of a surgical strike or a full-fledged war?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What are your expectations for the new year?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Share your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370256-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Today is the first anniversary of the death of Benazir Bhutto. She was slain after an election rally in Liaqat Bagh, Rawalpindi on 27th December 2007.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir is not among us today. She was a thoughtful politician and a world reknowned figure. She held a special status in national politics.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Although it's been a year now, the enigma of her death remains unsolved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Her efforts to bring democracy to Pakistan were not in vain.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Today, a democratic government exists in Pakistan, and her husband Asif Zardari currently holds the position of Pakistan's President.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you think if the role of martyr Benazir Bhutto is in Pakistani politics?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Who can be her behind murdering?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Recently,, she was given the global human rights award. What would you like to say about her democratic and political services?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After ruling over America for eight years, President Bush left the White House, for presidential camp office, Camp David, so that the White House can be decorated and prepared for new President Barack Obama, according to his wishes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In Bush's eight year presidency, the historic World Trade Center attack, the attack on the Pentagon, the action against Afghanistan and Iraq in the name of a global war against terrorism, in which armies of many countries were pulled into the war, and American resources were completely exhausted, were some of the memorable events of the Bush era.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As a result of this war, America had to face the worst economic and financial crisis in history.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What do you think the world got and what do you think it lost as a result of this war?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Were the policies of President Bush successful?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What are your views of the Bush era?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian government has stopped the Indian cricket team from touring Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Indian Cricket Team had to play three tests, five one day matches, and one twenty on the Pakistan Tour.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Vice-President of the Indian Cricket Board, Rajeev Shukla, who spoke to the news said that the board has asked the government to allow the Pakistan Tour but because of the serious matters between the two countries this tour is not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Is it right to use available political issues of the Indian government as the passport to cancel the cricket tour? Shouldn't the games be kept away from politics?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Isn't the decision of the Indian government towards cricket a loss?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Even though the security in India was poor, the English Cricket Team tour was going on, so why doesn't the Indian team do the Pakistan Tour?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion in this regard?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salman, Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="2">People who feel proud on going to India.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And their films and videos which are made there, now their eyes must be open to see how much the Indian people respect you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I remember one interview of Adnan Samee where he said I am not a Pakistani, my popularity is British.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan Sami needs to come to Pakistan at the first opportunity because respect was not accorded him even there.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fareed Ahmad</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="3">Indian attitudes have changed after the Mumbai attack.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jagjit reacted with hate toward Pakistan and Pakistani people.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan Sami sung seven songs of Asha Bhosla, now how can he be out of tune?  Adnan Sami should stay in India: no need to come here.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muhammad Shamshad Alam</seg>
     <seg id="2">I will only say this on the statement of Jagjit Singh in Karachi: he changes color like a chameleon.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who gives statements suitable to situation Pakistanis open your eyes that how much you are given worth in India, understand the thinking of Hindu.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the Mumbai incident, their hateful statements have increased and they are now spitting poison against popular singer Adnan Sami.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Without my permission at all, a dream takes place in my mind. I must have a house in a beautiful evergreen valley. There must be flowering trees on top of the hill.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Each morning at least one of the flowers that fall from the trees should reach the valley, where my small nest-like house situates.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The second thing was that about our future.</seg>
     <seg id="4">At night, while sleeping on the terrace, I am be able to view the whole star bloomed sky.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Seeing the melting mist in the valley, seeing the gold- bangled hands working in the tiled kitchen, watching my hard work blooming up in the compound.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Looking at the twinkling stars, feeling the softness of fondling fingers, inhaling the fragrance of night jasmine.</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion about this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">By wearing a mask repeatedly, you have lost your face. You have developed the art of having the brightness of truth even while uttering point blank lies.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I was always dominated by an uncontrollable thirst for affection.</seg>
     <seg id="3">When my problem is something concerned with money.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There are many problems faced by people in the world that are not under the control of human beings.</seg>
     <seg id="5">I feel the main cause is people not thinking clearly.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The consequence of not thinking clearly is having to face very dangerous problems that arise in the future.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Today itself start for the well beings of the people</seg>
     <seg id="8">What do people seriously think about that?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Poverty, financial crisis, and diseases are the main challenges that people going to face in the future.</seg>
     <seg id="10">What did the people think about the dangerous calamities that have affected many people?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Are you ready to start today?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We should firmly make a decision today about how to solve the problems. It is not going to be easy or without risk.  First of all we have to have a good mind and attitude towards our goal.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The world faced many calamities such as earthquakes, floods, and tsunamis.  However we have not learned yet to take precautionary measures beforehand. We only act after the calamities. Our scientists to find necessary steps to help us prepare before such devastation occurs.</seg>
     <seg id="3">From United Nation side made a 60 birthday on 10/December for Human Rights resolution.</seg>
     <seg id="4">At his oucation to accept work for human rights personalities and organization have been awarded in which Benazir Bhutto and also America ex-Attorney Cornall Lewis Rams Clark and international organization work for Human Rights Human Rights Watch included.</seg>
     <seg id="5">At that time UN Pakistani Diplomat, Abdullah Hussain Haroon and other Senior diplomats were also present.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you think about Ex-prime minster Benazir Bhuto Martyr   receiving this Award?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">September.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Chicago.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is true that she was martyred, but we also remember that she killed many innocent people in Karachi and that she was proud that Naiseer Ullah Baber had done a great job.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But than she totally changed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is it also true that he neglected senior members of his party and chose his son as a party leader? What kind of  Democracy is this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Jimmy Noor, Karachi, this news proved that the Quran said that Non-believers will support only Non-Believers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">An axe cant cut wood unless it has a wooden handle.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our leaders are responsible for the hardships and problems our country is in.</seg>
     <seg id="4">May God bless our leaders with righteousness.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The panel of the UN's Security Council has included the names of Hafaiz Saeed and three other Pakistanis in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The names of Hafiz Mohammad Saeed (the chief Jamat-ul-dawa), Rehman Lakhvi (Lashkar-i-taiba's Chief of Operations), and Haji Mohammad Ashraf (Lashar-i-taiba's Head of Finance) have been included in the list of terrorists. This list was approved by the Security Council's committee on Alqaida and Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Besides these, a Saudi citizen, Mehmood Ahmed, is also part of this list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jamat-ul-dawa, Passban-i-kashmir and Alrashid trusts are included in these organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The member countries will freeze the assets of these people and organizations. These persons will not be allowed to travel and they will be arrested if they do travel.</seg>
     <seg id="6">They have to face trials.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are these sanctions not made under the influence of Indian propaganda?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Why is India blaming these parties for the Bombay attacks without any proof?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Are there not any terrorist groups in India?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Are International groups not aware of the tortures being done to the minorities in India?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please inform us with your suggestions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Occasionally Eid represents happiness and joy, and monotheists sacrifice animals following the tradition of Ibrahim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During this turbulent time when inflation is at its peak, the political situation is not promising, even after the rich and poor prepare for Eid within their means and wish their relatives a happy Eid in different ways.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We are also providing you with a chance through this blog to wish your loved ones a happy Eid with short messages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You can also wish by writing verses with references to Eid</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Murtaza Jilani.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi, our leaders should understand that the people they are doing this operation against are the true valuers of Pakistan, who are tolerating all kinds of tortures because they love Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>

