<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="mturk">
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Supporting the French proposal</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The meeting of the committee took place in the Parliament under the chairmanship of Committee Chairman Mushahid Husain Syed. They proposed that the government to send a delegation, with representatives of all political parties, apart from humanitarian aid to Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="3">After the meeting, speaking to representatives of the press, Mushahid Husain Syed said that the committee welcomed the proposal given by France, in which Israel would call an immediate ceasefire and allow humanitarian work among the affected people of Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Calling the Israeli attacks on Palestine a crime against humanity, he said that all countries should derogate these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mushahid Husain made the double standards of the countries of the world a target of his attack, and asked, "Why are those who speak against terrorism quiet about the Israeli attacks on Palestine?"</seg>
    <seg id="6">The chairman of the standing committee of external affairs in the senate also targeted the leaders of Muslim nations who were taking a quiet stance on the matter of Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that the committee expressed hope that the newly elected American President, Barack Obama, would speak to the Muslim world within his first 100 days in office to bridge the gulf forming between America and the Muslim world.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mushahid Husain Syed said that the gap formed between the Muslim world and the West should be filled by taking not only sudden steps but also by solving longstanding issues like Kashmir and Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The minister of foreign affairs, Malik Imad, told the committee that he was going to Saudi Arabia to attend the meeting of the foreign ministers of the governments of Islamic countries.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This sudden meeting was called as a result of Israeli attacks on Palestine. He said that he was aware of the Palestinian matter and at present, the government was in contact with the premiers of other countries.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The Minister of State for Foreign Affairs has said that the issue of Palestine should be resolved in accordance with the resolutions of the United Nations.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Two journalists from Arab countries also joined the conference, and they told about the latest situation in Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In Islamabad, students of the International University protested against the Israeli attacks on Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="14">The protesters were holding banners and placards, of which had anti-Israel slogans written on them.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Abstention from dieting in order to avoid Flu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This research from the American Scientists has come up after the experiments on rats.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It has been proven by experiments that rats put on diets with fewer calories were more prone to the Flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Research has proven the old myth  of fasting during fever wrong.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to scientists, one should eat a lot during fever.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The researchers from Michigan State University say that the rats that were dieting were not as able to resist the infection, and their chances of dying had increased.  Whereas rats on normal diets had better resistance against the Flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to Professor Elizabeth Gardner, people who diet will not be affected with flu sooner but they will need more time to recover from it.</seg>
    <seg id="8">She also said that those people who receive the flu vaccine should also avoid dieting during the winter months.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'First nuclear experiment was done in 1990'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Thomas Reid, who has worked in the Lever National Laboratory in America as a weapon designer, has written this book with the help of the former director of technical intelligence at Los Alamos national laboratory, Dani Stillman.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This book was titled "Nuclear Express: Political History of the Bomb and Its Proliferation," and both writers have claimed that whichever country first made a nuclear bomb either stole the nuclear secrets of another country or had the support of another nuclear power.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In an interview with U.S. news agencies, Thomas Reid said that in 1990 during Benazir Bhutto's rule, China experimented with Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Thomas Reid said that for many reasons, he believes that China had experimented with Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The reasons include the design of the bomb and some information retrieved during talks with the Chinese scientists.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He further added that this was the reason that in 1998 in a span of only two weeks and three days, Pakistan was able to carry out nuclear experiments in response to Indian nuclear experiments.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Thomas Reid reminds us that in 1961 Russia suddenly carried out a nuclear experiment and besides possessing the bomb for a long time, it took 17 days for America to carry out nuclear experiments.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He said further that in May 1998, the atom bomb that Pakistan tested was made with care, and Pakistani scientists were completely trusted for it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">When Thomas Reed was asked if China supplied atomic technology to Pakistan, he replied that India is a mutual enemy of Pakistan and China.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said  evidence was also present that Dr. Abdul Qadir Khan had used the Chinese model. Later the Libyan documents confirmed this.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Another question was about mutual nuclear experiment. He replied that Anees Sonway openly performed a nuclear experiment in the desert of Nevada for Britain.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said Israel was predicted to have access to the results of this experiment.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Thomas Reeds was also asked if China was continuing nuclear proliferation.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On this Thomas Reeds said that China has been supplying raw material, instructions and the design to an Iranian nuclear facility in Asfahan.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Apart from this, China has also provided Iran with an enrichment plant in Kheeraj.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He said that China had been providing nuclear technology to Iran, Rome, Pakistan, Egypt, Libya and Yemen via North Korea.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">2008 the most successful year for Madonna.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The tour was organized around Madonna's album 'Hard Candy.' Tt also included a Ukrainian gypsy band and one or two Justin Timberlake songs.</seg>
    <seg id="3">An old racecar was also showed on the stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Celine Dion's tour in 2008 was the second best in terms of revenue, bringing in $236,000,000.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Canadian's tour, 'Taking Chances,' visited 24 countries whereas Madonna visited only 17 during her first tour in the last eight years.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The director of both tours was Jimmy King, who also organized the Spice Girls' tour, 'Reunion.'</seg>
    <seg id="7">Madonna broke her own record set in 2006.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In 2006, the 'Confession Concerts' tour made $193,000,000.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Polestar declared Bon Jovi's tour the third most successful with $17o,000,000.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bruce Springsteen finished fourth with $160,000,000, and The Police stood in fifth place with $126,000,000.</seg>
    <seg id="11">According to the magazine, in 2008 very few people in North America attended concerts and musical events except for those willing to buy expensive tickets.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In America the average cost of one ticket has risen eight percent, and on Madonna's show the most expensive ticket was sold for $350.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The Director of the Pollster newspaper, Gerry Bonguiny, said that the basis of the world economic share trades for the year 2008 has appeared good for the brokers.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They have celebrated for U2 and Springsteen in the year 2009 for their album being a hit.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Restriction on Co-education : Taliban</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Northern Wazeerastan's leader Meeran Shah and in another group posting the Taaliban had distributed pamphlets threatening the sub government and educational institutes where boys and girls are given co-education.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the pamphlet it said that if the co-education institutes were not closed by fifth of January then there will be steps taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In the pamphlet it said that the ladies identity cards will be restricted from the procedures of any government and educational departments and the ladies will be prohibited from going to any infrequent offices.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The territorial Taaliban had demanded the restriction of the ladies identity cards at the moment when many ladies had applied for the applications for the support of Benazeerankum program in the infrequent offices of Northern Wazeerastan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to the territory's people the pamphlets from the Taaliban had been read in the announcements in all the mosques of the Northern Wazeerastan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Therefore it wasn't mentioned in the letter that whether there is any restriction for the girls to study in separate educational institutes or not.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the pamphlet, after this announcement, if a woman gets caught when out to get education or get her ID made, she and her family will be punished under law.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Besides this, in the area of Bannu, the police says that a tunnel was blasted by gunpowder on Sunday on Bannu Mir Insha Road, killing one pedestrian and injuring another.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The injured was admitted to Bannu civil hospital.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Target Killing: More dead bodies found.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police, on Sunday morning, two decapitated bodies were found in the areas of the main Mangora, Green square and Sohrab khan square.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The deceased were said to be related to Frontier core and the police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">An eyewitness said that a letter was also found near the bodies in which there was a threat that whoever picks up these bodies before 11 in the morning is responsible for his own death.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Locals say that the bodies were lying in the market until 11:00 A.M., but later security officials picked up both bodies and transferred them to the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="6">There has been a dangerous rise in the numbers of target killing during the last few weeks in the city of Mangora and surrounding areas.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Local citizens including women and security officials are being killed</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to local sources, more than thirty people have been killed to date by these kind of incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="9">so far, no organization have taken responsibility for these killings.</seg>
    <seg id="10">the spokesman of the local Taliban in Swat Muslim Khan told us this Saturday that the dead bodies found last Friday included those of his fellows. It also included the dead body of the Taliban commander, Deolai Rafiullah</seg>
    <seg id="11">Muslim Khan said that Rafiullah was under custody of the security forces for one and half month.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He had said that the local Taliban sent notices before killing anybody.     On the other hand, the citizens of Mengora are worried about these incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="13">according to the local people, a large number of security forces have been deployed in Mengora,  but despite all these, attacks on the citizens are still increasing.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A Tribute to Benazir from Bakhtawar.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A rap song (a modern style of music) in Bakhtawar's voice is posted on youtube.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is 5 minutes long song contains pictures and video- clips of Benazir.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Eighteen years old Bakhtawar is a student at the Edinburgh University.</seg>
    <seg id="5">She has a deep affection for poetry and singing.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is said that she started singing pleasurable rhymes upon the encouragement from her mother.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Praising her mother, she said "She was intelligent and beautiful; she used to do everything in a certain way."</seg>
    <seg id="8">Regarding the December 27th incident, she said that she was hit near the cheek by a bullet. She left us at the age of 54, leaving behind three children.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The whole nation is desperate without her; she is present in all of their hearts.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bukhtawar is Benazir Bhutto's second child; Bilawal Butto is the first child.</seg>
    <seg id="11">She was always interested in music.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It is said that before returning to her mother's country, she had asked her journalist friend in America to introduce her to Grammy award winning producer and rapper, Puff Diddy; however, this meeting did not take place.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The translation of some of Bukhtawar's poetry has been published in some Sindhi newspapers; however, her voice is heard for the first time in a YouTube video.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Some of Benazir Bhutto's party workers and admirers have started making cd's of Bukhtawar's rap song.</seg>
    <seg id="15">on the other hand, the spokesman of Pakistan Peoples Party, Farhatullah Babar has confirmed that the poetry and voice in the song on Youtube is of Bakhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="16">he was told over the phone from Islamabad that the song was a tribute by a saddened daughter to her brave mother, and it was also being telecast by the government TV network as well.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar has said that his party has not decided yet to distribute the CD's of the song by Bakhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="18">He said that few years back a fake account of his young Chairman Bilawal Bhutto Zardari was made on Facebook which was closed later on.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ajmal Qasab is the Pakistani : Information Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Federal Minister for Information and broadcasting Sherry Rehman while confirming, through and SMS sent to BBC, the citizenship of Ajmal Qasab just added that further investigation is being carried out.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Before this the Advisor to Prime Minister for Interior Rehman Malik had denied his Pakistani citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He had said that there was no record for Malik in the record keeping institute, NADRA.</seg>
    <seg id="5">there is no information on this latest statement that on what basis the Government has changed its stance on Ajmal Qasab's citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, according to the foreign office spokesman, Ajmal Qasab's citizenship has been confirmed by the interior ministry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Earlier BBC Urdu service and some other newspapers and TV channels have told that Ajmal Qassab belongs to Farid Kot town of the Okara District in Province Punjab.</seg>
    <seg id="8">However, the government had been denying it.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It has not yet been established that this Ajmal Qassab does belong to Farid Kot or some other place.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Rockets fired from Lebanon</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Israeli Army and Police official have told media correspondents that 4 rockets were fired on the Israeli territory from Lebanon out of which one fell in the Neharia town of northern Israel which injured two people slightly.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In answer to the rockets fired from the Lebanese territory, the Israeli artillery has bombed Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It is not clear that this attack was carried out by Hizbullah or if the Palestinian groups active in Lebanon are behind it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Lebanese government says that it is also trying to figure out who is behind these rocket attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">BBC correspondents have declared that this as a very dangerous turn in the reigning situation in the region.</seg>
    <seg id="7">BBC's editor for Middle East Geremy Bowin has said that due to these rocket attacks is the danger of the war spreading out has increased.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Over the past few days, it has been feared that the military operation in Gaza may extend further north along the Lebanon- Israel border.</seg>
    <seg id="9">On Wednesday night, the Israeli Air Force conducted sixty air raids on the Gaza Strip.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the Israeli Army, these attacks targeted the offices, underground tunnels, weapons caches, rocket launching sites, and armed personnel of the Hamas Police Force.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Apart from the air raids, the artillery of the Israel Army and Navy continued shelling Gaza throughout the night.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The Palestinian Authorities said that a mosque was destroyed during the air raids on the Gaza city.</seg>
    <seg id="13">According to unconfirmed reports, tanks from the Israeli Army, aided by the helicopters in the air, have advanced towards the area of Khan Younus.</seg>
    <seg id="14">During this twelve-day conflict, approximately seven hundred Palestinians, including many women and children, have died.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other side, only twelve soldiers from the Israeli Army have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Israeli Security Forces have confirmed that a high-ranking defense official, Amos Gillad, is going to Cairo to settle the terms of a ceasefire.</seg>
    <seg id="17">A delegation from Hamas is also going to Cairo to conduct parallel talks with the Egyptian diplomats.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Additionally, the leader of the Palestinian Authority, Mehmood Abbas, is also reaching Cairo on Friday.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">My heart is broken, return my kidney.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Richard Batista says that eight years ago he gave his wife Dawnell his kidney to save her life.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the AFP news agency, Dr. Batista's claims his wife repaid his gift by cheating on him, and now she wants a divorce.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In an interview with a local newspaper, The Daily News, Dr. Batista stated that his wife's affair has put a hole in his heart.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Dr. Richard Batista's lawyer, though the doctor has demanded his kidney back,he actually wants monetary compensation for the kidney.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Dr. Batista will give take the stand in front of a judge within the next few days.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">140 year old, 9 kilogram lobster free</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">'George the Giant Lobster' was captured two weeks ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The city's seafood company purchased it for a hundred dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He instantly started using the lobster photos for his publicity.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"PETA", a group working for animal rights, demanded the release of the lobster. As a result, it will be released back into the sea.</seg>
    <seg id="6">George was caught in the sea in Canada. He then spent 10 days in the City Crab and Seafood Company tank.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The age of a lobster can be told by its weight.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The restaurant's manager, Keith Walanty, stated that their purpose was not to hurt the lobster at all. The reason to keep him in the tank was to provide entertainment for the customers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Engrid Newkurk from the animal rights group PETA states that the restaurant's decision is worth praise and is an example for those who want to keep these precious animals in a tank or want to eat them by boiling them alive.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Search for missing girl ends with the help of a cell phone.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When the officials heard that Natalie Maltais was missing, the police and firefighting forces of the city of Acton, Massachusetts came into action.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Officials discovered the location of the girl using the GPS on her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="4">With the help of Google Street View, it was determined that the girl was in a motel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">As of week ago Natalie's grandmother Rose Maltois took Natalie from her legal parents' custody.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Ethol's police chief Timothy Anderson told BBC that she said she would never give Natalie back and then she left the state.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Police contacted Miss Maltois, but when as she had promised she did not send Natalie back, the Police decided to search for Natalie through her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Since 2005 there is a regulation in America that the cellular companies will provide location for 67 percent of people in a range of 100 meters and 95 percent callers in a range of 300 meters.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on a visit to India.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This is Hamid Karzai's second Indian tour in last five months.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is expected that during his meeting with Prime minister Manmohan Singh, he will discuss after effects of the terrorist attacks in Mumbai.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this visit he wants to express the feeling of his people and solidarity with India over the Mumbai terrorists attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">During Karzai's visit, besides extremism he will discuss bilateral trade also.</seg>
    <seg id="6">A discussion on the bilateral cooperation to counter extremism between both countries is also expected.</seg>
    <seg id="7">During his last visit to India, president Hamid Karzai said that terrorism will not be interfere with the relations between India and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He also said that both India and Afghanistan are facing challenges of terrorism and merciless killings.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Peace and stability in both countries would be very beneficial for the whole world.</seg>
    <seg id="10">We understand the reality that both countries, and the whole world can only join hands to face this curse of terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="11"></seg>
    <seg id="12"></seg>
    <seg id="13"></seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2"></seg>
    <seg id="3"></seg>
    <seg id="4">Ajmal Qasab is now in police custody, and it is hoped that the police will file charges against him before January 24th.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ajmal Qasab does not have a lawyer to defend him.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In a letter written to the Pakistani government, Qasab asked for legal aid.</seg>
    <seg id="7">India has given Pakistan proof of the involvement of Pakistani extremists in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Pakistan has accepted that Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani civilian.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the police file, Ajmal Qasab and his partner Abu Ismail killed 6 police officers including ATS chief Hemant Karkare, Additional Police Commissioner Ashok Kamte and Encounter Specialist Police Inspector Vijay Salaskar, after which they fled with their squad car, which was later recovered near DB Marg, Gurgam Choupati.</seg>
    <seg id="10">During police action, Ismail Khan died and the police captured Ajmal alive.</seg>
    <seg id="11">No lawyer has been appointed yet, to follow Ajmal's case.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The lawyer chosen by the government, from the legal aid cell, Dinesh Mota, refused to accept the case on moral reasons.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Two other lawyers pulled out their names after protests and opposition by a political group.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Constitutional Amendment Committee to be Formed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After addressing a seminar on environment change, he told media representatives that for his sake, the parliamentary meeting will take place in which a committee will be formed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that until now, to complete the 17th amendment, the constitutional amendment bill had to be presented by the Joint National Movement to the National Assembly, where other political parties have also presented their constitutional bills to the parliament.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the Pakistan Peoples Party has also sent all the political parties a rough version of the 17th amendment and the committee would analyze their version.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In answer to a question, he said that the parliament would decide the balance of power between the President and the Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Prime Minister said that the Parliament has the complete right to make any decision.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In answer to another question, he said that aside from getting former President retired General Pervez Musharraf to leave his post, the former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Pakistan Peoples Party, Benazir Bhutto also played an important role, by forcing the global brotherhood to remove the uniform of President Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that the elected Vice President of America, Joe Biden was a supporter of Pakistan and democracy, and that the president honored him in return for his services with the Pakistani Crescent.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Replying to a question about the Indian governments warning of breaking all ties with Pakistan after the Mumbai incident, the Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Geelani said that the leaders are under extreme pressure from the public, which is why they issue such statements.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Protest Against the Removal of Journalists</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Tuesday the organization of journalists RIUJ held protests in front of the Islamabad Press Club against media owners and the government about the news channel and newspapers removing many of their employees.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking to the protesters, senior member of Pakistan's biggest journalist organization, Federal Union of Journalists, C.R. Shamsi said that the politicians used to protest with us until yesterday on the streets, today they have become rulers and are sitting in the parliament. Fearing a certain lobby of the media owners, they are not doing anything for the rights of the journalists.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the newspaper owners who speak of human rights have made their offices punishment houses and beggar camps, where despite earning millions of rupees per year, the workers are given meager wages and by removing hundreds of them, they are killing them economically.</seg>
    <seg id="5">An example of this is in front of us of the worker of a private TV channel, Channel 5, in Lahore, who committed suicide over not getting his salary for four months. And even today, due to being unfairly removed or not getting salaries for months, many workers are leading very difficult lives.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that there should be firm steps taken against the TV and newspaper owners, and the journalists should put a protest camp in front of the parliament to get their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="7">C.R. Shamsi criticized the governor of Punjab, Salman Taseer, saying that employees were removed from his Urdu Newspaper "Aaj Kal" staff without prior notice.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wheras Junah daily, Khabrein daily, Channel 5, Burns Plus TV and Aaj TV have removed dozens of workers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Speaking to the protestors, the General Secretary of PUFJ said that today, throughout the country, journalist organizations are observing a black day against the removal of journalists and newspaper workers, whereas journalists will go to the parliamentary session wearing black bands on their arms to get back their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Mazhar Abbas, in 50% of the Pakistani newspapers and TV channels the workers and journalists were being exploited, where they work without any agreement.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that until now, more than 200 journalists and workers have been removed from newspapers and TV channels, while it is being feared that the owners will remove hundreds more in the present year, making an excuse of the present financial crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas said that the journalist movement will continue until removed employees are reinstated, newspaper wages fixed by the Seventh Wage board award are enforced, and the salaries owed by TV channels and newspaper workers is paid.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Eleven member cabinet takes oath.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The new cabinet includes six ministers from the opposition party of former Prime Minister, Sardar Atheeq Ahmed, the Muslim Conference. Two members are from the Pakistan Peoples Party, two are from the Peoples Muslim League and one minister is from the Joint National Movement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The eleven cabinet members include one lady minister, who belongs to the Ateeq opposition Muslim Conference party.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The joint ruler said that the cabinet will be expanded next week, and it is possible that 12 more ministers will be brought into the cabinet. It should be clear that in the beginning of this month, Sardar Ateeq Khan's oppoisition removed him from the post of Prime Minister by showing lack of trust, and they made Sardar Ya'qoob Khan the new Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The jurisdiction of these ministers will be announced later on.</seg>
    <seg id="6">As their oaths were taken, members of the Peoples Party shouted slogans in favor of former Pakistani Prime Minister, Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">3.5 million users affected by virus</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A virus first detected in October 2008 is known by many names: Configure, Down and Up and Kido.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Microsoft has come out with a patch to deal with this virus, but still some 3.5 million computers and memory sticks were affected by the virus.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Experts say that the number of affected computers may be considerably greater.</seg>
    <seg id="5">To deal with this, users should use Microsoft's MS08067 patch.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Microsoft, this virus, which infected millions of computers, locates the "services.exe" file in Windows and then inserts itself into its code.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After that, the virus turns into a DLL file in the Windows System folder.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It also renames this file,</seg>
    <seg id="9">then changes settings in the Windows registry.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After activation, this virus creates a program which connects to an http server and changes the system restore point.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It then downloads files from the maker's website.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to Microsoft, this virus has infected computers all over the world.</seg>
    <seg id="13">These countries include China, Brazil, Russia, India, the United States and Great Britain.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'The Demand for a Quick Report on Indian Information'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In an interview with representatives of the media, after a meeting of the Home Ministry, he said that the information given by India</seg>
    <seg id="3">will help with an investigation in these regards.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that Pakistan was a sovereign nation and that when it came to the investigation of the information received from India, no country's</seg>
    <seg id="5">dictation would be accepted.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that apart from the information received from India, they were gathering other information as well.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The internal advisor said that the executive institutions have taken 124 members of practically non-existent groups into custody, solely out of fear of disturbances in the peace.</seg>
    <seg id="8">If any evidence is found against them, action will be taken against them, while innocent people will be freed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In an answer to a question, he said that no arrested person would be handed over to India, and that action would be taken against such individuals according to Pakistani law.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that action would be taken against these individuals according to the law of the FIA.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Answering one of the questions, he said that Indian law enforcing departments have collected information regarding the people involved in the Bombay incident in 42 days. Therefore, he is hopeful that India along with the International clan will give Pakistan some time to do its research on these findings.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He reiterated that the government has offered a separate interrogating team will be formed for the investigation of Bombay incident.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Be clear that a three member interrogating team has been formed under the supervision of additional director general FIA, which will investigate the information given to Pakistan from India regarding the Bombay attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="14"></seg>
    <seg id="15">Pakistan's High commissioner Shahid Malik met President Asif Ali Zardari in India, in which the president made it clear that if any Pakistani was found involved in Bombay attacks, action will be taken against him according to the country's law and no one will be handed over to India. Although Indian government is continuously pressurizing Pakistan to hand over anyone involved in this matter to India.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">""Anything is possible in America""</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mr. Obama will take the oath on 20th January as the 44th President of America.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Standing on the stairs of the building built in the memory of the 16th American president, Abraham Lincoln, addressing a music concert</seg>
    <seg id="4">Mr. Obama said that America faces hard challenges of its many generations and he is hopeful that America will take control of these problems.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Abraham Lincoln ended the culture of slavery in America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But at the same time Mr. Obama said that it will take time to solve problems that are facing the country and it is a tough road.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Nevertheless, I am hopeful that the dream of the founders of this country will live.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America, besides the wars of Iraq and Afghanistan, is fighting a great economic downfall.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Unusual steps are being taken for the ceremony of the oath taking.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Management thinks that 2 million people will attend this ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="11">America has a public holiday on Monday as on this same day the great leader of human rights Martin Luther King was assassinated.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Martin Luther King was black.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A tribute to Martin Luther King, The decision of doing work.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Martin Luther King was murdered in 1968.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barrack Obama paid tribute to Dr. Martin Luther King and told Americans to work together to fulfill the promises of this nation.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Here in Washington preparations are being made for an unprecedented gathering of the public for the oath taking ceremony by the new president on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is believed that near 2 million people will gather in Washington to watch the historic oath of presidency by Barack Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama started Monday by visiting a medical center in North Washington, where he met with injured American soldiers. After this, he visited a home for the homeless, and painted a wall.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Speaking to journalists, Barack Obama said: ""After the present crisis which we are facing, and the difficulties that many people are undergoing, we cannot sit quietly"".</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that Martin Luther King spent most of his life working for the people.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Barack Obama said, "Today, we are remembering and respecting him, so it is not a day for us to stop and think. It is a day for us to act".</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that the ceremony on Tuesday would be on the same path as that of Martin Luther King's 1963 'I have a Dream' speech.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In this speech, Martin Luther King said that the day will come when people would not be preferentially treated based on their color.</seg>
    <seg id="12">BBC's Mathew Price said that you can call it the patching up of history, that Martin Luther King Day came twenty four hours before the first black president in American history would take the oath of office.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In many of the southern states of America, Barack Obama's presidency is the interpretation of Dr. Martin Luther King's dream.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Where was the additional political agent?</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The additional political agent was kidnapped ten days ago from South Waziristan by unidentified masked men.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Sources say that the agent was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer faction of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the local government, around 4 o'clock in the evening, Tuesday, the Additional Political Agent of South Waziristan, Aamir Latheef was brought to Wana Scouts camp, by a group of tribals.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, they did not reveal who had kidnapped the additional political agent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The locals however, are saying that the political agent was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer faction of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Aamir Latheef was kidnapped while he was going from Wana to Tank.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On the 11th of January in 2009, seven masked men kidnapped the additional political agent, Aamir Latheef, along with his driver, from the tribal area Karkandah of South Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the government agent, the kidnappers first disarmed the guards and after that they seated the additional political agent in another car and took him away from there.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the local government, after the kidnapping of the additional political agent, security forces guarded all the check posts in South Waziristan and semi-tribal areas, and the people coming and going were searched thoroughly, and from the previous one week, the rulers have placed economic restrictions on Wana.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On December 8, 2008, an assistant political agent of north Wazirastan Asmatullah was kidnapped when he was going from Mir Ali to Bannu to enjoy his Eid vacation. A few days after this two people, including Tehsildar Amanullah, were killed by unknown masked perpetrators in north Wazirastan.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Victory of a British hacker in the court.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A 42-year-old British citizen has admitted that he hacked an American military website.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gary has Asperger's syndrome. It should be kept in mind that an Asperger's patient has the obsession to do similar kinds of tasks.</seg>
    <seg id="4">His lawyers say that if he is handed over to America then he will commit suicide.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, government officials say that they are no threat to Gary's health.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Lord justice Morskey and Mr. Justice Simon while announcing the decision said that Gary is permitted to file a review petition in a British court.</seg>
    <seg id="7"></seg>
    <seg id="8">He added that the secretary of interior has noticed this issue.</seg>
    <seg id="9">But the government prosecutors say that the secretary of interior had used his authority.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Gary has never denied hacking the American military website.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In 2001 and 2002, Gary hacked an American computer system which caused a loss to the American government of eight hundred thousand dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Gary hacked 97 computers including those of the American Navy and NASA.</seg>
    <seg id="13">However, Gary says that he did not do this with bad intentions, as he was just looking for information about aliens, which he thought the American government had kept secret.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Gary's mother, Janice Sharp, has said that she is happy with this decision.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Gary's lawyer has said that it is the right decision.</seg>
    <seg id="16">This case has continued since 2002, and finally a correct decision has been made.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Kashmir: Two Hizb Commanders killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Colonel Acharya, spokesman of the northern command of the Indian Army deployed in Jammu, told BBC, based on reliable information, that troops from twenty-four Rashtria rifles and Jammu Kashmir police besieged the place in Batihaas jungle within Tehsil Gandwa of the Doda district, where the armed extremists were hiding.</seg>
    <seg id="3">They fired at the army, and in retaliation, two extremists were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Correspondents say that among the two terrorists killed, one was also Zahoorudding, the district commander of the banned group Hizb-ul-Mujahideen. Hizb-ul-Mujahideen has been active for the last 12 years in the area.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The other with him is identified as Sajjad Hussain, who, according to the army , became associated with the extremists last year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Acharia, the operation is still going on in the mentioned area of the jungle. According to them, there is a possibility of presence of more extremists there. Army said two Kalashnikov were found during the first step of the operation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Yesterday, the head of the province police, Kuldeep Kumar Khudda,has declared this year the most peaceful year until now.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that in November and December during 7 stages of assembly elections, no torture was done.</seg>
    <seg id="9">More than 1350 candidates participated in these elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It is clear that Hizb-ul-Mujahideen has been active in Jammu Kashmir for the last eight years.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Hizb-ul-Mujahideen declared one sided cease fire in July 2000 for the first time after which Indian government and Hizb commandos had a talk.</seg>
    <seg id="12">But the cease fire was over in only 15 days.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Later many senior commandos of Hizb-ul-Mujahideen were killed in different operations.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On Thursday the Pakistan's famous daily "The News" has said, regarding the extremist groups existing in the Pakistani administered Kashmir that, Lashkare Taiba and Hizbul Mujahidin have decided to review the Kashmir policy.</seg>
    <seg id="15">It should be clear that both the organizations had a policy that the Kashmir dispute should be resolved through an armed resistance.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Dera Bugti: Blast Over the Gas Pipeline</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Police officials say that the 18 inches diameter pipeline going from Lui gas field to peer koh was blasted.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This pipeline goes towards the Sui plant.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Meanwhile, Sarbaz Baloch, presenting himself as a representative of the banned Baloch Republican army has accepted the responsibility of the blast on behalf of his organization over the telephone.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is the fourth pipeline that has been blasted in four days.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On Friday an 18 inch diameter pipeline was blasted in Dera Allahyar whose repair work was continued till Sunday morning.</seg>
    <seg id="7">General Manager of Sui Southern Gas in Quetta, Mushtaq Siddiqui has told that supply from this pipeline will resume in the afternoon.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This pipeline reached Quetta through Sibbi.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Quetta: Zyarat and other surrounding areas have an extreme shortage of natural gas for three days. On one side the snowfall continues and the temperature has dropped below freezing; the other side is where the stoves and heaters have gone cold.</seg>
    <seg id="10">In addition, there was a bomb blast in a motorcycle in Mal Mandi in the city of Dera Bugti. But according to the police, there was no fatality as a result of this blast.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Administrator for Jamat-ud-Dawa</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The headquarter of Jamat-ud-Dawa, Tayyaba Center, is almost 25 kilometers away from Lahore near Mureedkay.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This center has a hospital, a school and also a hostel for students.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The law minister of Punjab, Rana Sanaullah Khan, says that the assignment of a superintendent in the Jamat-ud-Dawa center came into being so that the work of the welfare organizations present there is not disturbed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Khalid Waleed, the son-in-law of Chief of Jamat-ud-Dawa Hafiz Saeed, qualified government official Khaqan Babar is appointed as an administrator to monitor the hospital, schools and other welfare organizations located in the center. Although, according to them, there has also been an increase in the police staff.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Security Council of the United Nations has placed restrictions on Jamat-ud-Dawa after which Pakistan's federal government did an operation against Jamat-ud-Dawa in the entire country. Many leaders were placed under house arrest, including Ameer Hafiz Saeed. The assignment of an administrator in the Tayyaba center from the government of Punjab was also part of the series of actions by the federal government against Jamat-ud-Dawa.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Khaqan Babar is related to DMG (District Management Group).</seg>
    <seg id="8">Hafiz Khalid Waleed has said that Lahore division commissioner Khusro Parvez Khan came to the Tayyaba Center on Sunday with the police and civil authorities and inspected several parts of the center. Khalid Waleed has disapproved of placement of an administrator from the government in the Jamat-ud-Dawa Center. It is also said that earlier operations of the government have already decreased the number of patients in the hospital and students in the school.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to a press release by Jamat-ud-Dawa, party chief Hafiz Saeed has written a letter for the General Secretary of United Nations, Ban Ki Mon, and Committee for Taliban, in which a request is made to cancel the restrictions on the party made by the Security Council.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It says in the letter that the one sided decision of the Security Council on banning Jamat-ud-Dawa is unfair. And Jamat-ud-Dawa has no relation with terrorism but it is busy in charitable activities.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Edhi on the aid mission of Gaza.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After going through many steps of receiving permission required to enter Gaza, he has only been successful in reaching Egypt from New York.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said while talking to BBC Urdu service from Qahira that he has still not reached Gaza because Egypt and Israel have created many obstacles.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said "It has been eight days since I am here but I still have not received the permission to enter Gaza."</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I am currently in Qahira and hopefully will get permission to go to Gaza."</seg>
    <seg id="6">He explained that: "First I was given only 7 days visa to go to Gaza and later on my insisting, Pakistani officials helped me and had it extended for one month but on this condition that I will go to Gaza only once that is single entry."</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that he has his son and daughters with him and they want to do charity work in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">I have brought some money.</seg>
    <seg id="9">A one million dollar check has been given to the Red cross of Egypt and ten thousand dollars in cash has been also given in order to send aid to Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Four more ministers in the cabinet, total of sixty three</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The four new federal ministers include two from the Mutahida Qaumi Movement and two from the Jamiat Ulamae Islam Fazalur Rehman Group.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Asif Ali Zardari took the oath from the new ministers.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani and members of cabinet were also present at the oath-taking ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After the inclusion of four new ministers to the federal cabinet, the number of federal ministers, state ministers, and advisers has reached a total of sixty-three.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Ministers Farooq Sattar and Babar Ghouri are from MQM, whereas Ministers Azam Swati and Molana Ataur Rehman are from the Jamiat Ulamae Islam Fazalur Rehman Group.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The departments of these ministers have not yet been announced.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Farooq Sattar is the convener of MQM, whereas Babar Ghouri is a senator from MQM whose term will expire on March 10.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Azam Swati was elected as a free senator and is considered to be one of the richest.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Moulana Ata-ur-Rahman is a member of the National Assembly and also Moulana Fazal-ur-Rahman's younger brother.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Remember that four statesmen holding posts in important ministries are not members of the National Assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Note that the cabinet was expanded on November 3, 2008, with 22 new ministers and 18 national ministries. So at that time it was thought that the members of MQM would also be included but due to disagreements on the distribution of the ministries, MQM stayed away.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bolochistan, Blasted Pipeline</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police, this is a 18-inch diameter pipeline which connects different wells of Parekoh and meets the Suyi gas pipeline. This was blasted by unidentified men in the early morning.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Apart from this, yesterday, well number 3 near Suyi had been totally destroyed by a blast and a gas pipeline near Dera-allayar was also damaged due to a blast.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Militant organization Baloch republican army's spokeperson, Saryaz Baluch, accepted the responsibility for these blasts on the behalf of his organization.</seg>
    <seg id="5">As 2009 began, there was an increase in violent incidents in Baluchistan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">This month, until now, several gas pipelines have been blasted.  Attacks on trains and on people belonging to the Punjab region have also increased.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Though the Prime Minister of Baluchistan, Nawab Aslam Rayisani, has expressed concern over such activities and ordered the police to exchange information from intelligence agencies, stopping such incidents has not been possible yet.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">$819 billion economic revival package approved</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">No member of the Republican party voted for President Obama's plan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Members of the Republican Party said that the economic plan is very expensive and will not prove effective.</seg>
    <seg id="4">240 votes were cast in favor of this package in the members assembly whereas 160 were cast against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This economic revival plan will be presented next week in the Senate where the ruling Democratic party has very little majority.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Concern is being expressed that great opposition from the Republican Party may make it difficult to obtain Senate approval.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After the approval of economic revival plan, Barack Obama insisted that this important plan should not cause political disagreement.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The president said that this plan, which hoped would be enacted by next month, will prove to make a peaceful atmosphere in the country and enhance the American economy.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to this plan, the public will be forgiven of loans from $275 billion to $540 billion for roads, bridges, 10,000 schools, unemployment benefits and research for new technology.</seg>
    <seg id="10">BBC writer Richard Luster has said in Washington that Barack Obama intended to introduce a new political culture by eliminating political disagreements, but discussion about this economic package has once again made politicians sore.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Republican members of the senate called the proposed bill a waste of government money, and said that it will not help in creating new employment opportunities.</seg>
    <seg id="12">They instead stressed the bill passed by their own party, in which more importance was given to tax cuts.</seg>
    <seg id="13">They said that more employment opportunities could be formed with less capital through their bill.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They said that compared to constructive plans, more employment opportunities could be formed through tax cuts.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bitterness between Israeli President and Turkish Prime Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Nearly screaming, Recep Tayyip Erdogan told the Israeli president that the blood of many humans were spilled in Gaza, and it saddened him to see that people could watch this armed killing from Israel and clap in agreement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Erdogan said that ""I believe that you are using such words to publicly ease your guilty conscience.  But you killed those people, and I will not forget those children who were killed near the shore.""</seg>
    <seg id="4">Simon said that Gaza's calamity is not due to Israel, but rather Hamas, who have established a dangerous dictatorship over there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A BBC journalist from Davos said that he had never seen such a scene in an global economic forum before.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, Erdogan later stated that he respected the aged Israeli president, falsely claiming that he was not yelling at him.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Turkey is one of the few Islamic countries which have diplomatic relations with Israel, but for the last few years there has been tension between them.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The attacks were not planned in Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Speaking to Indian news channel, NDTV, Wajid Shamsul Hasan, said that the report of the Pakistani investigations into the Mumbai blast will be prepared soon.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the attacks that took place in Mumbai, last Novemeber, more than 170 persons were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">India claims that the responsibility for the attacks belongs to the extremist group, Lashkar-e-Taiba.</seg>
    <seg id="5">India also said that Pakistani 'state factors' were guilty in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After the Mumbai attacks, the relations between the two countries were affected.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The high commissioner Wajid Shamsul Hasan gave his first statement about the report of the Pakistani investigations, from which it becomes evident as to what is within the report.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wajid Shamsul Hasan said that as far as investigation has gone, Pakistani land has not been used.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It must be some other place, not England either.</seg>
    <seg id="10">These are the two places (Pakistan and Britain) about which I was worried.</seg>
    <seg id="11">India and the international community have created a lot of pressure on Pakistan to take action against the culprits of the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Wajid Shamsul Haq said: We are not trying to cover it up.</seg>
    <seg id="13">We believe in taking action based on facts.</seg>
    <seg id="14">The world will accept our investigations.</seg>
    <seg id="15">We will try to satisfy India over the results of the investigation.</seg>
    <seg id="16">While defending the delay in the investigation in Pakistan, he said that it takes time to collect, understand and check these kind of things.</seg>
    <seg id="17">High Commissioner Wajid Shamsul Haq said that it took 45 days for India to present its dossier.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A black man elected as the republican leader too.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the sixth round of elections in the Republican party, Michael Steel has won, receiving 91 votes out of 168.</seg>
    <seg id="3">During the  election for the position of chairman of the party, Katen Dawsen, candidate opposite to Steel, was given 70 votes. Whereas, former chairman Dunken abdicated from the competition in the second round.</seg>
    <seg id="4">People say that of the five candidates who ran for the position of the chairmanship of the republican party, Michael Steel was considered the most conservative among them.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After his win, Michael Steel said in his speech "We are saying to our friends and enemies together, come with us, but those who will cause problems in this, be prepared to separate from us." Michael Steel is from Maryland, where he has also been the deputy governor.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He became famous in 2006 when he ran for a seat in the senate.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But after losing in the senate elections he was appointed as the chairman of one political conservative committee of the party.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Now after being selected as the chairman of the party, the efforts of the Republican Party campaign in the entire country will be under his supervision.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He fought elections for this promise that he will give the party a new cause. And that he will use a new technique to join conservative supporters to the party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Indian claims presence of Lashker-e-Tayyaba and Josh-e-Muhammad in Jammu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">There are reports that terrorists are present in the Poonch tribal area of Jammu.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to official sources, police and the army surrounded the area and started the search upon receiving secret information.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this, a fight started in which four militants, two soldiers and one policeman were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the sources, fights were going on until the last news broke.  In this area, where militants associated with Lashker-e-Tayyaba and Josh-e-Muhammad are present, more soldiers have been sent to fight them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">During this, chief minister Omer Abdullah, nominated by the involved officials, met with the governor.  He directly gave the news of the Assembly leader's election from his party national conference.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Congress, the ally of the National Conference, also informed the governor of their advocacy of Omar Abdullah.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Omar Abdullah will take oath as the chief minister of the state.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Remember, the National Conference became the biggest party by gaining 28 seats in the 87 member assembly in the current state elections. Keep in mind that separatist parties boycotted the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Congress, which secured 17 seats, accepted to form a coalition government with the National Conference.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Today, party workers welcomed Omar Abdullah with great fanfare on his arrival in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On this occasion, Omar Abdullah says that he will play his role in making the talks possible between the Indian government and separatists. However, this will not be possible until the elections in India and formation of the new government.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Role of EU for Peace in the Middle East.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">From the official point of view, the role of the European Union is decisive in the peace efforts to stop the war in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to Brussels' official stance, the efforts of Schwarzenberg delegation or Sarkozy were equally helpful in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The European Union's spokesman, Amadeu Altafaj, has said that every such effort is appreciated which is helpful in sending the European Union's message to the opponents of the war.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It seems alright as far as the official statement is concerned.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In reality, the European Union is portraying a very disappointing picture of the internal tensions.</seg>
    <seg id="7">As the head of the Union, the Czech Republic's role is even weaker than before.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Also, the internal issues have made it helpless.</seg>
    <seg id="9">On the other hand, the French President, Sarkozy, is behaving as if he is still the President of the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="10">France has completed its presidential tenure of six months.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Sarkozy wants to play a leading role, and he is capable of it, but he does not have the permission to do so.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The French foreign minister, Bernard Kouchner, is faced with a strange situation.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He is part of a delegation which is headed by the foreign minister of the Czech Republic, Schwarzenberg.</seg>
    <seg id="14">The problem is that both foreign ministers are issuing contradictory statements over the Middle East war.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Schwarzenberg says that Israel has the right for self defense, whereas Kouchner says that this cannot be considered as a war for self defense. Moreover, Germany has sent its special ambassador to the Middle East. Unless the European Union does not show unity based on common stance it can not succeed on the diplomatic front.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Its proof is the Israeli behavior which does not care about the efforts for reconciliation from the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="17">This is a golden chance for the European Union to do something since America, due to the policies of George W. Bush, has already failed in the Middle East.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Financial Crisis: Suicide of a billionaire German industrialist.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Adolf Merckle, a resident of Sawabia in Southern Germany, left a huge business group behind him.</seg>
    <seg id="3">But, a short while ago, common German citizens did not know much about it.</seg>
    <seg id="4">When he had to negotiate with 30 banks who lent money to his industrial group, he became the topic of the headlines. Then he could foresee the murky future of the Merckle group.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Merkle group had to face the loss of a few hundred million euros due to the arrival of the financial crisis after it bought shares in the German car manufacturing company Volkswagen.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Financial institutions then refused to give it the new 700 million to one billion euro loan it needed on an immediate basis, so Merkle was under intense pressure.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Some time before that, the same bank was prepared to give it the immediate loan that it needed, but Adolf Merkel had got to this position from being a small producer, to having a yearly turnover of nearly 30 billion euros, so he could not bear to lose his capitalistic power.</seg>
    <seg id="8">After the death of his father, Adolf Merkel took over his family business and developed it quickly, putting on new lines.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He called his company Ratiopharm, which is a very successful and large pharmaceutical company in Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Until a while ago, the value of this business was between 5 billion and 6 billion euros, and it still earns about 8.1 billion euros a year. After the superb success of Ratiopharm, the Merkel Group started buying many other institutions which included construction supply manufacturing companies like Hydelburg Cement to car manufacturing companies like Kassbohrer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The number of employees of the Merkel Group around the world is near 100,000, and its foundation company, the pharmaceutical company Ratiopharm, always had special importance.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Adolf Merkel has said many times in his life: "It has been four generations since I started making medicine.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Now the management of this group is in the hands of my children and I hope that the mangement of this company will remain in my family for a few hundred years."</seg>
    <seg id="14">After the suicide of Adolf Merkel, banks have approved 400 million euros in floating loans for his group, but under the condition that VEM will have to sell Ratiopharm so that it could improve its financial conditions in the long term.</seg>
    <seg id="15">After the death of Adolf Meerklay, the Meerklay group will not remain the same.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Crime rate among the immigrants in Germany.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the fresh statistics, crime rate among the immigrants from 2004 to 2007 is</seg>
    <seg id="3">Reduced from 9.22%</seg>
    <seg id="4">to 4.21%</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Joachim Herrmann, the interior minister of Baweria province, this is a positive change.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said: "It is important to note that the number of foreigners getting German citizenship is increasing."</seg>
    <seg id="7">Therefore it should also be mentioned in the statistics that even though the criminal is German, his background is foreign.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Herrmann said that his province will take this in to account when gathering statistics in 2010.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Besides Baweria, Hamburg is also thinking in the same lines.</seg>
    <seg id="10">A senator for foreign affairs from CDU, Christoph Ahlhaus, has said: "When research is done in a scientific manner, man can not pre-decide its results but it is based on the facts and figures that come out as a result of the research."</seg>
    <seg id="11">Ahlhaus diverted attention to a research report from the anti-crime provincial office which was prepared in 2006 and according to this report in Bergdorf, a part of Hamburg, it was discovered that out of all crimes happening there is a percentage that have the involvement of foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="12">results showed that the foreigners here have</seg>
    <seg id="13">Tthe crime rate was less as compared to crime all over the province.</seg>
    <seg id="14">By contrast, when a survey was done in 2006 on crimes in youth in Berlin, it was determined that young people having foreign background had a percentage of 44%.</seg>
    <seg id="15">was 7 percent</seg>
    <seg id="16">However, other political parties of Germany for example, SPD, Environmentalists organization Greens, and leftist organization Linkspartei,were against this proposal that while collecting facts and figures regarding crimes, this should also be inquired which German citizens have foreign backgrounds.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">We want quick evacuation of troops from Gaza: Olmert</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Ehud Olmert has stressed that for complete evacuation of the army, a future and permanent ceasefire agreement is inevitable.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamas and Israel declared ceasefire on Sunday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Islamic militant group Hamas while announcing a one week cease fire has asked the Israel army to leave the Gaza strip within one week and to end the barricade on the Gaza strip.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On other side, the leader of Hamas Ismail Hannan has said that Israel has been given victory from God in the Gaza war.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that in Gaza war, Israel has not been able to achieve its purpose.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Before that, in the city of Sharm Al Sheikh, Egypt, a conference was held of Arab and European countries on Sunday. Israel was asked to evacuate its army from Gaza immediately.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It was decided in the conference that soon an international aid conference will be held for Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="9">German Chancellor Angela Meerkal also attended the conference.</seg>
    <seg id="10">At least 1300 Palestinians including 10 soldiers and a total of 13 Israelis were killed in the war lasting for three weeks between the militants of Hamas and Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the other side, Palestinian President Mahmood Abbas has insisted on the formation of national government in the areas of Palestine.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A video message for Germany from Al-Qaeda</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this 30 minute video message, a man wearing a black turban with a covered face and holding a gun is giving a message to the German Government.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This man introduces himself as Abu Talha and speaks in German.</seg>
    <seg id="4">There are also Arabic sub-titles on the video message.</seg>
    <seg id="5">on the side of the screen is the logo of Al-Qaida and the date written in the video is October 2008.</seg>
    <seg id="6">in this message it is said to the German government that after deploying such a large number of troops in Afghanistan this country is thinking that it will not be attacked.</seg>
    <seg id="7">introducing himself as Abu Talha, this man however did not threaten to directly attack Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="8">the number of German troops amongst the Allied NATO forces in Afghanistan is around 3500.</seg>
    <seg id="9">last year the German parliament approved a bill to send one thousand more troops to Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">this is the first message to Germany from Al-Qaida.</seg>
    <seg id="11">having a critical eye on terrorism related issues, the famous expert Mikhail Luders says regarding this message: "The recent suicide attack on the German embassy in Kabul is proof of the fact that we should take it seriously in any case."</seg>
    <seg id="12">for the past few years Al-Qaida has been issuing video messages on the internet after which there were attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="13">On Saturday, the militant organization called the Taliban took responsibility for the suicide attacks that took place outside the German embassy.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Many German newspapers and thinkers are looking at this attack in connection with the Al-Qaeda message.</seg>
    <seg id="15">"They are targeting Germany."</seg>
    <seg id="16">Fundamentalist Muslims are viewing Germany's Afghan policy in a negative and critical manner.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They accuse the German government of following an extremist policy not only in Afghanistan, but also in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Because of this, they are increasingly considering Germany as their target.</seg>
    <seg id="19">In the meantime, the German government claims that the German secret agencies knew about this video before it became public.</seg>
    <seg id="20">The German joint crime control organization is busy studying the video.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama has been elected to the American Presidency.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this situation the whole world - to say nothing of the American public - has different hopes for Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Now that Barack Obama is receiving congratulatory messages from around the world after winning the presidency, expectations of him are also becoming clear.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The German Chancellor, Angela Merchel, also expressed hopes for the new American president.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I believe that the Joint Republic of Germany and the United States of America will be able to get together on the basis of a strong relationship and partnership to solve the problems facing us."</seg>
    <seg id="6">Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin said that Obama seems like a serious and open-hearted person, qualities he felt were positive.</seg>
    <seg id="7">As such, the previous American president's policies were subject to criticism.</seg>
    <seg id="8">However, the previous administration is definitely credited with persuading China to play a more constructive role on the international level. With regards to the new president, China's leader has said that he will have to work for strong military ties between the countries.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Gosuwe Hu, an expert on Chinese politics active in Bokhum, Germany, says:</seg>
    <seg id="10">From this viewpoint, I am certain that Obama and his economic team will, within the coming weeks and months, pressure the Beijing government into pegging the Chinese currency at a stable and market-representing exchange rate.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The previous American administration also increased ties with India.</seg>
    <seg id="12">About where Obama might take those ties, Professor Christopher Raj, expert on American sciences in New Delhi, says that we are now closer to a strategic partnership, but Obama cannot make any changes overnight.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In his message to Obama, Pope Benedict has stressed peace and co-operation in the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Provincial elections in Iraq.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">These are the first elections since 2005 in war stricken country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">There are 14400 candidates for 440 seats in provincial elections.</seg>
    <seg id="4">To keep peace during elections 800,000 police and soldiers have been deployed in Iraq.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The borders of Iraq were sealed one day ago, on Friday, because of the threat that a bombing or terror attack can happen on such an important day.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Also, the airports were closed and public transport was forbidden.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the news, due to disallowed traffic the roads of Iraq have been deserted and Iraqi children can be seen playing football on roads.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The security situation during recent elections will help in analyzing that after American withdrawal in 2011 whether the local security organizations will be able handle the country or not. On the other hand political analysts are watching this as an experiment with which it can assessed that how much Iraqi people are ready to bring change in the country through democratic way.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Provincial elections are being held in Iraq with the help of United Nations and approximately 800 international correspondents will monitor the elections.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Today, the Day of Aashura, was celebrated throughout Iran in remembrance, respect and honor of the great sacrifice of the chief of all martyrs, Imam Hussain.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to Mehr news agency, all small and large cities, including the capital city of Tehran witnessed the celebration of this day in the respect of the chief of martyrs, Imam Husain, with great respect and honor. On this occasion, the believers gathered in great numbers.  In such honorary gatherings, the people also remembered the deaths of the Holy Prophet (PBUH) and his family members. Today, the whole country of Iran is mourning the great sacrifice of the martyrdom of the Prophet's grandson, Imam Hussain, in the battle field of Karbala. The believers are remembering this unmatched sacrifice and attending such large honorary gatherings in its honor.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The retreat of Israeli soldiers from Ajleen province of Gaza didn't match the forbearance of Palestinian soldiers.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Urdu service of Mehr news agency, even on the 16th day of the fight between truth and falsehood in Gaza, there was beastly bombing by the Israel on the city population  of Gaza by the use of air, land and naval attacks.  Because of these attacks, 880 people have died so far.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Among the martyred are 275 innocent children, who have slept in the lap of death, smiling at the deception of the leaders of Arab countries, and of so called human rights organizations.</seg>
    <seg id="4">They always ready to die.  Mujahids of Ajeen province have defeated the Israeli army, with the power of faith and martyrdom, and a show of amazing forbearance and steadfastness, tightening the collar of life, around the necks of the Zionist enemies.</seg>
    <seg id="5">If it were not for the deception of the Egyptian president, Hasani Mubarak, the brave and loyal Hamas Mujahids would have defeated Israel a long time ago.  But apart from the Israeli siege, the Egyptians have also placed Palestinian Muslims under siege, which is the saddest story of Arab history.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Here, the Saudi Arabian and Jordanian governments are giving the Israeli government political and economic support.  They are helping Israel by deceiving the helpless Muslims of Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barack Obama: America will try a new policy in Iran.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report from Mehr News Agency, the newly elected president of America, Barack Obama told ABC news channel, in an interview with them, that they would take a new approach towards the Iran dilemma.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama said that Iran would be a very big challenge for the American government.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that there is a dilemma with regard to Palestinian Islamic organizations Hamas and Hizbullah's support of Iran and Iran's nuclear enrichment program.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But he will not retain the policy of present American president George Bush with regards to Iran, but would adopt different policies for Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama said that he would make his actual goal completely clear, while stressing the hope for mutual respect and dialogue.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Barack Obama has mentioned in the past that no prerequisites will be set with regard to dialogue with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the interview, he expressed hope that his government would make quick policy decisions on Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Regarding the Middle East crisis, Obama said that he would form a special team.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It will start working on establishing peace in the Middle East from the 20th of January.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush, unable and disliked president Bush accepted his mistakes and crimes in his last press statement.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency related from Associated Press that the American president George Bush, in the last press conference of his term, accepted many of his mistakes and crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking during the press conference at the White House, President Bush said that though newly elected president Obama has good intentions, the biggest challenge facing him would be preventing possible attacks on America.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the completion of the Iraq mission and social security reforms were his mistakes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush said that whatever he did, he did it for the sake of protecting America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Upon being asked various questions about the Israeli inflictions on Gaza, President Bush said that Israel has the right to defend itself. According to him, Hamas does not have the right to defend itself and Hamas should not do anything to Israel, and like America, the whole world should choke the oppressed rather than the oppressor.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The incapable and despicable president of the United States said that Hamas should not be given weapons either, while America is providing Israel the world's most destructive weapons. Israel is using American weapons to massacre Palestinians and Bush also praised the Israel-supporting Arabs, calling them the friends of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Bush expressed shame at some of the crimes going on in the Abu Ghraib and Guantanamo prisons.</seg>
    <seg id="9">People are opining that cases should be filed against Bush for his war crimes, and that the organizations which manage to do this will have done a great service to humanity.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Iranian President Ahmedinejad expressed sorrow over the silence of the Arab leaders.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by Mehr News Agency, the Iranian President Mahmood Ahmadinejad criticized the Arab leaders' silence on the Israeli inhumanity and oppression on Gaza, expressing his sorrow.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmadinejad said, expressing surprise over the Arab countries and their leaders' silence over the beastly acts of Israel, that Israel is subjecting the Palestinian public to a holocaust. They are making the Palestinian children, women and civilians targets of their barbarianism, and the Arab leaders have not even given one statement.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmede Nejad has called upon all the Arab countries to unite against Israel and to save the oppressed Muslims of Gaza from Israel's harm and tyranny.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ahmade Nejad says the Saudi King should clarify his stance on the  genocide being done in Gaza by Israel.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the report by MAHAR/MEHR news agency, President Ahmede Nejad in his message to the Saudi King Malik Abdullah declared that the silence on the human genocide in Gaza and muteness on the murder of innocent children and women by  the Muslim King of Saudi Arabia is encouraging the enemies of Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmede Nejad has said in his message: "You should show your true stance on Gaza and declare support for the oppressed, so that the enemy's efforts to plant differences in the Islamic block will fail."</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmede Nejad has said in his message: "You know that for the last 19 days Israel has been bent upon human genocide, murdering innocent children, and subjecting homes, mosques, schools and hospitals to barbaric bombing. The Zonist Regime is brutally murdering the unarmed Muslims in Gaza. In situations like these, silence on the part of leaders like you is only encouraging Israel."</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Ahmede Nejad has told Malik Abdullah that even non-Muslim countries like Valenzuela and Bolivia have taken concrete steps against Israel and that he is expected to take better steps.</seg>
    <seg id="6">President Ahmede Nejad told the Palestinians that success will be at their feet in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He says that the oppressed will win over the oppressors because that's Allah's promise.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090116.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush: Terrorism is Still a Threat to USA</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">MEHER/MAHAR news agency has copied from the German news agency that the US President, while addressing his successor Barak Obama and the nation in his farewell speech, said that though the US is safer than it was seven years ago, the threat of terrorism still looms over USA.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Bush said that because enemy terrorists are waiting patiently to attack America and have a strong determination to do so, America should never be unaware about its security.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The American president ignored the pain and suffering of the hundreds of thousands of Palestinians in Gaza and defended his policies, saying that America is still the biggest supporter of Gaza's independence. However, commentators do not accept the reality of the unpopular president's remarks, as America is neither a supporter of freedom, nor a supporter of human rights, but rather is the most mischievous country in the world. Not only does it support a blood thirsty country like Israel, but it is also directly involved in its crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Israelis openly kill woman, children and other civilians. Despite this, the American president is congratulating them. This is the American humanity and freedom which the world is seeing in Gaza and other places.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Usama Hamdan: Presence of army in Palestine continues</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by Mehr News Agency, Usamah Hamdan,  the Hamas leader in Lebanon, told French News Agency during an interview that a one-sided ceasefire from the Israeli side is against the comprehensive international efforts for a ceasefire. He said that as long as Israel is present in Gaza, a one-sided ceasefire is meaningless.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamadan said that the one sided ceasefire was an unsuccessful effort of Israel to escape defeat. He said that if Israel wants long term peace, it will have to accept Hamas's conditions as well as end this siege.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He made it clear that if Israel tries a one-sided ceasefire with its army remaining in the Gaza belt, there will be resistance.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Addressing a one-way conference from Beirut, Usamah Hamdan called for European nations to break ties with Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Hamas leader said that the increasing numbers of the martyred and injured will only increase our determination.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He also told the Palestinian public to stay firmly rooted and resist the enemy like a boulder.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Taliban have killed six people in Pakistan's tribal area of north Wazirastan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Meher reporting agency copied with reference to Reuters that Taliban have killed 2 Afghans and 4 Pakistanis over accusation of espionage in Pakistan's tribal area of north Wazirastan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to reports, on Tuesday morning locals found four bodies from Tehsil Chowk in Tehsil Mir Ali, who were shot dead.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Two bodies were found thrown in the market of a bazaar in the capital of Miranshah.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Letters written in Urdu have also been found near the bodies in which it is claimed that the dead were involved in espionage.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Also, two weeks earlier, in Miranshah, capital of north Wazirastan, two Afghanis were killed over accusations of espionage.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Over the last twelve days, fifteen people have been killed over charges of espionage for America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be clear that during last six years more than a hundred people have been killed in south and north Wazirastan on accusations of espionage. Taliban are accused of being involved in these murders.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barack Obama is expected to undersign the closure orders of the infamous Guantanamo Bay prison.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr Reporting Agency has cited sources that say the American president will sign off on the closure of the infamous Guantanamo Bay prison.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The new American president, Barack Husain Obama, started working on his campaign promises at the surface level.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this regard, President Obama called for making a plan for recalling the army from Iraq, while the American president will sign an order today to close the notorious Guantanamo Bay prison.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that President Barack Obama will probably sign the order today by which the Guantanamo prison will be closed within one year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Apart from this, the White House is expected to revise suspected terrorism investigation methods and ban ill treatment of prisoners during interrogation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President Barack Obama started to fulfill his election campaign promises from his first day in office, and first of all started by taking steps toward making the actions and workings of the government transparent.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Experts say that the American president has started making efforts to save the declining image of America throughout the world, but that would be difficult, because as long as it will keep supporting the blood thirsty Israeli government, it can not be expected to do anything good. Therefore if America wants to save its image, it will have to stop its support of Israel and have to disassociate itself from Israel's crimes.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tony Blair stresses the need to include Islamic organization Hamas in the talks.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr news agency quoted from British newspaper The Times that former Prime Minister Tony Blair stressed the need to include Hamas in the talks to bring about peace in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the newspaper, Tony Blair said that it is important that a path be found for bringing Hamas into the Middle East peace process. Blair criticized the Bush administration for speaking only to Mahmood Abbas and ignoring Hamas. It should be clear that the western countries have realized the democratic and organizational powers of Hamas and are calling for bringing them into the talks, whereas previously they used to consider it a terrorist organization. A terrorist organization which is trying to defend its country and struggling to save its own house from the clutches of others. Whose house and country have been in the hand of the occupying Israeli government for 60 years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Murder of Balochistan merchants in Karachi, Complete strike in Quetta</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Due to the death of four merchants from Balochistan in Karachi, a complete strike was in effect on Thursday against it, in Quetta and some other places.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this period all business centers remained closed, whereas traffic was also less than usual.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The strike was called by the "Anjuman Tajiran Balochistan" (Balochistan Trade Union), Pushtunkhwah Milli Awami Party and the Jamiat-e-Ulama-e-Islam. They accused the Karachi police of having openly fired at these merchants, when they were going by car to their vehicle showroom on Tariq Road.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The president of the Anjuman Tajiran, Abdur Raheem Kakad, demanded that the guilty police agents should be arrested and action should be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, the stance of the Karachi police regarding this incident was not immediately clear.</seg>
    <seg id="7">All four of the dead merchants were from the border city of Chaman.</seg>
    <seg id="8">A large amount of security was provided by the government during the strike, and police officers were posted throughout the city, at important locations.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A senior commander of Hamas was killed in Israeli attack.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In an air attack by Israel, a senior Hamas commander was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This is the second death of an important Hamas figure, in the week-long Israeli attacks on the Gaza belt.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Hamas officeholders said that Abu Zakariyya AlJamaal was killed in Shujaaiyah palace in the east of Gaza city on Saturday.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In another air attack by Israel on Thursday, Aalam Nazar Ra'iyan was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Hamas's evacuated leader Khalid Mushil (who stays in Syria) has promised to take revenge and warned Israel of launching a land attack on Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Thousands of Israeli tanks and soldiers are posted at the Gaza border and they are waiting for orders to attack.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America has called for a ceasefire but said that it is up to Israel whether to attack Gaza or not.</seg>
    <seg id="9">American President George Bush said in his weekly radio speech  that Hamas was escalating the situation. He also said that their attacks on Israel amounted to terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that America would work for a ceasefire but any one sided settlement would not be acceptable.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bodies found in North Waziristan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani Security officials said that the bodies of three people were found in the tribal regions of North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is suspected that the Taliban gave them the death penalty.</seg>
    <seg id="4">These bodies were found near the city of Meran Shah in northern Waziristan. And with them, notes are found accusing these men of being American spies.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officials said that probably one of the bodies is of the man who was kidnapped last week.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the other two bodies wounded with bullets are of Afghan residents.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Israeli attacks on Gaza continue on the tenth day.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A Palestinian child was injured in the Israel missile attack. The Israeli ground army is fighting with Hamas troops in the entire area of the Gaza strip whereas the Israeli air force continued attacks on the areas of militant groups on the tenth day.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The defense minister of Israel, Ehud Barack, said on Monday that they will continue the army operation until the people of Southern Israel are safe from the rocket attacks of Hamas.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In addition to the attacks of Israel, the rocket firing is continued from the side of Hamas in which four people including three local citizens were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hamas leader Mahmood Zuhr on Monday insisted that his friends demolish the Israeli Army and target local Israeli residents.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But one official of Hamas said that they plan to send a delegation to Egypt on Monday to discuss the current violent situation of their party.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In Gaza one Palestinian woman was injured. Medical sources in Gaza said that during the last ten days almost 530 people have been killed including those 11 civilians; at least five were children.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Israel informed of the death of one soldier and 30 more injured in the ground attack.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Israel has stopped foreign reporters from entering Gaza to cover army action.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Elected Vice President Joseph Biden has Reached Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Foreign Minister received American elected Vice President.</seg>
    <seg id="3">American elected vice president, Joseph Biden has reached Islamabad on his trip to Pakistan with his delegation on Friday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Foreign minister Shah Mehmood Qureshi and American Embassy officials welcomed them.</seg>
    <seg id="5">American senator Lindsy Graham is also with Biden in this tour.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Press officer of American embassy, Lu Finter has told Voice of America that the newly elected president will talk about different regional issues with Pakistan government in his tour. Although he refrained from giving more details.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the sources of foreign office, Joseph Biden will also meet Army chief General Ashfaq Parvez Kiyani besides other high government officials.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is expected that during these meetings, war against terrorism will also be discussed besides important bilateral and international issues.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Joseph Biden was awarded the Hilal-e-Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After having arrived in Islamabad, Joseph Biden met with President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="11">During the meeting, the president presented him with the Hilal-e-Pakistan for playing an important role in forming close relations between Pakistan and America.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Please have it cleared that last year Joseph Biden, together with Senator Richard Lugar, introduced a Bill as a chairman of Foreign Affair committee, favoring the increase in  America's foreign army provision to Pakistan in the coming 5 years by 3% to a total of 5.7 billion dollars.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Joe Biden played an important role in removing the previous president Parvez Musharaf, Prime Minister Gilani</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Yusuf Raza Gilani and Joe Biden ( File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="3">Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Gilani states Vice President Joe Biden promoted democracy in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Yusuf Raza Gilani made this statement during a talk with the press in Shipyard, Karachi.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Joe Biden presented a bill of 15 billion dollars aid for Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Prime Minister of Pakistan said they can not permit attacks of these kind in the country's premises.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He also expressed hope that after the succession of the new American government, change will come in American policy as well.</seg>
    <seg id="8">(File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="9">Yusuf Raza Gilani has said that the government has successfully separated the Taliban from ordinary tribesmen, but the drone attacks have proven to be very harmful to the efforts of the government as the terrorists once again join forces with the local tribes.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that the international community agrees with this stance of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The prime minister added that if reliable evidence is provided, then the Pakistani forces will operate in its own territory.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Gilani reiterated his stance against the Mumbai attacks and said that if India provides evidence, then investigation will be carried out on that basis, and if there is any proof of someone's involvement, he will be dealt according to the laws of the country.</seg>
    <seg id="13">While answering a question about Rehman Malik's tour to Britain and his meeting with the MQM leader Altaf Hussain, the prime minister said that Rehman Malik went to London on his approval.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Quetta, four policemen including DSP killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">File Photo</seg>
    <seg id="3">On an important highway in Quetta, Saryab road, firing by unknown people killed four policemen, including DSP "Deputy Superintendent of Police".</seg>
    <seg id="4">Wednesday morning two DSPs, one Sub Inspector and two Constables were on the way to the Police Training Center in a jeep. On Sariab Road near Degree College an unknown rider on a motor cycle attacked the police jeep. He fired continuously. In the attack Sub Inspector Mehdi, Constables Sibgat ul llah and Nasr ul llah died on the spot. DSP Hasan Ali died after reaching the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A source at the hospital said that the second DSP, Ghulam Mohammed, is in very serious condition. He is severely injured with bullet wounds in his head and neck.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Police besieged the area after the incident. So far no one has accepted responsibility for the attack.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">An Indian Software Engineer has been murdered in America</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In America an unknown person killed a software engineer who studied at Andhra Pradesh.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Two days ago an unknown person shot Akshya Vishal. Vishal died while being treated in the hospital. He was 26 Years old. He studied at Andhra Pradesh.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was an employee of Satyam Computers. In America he was working with Falcon Jet Airways.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Last year there were seven students from Andhra Pradesh who were killed in America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The students, who went to America for higher education and employment, were murdered. Their family, friends and relatives are now concerned about the children who reside in America.</seg>
    <seg id="7">To clarify, they prefer America for higher studies and for a better future in Andhra Pradesh.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to statistics from the American consulate in Chennai, 100,000 American visa applications are received from India, approximately forty percent of which come from from Andra Pardes.</seg>
    <seg id="9">During this time, the provincial government started trying to bring the dead body of the deceased to Hyderabad.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Bush: America should stay alert for Enemy's attack</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">President Bush insisted America needs to be alert for enemy attack in his last weekly radio speech.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Bush has that even today, America's biggest threat is another attack from terrorists. He has warned that enemies of the country are waiting patiently and are ready to attack again.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The retiring president has said that America should never be ignorant of its safety.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush has also expressed best wishes for President Barack Obama, who will take his oath on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Newly elected President Barrack Obama shed light on the historical importance of his oath taking ceremony in his speech on radio on Saturday.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that this ceremony is a tradition in which the power of one leader is transferred to another in a peaceful way, is highly related to the American greatness.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mr. Obama observed that in the entire world, there are many who can not even imagine that their leaders will retire from their positions without violence and the shedding of blood.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Meeting of the Sherif brothers and the joint home minister in Raiwand to exchange thoughts on political and security matters.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Pakistan Muslim Leagues (n)'s leader Nawaz Sherif and Pakistan's home minister Rehman Malik met on Sunday in Raiwand in which Punjabi Chief Minister Shehbaz Sherif was also present.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the local media, Rehman Malik probably got an important message from the Pakistan Peoples Party leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, speaking to journalists after the meeting, Rehman Malik did not disclose anything of the nature and only said that they talked about agreement politics and that he briefed the PML(n) leadership about the conditions after the Mumbai attack.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words "I let them know about the action taken so far".</seg>
    <seg id="6">It should not be forgotten that a lot of action was taken by the Punjab government and that the team that I formed will need the help of the Punjab government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Rehman Malik said that every day the media is not told but PML (n) leadership is sent messages. Here the Pakistan Muslim League (n) spokesperson Pervez Rasheed also spoke but avoided speaking about political matters and said that Rehman Malik has already said what needs to be told.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be known that Pakistan Muslim League (n)'s leadership met the Internal Advisor at a time when the state was in a state of hot political activity with 20 or more leaders belonging to the opposition party. PML (q) held a press conference with the Governor of Punjab, Salman Taseer, rejecting the steps of the government in the state and opposing the inclusion of the Governor of Punjab, who is from the Pakistan Peoples Party in this matter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama's Speech Is Glad Tidings For Pakistan's President Zardari.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani president, Asif Ali Zardari welcomed the opening speech of the new President of America Barack Obama, saying that his statement that he would advance the relationship with the Muslim world, based on mutual interests and mutual respect, is good news for Pakistan and it's public.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In a statement given on Wednesday, he said that the high ideals and values which the American President has promised to uphold gives the people worldwide hope of a new life.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the statement, President Zardari said that the responsibility for joining the global brotherhood and searching for roads to peace, development, and prosperity in the 21st century falls, no doubt, on the shoulders of America.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Let it be clear that President Obama said in his opening speech on Tuesday after taking the oath, that America wants a new approach towards the Muslim world, based on mutual interests and mutual respect.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He assured the people of poor countries that America will work with them to let there be cultural development and to reduce poverty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Obama has appointed a special representative to Afghanistan and Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Richard Holbrooke, the former ambassador to the United Nations, was appointed the special representative to Afghanistan and Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Holbrooke played an important role in bringing peace to Bosnia and Herzegovina.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Holbrooke said that he was ready to counsel President Obama on matters relating to Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He added that this would not be easy.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the histories of both countries were extremely different.</seg>
    <seg id="7">George Mitchell has been selected for Middle East, and he will try to revive the Arab-Israel dialogue.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mitchell is an ex-minister and he once played an important role in establishing peace in Northern Ireland.</seg>
    <seg id="9">While speaking at the State Department today, he said that the situation in the Middle East is very vulnerable, complicated, and dangerous.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Despite this, America will not step back from peace efforts there.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghanistan: Voter registration in danger.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Afghanistan's Election Commission has announced that it is delaying voter registration in some areas of the south due to concerns over security.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In southern Afghanistan, voter registration had to be started this week for the upcoming presidential election.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The commission has stated that voters in a few areas of the province Hilmand will not be able to get registered unless the security situation improves.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In those parts of the south, conflict has increased from last year, where rebel Taliban members have increased attacks on Afghan and international forces.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Meanwhile, Afghan and international forces have said that overnight from Wednesday into Thursday, they have killed at least 28 militants in battles across Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">NATO claimed that its military forces killed 22 enemy soldiers in land and air strikes in the Western province of Khost, near the Pakistani border.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Previously, the Afghan Defense Ministry had claimed that the Afghan army had killed eight rebels and injured two within the province.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is not clear whether the Afghani officeholders are referring to the same incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090123.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Two missile attacks in Waziristan, at least 18 killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistan Intelligence officials have said that in two doubtful American missile attacks in North Waziristan, at least 18 people were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to these officials, unmanned planes fired three missiles on a house in Mir province of north Waziristan, killing ten.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to local officials, five of the dead were non-national soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This region is considered the center of Taliban and Al-Qaidah activity.</seg>
    <seg id="6">A few hours after this incident, a missile attack was occurred on south Waziristan as well, killing at least 8 more.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Despite the objections of the Pakistani government, there have been about 30 missile attacks since mid-last year.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The present attacks were the first since President Barack Obama took office.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The Bush government had been avoiding acknowledging the attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="10">On Friday, suspected American spy planes dropped three missiles in the tribal region of North Waziristan. Five deaths have been reported.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The dead could not be identified.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to initial reports the missile attacks were on a house in the locality of Mir Ali.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It should be noted that these are the first missile attacks on the tribal regions of Pakistan since Barack Obama became president.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Sarhad state officials reject demand to restrict girls' education.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In Sarhad state, officials have rejected the Taliban's warning to restrict girls education, saying that this announcement is against both law and Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On Sunday, the education minister of Sarhad state, Sardar Husain Babar, added that the government will never allow such efforts to succeed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the extremists are attempting to deprive our region's children of education.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words: ""These people try to secretly blow up schools and frighten the boys and girls""</seg>
    <seg id="6">Talking about the environment of fear and insecurity, he said that the local government knows well and wants it to be known that no force can stop the spread of education in the land of the Pukhtons.</seg>
    <seg id="7">One day ago, the Taliban soldiers, led by Moulana Fazlullah, had demanded that girls be banned from studying in the Swat's educational institutions beginning on the 15th of January.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Despite the military activity going on in Swat during the last one and a half years, about 150 educational institutions were destroyed by the militants by the use of explosives and arson.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Due to the destruction of these educational institutions, thousands of girls and boys were deprived of an education.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Strict security arrangements in India on Republic Day.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The 60th Republic Day is being celebrated in India on Monday. On this occasion, strict security measures are being taken and thousands of soldiers were posted throughout the country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On the occasion of Republic Day, during the army parade in New Delhi, weapons, planes and other military equipment is displayed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Officials are saying that the security arrangements include anti aircraft missiles and sharpshooters and that police will be deployed to watch the roads of the parade. American President Barack Obama congratulated India on the occasion.</seg>
    <seg id="5">And he also wished Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, who had undergone a heart operation on Saturday, a speedy recovery.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Indian police claim to have killed two suspected Pakistani fighters near New Delhi after an encounter yesterday.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to local government the police recovered AK47 rifles, grenades, and papers from both persons which indicated that they were probably from Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Police are also investigating into whether these two people belonged to the banned organization 'Lashkar-e-Taiba' which was involved in last November's Mumbai attacks.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tea may help prevent breast cancer</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to new research, drinking three cups of tea every day</seg>
    <seg id="3">the risk for breast cancer is reduced by more than one third  in women under 50 years old.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Research conducted by the MOFT center in Florida, USA, has found that women under 50 years age that have breast cancer genes</seg>
    <seg id="5">The risk of breast cancer is reduced by 37 percent in women who drink three cups of tea per day.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The research shows that women over 50 years of age do not see any benefit from drinking three or more cups of tea a day.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The researchers think that for women under 50, the tea contains elements that are effective against the genes that cause breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Research was done on 5000 women who had Breast Cancer treatment at Moffitt Cancer Center in Tampa,Florida.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Their ages were between 20 and 74 years.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Specialists compared their medical records and lifestyles to those women who were free of breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Specialists also found that tea had the most effect on one specific kind of breast cancer, Lobes.  It reduced the risk by 66%.</seg>
    <seg id="12">One on every ten breast cancer patients has this kind of cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="13">This type of breast cancer is dangerous because it is deep inside and usually only diagnosed when it has become widespread.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Specialists found that having at least three cups of tea every day can readily reduce the chances of breast cancer in women of younger ages.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They found that incorporating tea as a regular drink in your daily routine helps create immunity against the cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Almost 40,000 women are diagnosed with breast cancer in Britain.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">According to Gates, the war in Afghanistan is the greatest military challenge facing America</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">American Defense Minister Robert Gates has said that the war in Afghanistan is the biggest military challenge faced by America.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gates will give a briefing today to the Senate and House over the strategies of the Obama office on the Afghanistan and Iraq wars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Gates told the Senate Armed Services committee that fighting is not the only solution to the Afghanistan issue. But he added that in order to secure several areas, sufficient numbers of troops are not deployed, and the Taliban take advantage of that to continue their operations.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Why Reduce Exercise With Age?</seg>
     <seg id="2">New Research</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="3">Exercise at any age is good for your health.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It energizes your heart, reduces cholesterol levels, helps in keeping weight low, helps to prevent diabetes and slows down the process of Alzheimer's or dementia.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Unfortunately the ability to exercise decreases for many people as they age.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Experts say that exercise keeps our body and brain active however age can affect it.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the American Medical Association, several health related problems can arise from not doing exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Dr. Pattricia P. Leka of the Mayo Clinic in Minnesota says that increase in age is a big reason for being handicapped from exercise and other physical activity.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Dr. Patricia teaches medicine at Mayo clinic.</seg>
    <seg id="10">She headed a research study regarding heart disease and man's ability to do exercise in older age.</seg>
    <seg id="11">A team of doctors used high frequency sound waves to observe the performance of heart</seg>
    <seg id="12">in which it's activity of pumping blood and its contraction and relaxation was studied.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Researcher focused their attention on the right side of the heart, which is the main part of pumping blood.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They came to know ,that with increase in age, problems increase in the relaxation action of heart.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Dr. Patricia says with increase in age, problems occur in the activity of relaxation of heart and this effects the ability to exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Dr. Garvin Ken was also part of this research.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He says that they were surprised to see that it has an effect  and it confirmed that bad exercising ability is very much related to the heart relaxing activity.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Sometimes blood pressure can cause disorders in heart functions and heart disease.</seg>
    <seg id="19">If the doctor and the patient work in tandem in this regard, the patient can take advantage of the benefits of exercise regardless of age.</seg>
    <seg id="20">A detailed report on this matter is published in a magazine from the American Medical Association.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">No Chances of an Immediate War with Pakistan: Indian Army Chief</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Indian Army Chief General Deepak Kapoor has said that there are no chances of an immediate war with Pakistan. "However/ we are always ready to defend our country and sacrifice our lives for it," he said.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He has stated that even with commitments from other nations and international pressure on Pakistan as a result of Mumbai attacks, the infrastructure of terrorism is not only existent but also proactive in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said this while talking to correspondents in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Indian Army Chief was on a one day tour to the valley of Kashmir in order to analyze the overall security situation in New Delhi-administered Kashmir and preparation of armed forces on the borders.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He was asked his thoughts on media reports that Pakistan has rejected the evidence provided from India regarding the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="7">General Kapoor said that the decisions of peace or war matters are made by the political leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Talking about terrorism in the land of Pakistan, he allegedly said that India will fight against the forces that are trying to destroy peace and weaken India.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He said that there are around 700 to 800 fighters present in Indian Kashmir, of whom almost 50% are foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="10">General Deepak Kapoor said that the governmental efforts of encroachment between Pakistan and Kashmir would be increased only when the weather improved, although India has increased security on the boarders.</seg>
    <seg id="11">They have refused the possibility of reducing the number of army soldiers in Indian Kashmir by stating that one can not compromise over the country's security.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May God answer the world's prayers that Barrack Obama be beneficial for the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Though there is not much hope, we shall see if the relationship between America and Pakistan is affected in our favor by this change.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What will Mr. Barrack Obama give to the world in the name of Martin Luther King's dreams?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Obama - whose middle name is Hussein - becoming president of America is historically important in many ways, and is also a great challenge.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Not only for himself but also for those who supported him with all their hearts.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It will also be challenging be for the white majority as it is not easy for them to accept that a colored man is ruling over them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here in South Asia, Muslims who have expectations from him, should remember that he has been elected as the President of the United States. And Obama should remember that being President of the United States actually means being the President of the entire world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A man whose brothers and sisters were brought to America as slaves and whose sweat and blood have strengthened the roots of the most powerful country of the new era, today a representative of this racially discrete nation will be called the 40th President of this very America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have expectations from this one man.</seg>
     <seg id="3">People who love him, have unreal expectations from him.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If Obama succeeds to an extent in reducing the hatred among races and religion in the world, this will be a win for the people who love him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What will be its effect on South Asia, and can a meaningful change be expected in the American policy regarding this matter?</seg>
     <seg id="2">How will this change effect the relationship between America and Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="3">?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Whether it is by Obama or some one else, the policy of the entire world is done by Jews who lobby billionaires and influence powerful and effective people.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And as far as Pakistan is concerned, after the series of recent Bombay blasts, the offensive reactions of India, America and Israel are in front of everyone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even for a while, after Pakistan was formed, the managing of Swat was left to the Ruler of Swat, which had its own army and law.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They surrendered their rule to the government of Pakistan according to a treaty.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But it's sad that our governments have treated Swat like a stepmother.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There has been no increase in the number of schools in Swat, since the rule of the Ruler of Swat was finished.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Nor was there any interest in construction and development over there.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The number of girls receiving education in the present rule is many times less than their number in the previous rule.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Sarhad state of Pakistan, the local Taliban have been targeting the educational institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The most schools were destroyed in Swat province, of which the majority were girls' schools.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Not only this, but the Taliban have announced the prohibition of girls' education in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thousands of male and female students are being deprived of education.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you think the Taliban have to gain by eradicating the education of women?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Why has the government been unsuccessful in stopping these illegal steps?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you think the government should do?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The question should be, what do the ISI and Pakistani agencies get?</seg>
     <seg id="2">The public of Swat must have realized that this was a game and that the army was there to serve the Taliban, rather than to kill them. Otherwise, how could five schools have been blown up in a single curfew night? How could people have been slaughtered during curfew and hung in the main circle of the town?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When the government is not allowed to have any say in Swat, how can the government be successful in stopping these illegal steps?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, the question arises as to why these four Taliban are not being controlled when the government has an armed military, new and dangerous weapons, a new spy system, and more.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The answer to this is that they have the hand of a hidden guide on their heads, because of which neither do their weapons get exhausted, nor do they get captured.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The conclusion is that the Taliban, via their dark activities, is making the work of the global leadership easier.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">15 years ago, there was war in Afghanistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">ISI used to control the Taliban when there was the opposition from the Northern Alliance, which was supported by Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Then, suddenly, the situation changed and the Taliban's works came to light.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And ISI also got an offer of money from America, so the former friend became an enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now the situation has changed, but the war is still going on and those supporting them in Pakistan are still Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Until man realizes what is wrong and what is right, he continues to make mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For instance, when a thief goes to steal something, if he realizes at that time that stealing is wrong, it is a curse and it will bring punishment, and he fears Allah, that person will not steal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Similarly, as long as Israel does not realize that it is doing wrong, and spilling the blood of the innocent, and it will receive punishment for that, it will continue to play God with the blood of the innocent people in Gaza.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Greetings</seg>
     <seg id="2">The question is whether war, armed resistance and terrorism are the solutions to the problem?</seg>
     <seg id="3">If not, then what is the magic recipe that will bring about a solution to the problem?</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is true that war and extremism do not solve problems, but rather give 'blessings' to them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Palestine, Afghanistan and Iraq should adopt the same model for their development that Nelson Mandela used in South Africa.</seg>
     <seg id="6">That is: to struggle character wise and politically more than with arms.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Seeing the Kashmiris taking part in the elections, it looks as if they have accepted this view point.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the third week of Israeli attacks on Gaza, and the number of deaths have come close to a thousand.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Despite worldwide diplomatic efforts, to date a ceasefire has not been possible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">According to another report, since the start of attacks on the 27th of December, 90,000 Palestinians have left their homes and moved towards safer locations.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here aid groups have accused Israel of being careless about Palestinian children, and said that a whole generation of Palestinian children will be victims of grave psychological and emotional difficulties.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What should happen?</seg>
     <seg id="7">How is permanent peace possible in Gaza?</seg>
     <seg id="8">For details, click here.</seg>
     <seg id="9">(Please note that due to the increase in discussions, comments typed in Urdu will only be published.</seg>
     <seg id="10">For this, press alt+shift on the On-Screen board and select Urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Give Taliban a Chance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Basit, Peshawar.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wake up! If the Taliban starts the real Jihad, who will slaughter innocent people?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Who will burn down girl's schools?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And kidnapping for ransom and if they do not get the ransom money, who will hang people on poles by claiming they were American spies?</seg>
     <seg id="6">The Taliban has damaged Islam in such a way that no other nation or religion has done.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pashtoon Rore</seg>
     <seg id="8">Kohat, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If the whole Muslim world just gave a joint threat to attack Israel, you will see how upset will father America will be.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And immediately not only talks on ceasefire but ceasefire will really happen as well.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But what can be done? Where should our Muslim leaders bring the courage from?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Someone tell Ahmed Nayad to take the first step, as he is very popular for his bravery at the BBC forums.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The responsibility of peace and human rights not only lies on Arab and the Muslim worlds but its the obligation of the whole world to raise their voice against tyranny.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This unfortunate incident is Bush's worst sin so far.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Just like in Pakistan and India before 30th June or the end of the fiscal year, the government institutions are looted, the American regime just before its end have given a green signal to Israel to do what ever it wants.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">On one hand America says that effort will be made for ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, the United Nations is passing resolution after resolution, but action-wise, has done nothing. There is only one meaning of this, and that is that the even the United Nations is openly in favor of destroying the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All Muslim countries should immediately end their membership in the United Nations, and should establish their own global organization.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We have many examples of where only promises and resolutions of America and the United Nations are seen, but the harm is only done to the Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What is the use of these vain efforts if BBC does not want to publish anything?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Where have all the rules of journalism been buried? When blood, specifically of Muslims, is spilled, the monster of unbiasedness gets onto BBC's back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It considers itself the standard bearer of truth.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Forget about breaking something on its own, the height of heartlessness is that it does not even publish comments from Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Forget about breaking something on its own, the height of heartlessness is that it does not even publish comments from Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The only difference between you and the Jews is that they call themselves Jews and martyr the Muslims, and the likes of you stay among Muslims, and call yourselves Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">[syja786]</seg>
     <seg id="3">A recent trend in BBC forums has been the subject of terrorism of India, and the subject sometimes arises while discussing suicide attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">These anti-Islamic comments often use the term extremism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But the real extremist is the person who made the above comment.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When will Muslims understand that Dajjal can not be fought with the sword?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Looking at the helpless people facing the Israel bombings, if the heart does not cry, what does it do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The most basic mistake behind this destruction and killing is that using the name of Jihad disfigures the beautiful face of Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When a majority of the Palestinians have accepted the existence of Israel, what need does Hamas have to send rockets into Israel or conduct suicide attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">The conduct of both sides is misanthropic.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The action of the United Nations and the United States seem to support the wrongdoings of Israel.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah allow the Muslim nation to unite. Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The real terrorists should be given the noble prize for this painful movement against terrorism. After all, they are doing the real work.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise, is this large scale terrorism possible without the support of some big feudal and everyone knows who these controller are.</seg>
     <seg id="4">So this situation, in common terms, is called DADAGEERI, which means do what ever you can.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It hits you hard on the head and does not even let you cry.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Medicine for the injured and coffins for the dead are being supplied by the Arab leaders and in case</seg>
     <seg id="2">the Israeli attacks should take place.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is the actual problem. The leaders of Muslim countries, including the Saudi crown prince are in a false sleep. They have an neither an army nor any plan for defense and just by providing aid they think they have fulfilled their responsibilities.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They should take immediate measures against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="5">For example, stopping the supplies of petrol to European countries and America but alas they</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salam to All brothers and sisters!</seg>
     <seg id="2">I believe that in this time of difficulty, telling Hamas to stop their struggle for the sake of peace is an injustice to thousands of widows and hundreds of thousands orphans, and it is the same as them declaring defeat.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If Israel and its supporters are at the height of their Pharoahism, soon Moses will be born within their house, as this is the rule of nature.  The steps taken by America and Israel have acted like a fertilizer, growing suicide bombers among the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Which these power intoxicated elephants don't realize.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Abu Abdullah, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Israel and Hamas should enter a truce so that the death and destruction can come to an end.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Mohammad Sarfaraz, Paris, France</seg>
     <seg id="3">Absolutely correctly stated.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Suppose that Hamas is 100% truthful, and they are struggling against oppression, to become successful in the eyes of Allah.  Even then, they should know that if a good deed results in the destruction of an established house, it is no longer a good deed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">For those who claim to love God, love the messenger, and love their religion, loving mankind is a part of their faith.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As if it is the order of Allah to wipe all the people of the Book from the face of the earth, other than Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeeb-ur-Rahman Psycho *Lahore* [Pakian]</seg>
     <seg id="3">No! It is not decreed to annihilate, but it is decreed to invite people to Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">People who have conspiracies against the religion are decreed to do Jihad against them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">One should fight with them until they finish their conspiracies, but this certainly does not mean that they can wear a jacket and blow up in a crowd.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Brothers, the consequence of a murder of children is disaster.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It's a request to my friends that yesterday Israelis did not have a roof over their heads and today they are so strong that they do not listen to anyone because all Jews are one.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They do not have Shiite nor Sunni, all are just Jews, and they have succeeded in every field and made everything.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Opposite to this, what is the condition of 55 Islamic Countries?</seg>
     <seg id="5">By lagging in every field now the condition is that they are so helpless that enemies are killing them and they are waiting for their death.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The point is that all Muslim countries should get together and should make a plan against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Feroz Magsi, Jhang, Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">and there is no better strategy, that recognize Israel, learn modern education and means of progress and let the world live in peace and harmony.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Muslims have plenty of land and means as well.</seg>
     <seg id="5">the need is of proper use.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The first and most disappointing factor is that Hamas and Alfateh could not unite.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Great leaders like Yasir Arafat and Sheikh Yasin were killed in an organized manner to weaken this brave nation which is doing Jihad for the Aqsa Mosque.  This was impossible without getting Yasin and Arafat out of the way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The world is witnessing that Palestine had been scattered after the death of these two leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and how the Jewish lobby gradually kept strengthening its grip.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In 1974 a Pakistani Prime Minister was so trusted worldwide that for the first time in history he manged to gather all the Muslim leaders under one roof with hundred percent attendance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today on his 81st birthday, is it a very difficult task for the whole nation to promise to keep unity in its lines.</seg>
     <seg id="3">While eradicating the differences between other Muslims, the formation of an Islamic common wealth will be carried forward.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is a monster that has gripped Palestine for half a century.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This monster has many faces.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Many times, this monster criticizes itself from its own different mouth to divert the pressure and attention of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Its other mouths are eating humans in Iraq, Afghanistan, Iran and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This monster is most unhappy with Islam, because it knows that whenever it will be kicked out it will be through Islam. Muslims and the perfect religion of practical Islam, have put giants like Abu Jehl on the right path.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Bombing from Israeli fighter planes on Gaza has continued  since the 27th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="2">More than three hundred Palestinians have been killed in these attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="3">After the Arial attacks, Israeli tanks and armed vehicles have reached the Gaza border with complete preparation for a ground attack.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Through a unanimous resolution in an emergency meeting of the security council, the United Nations has demanded Israel and the Palestinian authorities to ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="5">However, the Israeli authorities say they will continue operation in Gaza until they make sure the rocket attacks on Israel have stopped.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In your opinion, is this claim by Israel true?  Is Israel  doing all this to defend its own sovereignty?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is the world community doing enough in this situation?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Does this aggression have any relation to the upcoming elections in Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Can any improvement be expected in the situation in the middle east after the newly elected American president Barak Obama takes office?</seg>
     <seg id="10">(Kindly note that due to the increase in number of reviews, only those typed in Urdu will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="11">To select Urdu, press Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Palestine will forever remain a sacred place for Muslims and its protection is a must for us.</seg>
     <seg id="2">and we should also remember that it is also our Qibla e Awwal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel and India have to vanish one day since these countries are destine to be broken.  God will surely torment these disbelievers. Sajid Sadiq, Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="4">"When has a lonely night passed merely by weeping? When has misfortune departed by praying only?" (Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
     <seg id="5">"When has a lonely night passed merely by weeping? When has misfortune departed by praying only?" (Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The BBC makes it a point to dig out and publish such accounts.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After all, they have to maintain the illusion of neutrality.</seg>
     <seg id="3">By the way, BBC news is factual, but an essential factor is the tone in which the news is delivered.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Which news to be made prominent and which news to be considered as insignificant.</seg>
     <seg id="5">etc. etc.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="7">Now even the electronic media and printed media of Pakistan, specifically a few Urdu newspapers and columnists, are not behind anybody else in exhibiting this skill-- who, while giving coverage of the increasing extremism and terrorism, and while writing about it, hide facts about the grudge mafia.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It has been said that the United Nations seemingly supports human rights and peace but actually the Muslims are being subjected to extreme levels of cruelty and brutality. And what we hear from the United Nations is that Hamas should stop the attacks. How long will this hypocrisy carry on?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why there is so much atrocity committed on Muslims. If people like Americans are backing up the Jews then Allah Almighty had said that this nation will live a shabby life and this nation can never live a right life. So, Americans, if you have courage then stop supporting them and see then what their fate is.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">So-called writers and murderers in name of peace should understand that peace in the world can only be obtained through justice not through genocide.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If any nations perish through genocide and results of choice can be obtained then after actions of Hitler, existence of Jews and their uprising was impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As poet says.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Atrocity is atrocity, it vanishes when it rises.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Blood is blood, clots when drop.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now who will tell whom what is terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Is this comes in terrorism, why? because own pain is only felt.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Other people are not humans or blood of Muslims is so cheap or color of these innocents' blood was not red?</seg>
     <seg id="4">And now why there is no condolence message coming from anywhere?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I saw Bombay blasts operation like this fire was in my own house. Can not see the sorrow of mankind. And can anyone not see this sorrow? Alas if Muslims would think as one.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I can not find the words that are strong enough to condemn the actions that resulted in the dead bodies on the road, and the helpless, injured, and innocent faces soaked in blood.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I feel like crying over the helplessness of the Muslims in this situation.  On the one hand, because of the killing in India the rest of the world comes over to Pakistan without any proof and asks to perform operations that we would normally do on our own.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the other hand, Israel is killing generations of muslims in front of everyone and the world is silent.  This is unbearable!</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is delay but NEVER in the house of God and only then will this darkness be shed. Then</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the presence of America, danger to the integrity of Israel is a joke.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Elections are important for securing the people's support, especially in countries like Israel, and rulers should continue to hold them.  However, history is the witness that no American leader has gone against the policy so Barrack Obama likely won't either.  Regime, whether black or white, is still a regime.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">From the debates in the forum it is evident that everyone is sad about Benazir's death, however we can not ignore her political mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">There's room for debate about whether Benazir gave her life for democracy or for power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If democracy was so dear then why did it take American involvement to end Musharaf's ten year dictatorship?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir did not come to Pakistan when the public needed her. Unfortunately, she came at a time when her acquittal from her cases and her supremacy was promised.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When each and every historic personality is being accused, there is no one to say anything about this.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="3">Few things are ignored thinking that nothing can be done about them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Another reader.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir, probably you should not only study Pakistan's history but that of 4 friends and 7 other countries. Maybe you would agree with Psycho's point of view.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tariq Ayaz</seg>
     <seg id="7">"Those who don't have a good nature can't be corrected through training."</seg>
     <seg id="8">Living green in the water made the reflection of the wheat plant look like a cypress.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Britain never let them unite and established the Hindu-Muslim conflict which was later on brought up by Sir Syed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">psycho</seg>
     <seg id="3">How brutal is our nation?  Not only we are blind while writing odes on ourselves and our parties, but now we are picking, accusing and criticizing every historical scholar and no body is there to say any thing about it.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Enough of development that we have made.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="6">Few things are ignored just by thinking that nothing can be done with them. Just like a donkey can not become a scholar by just loading books onto it.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Because of the Mumbai attacks, there has been a setback in the dialog between Pakistan and India.  However, Pakistan and India should continue these dialogs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If we talk of war then it will bring loss of life on both sides.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India says that the man caught in the Mumbai attacks is a Pakistani citizen and he has written a letter to Pakistan in Urdu.  On the other hand, when India initially apprehended this extremist, they said he is a great engineer.  Shortly afterwards he was declared as a 4th grader; point to be noted.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First of all Merry Christmas to Mr. Bhana and to all the Christian brothers of the forum.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Greeting to all friends of the Forum: Mr. Psycho, A. Raza, Sister Sana, Sister Shahida and Mr. Akram.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We do not want the flames of fire; but the flowers of peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">War itself is a problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Will war give a solution to our problems?</seg>
     <seg id="6">It will be blessed with fire and blood.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It will give hunger and exigence.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Therefore wise humans</seg>
     <seg id="9">It's better to avoid war.</seg>
     <seg id="10">In our yard.</seg>
     <seg id="11">It's better that the glim keeps lightened</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The India-America relations have deepened and India knows that when the time comes, America will openly betray Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is the history of America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the case of an Indian attack, America's goals will be fulfilled, and the expenses will be India's.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan should clearly announce that it will not start a conflict, but if a conflict is caused, there will be no talks of peace or truce. The war will not stop until India is completely destroyed or captured, even if it involves our own destruction.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is Islamic history.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Before the resolution, the message that had to be given by the public and the army was released.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In compensation for the Mumbai attacks, the abnormal diplomatic and military benefits that India tried to gain, made it more a victimizing party, than a victim. That is why, in contrast to the harsh initial global reactions, the world has now reduced their force on Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The satisfaction expressed by the United Nations over Pakistani efforts and the praise by the Interpol leader of Pakistani efforts, in disregard of India's commotion, shows the side effect of India's more than necessary diplomacy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no argument about the brutality of these actions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But the question is, when thousands of Taliban were attacking Pir Samiullah's town, where were the Pakistani Army, and what were they doing?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Should the army not be taken into account, for what they did there in a year?</seg>
     <seg id="4">How many Taliban die each day due to their firing of thousands of mortar and canon shells?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I appeal to the ICI that they stop their guardianship of the Taliban, for God's sake, and let us live peacefully in paradise like Swat,</seg>
     <seg id="6">and that they stop this fixed operation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The day is not far when a resolution will be passed in the United Nations against army intervention in Pakistan, the same way as it was passed against Jama'athud-Da'wah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Riyaz Ahmad Farooqi</seg>
     <seg id="3">First of all, our radicalism and our protecting them, is alone, sufficient to provide complete proof and permissibility for action against us. And the very day such a resolution is passed, there is all probability that no voice will be raised in our support, in the United Nations.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And supposing the passing of such a resolution is delayed, some other strength will definitely leave our aid to ourself,, keeping the example of America in front of them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We do not know about the personality and works of Pir Samiullah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Perhaps he was not a revolutionist.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The bodies of Comrade Che Guevara, Nawab Akbar Khan Bagti, Dr. Najibullah, and thousands of other revolutionists were dishonored at the hands of the enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are eternal even after death.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But here an international game is being played. Here ferocity and animosity are created to do the ruling.</seg>
     <seg id="6">So there can be reason created that if we are not here then these vandals and animals can come take over the government.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the name of religion, activities of these so-called Islam lovers is highly condemned.</seg>
     <seg id="2">America sees the torture of these extremists but instead of being sad about these faithless activities, they easily call them "tribal culture".</seg>
     <seg id="3">The reason for these faithless activities, sometimes given in the name of tribal culture and other times in the name of Islam, is not something done by a person with a heart.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, people of our army are with these people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">That is because when they change destination, it takes time. But to catch them, forget about getting there on time, even if they are on the spot, they leave from there.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are they so brave that they keep 50-70 people hostage and our army just watches it as spectators?</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are also men of God and so is our army.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is very clear that there is something fishy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Instead of promoting God's blessing and merciful nature, discussing various disastrous and lesson-gaining occurrences to create an air of fear and terror in the name of religion was being seen. Besides the event of hanging the dead body, their literature and books like "What Will Happen After Death" also create fear and terror.</seg>
     <seg id="2">These people are using this fear and terror as a shield for the purpose of obtaining world power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wiso!</seg>
     <seg id="4">You have scared the world with the fire of hell.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You, yourself, have become the reason for fear.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It comes as a surprise when it is said that this was not done by a Muslim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We are either unaware of our history or we choose to not know about it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who burned the closed door of the Prophet's daughter on the refusal of the oath after the Prophet passed away and who took her husband by the rope around his neck?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Did they come from abroad?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Was the attack of Yazid's forces on Medina not the act of Christians and the Jews?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Motives cannot be diminished and correcion cannot be made without accepting reality.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">O' BBC please stop this dual-headed policy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">better than this topic the super hit title: Shoe-ing of Bush fair or unfair?</seg>
     <seg id="3">'should have been</seg>
     <seg id="4">Tahir Choudhry, Japan</seg>
     <seg id="5">A human was pulled out of his grave and hanged over a pole just because he raised his voice against oppression, and you are concerned about the topic of the box office?  Please show some modesty.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the success of Operation Sherdil and Operation Lion Heart across the border depends on who is in the favor of public opinion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is an act of American and Pakistani agencies and Peer.  Sahab is a victim of this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now that secret agens have successfully joined the Taliban and they are doign what the can to change public opinion, all discussions on this forum will now be anti Taliban.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I only want to ask, when this body was hanging for a whole day, what was the army doing? Are they only there for targeting the public? They even report something like this: "Bombing of Taliban residences, a shell falling on a house kills two children and their mother".</seg>
     <seg id="2">Did they not know about this mistake?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Or were they watching the show?</seg>
     <seg id="4">We fold our hands and request them to please, for God's sake, stop this game.</seg>
     <seg id="5">After all, there is a ruler above you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Whether the question asked by BBC is understandable or not, it is saddening to see the lack of perspective of the writer. For instance, no one asked what the army of 30,000 in Swat went there to do.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The bodies of the Taliban who help the army are left hanging on poles throughout the day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Whatever the green footed Pakistani government did with the Swat public, the media, including BBC did not do good by keeping the world ignorant about the reality.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Pakistani Army is putting up a drama.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Every child in Swat is saying that this is a bloody drama.</seg>
     <seg id="6">For God's sake, stop this drama.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These Taliban members have tarnished the Muslim image.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If, around the world, true Muslims don't call these terrorists Muslims, then why are these elements able to live in the lands of true Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Those who become shameless can't do hard labor, and they pick up guns and become the members of terrorist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Islam did not spread on the point of a sword or barrel of a gun.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Feel the shame.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">No religion or family tradition allows this.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All the media, incl present their views on the Taliban or the tribal people in different styles.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No one, other than us tribal people, are aware of the ground realities, what the truth is, and what really is the matter.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In short, it's a game in which CIA, RAW, MOSAD and our own ISI are invloved. No one is a Talib or a tribal. Warmongers, who are against Islam, Taliban, Madrassa's, Pushtoon people, tribes and tribal traditions, made these institutions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This move has ashamed all Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I salute MQM's Altaf Hussain and the leadership of ANP and PPP who speak against this cancer that is the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This cancer is a product of Zia-ul-Haq, a man who died but also destroyed Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But I am hopeful that the current leadership will end this  cancer.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the Mumbai attacks, India said that extremists are behind the attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan rejected the accusations and said that it will help India in investigating the attacks in every possible way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India said that it has given a list to Pakistan that has 20 suspected extremists being sought by India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now Pakistan has said that included in the list is Jaish-e-Muhammad's Molana Azhar Masood, who is not in custody and the government of Pakistan has no information about him.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Before that, Pakistan President Asif Ali Zardari refuted the view that the West's secret agencies and the Indian government had given evidence related to the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">President Zardari has said that it has not been proven that Ajmal Kasab is a Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Prime Minister Manmohan Singh warned Pakistan that its relations with India are not going to improve until its land is ceased to be used for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In latest development, the Indian cricket team has cancelled their tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should sports be effected due to recent political events?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What future to you see for India-Pakistan relations?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Neither America nor India broke Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan was broken by the Pakistanis themselves.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What else could be expected after such regionalism, communalism and vandalism.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even Jinnah did not do good for the Muslims of India. Time has proved this.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Yasmin, Chicago</seg>
     <seg id="6">If we had kept working on the vision of Jinnah, destroying the cancer of communalism, then regionalism and vandalism would not have spread in Pakistan, and the Muslims of India would not have been treated poorly.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It's our fault that we could not bring up a leader of his stature.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If we can not care for our heroes, then</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">this region has great capabilities.</seg>
     <seg id="2">God knows when we'll understand and the region will progress with the blessing of unity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In both countries, enemies of peace like Mullas, Pandits, Taliban, Shiv sena, RSS have been raised.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The evil powers don't want this region to progress, therefore these countries are controlled like puppets.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can you imagine what status this region of Pakistan, India and China will have in the world?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Pakistan is under persecution from God that these thieves, bandits and criminals have been imposed as leaders of the nation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah protect our country from any harm, Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But sir, open your eyes to see the surrounding situation and reality on the ground, and you will figure out how far American forces have penetrated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Moreover, the internal affairs don't seem to be good, as you can see the circumstances in NWFP, Balochistan and in Karachi in Sindh.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In this situation the country needs such a leader who can unite us as one nation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">O Allah bestow your mercy upon us.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">According to my understanding, a final war is inevitable.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is enough of it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now it should be do or die.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This problem cannot be solved through these acts of insincere dialogues.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And not through small scale terrorism in each other's country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">After all, Europe got settled after the final world war.</seg>
     <seg id="7">And if this world war had not taken place, then these countries, just like Pakistan and India, would have been clattering.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Almost all of our political parties agree on this matter that these terrorist and denominational activities should be terminated from the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But our army rule does not seem sincere in this matter. On one hand, American and Europe are made to believe that we are with you on this war against terrorism and the other hand, we also help Taliban secretly.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We have to think now and decide our direction and only choose one way. Thank you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no doubt in this that majority of the members of Jamaat-ud-Dawa are the members of Lashker-e-Tayyaba, who joined  the party  named Jamaat-ud-Dawa Pakistan after Lashker-e-Tayyaba was invalidated.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Although these members preferred subsidiary activities and now after India's great persistence, The United Nation has invalidated it also and Government of Pakistan is continuing the crack down against them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, it is better if Jihadi groups leave religious extremism and continue religious and subsidiary activities.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Terrorist groups present in Pakistan, who support professional criminals and the heads of those Mullahs are those who call Pakistan the land of destruction and what not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And now they are doing everything to destroy Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In reality, they do not even deserve to be called human beings, let alone Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Without cleaning Pakistan from these evil doers, the country's existence will be in jeopardy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can we still afford to wonder whether we should ban these mutinous people or not?</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this world of callous leaders, there is no place for those whose work is only to kill.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This news breaks my heart to pieces.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What kind of world is this where it is hard to live for one who takes the name of one major pillar of Islam,  religion of Allah.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Non-Muslims can kill Muslims but when Muslims even try to take revenge, all our hypocrite leaders together with all the non-Muslim world treat people with the true and right pain of religion just like our great leader Hafiz Saeed is being treated today.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">India in impunity of Bombay attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan relations are bitter. The better relationship as a result of last few years between the two countries have been jolted greatly.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India has always held the military and non-military groups in Pakistan responsible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And putting the relationship back on track is being conditioned by operations against these groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Indian security departments have held Lashkher-e-Tayyaba responsible for the Bombay attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this case, the name of Jamat-ud-Dawa has come to the forefront many times.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the first time that relationship between both the countries has worsened due to terrorist activity in India.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In December 2001, after the attacks on the Indian Parliament, these two neighbors were on the brink of war.</seg>
     <seg id="9">After that, in 2002 Lashker-e-Tayyaba was banned and included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Now it is about Jamat-ud-Dawa, which Security analysts say that is in reality a new face of Lashker-e-Tayyaba. Restrictions on the party are being requested.</seg>
     <seg id="11">In your opinion, should this group be banned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Should Pakistan conduct decisive operations against extreme activists on its land?</seg>
     <seg id="13">By banning Jamat-ud-Dawa, can  the current Pak-India crisis be brought to a close?</seg>
     <seg id="14">And how important is it to close down the armed groups to keep constant peace between both countries?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Security Council of the United Nations has banned Jamat-ud-Dawa. After all, what proof does the Security Council have to decide this so quickly?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Does the Security Council always show urgency against the Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is what they call a slow complainant and a fast witness.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If you look at it, even India has become an unsuccessful country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whose intelligence, army and security institutes failed, and were forced to dance at the fingertips of a few terrorists for 72 hours? India. And they want to put the blame for it's inability on Pakistan, to fool the whole world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When one disbeliever dies, there is hue and cry in the whole world. Why these double standards?</seg>
     <seg id="2">To a non political, religious and social organisation of our dear country---</seg>
     <seg id="3">Furqan Farooq, Faisalabad</seg>
     <seg id="4">As long as our Prophet (PBUH), the Awliya Kiram and the Sufis, continued to teach people the lesson of love and respect, the religion of Islam would spread and prosper with peace.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Muslims have also advanced in every field.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But when there was a rise of Mullaism in the religion, there was a division of people into Muslims and Kafirs, and new avenues of mischief were opened, which were not known to the world previously.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salam: Please do it with pleasure but act on your own.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Do not do it under American pressure.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If India is aggrieved, it should provide the evidence.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why doesn't it give it?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And why does it accuse us of everything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">There are extremist groups and organizations in India as well. Why don't they put sanctions on them?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are we the only terrorist in the world?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What India is doing in Kashmir, what is that?</seg>
     <seg id="9">What Israel is doing, what is that?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The truth is, we are the first nuclear Muslim state. Why is this the main issue?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is now in the last stages.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Kamran Hassan, ABU DHABI</seg>
     <seg id="3">Your talk touches the heart.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now American magazines are very boldly printing the new map of Pakistan and all these sanctions seems to be part of this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">American are not slowly but now very swiftly tightening their grip on Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">We must remember that in these circumstances, if we as a nation dos not display unity and solidarity, then if Bangladesh can be created, anything can happen.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Terrorism is condemned, whether it is in a hotel in Mumbai or in a Marriott Hotel in Islamabad or in Palestine.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Likewise, regardless of the origin of the terrorists, they should be eliminated, whether they are Pakistani or Indian or American or Israeli.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now the question is that why the whole world, including Pakistani officials, are silent on the terrorist attacks that are conducted daily in Pakistan, resulting in the death of hundreds of people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Was the attack carried out on the Marriott Hotel not a terrorist attack?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Then why?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Hale to the adviser for interior Rehman Malik, how brave and bold the gentleman has become.</seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">Not only this; but according to BBC Mr. Malik has denied this impression with intensity. That the arresting of the terrorists has been carried out under "someone's pressure".</seg>
     <seg id="4">Wow, praise to the Almighty!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Whether having the ability to say that I don't want to or not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We, the Pakistanis, are fighting whose war?</seg>
     <seg id="3">We have our own interests which we shall do our best to protect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">No one has a right to interfere with anyone's national affairs.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The colonial system is apparently not there.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If people expect justice, demand that an external united court be established, respect democratic institutions, and not help any dictator or army man, there will be peace in the third world, including Pakistan. I do not believe this is acceptable by those calling for unity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As such, Pakistan is always following the goals set by Europe and America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This happens, despite the opposition of a majority of the Pakistani population.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And this causes more feelings of opposition.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If they trust America and the United republics, then let them leave the style of new populations, and let them work on those lines, upholding the sovereignty of the state.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan has the ability to arm and disarm.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Pakistan-occupied Kashmir, security forces captured a proved camp of practically non-existent Lashkar-e-Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Since the Mumbai attacks, pressure is increasing on Pakistan to act against the extremist organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India's accusation is that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
     <seg id="5">It is their claim that without a doubt, the extremists who carried out the Mumbai attacks used Pakistani land.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Meanwhile, officials in Peshawar claim that the lot of trucks which carry supplies to the united forces in Afghanistan was burned by unidentified armed people, because of which more than 50 trucks were destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the second attack in Peshawar on NATO and American supplies in the last 48 hours.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Meanwhile, Pakistan captured an established camp of the almost non-existent Lashkar-e-Taiba. Previously, lots of efforts were carried out to try to disarm groups all the way from Karachi to the tribal regions, which included giving compensation to those who returned their weapons and even assuring them that no action would be taken against them.</seg>
     <seg id="9">The situation is telling us that the efforts undertaken in the regime of General Ziyaul Haqq, after the previous Soviet Union's interference in Afghanistan to get rid of the armed groups that formed as a result of the resistance that started through American and Saudi funding, and to bring an environment similar to that before 1980 were not successful.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The question is what does Pakistan want to do?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Does Pakistan have the ability to do so?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Click here for details.</seg>
     <seg id="14">(Please note that since there is an increase in the number of comments, only those comments typed in Urdu will be published.)</seg>
     <seg id="15">For this, click Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard and select Urdu)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I have only one question for the standard bearers of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If you kill their children, will they come to give you garlands? It is impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4">And I ask you, does any science, from Islamic sciences to the sciences of the East and the West, any logic or philosophy, anywhere, give the permission to kill innocent people, including worshipers, laborers, and poor workers, in revenge for the American attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">If your answer is in negative, then you really need to fix your viewpoint.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The people were armed when there was the fear that Russia would head towards Pakistan after finishing Afghanistan, and that is why they were supplied with arms.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, when there is the fear that America will capture Pakistan, via Afghanistan, as the present American president has clearly mentioned in his presidential mission, why should we disarm them now?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Only such that after defeating the American or Indian army it does not have to face any resistance from the public?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Yes, if any of them are guilty of being involved in any destructive work, Pakistan can take action against them alone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is sad that the fact that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved, proves India's claim that Pakistan is guilty in this.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeebur Rahman Syco, Lahore</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even if we accept that Lashkar-e-Taiba is guilty, it's still not correct to blame the Pakistani government.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Another question is that were these terrorists supported by an Indian governmental or non-governmental agent?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are terrorists only born or trained in Pakistan, and not any other country in the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post63" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As for Lashkar-e-Taiba, the present terrorism is in no way connected to it.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It must be remembered that Hafiz Saeed is the first 'Jehadi leader' who called the Taliban actions 'mischief'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I'm sure that the Taliban effect is a inseparable result of American plans, and hence every person who can stand in the way of the Taliban must be removed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Despite the support of the whole nation, the fact that Zardari and co. took action against the Lashkar is a clear sign of their frigid and kiss-up nature.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To stop the project that is running on Saudi-American funding, they must be requested themselves to regather the filth that has polluted our society.</seg>
     <seg id="2">America and Saudi spread in our country dangerous weapons and so-called "Jihadi", which is in reality hate-inciting and cultural virus enticing literature. Our country has become a human slaughterhouse because of this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Due to the risk of attack from India, The Pakistani Army's announcement that it would remove forces from the Afghan border and post them at the Indian border, and the Taliban's announcement that it would handle the Afghan border caused America to stumble and pressure India not to attack Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This showed the strength of America in the region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Though India did not warn that they would attack, nor do they have that much courage.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Taliban attacked and finished most of the remaining American supplies.</seg>
     <seg id="5">That proves that without the Pakistani Army and tha Pakistani government, America is nothing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Karachi is the trade and financial center of Pakistan, and the Dubai of the backward regions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Hundreds of thousands never return from here empty handed, but ever since the law and order situation in the western border regions was lost, all people diverted their attention here.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now they want to kidnap this city.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pathans are now called Pukhtons, made foreigners, and forced to fight, while the need in Pakistan is for unity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One solution to the problem is to have the Urdu speak or learn Pushto or the Pushto to speak or learn Urdu. Alternatively, it would be best for everybody to learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You must be thinking its a funny suggestion, but don't you think the cause of the conflict is also funny?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The cause of the torture is language.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir in my childhood I had actually given the same suggestion many times to my friends ,which included people from every religion and rhetoric groups, but people used to laugh over these suggestions.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At that time, these rhetoric and religious differences were not that evident but they were boiling up inside.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is hard to understand what is happening and why.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are these the signs of judgement day?</seg>
     <seg id="3">What are these innocent and innoxious people being killed for?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The reason is in front of everyone; there are those who want to break Pakistan into pieces and those who do all this neither belong to this religion nor this country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whether it be Karachi or Mumbai, the house was burnt by the houses own lanterns</seg>
     <seg id="6">Whichever government comes, it only changes the names of the places and starts working for fame, just like how nowadays, the airports, roads and buildings are all Benazir.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Does Benazir mean that is what is happening to the public of Karachi and Pakistan?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At the height of the Mumbai attacks, efforts to cause mischief on linguistic and racial lines in Karachi failed, which is proof that those politicians working on racial parole have resigned from their jobs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The taking of the lives of innocent Pushtu speaking laborers, and the Indian warnings have awakened the sleeping Pakistani feelings from Karachi to Khyber.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The identical country loving reaction of all the political, religious, linguistic and national parties has not only taught India the manners of diplomacy, but it has also given the American policy makers a chance to think again.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The responsible parties for the worsening situation in Karachi are the United and the ANP. The government is taking sides.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The government can control the situation in one hour, but it is purposely allowing it to grow.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The police and rangers are avoiding action because of the pressure on them by the political parties.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The talk of uniting is only restricted to speeches. The political parties should leave their interests and work for the interest of the common man.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Until pressure is put on the administration, these kinds of incidents will keep taking place.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I think these people are terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Foreign powers are definitely involved in this, but no one knows who they are.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If these incidents were in any city of NWFP, then what would the government have done over there?  Because it's not in NWFP, the government seems to be helpless.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government should operate here and save a large and very important city from terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">otherwise Pakistan will face a huge financial crisis.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC Urdu is also not writing the truth under pressure, and Pakistani media's condition is already weak.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The whole truth is on BBC English.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One solution to the problem is that either Urdu speakers should learn Pushto, or Pushto speaking learn Urdu, or better if every body learns English.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You will definitely take this as a funny suggestion, but don't you think the cause of the conflict is also funny?</seg>
     <seg id="5">The reason for persecution may be language.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Another story of murder has finally been published in Karachi, which was being dreaded by all the citizens for a long time.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The criminals do not let go any opputunity of a crime. The news reports and the media are only telling 50% of what actually happened here in 4 days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We have spent the last three nights without sleeping and the fear is still there.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Those who make the people evacuate hotels, those who kill the shoe-makers and the peanut-sellers.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Those who rob and kill at the Super Highway, and cut off the ears of innocent citizens, they are ignorant of the wrath of Allah which will eventually entrap them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What could be the reasons of this sudden turmoil in your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="2">(B.B.C)</seg>
     <seg id="3">Keeping in view, the gruesome bloodshed event in Mumbai, we do not need to delve deep into the matter to find the reason of disorder in Karachi. It is simple and easy to guess that the turmoil is just due to an unconcious trade of blood.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Obviously if somebody infuriates a father, it would not be surprising if the son reacts violently.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The blood of the loyalists of Liaqat Ali Khan also belonged to the same place, but to eliminate Mr. Psycho's misunderstanding I am writing this verse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We will also repeat our elders traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We made it by sacrificing lives, and will save it by doing the same.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Faizan Tauseef Siddiqui</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is very disappointing that the whole country is at stake and we are fighting with each other.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mr. Siddiqui, I request if wikipedia.</seg>
     <seg id="7">See Liaqat Ali Khan, you will find out that he belonged to a noble Punjabi family from Karnal, in Punjab.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Due to his steps for the migrants, today the migrants consider him as one of them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is always a reaction to every action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">One can afford on oneself.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Ejaz Aiwan</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sir, before you gather a huge crowd very quickly, I should tell you that you are finding the graffiti of real gangsters these days on the walls of Karachi in the form of wall chalking and posters.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We have been tolerating both kinds of actions.</seg>
     <seg id="6">These thugs did not even forgive Pakistan and the founder of Pakistan. They did not face any reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="7">On the contrary, we are writing our hearts on the chest of Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One Muslim League Q was left, and even they made a draft of the 18th amendment and gave it to the People's Party.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Before this, MQM and Muslim League Q made and submitted a draft of the 18th amendment to the National Assembly and the Senate.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Until now it seems that drafts of the 18th amendment are a political trick and no one is sincere in getting this amendment approved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the reason why no one has made a fuss in the assembly or senate floor in favor of this amendment, nor has anyone forced the assembly to approve this change.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It seems like after submitting the drafts of the 18th amendment, these parties have done their part. That is, they will be able to say tomorrow that they submitted the draft and the government speaker did not take any action.</seg>
     <seg id="6">How is it possible that MQM coalition partner of the government, Muslim League N an underhand ally of the government and Muslim league Q the party to approve the seventeenth amendment be sincere enough to approve the disapproved amendment?</seg>
     <seg id="7">It's just like writing your name amongst Shaheeds by just putting color on yourself.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The People's Party is not in a hurry to dismiss the seventeenth amendment anyways.</seg>
     <seg id="9">What would one think of getting his own hands cut?</seg>
     <seg id="10">As long as Zardari is the president, the seventeenth amendment is not going to be canceled.</seg>
     <seg id="11">This is the opinion of the majority in our survey takers and so is deemed to be the truth.</seg>
     <seg id="12">If the seventeenth amendment had been canceled then Zardari would never had become the president.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Now he is even more powerful than President Musharaf because along with being the president he is also the chairman of the People's party.</seg>
     <seg id="14">As long as he is the president, the seventeenth amendment will remain intact.</seg>
     <seg id="15">In order to cancel the seventeenth amendment, the political parties will first have to dismiss President Zardari from the presidency.</seg>
     <seg id="16">Neither MQM nor other parties want this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Most of the elders from our family belonged to the labor community.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In our childhood, when we used to see our uncles doing labor work, we used to pray to Allah to save us from this hard work.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To avoid this, we wrote a letter to the editor of the daily Amroz and asked him what we should we do after matriculation so that we don't have to do labor work.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The editor wrote in reply that we should select certain subjects and become doctors or engineers.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Right from beginning, my trend was towards engineering. I had selected technical drawing instead of Biology as well.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But at the time of admission in F.Sc. my elder brother forced me to become a doctor after doing F.Sc. in medical.</seg>
     <seg id="7">I studied biology for a month and then took math as an alternate subject when nothing worked out.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The fear of labor work made me an engineer and now I am in a better position than other in my family, for which I am always thankful to God.</seg>
     <seg id="9">I remembered that when my two sons and I were trying to remove the carpets from our old house.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It was only half an hour since he started working that the little boy said, "Daddy, I am not born to do this".</seg>
     <seg id="11">I said that if this is true, then study a lot like us and get rid of the physical labor.</seg>
     <seg id="12">The son said, "I am studying and I will get through it, but it is the work that I cannot do".</seg>
     <seg id="13">We did that work in three hours and came back home.</seg>
     <seg id="14">The point of this story is that if a person picks his destiny, whatever is the reason behind it, no one can stop him from achieving that destiny.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Here if you do not know what you have to do then may God help you!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is said that you should not say bad things about the dead, but what shall we do? We see only bad things in Benazir, even on the anniversary of her first death.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir, for her selfish purpose, crushed the independence movement of the Sikhs after giving the list of the names of those who were fighting for freedom. On the other hand, she gave India the chance to keep its full attention on Kashmir after helping to suppress the Punjab movement.</seg>
     <seg id="3">A tug-of-war between Benazir and Nawaz Sharif rule is part of the history and has pushed the country back many years.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir continued to give negative comments on Kashmir and the nuclear program after being exiled.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Benazir violated the London agreement with Nawaz Sharif and made a deal with General Musharaf.</seg>
     <seg id="6">During her rule, Benazir gave a free hand to her husband to make money. That is why he is known as "Mr. Ten Percent".</seg>
     <seg id="7">During Benazir's rule his brother got killed, but his murderers are still safe from any punishment.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Although she was a woman herself, Benazir avoided fighting for women's rights.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Just as Benazir conducted her politics over her father's dead body, similarly her widower is doing the same over her dead body.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Benazir came into power twice, but she could not punish the culprits of her father's political murder. Even she couldn't register a case against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It has been 37 years since East Pakistan separated from us, but look at the extreme of senselessness of our people and leaders that we never celebrate the mourning day.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What should have happened instead is that we should have celebrated December 16 as a didactic day and take measures to ensure that this kind of incident doesn't happen again.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On this day, we can send greetings to the people of Bangladesh and try to bring them closer to ourselves again.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The rulers would reopen the Hamudur Rehman commission reports and discuss the reasons for the separation of East Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They used to make arrangements to bring back the Bahari's stuck in Bangladesh and send them presents to raise their spirits.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But we lack feelings now. We are not even aware if someone dies in our neighborhood.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We do not care about our brothers and sisters because we have become selfish.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Even if a great accident occurs, we are busy in our daily routines.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If only East and West Pakistan could be one together just like East and West Germany was united once again.</seg>
     <seg id="10">We can be one again if we both sacrifice for each other and come out of the hole of selfishness.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But this wish does not seem to be granted in the near future.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It was announced today that the governor of Illinois was arrested on corruption charges.</seg>
     <seg id="2">When the state Congress started getting ready to remove him from the position of the governor as soon as possible, then there is this one American companion who has a close watch on the circumstances of Pakistan, boastfully claimed to us that this is what we call democracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In America, even the higher level people can not transcend the law.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And there is your country, whose President was made after he had the corruption charges dropped.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We felt our nerve of wit and said, "what if a governor was arrested in America?  In our Pakistan our Prime Minister was once arrested during the night and was hanged.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tell me if anything like this has happened in America.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan awarded Guard of Honor and bid farewell from the President's house, who broke the law of the country. Tell me if anything like this has happened in America.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Chief Justice of Pakistan was laid off in such a way that even after the nations support, he has not yet been reinstated. Tell me if anything like this has happened in America.</seg>
     <seg id="9">In Pakistan, a fake degree holder was appointed as Health Minister. Tell me if anything like this has happened in America.</seg>
     <seg id="10">After listening to this, the poor American could not stop laughing and also accepted defeat.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In this picture, President Zardari is smiling even after being surrounded by Americans from all sides.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It seems from his smile</seg>
     <seg id="3">America is with his government. But he is forgetting that last year, the same people were with Parvez Musharaf.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The picture looks like that of a family.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Before that no picture as such has been published in which the President is in the company of 3 American authorities.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Look like that America's work has been increased in Pakistan and one and more Authorities are working on it or they might not believe that person as compared to the first one.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It might be possible that they have planned this also, keeping in mind President Zardari's promise of fulfillment.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Had he been an intelligent politician then he  would be at least not been smiling in this picture and his face would show some signs of embarrassment.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If the principle of democracy applied on this picture than President Zardari is in Minority</seg>
     <seg id="10">In Democracy Majority rules the Nation and who are they picture is showing</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The  Swat ares of Pakistan is like heaven on earth and is also known as Switzerland.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Till now, according to the Government Policy, cross talks are  going along together with the use of power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the use of power is resulting in increasing the power of Taliban and increasing sympathy for Taliban.It is also not providing any benefits.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government must, instead of using the power, eliminate the causes of the issue.</seg>
     <seg id="5">by eliminating the causes, Fazlullah and Taliban will automatically disperse.</seg>
     <seg id="6">the Sharia bill proposed by ANP will, to a great extent, become the solution of the problems of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="7">But besides implementation of the Sharia, the government will have to give more attention to the economical issues.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At the beginning of General Musharaf rise, it looked like the nation had rid itself of the incompetent politicians, but the lust for power changed all his plans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">all the hopes were from the participation in the "War of terror", he had started considering himself immortal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">those steps which were expected, all broke-off.</seg>
     <seg id="4">as soon as Bush's era came close to an end he started worrying about the end of his rule and in that bewilderment, made a deal with the thieves.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Even then General Musharaf could control the Army but never know what wass happening to the present government.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Either its Bajor or Swat, the army does not control terror but bombs the ""Enemy"" public; along with loss of lives and wealth if you make the enemy a mentally sick, then aren't we the Enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Swat, the strongly affected part of Sarhad state, despite the continuity of military action for over one year, the situation is still going from bad to worse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On one side, the government is only reiterating the passing of a reproachful resolution in the national assembly. On the other side, the Taliban's illegal radio FM channel is having much more influence in the region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the third side, the common man considers it safest to listen to the one who actually has control over the region.</seg>
     <seg id="4">During the action of the security forces, there were claims of destroying the fundamentalists by the bombing of gun ship helicopters and cannon houses, but despite these destructions, the Taliban only became more powerful, and according to an estimation, their control over Swat increased that much more.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a result, on the one hand the government is not ready to accept defeat, and on the other hand the Taliban is getting stronger.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Who are stuck in between? The poor civilians.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is said in Swat, that someone asked what kind of people the Taliban were, so he got the answer, 'They are very good, as they are protectors of the religion and they fight against the enemies of Allah and the religion'.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Then he asked how the army was, so he got the answer, 'They are very good, as they are the protectors of the country and they fight against the enemies of the country'.</seg>
     <seg id="9">He then asked who the enemies of the religion and the country were, so he got the answer, 'We civilians'.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I am wondering how the Pakistani Army will fight the Indian Army, when they couldn't control a small faction of the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They could not track the illegally set up FM channel of the Taliban, which I believe was very easy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But still, the FM channel is spreading poison with vigor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First the girls' schools and now boys' schools are being destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Curfews are called so that the Taliban can move around easily.</seg>
     <seg id="6">During curfew tonight, eight trucks entered the outskirts of Mengorah and formed barriers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The question arises as to how they got there despite the curfew.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The army could kill Akbar Bugti in his house, but salutes the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="9">For God's sake, can someone convince the army to save the poor public from the grip of the Taliban and prove that the army can defeat any enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">You say that mostly blood is spilled in the world because of religion. Tell me, if there was no religion today, would all this killing not take place?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are Punjabi, Pathan, White, Black, Mahsood and other tribes the result of religion?</seg>
     <seg id="3">No! No way! Sir, religion is what teaches that no one is black or white, punjabi or muhajir. Otherwise, if religion was not present then half world would have vanished for the war between white and black and other half fighting over the status and sect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Actually, religion gives moral teachings to the man. And binds him that he is not here on his own choice but the creator of the universe has sent him here. And he should spend his life according to his rules.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a Muslim, I have total faith that Islam is a complete way of life and a true religion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After living in London, for many years I used to ask wellness of my family over the telephone every morning, although many did not even call once to find out how we were. It was then I realized that they do not even tolerate our phone calls so we stopped calling.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Living here in France for the last two years, I have also felt the same thing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I do not know why people expect us to call.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A resolution passed about Iraq in a few hours, Darfar has absolutely no problem in sending peace army.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Bombay attacks were condemned in no time and banning dubious groups is only a matter of a few hours.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And where death is dancing, we are doing consensus.</seg>
     <seg id="4">O caretakers of international peace, life is finishing here!</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is it for real that every one is waiting for it to end?</seg>
     <seg id="6">So that no other victim will even think about using a great damage causing weapon like a gun to fight for his rights?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Doesn't your heart ache whenever a father runs holding his son's dead body?</seg>
     <seg id="8">If no, then you have no right to be called a human being.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But you are a shame to humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At least it was proven that this area was Israel's country for thousands of years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What should happen is that both the nations should live together happily and with love. But since they are controlled by either west or arab countries,  peace therefore,  cannot be formed here without their consent.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But even Iran wants to fight its proxy war right now.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even if operations in Israel are halted for the time being, they will start again after another incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The interest of BBC's country is subject to the bestowing of America and Israel. And this is the reason why in the name of ""enlightenment"", they have come with a series of blogs based on ""darkness"" and doing one-way and a blind propaganda.</seg>
     <seg id="2">BBC is only completing a formality, and its goal and intent is to gather well wishes.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I request the moderator to publish this comment of Fidwi, so it be known that at least a little bit of affinity towards truth is still remaining in BBC</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thank You.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I don't know who wrote this story or how this story came to being, but one thing is for sure, in every age, Dracula's have been drinking the blood of innocent people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In every age, wars have been fought and blood has been spilled.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the surprising thing is that this 21st century man, who considers himself civilized, is quiet over this ruthless open massacre.</seg>
     <seg id="4">How could I not feel that whatever is happening is presenting a very ugly picture of mankind.</seg>
     <seg id="5"></seg>
     <seg id="6">Well wisher, Sajjad Alhasnain, Hyderabad, Deccan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At this time, including Derah Gahzi Khan, summer showers are taking place throughout the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Here is a poem according to the weather. Enjoy the weather along with this poem.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These rains are with your presence.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If it rains, it's spring.</seg>
     <seg id="5">If it stays, then it's peace.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Sometimes it comes without a reason.</seg>
     <seg id="7">At times it spreads over day and night.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Sometimes very noisy and sometimes very quiet.</seg>
     <seg id="9">These rains are with your presence.</seg>
     <seg id="10">In a memory, at night.</seg>
     <seg id="11">To buried ash.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sometimes the wind put it out.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Sometimes it burned itself.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Sometimes each drop seems sorrowful.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Even these rains are from you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All these rulers are going to run away carrying a suitcase. What it means to them is whether the country lasts or not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whether the public sells scrubs or takes lemon peels and scrubs the temple bells with them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our media is corrupted, like our leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It's goal is only to extract money from the government and nothing else.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As for the public, they are ignorant. To speak about them is the biggest ignorance.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Yesterday afternoon something surprising happened.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All of the policemen are running here and there, but aren't asking about illegal parking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What's more, NYPD traffic was not in the state where it could look at illegally parked vehicles.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What happened was, a plane of the US Air transformed into a ship and landed in the Hudson river.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Until now, we only know that terrorists are descendants of geese.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It was historically cold in New York yesterday.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The temperature usually does not drop like this.</seg>
     <seg id="8">My jaws began to hurt from my thirty minute walk.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Imagine, how the people who jumped from the plane into the water felt.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It is a matter of happiness that all people were safe.</seg>
     <seg id="11">It was also sad that the company's plane sunk during this financial crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="12">I went by the West Side Highway to New Jersey, watching all this, and I saw that Southbound was blocked, but what did I still do?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Yes, I got stuck in the same rush on the way back.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Thankfully, during my one-hour trip the way had opened at least a bit, so I was able to use the 56th street exit.</seg>
     <seg id="15">When I saw the lines waiting at them, I had not taken the previous two exits.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Makki, My Pakistan: Well, Congratulations, Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ammar: Of course, believing women.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Shaguftah: Well, Congratulations, Eid Mubarak, to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sarah: I have slaughtered two chickens and how they are slaughtered and Jahanzeb has already mentioned how I did it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Apart from this, there is no other way to do it.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At this farm one has to get his own meat done, including removing the skin.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Bossom: It may take some time for the dot net to get fixed</seg>
     <seg id="8">What happened on the forum?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Linko.</seg>
     <seg id="10">To fight with the "Listen to the blog", use Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Duffer: Khair Mubarak! Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sir please use Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="13">It will snow till it disappears.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">For no reason had we thought that the Taliban group from Sawat was non religious, who were only against women education.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They were expressing this irritation by demolishing schools and colleges for women every day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But like majority of the ideas, this was not proven right also. According to this news of CNN, on the lucky day of Monday, a group of Taliban demolished a Boys school with gunpowder.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Taliban has destroyed a boys school in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The girls schools were already destroyed, acting according to the famous English saying "Ladies First".  I do not know why people are still bent on calling the Taliban uncultured and barbaric.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Another thing that becomes clear from this is that the accusation of the Taliban being against girls education is not true.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Rather, they are against education altogether.</seg>
     <seg id="8">May Allah give these Mujahideen more power, and the evil government less.</seg>
     <seg id="9">May He help them in uprooting the evil government.</seg>
     <seg id="10"></seg>
     <seg id="11"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">Just before this, the wedding between a dog and a girl took place.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Look at that groom.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Humanity is still a rarity in the twenty first century.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the era of computers and its involvement is ever increasing in every sphere of life.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have reservations over this increasing involvement of the computer in financial matters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Where use of credit cards bring ease to life, it also gives better control to law enforcement agencies over your private life.</seg>
     <seg id="4">So that now, you can be located by transactions from your credit card.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And in future when use of real currency will reduce to a great extent, its benefits will increase more and more.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Similarly in the world of crimes, instead of playing with the dangers of robbing a bank, it is easier to steal credit card information.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Similarly computers have become the source of friendship.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Social networking sites such as Orkut, Facebook and Myspace have achieved an initial level of acceptance.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Yet, do you think it's possible that the more we use these social networking sites, the further we distance ourselves from people in real life?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Also consider match-making websites, where your preferences are matched to a list of people with similar desires as you.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But do you want to live with a person who is just like you?</seg>
     <seg id="12">I know that I would not want to.  Why else would a spouse be called the better half</seg>
     <seg id="13">unless they can get rid of the faults within me?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Perhaps I have some good sense.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I used to believe that anything that someone older than me said was true.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the same way, I thought my father knew the answer to every question on earth.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I even used to get laughed at a lot for this.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But only what is possible seems true.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It is very troubling that lies need to be told.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Even at this age, he was harmed by this.</seg>
     <seg id="8">That is why I try to lie as least as possible.</seg>
     <seg id="9">that I do not falsely please others in the name of Allah.</seg>
     <seg id="10">And that I say, "Insha Allah", (If God Wills) only when I am asking Allah to complete the work.</seg>
     <seg id="11">As for the intentions, only Allah knows best.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a despicable matter that arose due to distance between religions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to both our religions and Pakistani law, young children should stay with their mothers.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Their expenses are to be borne by the father, and the father can meet his children.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Then when they become mature, they can live with whom they want.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The actual problems are the relatives who misguide them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Feudalism has overshadowed our deeds.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Even here is thinking is prevailing that there will be more partners in father's property so it is resisted, although this act of the father is commendable should be imitated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These restrictions regarding relations have created many evils in society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Concept of remarriage of a divorced women, or a widow is becoming rare.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Due to these unnecessary beliefs and traditions, the family system is facing disarray.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Why is it in our society, if a wife of a 50 or 55 years old man dies or a husband of wife passes away and they remarries, it is not appreciated?</seg>
     <seg id="2">A Pakistani uncle near us whose wife died a good 10 or 12 years ago,  had all his children married, but when he married a widow, his own children went against him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, this is due to religion, is it not?</seg>
     <seg id="4">What type of mentality is the "'while we are there, no one can take our mother's place" kind of mentality?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I believe that this person's children should have thought what's wrong if he married a widow after he married off all his children?</seg>
     <seg id="2">This widow also got support and the uncle also got someone to look after the house.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As the children would get busy in their own worlds and would not be able to give time to him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The reason for this is ignorance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Tomorrow, if their wives refuse to look after them when they are old, what will they do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is a result of the force of society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When people begin to make fun of such a family for doing something like that, children start to feel ashamed of their father's second marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Though they should face the environment and say that their father's action is in perfect accordance with Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is the curse of our society we are facing for the last 40-50 years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is acceptable for a wife to not let her husband marry another women, even if he commits crimes.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If it's in her power, she will not let him do so even after she dies.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Destroys her afterlife along with her husband's, while spreading immorality in the society.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Nothing happens with singing about Islam. We actually like what our traditions and cultures are.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For example, preventing girls from being educated, and fear of love and marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And about your question, when a man instead of bringing his wife home goes to someone else's wife, the dependents just make a fuss for the show then stay quiet and satisfied. (Later the relatives of the wife get angry.)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Indian subcontinent, we accepted Islam centuries ago but we still thought of culture and tradition as being more valuable than Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In this way of thinking a man's 2nd marriage is considered ridiculous, divorce is seen as denigration, the divorced are untouchable, love in marriage is dishonorable, and a man marrying an older woman is devaluation of women.    Considering man's 2nd marriage as ridiculous, divorce as denigration, divorced as untouchable, love marriage as dishonor and considering a man marrying an older women is dissimulation of the women is only the result of this way of thinking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">By copying the western world we are declaring the religious and veiled to be old fashioned.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Accepting Islam was easy, but getting rid of the old ways of thinking is very hard.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Allah grant us all spirit and courage for this.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Writing Urdu was never so difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Centuries passed with such little writing.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Know that little is much.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Allah Hafiz</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Ameer Taimoor in his book "I am Taimoor" writes, "I found this secret in my life that if the leader of any army is in the front line then that army will never lose."</seg>
     <seg id="2">But that's not the situation here.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They say that common people are there to die for us and they die as martyrs.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But when the common man dies it's murder.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah bless and have mercy on you.</seg>
     <seg id="2">When I was coming back to the shop after Isha prayer tonight, one man who was sitting in his car raised his hand and asked me to come.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I thought maybe this man has forgotten his way or maybe he wants to ask something. I stopped, and his whole family was in his car.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He asked if I can understand Arabic very well or not. I said that there is no problem. You can tell me what is the matter.</seg>
     <seg id="5">He started saying, I have come from Riyadh but here some one in Medina picked my pocket and I need help. I said no, because this has happened with me earlier also as I gave this man 20 riyals to pay for gas and go back to Riyadh but he started doing the same thing after moving forward a little.</seg>
     <seg id="6">I got really angry and when I threatened to tell the police, he vanished.</seg>
     <seg id="7">So now this is the condition of us Muslims that even when we come to beg money, we come with families riding in cars and daily manage to get at least 2 or 3000.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Although there is an saying of the Prophet (P.B.U.H) that the hand above is better than the hand below and the hand above is the giving hand the lower is the taking hand.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Allah have mercy on us and make us true Muslims (Amen)</seg>
     <seg id="10">Wassalam</seg>
     <seg id="11">Javed Iqbal</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The wife of the famous singer Adnan Sami went to a police station in Bombay accusing him of torturing her.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The police station suggested for her to contact a court.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Adnan Sami's wife, Saba Guladari, submitted a plea against her husband stating that Adnan Sami tortures her continuously.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and treats her inhumanely.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This has exceeded her tolerance limit, therefore a case should be recorded against Adnan Sami.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Police, instead of recording a report, suggested that she should contact the court by saying that this matter is not what is covered under police control.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In your opinion, is the accusation of Adnan Sami's wife on him correct?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What if this accusation is an attempt of tarnishing the name of Adnan Sami?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Let us know of your comments regarding this matter.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Adam Sanghar, Mehr.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As far as allegations are concerned, anyone can post it on someone else.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Nothing comes before prestige.</seg>
     <seg id="4">however may be the relations between Adnan Sami and his present wife, he left his respectful life and went to India to make money and now this fame has caught him badly.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is a consequence of his own deeds.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Washington...</seg>
     <seg id="2">Top American officials say that president Obama will take a strict stance over Afghan president Hamid Karzai.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the new American policy over Afghanistan there is more emphasis on war than development.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Officials say that Hamid Karzai is considered to be a hurdle in the achievement of American goals Since in his government, there is corruption, drugs business has increased and Taliban are regaining their power.</seg>
     <seg id="5">American officials say that people, who are putting more pressure on Hamid Karzai to do more, include vice president Joe Biden and President Obama's representative for Afhanistan and Pakistan Richard Holbrooke.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that this good administration was noticed after President Bush left, who used to have a video conference with Hamid Karzai every 2 weeks, which used to emphasize the role of America in Afghanistan and the development of its city departments.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Officials say that the Obama administration will work with state leaders as a backup to the main government.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Officials say that they will emphasize to Hamid Karzai the importance of fighting against corruption.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Hamid Karzai faces new elections this year. It is not yet clear whether Obama and his administration will favor his re-election or not.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Is this statement of the American officials a forecast of change in America's policy regarding Afghanistan?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Is this era of Hamid Karzai ending?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What are your thoughts in this matter?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the series of three one-day matches between Pakistan and Sri Lanka, Sri Lanka defeated Pakistan with a score of 2-1.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan defeated Sri Lanka in the first day's match, but Sri Lanka won the next two matches.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the third match, the nation's team performance was very poor. They scored only 75 runs in 23 overs against 309 runs made by the national team of Sri Lanka, and this is how we were defeated.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The result of the series proves that the National team has no consistency in its performance.</seg>
     <seg id="5">besides the home ground and all claims, the national team was defeated, what are the reasons of this in your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Which facets of the game should be addressed most by the authorities?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are you satisfied with the selections for the team?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Which department would you hold responsible for the defeat- the fielding, batting or bowling department?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Please provide your feedback.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Babar Hussain, Judah, it is very disappointing that even today these kinds of heathenish traditions continue to occur. These feudal lords target innocent people using their authority, who would call them Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="2">A Sardar, himself should walk over these embers. Why doesn't the present government act against them?</seg>
     <seg id="3">When will the judicial justice be of use?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370243-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Shrilanken cricket team has arrived Karachi to play One Day internationals.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Besides the Indo-Pak sullenness, a visit by a foreign team to Pakistan is very pleasing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Upon reaching the Karachi airport, the Srilankan team was very warmly welcomed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Two one days between Pakistan and Srilanka in Karachi, whereas the third one day will be played in Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Both teams have there claims over bowling, batting and fielding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If the Srilankans are proud of their spinners, the Pakistanis trust their fast bowlers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Srilankan Captain Mahela Jayvardena has said that not a single player but the whole team from Pakistan is dangerous</seg>
     <seg id="8">Murli dharan and Mendis will be the trump cards whereas the Pakistan Captain says that it will be a tough competition.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Shoaib Malik has said that "We have played Murli dharan and we'll see Mendis as well. We have prepared a secret game plan and we shall implement that in the ground"</seg>
     <seg id="10">Will the Pak-Srilanka Series be really as interesting and exciting as they claim are?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Who will dominate the series between Pakistan and Srilanka?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Who will win the series?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Who will be the man of the series?</seg>
     <seg id="14">Give your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Gulpham, London, publishes his own views and you also prefer these views. I wish you would also write some truth, and not change your words like Mukherjee, because the order is to speak the truth in front of a tyrant king, and this is equivalent to Jihad. What should be said of Mukherjee, he tries to change his statements and stay in the news.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Yusuf, Dubai.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Kashmiri people have been fighting for independence for the last 60 years.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, no one asked, and they are now stuck in their war of extremism and terrorism, so they start talking about making up.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First they openly killed the Muslims, now they are trying to set things right.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Anyway, Pakistan will have to understand their double edged policies.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Asad Khan, London.</seg>
     <seg id="2">India is creating such a situation so that the world's attention can be diverted from Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But Pakistan has always shown the real face of India to the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now the British Government is also understanding that the Indians are taking cover from their occupation over Kashmir by accusing Pakistan of terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They hesitate to talk to Pakistan about this issue.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">British foreign minister David Milliband has said that resolving the issue of Kashmir will bring an end to extremism, and the government of Pakistan will effectively handle the threats rising on the borders.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It should be clear that newly-elected American President Obama has also expressed similar views about the Kashmir dispute.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The British foreign minister has written in an article and told the media that the idea of the war against terror is wrong and killing people just for the threats to one self was the policy of President Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="4">David Milliband has said that Pakistan should not be lenient with the extremist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Due to the stress over the need for resolution of the Kashmir dispute from the major powers, isn't India trying to divert the attention from this issue by creating unrest in the region?</seg>
     <seg id="6">isn't the terrorism in Mumbai a part of this strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is India using terrorism as a base to escape from comprehensive dialog?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Let us know of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Usman Aftab,</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think the big powers do not want to harm Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rather it wants to keep it in check, and hence is thinking of taking certain steps. They know that Pakistan is a nuclear state.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They want to bring about some kind of revolution here.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Foreign countries are only thinking that if they corner Pakistan, they would face some political and geographic problems. They want to help Pakistan, but also want to be successful in their goal.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A citizen, USA.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It has always been a Hindu tradition, that in the side is a knife, and on the mouth is Ram.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I think that they get stomach aches over small issues and begin to warn Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are ready in all ways, the Indian Chief of Army should keep his mouth shut or else, we know how to give mouth breaking anwers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Faheem Siddiqi</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ras al Khaima, This conversation is going on due to American mischief. America's mind was already spoiled, but they  know India is also becoming like that. Let them attack, and they will see the reality, as to who is now deep waters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel is attacking Hamas, but no one has the courage to stop it. Watching Israel, India also wants to do all that.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Prime Minister, Syed Raza Yusuf Geelani said that the newly elected American vice president, Joe Biden, played an important role in removing the ex-president Musharraf's uniform and replacing it with a lame democracy, which is why the Pakistani government has honored him with a special star.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The credit for removing the uniform and replacing the democracy should not go to any political party. The Parliament is not a rubber stamp.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All decisions will be made in the parliament.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Prime Minister said that Qadeer's door was closed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In your opinion, do the public protests against Mina Marriot not mean anything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Has the lawyers movement not played any role?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you have to say about this statement, in regards to the Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Make us aware of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American President, George W. Bush, in his outgoing press conference, advised newly elected President, Barack Obama. Former president G.W. Bush said that he had made many mistakes in his presidency and that Barack Obama should do whatever he feels is appropriate.</seg>
     <seg id="2">'I did, as a president, whatever I felt was appropriate, according to the situation, and the American law and constitution, giving preference to American interest over my own acceptance'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">President Bush said that the enemies of America are still planning to attack America, and that the biggest challenge for Barack Obama would be to stop those attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He said that not being able to find weapons of mass destructions in Iraq was the biggest disappointment for him, and considering the Iraq mission to be complete was his biggest mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Speaking at his last press conference at the White House, the American President said that this would be his last press conference, and thanked the journalists and other friends who were present in the press conference.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you think Obama will repeat the mistakes that Bush made?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Did Bush delay accepting his mistake?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Will Obama be able to follow Bush's advice?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Give us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American Vice President Dick Cheney said, "I want to see Osama Bin Laden alive or dead."</seg>
     <seg id="2">He said that Osama Bin Laden is hiding in some hard to reach area and is of no use to his organization, and if Osama Bin Laden is arrested alive or dead then his organization must be destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">America intends to arrest Osama and the search for Osama is on.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Will Dick Cheney's goal to arrest Osama be accomplished?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Give us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the completion of Quaid Azam Trophy match between PIA and Habib Bank, the all-rounder cricketer Shahid Affridi had a altercation with one fan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">When Shahid Affridi came out of the drawing room after playing the match on the UBL ground, a large number of fans gathered around him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In one instance, a fan held his hand and asked to take a photo with him, after which Shahid Affridi removed his hand from the fan's and said that he can take the photo tomorrow. After further insistence from the fan, Affridi became angry and slapped him. An altercation then began between Affridi and the fan, though the crowd seemed to dismiss the matter there.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Shahid Affridi later said that he had been in a hurry to attend the prayer.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Nevertheless, I shall apologize to that spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What would you say about this behavior of Shahid Afridi?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Let us know your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian Prime Minister, Manmohan Singh, has once again accused Pakistan of provoking a war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan is using terrorism as a state policy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">While addressing a Chief Minister's conference in New Delhi, Manmohan Singh said that the terrorist elements are backed by neighboring countries and especially Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The terrorists of the Mumbai attacks used the far out to sea route and were safe from the Indian coast guards.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian Prime Minister said that the November attacks were carried out by Lashkare Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He added that the terrorists are using modern techniques and the latest communication systems and said, "We'll have to be more rigorous over the line of control where the intrusion takes place". He said that terrorism will not be tolerated in any case and that is their policy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">How do you see this allegation from the Indian Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Do the internally opposed and separatist movements of India show the disturbed situation in India?</seg>
     <seg id="9">On whose orders is India taking this warning stance?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Give us your views.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Zubair Khan, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is a sad calamity that Israel is massacring the Palestinians and the same situation is prevalent in Kashmir, but there is no effect on the Security Council.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the organizations present in Palestine and Kashmir should keep their war going until they gain independence, and they should form unity among themselves and keep facing any type of harm, and eventually their martyrdom will give fruit, God Willing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The air attacks by Israel on Gaza are continuing just the same. Until now, hundreds of Palestinian men, women and children have been martyred.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Important Hamas leader Nazariyan was killed along with his wife and children.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Here the Security Council meeting concluded without any decision.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The meeting saw American opposition to the derogatory resolutions passed against Israel by Libya and other Arab countries.</seg>
     <seg id="5">For the last few days there have been bombings by Israeli planes on the Palestinian civilian population.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The whole world cried out about the Mumbai issue, but the Israeli attacks do not seem to matter to anyone including America and Britain.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Why are the important Islamic countries quiet?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What can say about this double standard of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Saeed, New York</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think that most of our people are ignorant. They do not know where their money is going. The government fixes taxes and likes to fulfill its duties. The electricity and gas crisis will not be like this.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because everyone knows the role of those selected by the people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The electricity and gas crisis across Pakistan has taken a serious position.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other side, there was an increase of an average of 18% in gas rates, while the unavailability of petrol in some cities has become a cause of great difficulty for the public.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Among the manufacturing and business circles, there are strong protests and severe protests against the long power cut and gas crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The producers have given the ultimatum to close the factories.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Here in Karachi, the public is perturbed over the 8-10 hour load shedding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The production life cycle has become practically paralyzed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The government institutions are blaming each other to explain their stances.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Are the talks of increasing the prices of electricity and gas a joke against the nation?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Why is attention not being paid to solve the problems?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Are the wheels of national development not seeming jammed to the government?</seg>
     <seg id="11">What immediate steps can you suggest to gain control over this crisis?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Let us know your opinions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Imran Khokhar, Madina Munawwarah, I want to say that, as the people, the rulers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I am surprised that government is carrying slogan of public service is itself hurting them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The unavailability of electricity, gas, and petrol has become a persecution.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Government has no control over the institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Law and order is deteriorating every day, may Allah bestow his mercy on this country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The new year has started.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Last year was the year of outbreaks and political ups and downs. It will also be remembered in reference to the terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The stepping down of President Musharf and the end of the eight years rule of president Bush; throwing of shoes on Bush and formation of democratic government in Pakistan; calamities; earthquake in Baluchistan; global financial slump and monopoly.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The new year is arriving, how do you foresee it?</seg>
     <seg id="5">In your opinion, what will be the result of the political or geographical situation? What will be Obama's strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is there a hope of a development towards eliminating terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Will the judicial crisis in Pakistan come to an end?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What turn will the Indo-Pakistani relations take?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is there any chance of a surgical strike, or maybe a full-fledged war?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What are your expectations for the new year?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Share your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370256-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the first anniversary of the death of Benazir Bhutto. She was slain after an election rally in Liaqat Bagh, Rawalpindi on December 27th, 2007.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Unfortunately, Benazir is not among us today. She was a thoughtful politician and a world renowned figure. She held a special status in national politics.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It's been a full year now, yet the enigma of her death still remains unsolved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir's efforts to bring democracy to Pakistan were not in vain.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Today a democratic government exists in Pakistan and her husband, Asif Zardari, currently holds the position of Pakistan President.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you think if the role of martyr Benazir Bhutto is in Pakistani politics?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Who can be her behind murdering?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Recently,, she was given the global human rights award. What would you like to say about her democratic and political services?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After ruling over America for eight years, President Bush left the White House, for presidential camp office, Camp David, so that the White House can be decorated and prepared for new President Barack Obama, according to his wishes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In Bush's eight year presidency, the historic World Trade Center attack, the attack on the Pentagon, the action against Afghanistan and Iraq in the name of a global war against terrorism, in which armies of many countries were pulled into the war, and American resources were completely exhausted, were some of the memorable events of the Bush era.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As a result of this war, America had to face the worst economic and financial crisis in history.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What do you think the world got and what do you think it lost as a result of this war?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Were the policies of President Bush successful?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What are your views of the Bush era?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian government has stopped the Indian cricket team from touring Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Indian cricket team was supposed to play three tests, five one-day matches and one 20-20, during the tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rajiv Shekhla, the Vice President of the Indian Cricket Board, when interviewed by Jeev News, said that the board had asked the government for permission to go on the Pakistan tour.  Due to the difficult situation in the two countries, the tour was not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Is the Indian government's decision to cancel the trip due to the present political situation a proper step? Shouldn't sports be separate from politics?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is the Indian government's decision harmful for cricket?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Despite the fact that the security conditions are so bad in India, the England cricket team is continuing its tour. So why can't the Indian team make the tour of Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion on this matter?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salman, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">Their are people who are proud about going to India.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They make their films and videos over there. Their eyes should now be open to how much the people of India respect them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I remember an interview of Adnan Sami, in which he said that he is not Pakistani, rather, his citizenship is of England.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan Sami should return to Pakistan first chance he gets because respect did not suit you there either.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fareed Ahmed</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="3">Indian's attitude has changed after Bombay Attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jagjit Singh has showed in  his reaction  that he hates Pakistan and Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="5">One should know that Adnan Sami has sung with Asha Bhonsley. How is he a bad singer now? Adnan Sami should stay in India, there is no need to come here.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muhammad Shamshaad Alam</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi, On the statement of Jagjit Singh, I would only say that he changes color like a chameleon.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who gives statements in relation to the circumstances. Pakistanis! Open your eyes to how much value you are given in India. Understand their mentality.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the Bombay incident, their hateful statements have increased. The same people are now saying evil things against the famous singer Adnan Sami.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">According to a foreign news agency, during his final visit to Iraq when American president Bush along with Iraqi president Noori Almaliki were in a press conference in his office, the situation went ludicrous when an Iraqi journalist while addressing President Bush said ""You dog this is a farewell kiss""</seg>
     <seg id="2">After that the journalist removed his shoe and threw it towards Bush. president Bush expertly ducked before the shoe could hit and saved himself.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The second shoe hit the American Flag.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Security personnels dragged the journalist away from there.</seg>
     <seg id="5">at this point, president Bush said that he didn't know why he had done so , Shoe was of number 10, I had no problem.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you think this reaction of the journalist wasn't an expression of deprecation or President bush from the Iraqi people?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What would you say on this incident?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The tension between Pakistan and India's relations after the terrorism in Mumbai got further intense when the fighter planes from the Indian Air force violated the Pakistani airspace in Lahore and Kashmir sectors.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As a result of retaliation from Pak Air force, the Indian planes were forced to go back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Sources say that both Indian planes were loaded with ammunition.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the first of its kind incident in the current tensed situation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan Air Force says that it is ready to defend the country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Information Minister Sherry Rahman says that Indian officials have accepted that aerial boundaries have been crossed, although this happened by mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan military sources have declared this incident felonious.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In your opinion, does India really have an intention of an air strike on Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is this statement of India correct that this violation was a mistake or this was to find out the ability of the Pakistan Air Force?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Is this incident not going to aggravate the current estrangement among the two countries?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please inform us with your comments.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Respected martyr Benazir Bhutto was given the International Award for Human Rights after her death, which was received by her son and chairperson of the People's Party Bilawal Bhutto Zardari.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During a session of the General Assembly in the United Nations headquarters, the former prime minister of Pakistan, martyr Benazir Bhutto, was presented with this award for acknowledgment of her efforts for human rights in a ceremony.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The 60th anniversary of the passing of the human rights resolution by the United Nations was celebrated on the 10th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Among those people and institutes being honored on the occasion for working for human rights, apart from Benazir Bhutto, were:  former American Attorney General, Louis Ramsey Clark, and the Human Rights Watch, the organization that works around the world for human rights.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On this occasion, the Pakistani Ambassador to the United Nations Abdullah Husain Harun and other senior embassy agents were present.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you think about the former martyr Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto receiving this award?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Samir</seg>
     <seg id="2">Chicago</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is true that she was martyred, but we also remember how many innocent people she killed in Karachi, upon which she was proud that Nasirullah Babar did well.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But later, she completely changed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is also true that she ignored the senior members of her party and made her son the representative of the People's Party. What kind of democracy is that?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Jami Noor, Karachi, This news proves that disbelievers will only help disbelievers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But until the iron ax is fitted with a wooden handle, it cannot cut a wing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our rulers are just like this, in that they are adopting secretive ways. This is why calamities are befalling the country.</seg>
     <seg id="4">May Allah guide our rulers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Security Council panel of the United Nations has included the name of Hafiz Sa'eed and two other Pakistani citizens, and that of Jama'athud Da'wah as well as four other organizations in their list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Pakistanis whose names were included in the terrorist list by the Al-Qaida and Taliban Sanctions Committee of the Security Council included Jama'athud Da'ah chief, Hafiz Mohammad Saeed, the practically non-existent organization Lashkar-e-Taiba's Operation Chief Zakiur Rahman Lakhwi, and Financial Chief Haji Mohammad Ashraf.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Apart from this, a Saudi national, Mahmood Ahmad Bazek, was also included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Among the organizations were Jama'athud Da'wah, Pasban Kashmir, Al-Rasheed Trust, and Al-Akhtar Trust International.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The host countries will immediately freeze all the assets of these individuals and organizations, and they will be restricted from traveling and will be placed under arrest.</seg>
     <seg id="6">They will have to face charges.</seg>
     <seg id="7">These regulations are not as a result of Indian influence, are they?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Why is India accusing these organizations of responsibility for the Mumbai Attacks without any proof?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Doesn't India have any local terrorist groups ?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Aren't the world organizations aware of the persecution of minorities in India?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Share your opinion with us.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Eid is a festival of happiness and serenity, and on Eid-ul-Azha the muslims sacrifice a domestic animal to commemorate the sacrifice of Prophet Ibrahim A.S. (the Prophet Abraham).</seg>
     <seg id="2">In these troubled times, when inflation is at its peak and the government is highly unstable; everybody, poor or rich, still prepares for Eid and wishes loved ones a Happy Eid in their own different ways.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We are also giving you an opportunity to wish your loved ones Eid greetings through our blog in the form of short messages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You can also send Eid wishes in the form of short Eid poems.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">-Murtaza Gilani</seg>
     <seg id="2">from Karachi says: Our leaders should understand that the people they are targeting by their military operations are the ones who are actually the true patriots, who are enduring all types of cruelty but continue to love Pakistan more than their own lives.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>

