<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="mturk">
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Defending the thinking of France.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The meeting of the committee took place in the Parliament under the chairmanship of Committee Chairman Mushahid Husain Syed. They proposed that the government to send a delegation, with representatives of all political parties, apart from humanitarian aid to Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking to representatives of the press after the meeting, Mushahid Husain Syed said that the committee welcomed the proposal given by France, in which it was stated that Israel calls for an immediate ceasefire and allows humanitarian work among the affected people of Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Calling the Israeli attacks on Palestine a crime against humanity, he said that all countries should criticize these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mushahid Husain attacled the the double standards of the countries of the world and said,  "Why are those who speak against terrorism quiet about the Israeli attacks on Palestine?"</seg>
    <seg id="6">The chairman of the Committee for External Matters criticized the slow action of leaders.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that the committee expressed hope that the newly elected American President, Barack Obama, would speak to the Muslim world within his first 100 days in office to bridge the gulf forming between America and the Muslim world.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mushahid Hussain said that to decrease the tension between Muslim Umma and the West, emergency measures should be taken, but the old issues of Kashmir and Falastin should also be resolved.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The minister of foreign affairs, Malik Imad, told the committee that he was going to Saudi Arabia to attend the meeting of the foreign ministers of the governments of Islamic countries.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This sudden meeting was called as a result of Israeli attacks on Palestine. He said that he was aware of the Palestinian matter and at present, the government was in contact with the premiers of other countries.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The Minister of Foreign Affairs said that the issue of Palestine should be resolved according to the resolutions of the United Nations.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Two reporters from Arab countries also attended the seminar and they talked about the current situation of Palestine in the seminar.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Here the students of International University in Islamabad held a strike against Islaean attacks on Falastin.</seg>
    <seg id="14">The protesters were holding banners and placards with anti- Israel slogans.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Avoiding Dieting to Prevent the Flu.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This research of American scientists was published after many experiments on mice.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Experiments proved that mice on a lower calorie diet had comparatively less ability to fight the flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Research has proven the old myth  of fasting during fever wrong.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the scientists, one should eat a lot when one has a fever.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The researchers from the Michigan State University say that the rats on a diet had less power to resist the infection and their chances of dying had increased, whereas rats on a normal diet had better resistance against the flu virus.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to Professor Elizabeth Gardner, people who diet will not only be affected by the virus flu sooner but, will also have a longer recovery time.</seg>
    <seg id="8">She also said that those people who have taken the flu vaccination should also avoid dieting during the winter months.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">First Nuclear Test Done in 1990.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Thomas Reid, who has worked in the Lever National Laboratory in America as a weapon designer, has written this book with the help of the former director of technical intelligence at Los Alamos national laboratory, Dani Stillman.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This book was titled "Nuclear Express: Political History of the Bomb and Its Proliferation," and both writers have claimed that whichever country first made a nuclear bomb either stole the nuclear secrets of another country or had the support of another nuclear power.</seg>
    <seg id="4">in an interview with US news, Thomas Reed said that in 1990, during the rule of Benazir Bhutto, China texted Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Thomas Reid said that, for many reasons, he believes that China had tested Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The reasons include the design of the bomb and some information gained during talks with the Chinese scientists.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He further added that this was the reason that in 1998 in a span of only two weeks and three days, Pakistan was able to carry out nuclear experiments in response to Indian nuclear experiments.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Thomas Reid reminds us that in 1961 Russia suddenly carried out a nuclear experiment and besides possessing the bomb for a long time, it took 17 days for America to carry out nuclear experiments.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He further said that atomic bomb test Pakistan conducted on May 28, 1998 was made with extreme care, and Pakistani scientists had complete confidence in it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">When Thomas Reid was asked whether China had provided nuclear technology to Pakistan, he said India was the common enemy of both China and Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that there was proof that Dr. Abdul Qadeer Khan used the Chinese design, and that the documents received from Libya will verify this fact.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Upon further questioning as to whether joint nuclear testing was common, he said that America had openly performed nuclear tests for England in the deserts of Nevada in 1990.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said that he also assumed that Israel was given access to the results of this test.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Thomas Reid was also asked about China's nuclear distribution program which is ongoing.</seg>
    <seg id="15">In answer, Thomas Reid said that China has been providing raw material, guidance and design for the nuclear setup in Esfahan, Iran since 1991.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Apart from this, China has also provided Iran with an enrichment plant in Kheeraj.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He said that China has been providing nuclear technology to Iran, Syria, Pakistan, Egypt, Libya, and Yemen through North Korea.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">2008 Best Year for Madonna</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This show was organized for Madonna's album 'Hard Candy' and it also included a Ukrainian gypsy band and Justin Timberlake's one or two songs.</seg>
    <seg id="3">An old racing car was also kept on the stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It was Celine Dion's second most profitable show of 2008, in which $236.6 million was made.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Canadian show 'Taking Chances' toured 24 countries whereas Madonna only toured 17, which was her first world tour in the last eight years.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The director of both shows was Jimmy King, who also organized the tour 'Reunion' or 'Spice Girls'.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Madonna broke her own record set in 2006.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In 2006, she had earned 193.7 million dollars from her 'Confession' concerts.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Pollstar said that the third most successful singer, Bon Joy, made $170 million.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bruce Springsteen finished fourth with $160,000,000, and The Police stood in fifth place with $126,000,000.</seg>
    <seg id="11">According to a magazine in year 2008 very few people in North America had attended concerts and musical events and only those people participated who were willing to buy expensive tickets.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In America, there was an average increase of 8% in the price of one ticket. In Madonna's show, the most expensive ticket sold was $350.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The editor of Pollstar magazine, Gary Bongiovanni, said that given the economic environment, the year 2008 was a good year for musicians.</seg>
    <seg id="14">He predicted that the year 2009 would be a good year for Springsteen and U2, whose albums are to be released this year.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">stops on co-education:Taliban</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Taliban members of the Hafiz Gul Bahadur group have distributed literature in  the area of North Wazeerastan Meeran Shah which contain threats governmental and civilian institutions which participate in co-education.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the pamphlet it said that if the co-educational institutes were not closed by January 5 then there will be steps taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It was mentioned in that circular that there will be restriction on the government help, and making identity cards for other education affairs and women will stop to go to Nadra offices.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The announcement of the ban on women's identification cards was made by the Taliban at a time when, in North Wazeerastan, 200 women had submitted forms for Nadra identity cards for the Bay Nazir support program.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to the locals, the pamphlets issued by the local Taliban was read out loud on the loudspeakers of all the mosques in North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">However, the letter did not state whether there would be a ban on separate girls educational institutions.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the pamphlet, after this announcement, if a woman gets caught when out to get education or get her ID made, she and her family will be punished under law.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Police in the area of Bannu say that on Sunday a tunnel of gunpowder was blasted on Bannu Mir Insha Road, killing one pedestrian and injuring another.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The injured was admitted to the Banu Soul Hospital.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Target Killing: More dead bodies found.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police, in the central area of Mengoora, at Green circle, and Sehrab Khan circle, two decapitated bodies were found.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The deceased were said to be related to Frontier core and the police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Eyewitnesses say that a letter was also found near the bodies, in which it was warned that whoever moved these bodies before 11:00 would be responsible for his own death.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Locals say that the dead bodies were lying in the market until 11am, when security officials transferred them to the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="6">There has been a dangerous rise in the numbers of target killing during the last few weeks in the city of Mangora and surrounding areas.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Civilians, including women, and security officers were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to local sources, more than 30 people have been killed in these events.</seg>
    <seg id="9">No organization has accepted responsibility for these deaths yet.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Local spokesman for the Taliban, Muslim Khan, told BBC on Saturday that three of the dead bodies found on Friday were members of their group, including the Taliban commander of Dulai, Rafullah.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Muslim Khan said that Rafi'ullah was in the custody of the security forces for the last month and a half.</seg>
    <seg id="12">They had said that when local Taliban kills someone, they first issue him a notice. On other side, activities in Mengora were of severe concern for the locals.</seg>
    <seg id="13">according to the local people, a large number of security forces have been deployed in Mengora,  but despite all these, attacks on the citizens are still increasing.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tribute to Benazir by Bakhtawar in Song.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A rap song (a modern style of music) in Bakhtawar's voice has been posted on YouTube as well.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this video of 5 minutes, pictures and video clips of Benazir have been shown.</seg>
    <seg id="4">18 year old Bakhtawar is a student of Edinburgh University.</seg>
    <seg id="5">She has a deep affection for poetry and singing.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is said that she started singing rhymes, with encouragement from her mother.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Paying tribute to her mother, she said she was a beautiful and intelligent lady who did everything with style.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Regarding the December 27th incident, she said that she was hit near the cheek by a bullet. She left us at the age of 54, leaving behind three children.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The whole nation is desperate without her; she is present in all of their hearts.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bukhtawar is second among Benazir Bhutto's children, to Bilawal Bhutto.</seg>
    <seg id="11">She has been taking interest in music from early days.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It is being said that before returning to her mother's country, she had asked her journalist friend, in America, to introduce her to Grammy award winning producer and rapper, Puff Daddy, but this meeting could not take place.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Translation of Bakhtawar's poetry was published by some Sindhi news papers as well but her voice is being heard for the first time through You Tube.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Some workers and followers of Benazir Bhutto have started preparing CDs of Bakhtawar's rap song.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other hand, the spokesman of Pakistan Peoples Party, Farhatullah Babar, has confirmed that the poetry and voice in the song on Youtube is of Bakhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="16">He told over the phone from Islamabad that its a tribute by a saddened daughter to her brave mother, and it is also being telecast by the government TV network as well.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar said that at the moment no plan was made by his party to distribute the CDs of Bakhtawar's song.</seg>
    <seg id="18">He said that a few months ago, a fake page belonging to their party's young chairman, Bilawal Bhutto Zardari, was created on Facebook which was later removed.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani : Information Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Federal Minister for Information and broadcasting Sherry Rehman while confirming, through and SMS sent to BBC, the citizenship of Ajmal Qasab just added that further investigation is being carried out.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Before this, the Advisor to Prime Minister for Interior Rehman Malik had denied his Pakistani citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He had said that there was no record for Malik in the record keeping institute, NADRA.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is not yet clear why the government of Pakistan has changed its stance over the citizenship of Ajmal Kasab.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, according to the foreign office, the citizenship of Ajmal Kasab has been verified by the Interior Ministry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Before that, BBC Urdu Service and some other newspapers and TV channels showed that Ajamal Qasab belongs to District Okara's Faridcoat village in the Punjab province.</seg>
    <seg id="8">However, the government had been denying it.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is still not clear that either Ajmal Qasaab belongs to Faridcort or some other area.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Rockets fired from Lebanon, retaliatory bombardment.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Israeli army and police officials reported that four rockets were fired from Lebanon territory into Israel, one of which landed in the northern Israeli town Nahrya and caused minor injuries to two civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In response to the rockets fired from the Lebanese territory, the Israeli artillery has bombed Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It is not clear that this attack was carried out by Hizbullah or if the Palestinian groups active in Lebanon are behind it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Lebanese government says that it is also trying to figure out who is behind these rocket attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">BBC correspondents have declared that this is a very dangerous turn in the prevailing situation in the region.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The BBC's editor for the Middle East, Jeremy Bowen, stated that because of these rocket attacks the danger of the war spreading has increased.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In the last few days, it was feared that the action going on in Gaza might spread to the Israeli border with Lebanon in the north.</seg>
    <seg id="9">There, on Wednesday night, the Israeli Air Force conducted sixty air raids on Gaza Strip.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Israeli army, the police stations of Hamas, their tunnels, weapon stocks, rocket launching pads, and armed workers were targeted in these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Apart from the air attacks, the Israeli army and the naval launching pad also bombarded Gaza all night.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The Palestinian Authorities said that a mosque was destroyed during the air raids on the Gaza city.</seg>
    <seg id="13">According to unconfirmed reports, Israeli tanks, with helicopter air support, have advanced towards the area of Khan Younus.</seg>
    <seg id="14">In this war that has been going on for the last 12 days, about 700 people, with a large number of women and children, have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other side, only twelve soldiers from the Israeli Army have been killed.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Israeli security forces have confirmed that a high defense agent, Amous Gilad, is going to Cairo to decide the conditions for ceasefire.</seg>
    <seg id="17">A delegation from Hamas is also going to Cairo to conduct parallel talks with the Egyptian diplomats.</seg>
    <seg id="18">In addition to this, the leader of the Palestinian Authority, Mehmood Abbas, is also arriving in Cairo on Friday.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">My Heart Is Broke, Please Return My Kidney.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Richard Batistant said that he donated his kidney to his wife, Dawnell, to save her life twenty-four years ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to news authority AFP, Dr. Batistant said that in return for his kidney, his wife has given him deception by loving someone else and asking for a divorce.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During an interview with a local newspaper, Dr. Batista said "that her love affair has put a hole in my heart that still exists".</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Dr. Richard Batista's lawyer, though Dr. Batista is demanding his kidney back, but he actually wants a monetary compensation for the kidney.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to his wife, she will deliver her testimony in few days in front of the judge.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">140 year old, 9 kilogram lobster free</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">George, the giant lobster, was caught from the sea two weeks ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The city's seafood company purchased it for a hundred dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">They started using pictures of the lobster for publicity.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"PETA", a group working for animal rights, demanded the release of the lobster. As a result, it will be released back into the sea.</seg>
    <seg id="6">George was captured from the sea in Canada, after which it stayed in the tank of City Crab and Seafood Company for ten days.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The age of the lobster can be estimated from its weight.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The restaurant's manager, Keith Walanty, says that their intent was never to harm the lobster. The reason for keeping him in the tank was to provide entertainment for the customers.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Engrid Newkurk, from the animal rights group PETA, says that the restaurant's decision is praise-worthy and provides an example for those who want to keep these precious animals in the tank or want to eat them by boiling them alive.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Search for missing girl ends with the help of a cell phone.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When the officials heard that Natalie Maltais was missing, the police and firefighting forces of the city of Acton, Massachusetts came into action.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Authorities found the exact location of the baby with the help of the GPS system installed in her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="4">With the help of Google Street View, it was determined that the girl was in a motel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">One week ago, Natalie's grandmother Rose Maltise had taken Natalie away from the supervision of her legal parents.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Police Chief of Athule, Timothy Anderson, told BBC that she said that she will never return Natalie, and she left the state.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The police contacted Mrs. Maltise but when she did not return Natalie, as promised, the police decided to trace Natalie using her mobile phone.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Since 2005, there is a regulation in America that the cellular companies will provide location for 67 percent people in a range of 100 meters and 95 percent callers in a range of 300 meters.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamid Karzai Visits India.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This is Hamid Karzai's second tour to India in the last five months.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is expected that during his meeting with Prime minister Manmohan Singh he will discuss after effects of the terrorist attacks in Mumbai.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this trip, he wants to express the feelings of Afghanistan and its public about the Mumbai attacks, and show its solidarity with India.</seg>
    <seg id="5">During this visit of Karzai, mutual trade will be discussed apart from terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is expected there will be discussion about mutual collaboration to fight terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="7">During his last visit to India, President Hamid Karzai said that terrorism will not be allowed to interfere with the relations between India and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He also said that both  India and Afghanistan are facing the challenge of terrorism and mercilessness and slaughtering activities.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Peace and stability in both countries, in the region, and in the whole world are beneficial for everyone.</seg>
    <seg id="10">We understand this truth that both countries and the entire world can fight this curse only when united.</seg>
    <seg id="11"></seg>
    <seg id="12"></seg>
    <seg id="13"></seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2"></seg>
    <seg id="3"></seg>
    <seg id="4">Ajmal Qasab is now in police custody, and it is hoped that the police will file charges against him before January 24th.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ajmal Qasab has no lawyer to defend him.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In a letter written to the Pakistani government, Qasab asked for legal aid.</seg>
    <seg id="7">India has given Pakistan proof of the involvement of Pakistani extremists in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Pakistan has accepted that Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani civilian.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the police case, Ajmal Qasab and his partner Abu Ismail killed 6 police officers including ATS chief Hemant Karkare, Additional Police Commissioner Ashok Kamte and Encounter specialist Police Inspector Vijay Salaskar, after which they fled with their squad car, which was later recovered near DB Marg, Girgaum Chowpatty.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Ismail Khan was killed and Ajmal was captured by the police.</seg>
    <seg id="11">No lawyer has been appointed yet, to follow Ajmal's case.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Daneesh Muta, the lawyer whom was selected by the government, denied to accept the case on moral grounds.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Two lawyers retracted their names after protests and opposition by the members of a special-interest group.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Constitutional Amendment Committee to be Formed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Tuesday in Islamabad,after addressing a seminar held for environmental changes, while talking to media representatives, he said; that a hearing of the parliament will be called for. Where this committee will be formed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that until now, to complete the 17th amendment, the constitutional amendment bill was presented by the Joint National Movement to the National Assembly, whereas other political parties have also presented their constitutional bills in this regard to the parliament.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the Pakistan Peoples Party has also sent all the political parties a rough version of the 17th amendment and the committee would analyze their version.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In answer to a question, he said that the parliament would decide the balance of power between the President and the Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The prime minister said that the Parliament holds power to make all decisions.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In answer to another question, he said that in getting the former President retired General Pervez Musharraf to leave his post, apart from the role of political parties, the former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Pakistan Peoples Party, Benazir Bhutto also played an important role, by forcing the global brotherhood to remove the uniform of President Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that the elected Vice President of America, Joe Biden was a supporter of Pakistan and democracy, and that the president honored him in return for his services with the Pakistani Crescent.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Replying to a question about the Indian governments warning of breaking all ties with Pakistan after the Mumbai incident, the Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Geelani said that the leaders are under extreme pressure from the public, which is why they issue such statements.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Protest against the siding of Journalists.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Tuesday, the organization of journalists, RIUJ, held protests in front of the Islamabad Press Club of Journalists and Newspaper Workers against media owners and the government about the news channel and newspapers removing many of their employees.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking to the protesters, a senior member of Pakistan's biggest journalist organization, the Federal Union of Journalists,  C.R. Shamsi said, "The politicians who protested with us yesterday on the streets, today, have become rulers and are sitting in Parliament. Out of fear of a certain lobby of media owners, they are not doing anything for the rights of journalists."</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the newspaper owners who speak of human rights have made their offices punishment houses and beggar camps, where despite earning millions of rupees per year, the workers are given meager wages and by removing hundreds of them, they are killing them economically.</seg>
    <seg id="5">An example of this is in front of us of the worker of a private TV channel, Channel 5, in Lahore, who committed suicide over not getting his salary for four months. And even today, due to being unfairly removed or not getting salaries for months, many workers are leading very difficult lives.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that there should be firm measures taken against the TV and newspaper owners, and the journalists should establish a protest camp in front of Parliament to fight for their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="7">C.R. Shamsi criticized the governor of Punjab, Salman Taseer, saying that employees were removed from his Urdu Newspaper "Aaj Kal" staff without prior notice.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Daily Jinnah, Daily Khabrain, Channel 5, Business Plus and Aaj News have sacked dozens of their employees.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Speaking to the protestors, the General Secretary of PUFJ said that today, throughout the country, journalist organizations are observing a black day against the removal of journalists and newspaper workers, whereas journalists will go to the parliamentary session wearing black bands on their arms to get back their rights.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to Mazhar Abbas, in 50% of the Pakistani newspapers and TV channels the workers and journalists were being exploited, where they work without any agreement.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that until now, more than 200 journalists and workers have been removed from newspapers and TV channels, while it is being feared that the owners will remove hundreds more in the present year, making an excuse of the present financial crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas said that the journalist movement will continue until removed employees are reinstated, newspaper wages fixed by the Seventh Wage board award are enforced, and the salaries owed by TV channels and newspaper workers is paid.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">11 member cabinet takes oath.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The new cabinet includes six ministers from Anti, ex prime minister Sardar Atiq Ahmed Khan's Muslim Conference group, two from the Pakistan Peoples Party, two from the Peoples Muslim Conference and two from the Mutahida Qaumi Movement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The 11 cabinet members include one lady minister, who belongs to the Ateeq opposition Muslim Conference party.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The joint ruler said that the cabinet will be expanded next week, and it is possible that 12 more ministers will be taken into the cabinet. It should be clear that in the beginning of this month, Sardar Ateeq Khan's opposers removed him from the post of Prime Minister by showing lack of trust, and they made Sardar Ya'qoob Khan the new Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The departments of these ministers will be announced later.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On the occasion of oath taking, members of the Peoples Party shouted slogans in favor of former Pakistani Prime Minister, Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">3.5 Million Users Affected by Virus</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Discovered for the first time in October 2008, this virus is known by names like Confecker, Down and Up, and Kido.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Microsoft had released a patch to tackle this virus; but, despite that, almost 3.5 million computers and memory sticks have been affected with it.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Experts say that the number of infected computers could be many.</seg>
    <seg id="5">To get rid of this, dealers need to use Microsoft's MS08-067 patch.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Microsoft says that virus which affects thousands of computers, searches for windows file 'services.exe' and adds itself into its code.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After that, the virus turns into a DLL file in the Windows System folder.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This virus also changes the name of the file.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Then it changes the details of the Windows registry.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This virus creates a problem after it gets active which comes out as 'HTTP Server' and changes the restore point of the machine.</seg>
    <seg id="11">After that, it downloads files from the hacker's website.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Microsoft says that this virus has affected computers in different countries.</seg>
    <seg id="13">These countries include China, Brazil, Russia, India, America and Britain.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'The Demand- Quick Report on Indian Information'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">On Monday, after a meeting in the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, while talking to the media representative, he said that information given from India</seg>
    <seg id="3">to help investigate this matter.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that Pakistan was a sovereign nation and about the investigation on the information received from India, no country's</seg>
    <seg id="5">They will not accept any dictation.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that apart from the information received from India, they were gathering other information as well.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The foreign ministry adviser said that the organization that controls law and order arrested 124 members of a blacklisted organization for the risk of threat to peace.</seg>
    <seg id="8">And if any evidence is found against them, action will be taken against them, while innocent people will be freed.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In an answer to a question, he said that no arrested person would be handed over to India, and that action would be taken against such individuals according to Pakistani law.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that action would be taken against these individuals according to the law of the FIA.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In reply to a question, he said that law enforcement agencies in India took 42 days to gather information about the guilty people in the Mumbai incident, so we hope that India, along with the global community, will give Pakistan some time to verify this information.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He reiterated the offer by the government that a separate interrogating team will be formed for the investigation of the Bombay incident.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He clarified that a three-member interrogating team has been formed under the supervision of an additional Inspector General of the FIA,</seg>
    <seg id="14">which will investigate the information given to Pakistan from India regarding the Bombay attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="15">The High Commissioner of Pakistan in India, Shahid Malik, met President Asif Ali Zardari, in which meeting the president made it clear that if any Pakistani group or individual is found guilty in the Mumbai attacks, action will be taken against them according to the country law, and no one would be handed over to India. This, when the Indian government is continuously pressuring Pakistan to hand over the guilty people to India.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Anything is Possible in America'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mr. Obama will take the oath on January 20, becoming America's 44th president.</seg>
    <seg id="3">while standing on the stairs of the building built in memory of 16th American president Abraham Lincoln and addressing a musical concert</seg>
    <seg id="4">Mr. Obama said that America is facing the most bitter challenge in many generations, and he is hopeful that America will resolve it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Abraham Lincoln ended the practice of slavery in America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">At the same time, Mr. Obama said that it would take time to resolve the problems facing the country, and that the path would be trying.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Nevertheless, I am hopeful that the dream of the founders of this country will live.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America, besides the wars of Iraq and Afghanistan, is fighting a great economic downfall.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Extraordinary steps are being taken for the swearing-in ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Organizers believe that two million people will attend the function.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Monday is a national holiday in America, as on that date, the great standard bearer of human rights, Martin Luther King was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Martin Luther King was black.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Salutation to Martin Luther King, a resolution to work.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr. Martin Luther King was killed in 1968.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama paid tribute to Dr. Martin Luther King and told Americans to work together to fulfill the promises of this nation.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Here in Washington, preparations are being made for an unprecedented gathering of the public for the oath taking ceremony by the new president on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Nearly two million people are expected to participate in this historic swearing in ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On Monday, Barack Obama started his day by visiting a medical center to meet wounded American soldiers. After this he went to a shelter for homeless people and painted a wall.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Speaking to journalists, Barack Obama said: "After the present crisis which we are facing, and the difficulties that many people are undergoing, we cannot sit quietly."</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that Martin Luther King spent his life serving the people.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Barack Obama said today we are honoring his memory. This is not a day to just pause and think, it is a day to act.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that the ceremony on Tuesday would be on the same path as that of Martin Luther King's "My Dream" speech, which was heard by many thousands of people gathered in 1963.</seg>
    <seg id="11">In this speech, Martin Luther King said that the day will come when people would not be judges based on the color of their skin.</seg>
    <seg id="12">BBC's Matthew Price pointed out that it is a strange historical coincidence that Martin Luther King Day should fall on the day before the first black president of the U.S. will take his oath.</seg>
    <seg id="13">For many in the southern states, Barack Obama's presidency will be a realization of Dr. Martin Luther King's dream.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Additional Political Agent.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The additional political agent was kidnapped ten days ago from South Waziristan by unidentified masked men.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Sources say that the agent was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer faction of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the local government, on Tuesday afternoon, around 4 o'clock, other political agent of South Waziristan, Aamir Latheef was brought to the Wana Scouts camp by a group of tribal members.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, they did not reveal who had kidnapped the additional political agent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, the locals are saying that the political agent was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer faction of local Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Aamir Latheef was kidnapped when he was going from Wana to Tank.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On January 11, 2009, seven masked men kidnapped the political agent, Aamir Latheef, along with his driver, from the tribal area of Karkandah in South Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Official members say that the kidnappers first unarmed the security available in the cars and then made the Additional Political Agent to sit in another car and took him away.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the local government, after the kidnapping of the additional political agent, security forces guarded all the check posts in South Waziristan and semi-tribal areas, and the people coming and going were searched thoroughly, and from the previous one week, the rulers have placed economic restrictions on Wana.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On December 8, 2008, an assistant political agent of north Wazirastan Asmatullah was kidnapped when he was going from Mir Ali to Bannu to enjoy his Eid vacation. A few days after this two people, including Tehsildar Amanullah, were killed by unknown masked perpetrators in north Wazirastan.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">British hacker wins in court.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A 42-year-old British citizen has admitted that he hacked an American military website.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gary has asperger syndrome. A person with asperger syndrome has an obsession to do similar kind of things.</seg>
    <seg id="4">His lawyers said that if he is handed over to America, it is possible that he will commit suicide.</seg>
    <seg id="5">However, the government officials say that there isn't much threat regarding Gary's health.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Lord justice Morskey and Mr. Justice Simon, while announcing the decision, said that Gary is permitted to file a review petition in a British court.</seg>
    <seg id="7"></seg>
    <seg id="8">They further said that the Home Secretary did not study the matter.</seg>
    <seg id="9">But the government prosecutors say that the secretary of interior had used his authority.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Gary has never denied hacking of the American military website.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He had hacked the American computer system in 2001 and 2002, causing the government suffered to lose $800,000.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Gerry has hacked 97 computers, including the American Navy and NASA.</seg>
    <seg id="13">However, Gary says that he did not do this with bad intentions, as he was just looking for information about aliens, which he thought the American government had kept secret.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Gary's mother, Janice Sharp, has said that she is happy with this decision.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Gary's lawyer has said that it is the right decision.</seg>
    <seg id="16">This case has continued since 2002, and finally a correct decision has been made.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Kashmir: Two Hizb Commanders Killed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Colonel Acharya, spokesman of the northern command of the Indian Army deployed in Jammu, told BBC, from a reliable source, troops from 24 rashtria rifles and Jammu Kashmir police besieged the place in the batihaas jungle in tehsil Gandwa of the Doda district where the armed extremists were hiding.</seg>
    <seg id="3">They fired at the army and in the crossfire two armed extremists were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The spokesman said that one of the two killed extremists is district commander Zahoor-ud-din of prohibited Hizbul Mujahiddins, who was active for 12 years in the district and was an expert in gunpowder explosives.</seg>
    <seg id="5">His partner has been identified as Sajjad Hussain, who according to Army sources, got connected with extremists  last year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Acharya, operations are continuing in the mentioned jungle region and there is the possibility of more extremists being present there. The army alleges that two Kalashnikov rifles were recovered during the first stage of the operation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Yesterday, state police chief, Kuldeep Kumar Khudda released the stats for 2008, saying that this was the most peaceful year so far.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that there was no violence in the election of the assembly held in seven phases in November and December.</seg>
    <seg id="9">More than 1350 candidates participated in these elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It should be known that Hizbul Mujahideen has been active in Jammu and Kashmir for the last 18 years.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Hizb called a one sided ceasefire for the first time in July 2000, after which the Indian government and Hizb commanders held dialogs.</seg>
    <seg id="12">However, the ceasefire ended within 15 days.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Afterwards, several elite commanders of Hizb-ul-Mujahddins were killed in different operations.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On Thursday, the renowned daily, "The News" wrote about the extremist groups operating in Pakistan occupied Kashmir.  Lashkar-e-Taiba and Hizbul Mujahideen have decided to revise their Kashmir policy.</seg>
    <seg id="15">It should be clear that the policy of both groups until now, has been that the Kashmir issue could be resolved through armed resistance.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Dera Bugti: Gas Pipeline Blast</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to police officials, the Eighteen inch diameter pipelines running from Loti Gasfields to Peer Mountain were blown up in a blast.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This pipeline goes towards the Sui plant.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Meanwhile, Sarbaz Baloch, presenting himself as a representative of the banned Baloch Republican army has accepted the responsibility of the blast on behalf of his organization over the telephone.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This is the fourth gas pipeline being blown up in four days.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On Friday, in Dera Allah Yar, another 18-inch Qatar pipeline was destroyed whose maintenance continued until Sunday morning.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Mushtaq Siddiqui, General Manager of Sui Southern Gas in Quetta, has said that supply from this pipeline will resume in the afternoon.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This pipeline comes to Quetta through Sibbi.</seg>
    <seg id="9">there has been a severe shortage of gas in Quetta, Ziarat and other surrounding areas for the past three days. Snow is continuing to fall and temperatures have fallen below the freezing point.   Heaters and stoves are out of gas.</seg>
    <seg id="10">In addition, there was a bomb blast in a motorcycle in Mal Mandi in the city of Dera Bugti. But according to the police, there was no fatality as a result of this blast.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Administrator for Jamat-ud-Dawa</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The central headquarters of Jamaa'athud Da'wah is in Taibah, about 25  kilometers from Karachi.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This center includes a hospital, a school and a hostel for students.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Law minister of Punjab, Rana Sanaullah Khan says that a superintendent in the Jamat-ud-Dawa was assigned so that the work of the welfare organizations present there is not disturbed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Khalid Waleed, the son-in-law of Chief of Jamat-ud-Dawa Hafiz Saeed, qualified government official Khaqan Babar is appointed as an administrator to monitor the hospital, schools and other welfare organizations located in the center. Although, according to them, there has also been an increase in the police staff.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Security Council has passed a ban on Jamaa'athud Da'wah, after which the Pakistani government has started taking action against Jamaa'athud Da'wah across the country, and has put the chief of the Jamaa'ath, Hafiz Saeed, along with other leaders under house arrest. The appointment of the administrator in the Taibah center by the Punjab government was also a part of the action being taken against Jamaa'athud Da'wah by the joint government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Khaqan Babar belongs to the DMG or District Management Group.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Hafiz Khalid Waheed has told that on Sunday the Commissioner of Lahore Khusro Pervez Khan, along with police and civil administration, came to the Taiba Center and inspected its different parts. Khalid Waheed has disapproved of the appointment of the administrator in the center of Jamaat al Dawa and said that due to the actions of the government, the number of patients in the hospitals and children in the schools of the center have already decreased.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to a press release by Jamat-ud-Dawa, party chief Hafiz Saeed has written a letter for the General Secretary of United Nations, Ban Ki Mon, and Committee for Taliban, in which a request is made to cancel the restrictions on the party made by the Security Council.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It says in the letter that the one sided decision of the Security Council on banning Jamat-ud-Dawa is unfair. And Jamat-ud-Dawa has no relation with terrorism but it is busy in charitable activities.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Aidhi's Gaza humanitarian mission</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After going through many steps of receiving permission required to enter Gaza, he has only been successful in reaching Egypt from New York.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Speaking to BBC Urdu service from Cairo, he said that he was not able to reach Gaza yet, as Egypt and Israel have placed many barriers.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that he had been here eight days and till now didn't get the permission to go to Ghaza.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I am now in Cairo, and hopefully I will be permitted to reach Gaza tomorrow."</seg>
    <seg id="6">He explained that: "First I was given only 7 days visa to go to Gaza and later on my insisting, Pakistani officials helped me and had it extended for one month but on this condition that I will go to Gaza only once that is single entry."</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that with him are his son and daughters and they want to do the relief work in Ghaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">I have brought some money.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Red Cross Egypt has been given a $100,000 check and $10,000 in cash so it can send aid materials to Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Four more ministers in the cabinet, total of sixty three</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The four new federal ministers include two from the Mutahida Qaumi Movement and two from the Jamiat Ulamae Islam Fazalur Rehman Group.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Asif Ali Zardari took the oath from the new ministers.</seg>
    <seg id="4">At the oath taking ceremony of the Prime Minister Yousuf Raza Gilani, members of federal cabinet were present.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After the inclusion of four new ministers to the federal cabinet, the number of Federal ministers, ministers for state and advisors has reached a total of sixty three.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Farooq Sattar and Babar Ghuari are two ministers from MQM while Azam Swati and Mulana Atta  Rehman are from Jamiat e Ulami Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The departments of these ministers have not yet been announced.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Farooq Sattar is the convener of MQM whereas Babar Ghori is a senator, and his term ends on March 10th.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Azam Swati was elected as a free senator and is considered to be one of the richest.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Moulana Ataur Rahman is a member of the National Assembly and is Moulana Fazlur Rahman's younger brother.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It should be noted that four important advisors are not members of the National Assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It should be noted that when on November 3rd 2008 22 new ministers and 18 state ministers were added in the cabinet. It was thought that MQM would be added in the cabinet; however, due to disagreement over division of ministries, MQA was not included.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Balochistan pipe line blown up.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police, this was an eighteen inch wide pipeline that goes to the various wells in the gas plant of Peer mountain, and it was blown up by unidentified individuals in the morning.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Apart from this, well number 3 in Sui was completely destroyed yesterday, and a gas pipeline was damaged near Dera Illa Yar.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Militant organization Baloch republican army's spokeperson, Saryaz Baluch, accepted the responsibility for these blasts on the behalf of his organization.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Violent incidents have increased in Balochistan since the start of 2009.</seg>
    <seg id="6">This month dozens of gas pipelines have been destroyed, and the attacks have increased on trains and on people from Punjab.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Even though the Prime Minister of Baluchistan, Nawab Aslam Rayisani, has expressed concern over such activities and ordered the police to exchange information with intelligence agencies, stopping such incidents has not yet been possible.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">$819 billion economic revival package approved</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">No member of the Republican party voted in favor of President Obama's plan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Republican party said that this economic plan was very expensive and that it would not be successful.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In The House of Representatives, 240 votes were cast in favor of the plan, while 188 votes were cast against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This economic reform plan has to be presented in the Senate next week, where the ruling Democratic party has a significant majority.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is feared that due to opposition from the Republican party, its passing in the senate may not be easy.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After the passing of the economic reform plan the house, Barack Obama said to the members that they should not let political differences get in the way of this important plan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The President said that plan, which he hoped would become law by next month, would prove helpful in creating a suitable environment in the country for business would prosper.</seg>
    <seg id="9">With this plan, taxpayers and and businesses will be relieved of $275 billion in loans, $540 billion dollars will be put toward roads and bridges projects, 10,000 schools, unemployment benefits, and research for new technology.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The editor of BBC in Washington, Richard Lister said that Barack Obama had decided to put political differences behind his back and prepare a new political culture, but this economic package has once again created bitterness on political lines.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Republican party members in the assembly declared the bill proposed by the government a waste of government money, and they said that this will not help in creating new jobs.</seg>
    <seg id="12">They insisted on the bill proposed by their party in which attention has been given to reduced taxes.</seg>
    <seg id="13">They said that more employment opportunities could be formed with less capital through their bill.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They said that compared to constructive plans, more employment opportunities could be formed through tax cuts.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bitterness between Israeli President and Turkish Prime Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Rajab Tayyab Erdogan almost shouted at Israeli President and said that the blood of many people has been shed in Gaza. He felt sorrow watching that people can actually applaud this military action from Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Erdogan said "I think you are using such words to erase your guilt and that in a high voice. But you killed people and I am remembering those children who were killed near the shore."</seg>
    <seg id="4">Simon said that Gaza's calamity is not Israel, but Hamas, who have established a dangerous dictatorship over there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A correspondent of BBC from Davis says that nothing like this has been seen before in an international economic forum.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, Erdogan later stated that he respected the Israeli president and his age, which is why he did not scream at him, but whatever he was saying was very far from the truth.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Turkey is one of the few Islamic countries which have diplomatic relations with Israel, but for the last few years there has been tension between them.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The attacks were not planned in Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Speaking to Indian news channel NDTV, Wajid Shamsul Hasan, said that the report of the Pakistani investigations into the Mumbai blast will be prepared soon.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the attack on Mumbai last November, more than 120 people were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">India claims that extremist group Lashkar-e-Taiba is responsible for the attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">India also said that Pakistani 'state factors' were guilty in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After the Mumbai attacks, the relations between the two countries were affected.</seg>
    <seg id="7">When talking about the Pakistan investigation report on the incident, High Commissioner Wajid Shamsul Hassan has given out a hint about the whereabouts of the report.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wajid Shams-ul-Hasan said that the investigative report denied that Pakistani soil has been used.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It must be some other place, not England.</seg>
    <seg id="10">These are the two places (Pakistan and Britain) about which I was worried.</seg>
    <seg id="11">India and the global brotherhood has put considerable pressure on Pakistan to take action against the perpetrators of the Mumbai attacks. Pakistan says that it has arrested dozens of people during the action against groups which were clearly involved in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Wajid Shamsul Haq said: "We are not trying to cover it up."</seg>
    <seg id="13">We believe in taking action based on facts.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Our investigations will be accepted by the world.</seg>
    <seg id="15">We will try to satisfy India with the results (of the investigation).</seg>
    <seg id="16">while defending the delay in the investigation in Pakistan he said that it takes time to collect, understand and check these kind of information.</seg>
    <seg id="17">High Commissioner Wajid Shamsul Hasan said that India took 45 days to hand over its dossier.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Republican Leader Also Elected Red Indian</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the sixth round of elections of the Republican party, Michael Steele,who got 91 votes out of 168, won.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the selection for the post of Chairman, the candidate opposing Steele, Katon Dawson, got 77 votes, whereas the ex-Chairman Duncan withdrew from the competition in the second stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Newspaper writers say that among the five candidates who stood for the chairmanship of the Republican Party, Michael Steele was considered the most moderate leader.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After his win, Michael Steel said in his speech "We are saying to our friends and enemies together, come with us, but those who will cause problems in this, be prepared to separate from us." Michael Steel is from Maryland, where he has also been the deputy governor.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He became famous in 2006 when he ran for a seat in the senate.</seg>
    <seg id="7">After losing the Senatorial election, he became the chairman of the Political Conservative Committee of the party.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Now, after being selected the chairman of the party, the country-wide projects of the party will be under his supervision.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He fought elections promising that he will give the party a new cause and use new approaches to add conservative supporters to the party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Indian Claim Presence of Lashkar-e-Taiba and Jaysh-e-Mohammad in Jammu</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">There are reports of the presence of militants in the Ponch province of Jammu.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to official sources, on receiving secret information, police and army have surrounded the area and begun a search.</seg>
    <seg id="4">At this time a fight started in which four militants, two soldiers and one policeman were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the sources, fights were going on until the last news broke.  In this area, where militants associated with Lashker-e-Tayyaba and Josh-e-Muhammad are present, more soldiers have been sent to fight them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Meanwhile, the Chief Minister selected by the joint government, Umar Abdullah, met with the governor and informed him about his being selected the leader of his party, the National Conference in the assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Congress, the ally of the National Conference, also informed the governor of their advocacy of Omar Abdullah.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Umar Abdullah will be administered the oath as the Chief Minister of the State tomorrow.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Remember, the National Conference became the biggest party in the current state elections by gaining 28 seats in the assembly of 87 members. Keep in mind that Separatist Parties boycotted the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Congress, which secured 17 seats, accepted to form a coalition government with the National Conference.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Party workers welcomed Omar Abdullah with great fanfare on his arrival in Srinagar today.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On this occasion, Omar Abdullah says that he will play his role in making the talks possible between the Indian government and separatists. However, this will not be possible until the elections in India and formation of the new government.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The European Union's role in Peace in the Middle East</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">From the official point of view, the role of the European Union is decisive in the peace efforts to stop the war in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to Brussels' official stance, the efforts of Schwarzenberg delegation or Sarkozy were equally helpful in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The spokesperson of the European Commission, Amadeu Altafaj, said that every effort which helps advancing the joint message of the European Union to the two parties is welcome.</seg>
    <seg id="5">As far as the state policy is concerned, everyone seems alright.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But in reality the European Union is portraying a very disappointing picture of the internal tensions.</seg>
    <seg id="7">As the President of the Union, the Czech Republic's role is weak.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On top of that, internal fighting has made it all the more helpless.</seg>
    <seg id="9">On the other hand, the French President, Sarkozy, is behaving as if he is still the President of the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="10">France has completed its 6 month presidency period.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Sarkozy wants to play a presidential role, and he is able to, but he does not have the permission to do so.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The most funny situation is faced by the French foreign minister Bernard Kouchner.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He is part of a delegation which is headed by the foreign minister of the Czech Republic, Schwarzenberg.</seg>
    <seg id="14">What's worse, both the foreign ministers are giving different statements about the war in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Schwarzenberg says that Israel has the right to defend itself, whereas according to Kouchner this war does not come under defense policy. On the other side, Germany has also sent its special ambassador to the Middle East. The European Union will not succeed on a foreign platform until they express agreement based on the same issues.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Its evidence is the reaction of Israel, which does not give any importance to the conciliation efforts of the EU.</seg>
    <seg id="17">This is a golden chance for the European Union to do something since America, due to the policies of George W. Bush, has already failed in the Middle East.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Financial Crisis: Suicide of Billionaire German Industrialist.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Adolf Merckle, a resident of Sawabia in Southern Germany, left a huge business group behind him.</seg>
    <seg id="3">But earlier common German citizens did not know much about him.</seg>
    <seg id="4">when he had to negotiate with 30 banks who lent money to his industrial group, he became the topic of the headlines and he could foresee the murky future of the Merckle group.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Merkle group had to face a loss of a few hundred million Euros due to financial crisis after it bought shares in the German car manufacturing company, Volkswagen.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Financial institutions then refused to give it the new 700 million to one billion euro loan it needed on an immediate basis, so Merkle was under intense pressure.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Some time back, the bank agreed to provide Merkel Group an emergency loan. But, Adolf Merkel,who raised a small industrialist group to the position of a strong industrial group whose annual income was approximately 30 billion Euro, could not bare the loss in his investment capability.</seg>
    <seg id="8">After the death of his father, when Adolf Merkel took over his family business, he developed it quickly, putting it on a new track.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He called his company Ratiopharm, which is a very successful and large pharmaceutical company in Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Until a while ago, the value of this business was between 5 and 6 billion Euros, and it still earns about 8.1 billion Euros a year.After the superb success of Ratiopharm,the  Merkel group started buying many other institutions which included construction supply manufacturing companies like Hydelburg Cement to car manufacturing companies like Kassbohrer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The number of employees of the Merkel Group around the world is near 100,000, and its foundation company, the pharmaceutical company Ratiopharm, always had special importance.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Adolf Merkel has said many times in his life: "It has been four generations since I started making medicine.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Now the management of this group is in the hands of my children and I hope that the management of this company will remain in my family for a few hundred years.</seg>
    <seg id="14">After the suicide of Adolf Merkel, banks sanctioned 400 million euros in floating loans for his group, but under the condition that VEM will have to sell Ratiopharm so that it can improve its financial conditions in the long term.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Likewise after the death of Adolf Meerklay, the Meerklay group will not remain as it was.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Crime rate among the immigrants in Germany</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the fresh statistics, crime rate among the immigrants from 2004 to 2007 is</seg>
    <seg id="3">dropped from 22.9%</seg>
    <seg id="4">to 21.4%</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Joachim Herrmann, the Bavarian Interior Minister, this would appear to be a positive change.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said: "It is important to note that the number of foreigners getting German citizenship is increasing."</seg>
    <seg id="7">Therefore this should also be mentioned in the statistics that even though the criminal is German, his background is foreign.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Herrmann said that his province will take this into account when gathering statistics in 2010.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Besides Bavaria, Hamburg is also thinking  along the same lines.</seg>
    <seg id="10">A senator for foreign affairs from CDU, Christoph Ahlhaus, has said: "When research is done in a scientific manner, man can not pre-decide its results but it is based on the facts and figures that come out as a result of the research."</seg>
    <seg id="11">Ahlhaus diverted the attention to a research report from the anti crime's provincial office which was prepared in 2006 and according to this report in Bergdorf, a part of Hamberg, it was investigated that out of all crimes happening there what percentage have the involvement of foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="12">results showed that the foreigners here have</seg>
    <seg id="13">had a lower crime percentage than the crimes taking place in the whole state.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Contrary to this, during 2006, when the percentage of youngsters committing crimes was calculated, it became evident that the youngsters from a foreign background committing crime was 44</seg>
    <seg id="15">.7 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="16">However, other political parties of Germany for example, SPD, Environmentalists organization Greens, and leftist organization Linkspartei,were against this proposal that while collecting facts and figures regarding crimes, this should also be inquired which German citizens have foreign backgrounds.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">We want quick evacuation of troops from Gaza: Olmert</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Ehud Olmert has stressed that for complete evacuation of the army, a future and permanent ceasefire agreement is inevitable.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamas and Israel announced a ceasefire on Sunday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Islamic militant group Hammas, while announcing a one-week cease fire, has asked the Israeli army to leave the Gaza strip within one week and to end the barricade of the Gaza strip.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On other side, the leader of Hamas Ismail Hannan has said that Israel has been given victory from God in the Gaza war.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that in the Gaza war Israel was not able to achieve its purpose.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Prior to that, in the Egyptian city of Sharm Al Sheikh, a conference was held of Arab and European countries on Sunday, in which Israel was asked to evacuate its army from Gaza immediately.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It was decided in the meeting that soon an international aid conference for Gaza would be held.</seg>
    <seg id="9">German Chancellor Angela Merkel also attended the conference.</seg>
    <seg id="10">At least 1300 Palestinians and 13 Israelis, including 10 soldiers, were killed in three-week war between Israel and the Hammas militants.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the other side, Palestinian President Mahmood Abbas has insisted on the formation of a national government in the Palestinian areas.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Al-Qaida's Video Message to Germany</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this thirty minute video a man wearing a black turban, covering his face, and holding a gun in his hand addresses the German government.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This man introduces himself as Abu Talha and speaks in German.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Arabic subtitles The video contains Arabic subtitles.</seg>
    <seg id="5">There is a log of Al-Qaeda on the side of the screen and video has the date of October 2008.</seg>
    <seg id="6">in this message it is said to the German government that after deploying such a large number of troops in Afghanistan this country is thinking that it will not be attacked.</seg>
    <seg id="7">introducing himself as Abu Talha, this man however did not threaten to directly attack Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="8">the number of German troops amongst the Allied NATO forces in Afghanistan is around 3500.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Last year, in October, the German Parliament approved sending and additional 1000 soldiers to Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This is the first message received by Germany from Al-Qaeda.</seg>
    <seg id="11">having a critical eye on terrorism related issues, the famous expert Mikhail Luders says regarding this message: "The recent suicide attack on the German embassy in Kabul is proof of the fact that we should take it seriously in any case."</seg>
    <seg id="12">For the past few years Al-Qaida has been issuing video messages on the internet and there have been attacks after such messages.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The militant group the Taliban has taken responsibility for the terrorist attack outside the German Embassy this weekend.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Many German newspapers and pundits are looking at this attack in connection with the Al-Qaeda message.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They are targeting Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Fundamentalist Muslims are viewing Germany's Afghan policy in a negative and critical manner.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They blame the German government for adopting biased policies not just towards Afghanistan, but also toward the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="18">And for this reason they are increasingly finding Germany as their enemy.</seg>
    <seg id="19">In the meantime, the German Government says that the German intelligence agencies already knew about this video before it came to light.</seg>
    <seg id="20">The German joint crime control organization is busy studying the video.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama has Taken Charge of the American Presidency</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Not only the American public, but the whole world has increased expectations concerning Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Now that Barack Obama is receiving congratulatory messages from around the world after winning the presidency, expectations of him are also becoming clear.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this regard, German Chancellor Angela Merkel also expressed high expectations for the new American President.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I am sure that based on the friendship between the Federal Republic of Germany and the United States of America, we can resolve all the issues faced."</seg>
    <seg id="6">Russian Prime Minister Vladimir Putin said that Obama seems a serious and open-hearted person, a good sign.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Though the policies of former American president George W. Bush have been facing criticism.</seg>
    <seg id="8">However, his regime is appreciated for promoting China to play a more constructive role internationally. Whereas, China has said about the new American president will have to work for stronger military relations between both countries.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Based in the German city of Bochum, Chinese political expert Kusuay Wu says,</seg>
    <seg id="10">"In this regard, I am sure that in the coming weeks and months, Obama and his team of economists will put immense pressure on China to have a more flexible and competitive market exchange rate for the Chinese currency."</seg>
    <seg id="11">The former American regime has also improved its relations with India.</seg>
    <seg id="12">As to how far Obama can take these relations, Christopher Raj, professor of American Studies in New Delhi says, "Now we have come closer in strategic partnership. However, Obama can not bring an overnight change."</seg>
    <seg id="13">In his message to Obama, Pope Benedict has stressed on peace and cooperation in the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Provincial elections in Iraq.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">These are the first elections since 2005 in this war-stricken country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">More than 14,400 people entered the race for 440 seats in the state elections.</seg>
    <seg id="4">To maintain peace and safety during the elections, 800,000 police and soldiers were posted in Iraq.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Due to the danger of an explosion or any terrorist attack on this important day, all of Iraq's  boundaries were sealed before Friday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Also, the airports were closed and public transport was forbidden.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to reports, due to the restrictions on public transport, there was no traffic on the roads of Baghdad, and children were seen playing football on the roads.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the present Iraqi elections, the security arrangements will determine whether or not the local security agencies will be able to take over the country after the return of the American forces from Iraq in 2011, and also, political analysts are using this as a test as to what extent the public is prepared to bring change to the country in democratic ways.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Provincial elections are being held in Iraq with the help of United Nations and approximately 800 international correspondents will monitor the elections.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Yaom-e-Ashura: The day of Aashura and the great sacrifice of Hazrat Imam Hussain was celebrated with respect in Iran today.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Mahar news agency, in all small and big cities including Tehran, the capital of Iran, people mourned the sacrifice of Hazrat Imam Husain (peace be upon him), the leader of martyrs.  Huge crowds attended the mourning processions and meetings. Due respects and condolence were given to the Ahlu Baith (the Prophet's-- PBUH--inheritors). The whole of Iran observed with great sorrow and lamentation the supreme martyrdom in the Karbala battleground of the Prophet's grandson, Imam Hazrat Husain (PBUH). The true believers cherished the memory of the unique sacrifice of Hazrat Imam Husain in Karbala. Large crowds attended the condolence meetings and processions.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Retreat of Israeli soldiers from Ajleen province of Gaza: unmatched forbearance of Palestinian soldiers.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the Urdu service of Mehr news agency, even on the 16th day of the fight between truth and falsehood in Gaza, there was beastly bombing by Israel on the city population of Gaza, by the use of air, land and naval attacks, in which 880 people have died so far.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Among the martyred are 275 innocent children, who have slept in the lap of death, smiling at the deception of the leaders of Arab countries and of so-called human rights organizations.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Today, freedom fighters forced the Israeli forces back from the area of Ajeen and showed glorious righteousness. They had the power of the faith and shahadat.</seg>
    <seg id="5">If it were not for the deception of Egyptian president, Hasani (not) Mubarak, the brave and loyal Hamas Mujahids would have defeated Israel a long while ago, but apart from the Israeli siege, the Egyptians have also placed Palestinian Muslims under siege, which is the saddest story of Arab history.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Here, the Saudi Arabian and Jordanian governments are giving the Israeli government political and economic support, and are helping Israel by deceiving the helpless Muslims of Gaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barack Obama to Launch a New Iranian Policy</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a news agency, the elected president of America, Barak Obama said talking to ABC News that he will do a new policy about the issues of Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barack Obama said "Iran will be a big challenge for the American government."</seg>
    <seg id="4">Barack Obama said that he is concerned about Iranian support of Palestinian organizations Hamas and Hiza Ullah and Iran's uranium enrichment program.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But he will not continue the existing policy of current American president Bush, and he will adopt a different policy about relations with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama said that he would make his actual goal completely clear, while stressing the hope for mutual respect and dialog.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Barack Obama has said that there will be no conditions to talk with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the interview, he expressed the hope that his government would take quick policy decisions on Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Regarding the Middle East crisis, Obama said that he would form a special team</seg>
    <seg id="10">That will start working for peace in the Middle East beginning January 20.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush, unable and disliked president Bush accepted his mistakes and crimes in his last press statement.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency related from Associated Press that the American President George Bush, in the last press conference of his term, accepted numerous mistakes and crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In a Press Conference at the White House, President Bush has said that he has good wishes for newly-elected President Obama but the biggest challenge will be to protect the USA from terrorist attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the completion of the Iraq mission and social security reforms were his mistakes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush said that he did everything for the protection of America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Upon being asked various questions about the Israeli inflictions on Gaza, President Bush said that Israel has the right to defend itself. According to him, Hamas does not have the right to defend itself and Hamas should not do anything to Israel, and like America, the whole world should choke the oppressed rather than the oppressor.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The incapable and despicable president of the United States said that Hamas should not be given weapons either, while America is providing Israel the world's most destructive weapons. Israel is using American weapons to massacre Palestinians. and Bush also praised the Israel-supporting Arabs, calling them the friends of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Bush expressed shame at some of the crimes going on in the Abu Ghraib and Guantanamo prisons.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Experts say that Bush should be put on trial for war crimes and the organizations who will do this will do great benefit to mankind.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Iranian President Ahmedinejad expressed sorrow over the silence of the Arab leaders.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by Mehr News Agency, the Iranian President Mahmood Ahmadinejad criticized the Arab leaders' silence over the Israeli inhumanity and oppression on Gaza, expressing his sorrow.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmadinejad said, expressing surprise over the Arab countries and their leaders' silence over the beastly acts of Israel, that Israel is subjecting the Palestinian public to a holocaust. They are making the Palestinian children, women and civilians targets of their barbarianism, and the Arab leaders have not even given one statement.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmedinejad said that all Arab countries should unite against Israel and save the oppressed Muslims of Gaza from the harm and oppression of Israel.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ahmadinejad: The king of Saudi Arabia clarify his position on the massacre in Gaza by Israel.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the report by MAHAR/MEHR news agency, President Ahmede Nejad in his message to the Saudi King Malik Abdullah declared that the silence on the human genocide in Gaza and muteness on the murder of innocent children and women by  the Muslim King of Saudi Arabia is encouraging the enemies of Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmedinejad said in his address, that you must clarify your position and support the oppressed openly, so that the efforts of the enemies to cause differences in the Muslim platform may be unsuccessful.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmede Nejad has said in his message: "You know that for the last 19 days Israel has been bent upon human genocide, murdering innocent children, and subjecting homes, mosques, schools and hospitals to barbaric bombing. The Zonist Regime is brutally murdering the unarmed Muslims in Gaza. In situations like these, silence on the part of leaders like you is only encouraging Israel."</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Ahmedinejad addressed King Abdullah, saying non-Islamic countries like Venezuela and Bolivia have taken definite steps against Israel, so only better steps can be expected from you.</seg>
    <seg id="6">President Ahmadinejad said that Palestinians will be successful in Palestine.</seg>
    <seg id="7">and the oppressed will win over the oppressors and that's Allah's promise.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090116.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush: Terrorism Still a Threat for America</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr news agency reported from German news agencies that American President George Bush said in his farewell speech, addressing his successor Barack Obama and the whole nation, that if compared to seven years ago, America is relatively safe, nevertheless, the threat of terrorism is still floating over the head of America.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Bush said that the enemy terrorists are waiting patiently to attack America, and they have a strong determination to attack America so America should never be unaware about its security.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The American President ignored the hurt and suffering of the hundreds of thousands of Palestinians in Gaza, and defended his policies saying that America is still the biggest supporter country of independence. However, commentators do not accept the reality of the unpopular president's remarks, as America is neither a supporter of freedom, nor a supporter of human rights, but rather it is the most mischievous country in the world, which not only supports a bloodthirsty country like Israel, but is also directly involved in its crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Israel is committing massacre by slaughtering children, women and common people and America's President is praising him. This is the humanity and freedom the America that the world is witnessing in Gaza and other parts of the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Usama Hamdan: Presence of army in Palestine continues</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by Mehr News Agency, Usamah Hamdan,  the Hamas leader in Lebanon, told French News Agency during an interview that a one-sided ceasefire from the Israeli side is against the comprehensive international efforts for a ceasefire. He said that as long as Israel is present in Gaza, a one-sided ceasefire is meaningless.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that the one-sided ceasefire was an unsuccessful effort of Israel to escape defeat. Hamdan said that if Israel wants long-term peace, it will have to accept Hamas's conditions as well as end this siege.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The Hamas leader in Lebanon made it clear that if Israel tries a one-sided ceasefire with its army remaining in the Gaza belt, there will be resistance against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In Beirut, attending a conference in solidarity with the Gaza people Asama Hamadan asked the European countries to discontinue diplomatic relations with Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Hamas leader said that the increasing numbers of the martyred and injured will only increase our determination.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He told the Palestinian public to stay firmly rooted and resist the enemy like a boulder.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan: Taliban kill 6 people in Pakistani tribal region of North Waziristan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A news agency quoted a report that in the tribal area of North Waziristan two Afghan citizens and four Pakistanis have been murdered, blamed for spying.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to reports, on Tuesday morning locals found four dead bodies from Tehsil Chowk in Tehsil Mir Ali, who were shot dead.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Whereas two more dead bodies were found from the main area of Miranshah, they were thrown in the market of a Bazaar .</seg>
    <seg id="5">Letters written in Urdu were also found close the corpses, claiming that the dead were killed for spying.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Two weeks earlier in Miranshah, the capital of North Waziristan, two Afghan citizens were also killed accused of spying.</seg>
    <seg id="7">During the last twelve days days fifteen people have been killed over the accusation of spying for America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Within the last 6 years, more than 100 people have been killed as accused spies in South and North Waziristan. The Taliban are accused of being involved in these cases.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Barack Obama expected to sign order closing    notorious Guantanamo Bay prison.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr News Agency report sources say that the American President will sign the order to close down the notorious Guatanamo Bay prison.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The new American president, Barack Obama, started working on his campaign promises at the surface level.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this regard, President Obama called for making a plan for recalling the army from Iraq, while the American president will sign an order today to close the notorious Guantanamo Bay prison.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that President Barack Obama will probably sign the order today by which the Guantanamo prison will be closed within one year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is expected that White House will review the investigative methods from suspected terrorists. Misbehavior with prisoners can also be banned.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President Barack Obama started to fulfill his election campaign promises from his first day in office, and first of all started by taking steps toward making the actions and workings of the government transparent.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Experts say that the American president has begun efforts to save the falling image of America throughout the world. That will be difficult, because as long as it keeps supporting the bloodthirsty Israeli government, it can not be expected to do anything good. Therefore, if America wants to save its image, it will have to stop its support of Israel and disassociate itself from Israel's crimes.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tony Blair stresses need to include Islamic organization, Hamas in talks</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr news agency quoted from British newspaper The Times that former Prime Minister Tony Blair stressed the need to include Hamas in the talks to bring about peace in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the newspaper, Tony Blair said that it is important that a path be found for bringing Hamas into the Middle East peace process. Blair criticized the Bush administration for speaking only to Mahmood Abbas and ignoring Hamas. It should be clear that the western countries have realized the democratic and organizational powers of Hamas and are calling for bringing them into the talks, whereas previously they used to consider it a terrorist organization. A terrorist organization which is trying to defend its country and struggling to save its own house from the clutches of others. Whose house and country have been in the hand of the occupying Israeli government for 60 years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Murder of Balochistan Merchants in Karachi, Complete Strike in Quetta</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After the killing of four Baluchistan traders in Karachi, there was a full strike on Thursday in Kwetta and other areas.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this period all business centers remained closed, whereas traffic was also less than usual.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The protesting strike was called by the 'Anjuman Tajiran Balochistan' (Balochistan Trade Union), Pushtunkhwah Milli Awami Party and the Jamiat-e-Ulama-e-Islam. They accused the Karachi police for open fire at these merchants, when they were going to their vehicle showroom on Tariq road.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The president of the Anjuman Tajiran, Abdur Raheem Kakad demanded that police agents at fault should be arrested and action should be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, the stance of the Karachi police regarding this incident was not immediately clear.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The four traders were from the capital city Chaman.</seg>
    <seg id="8">At the time of strike, many arrangements were under taken by the government and there were police at main points.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamas Senior Commander Killed in Israel Attack</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">a senior Hamas commander was killed in an Israeli air attack.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This is the second death of an important Hamas figure, in the week-long Israeli attacks on the Gaza belt.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The office bearer of Hamas has said that Abu Zakaria Al Jamal died on Saturday in the Al Shujahia street, located in the east of Gaza City.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In another air attack on Thursday, Hamas scholar Alam Nazar Rehan was also killed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Hamas's evacuated leader, who stays in Syria, Khalid Mushil has promised to take revenge and warned Israel of launching a land attack on Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Thousands of Israeli tanks and soldiers are posted at the Gaza border, and they are waiting for orders to attack.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America has appealed for a cease fire, but has said that the decision ultimately rests with Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="9">American President George Bush, on his weekly radio speech, has accused Hammas of excitation to aggravate violence. And has adjudged their rocket attacks on Israel as terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He has said that America is working on a cease fire, but a one-way agreement will not be accepted.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Three Dead Bodies Found in Northern Waziristan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani security officials have said that three bodies were found in the tribal areas of Northern Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is suspected that Taliban gave them the death penalty and killed them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">These bodies were found near the capital city of north Waziristan, Meeran Shah, and such papers were found on them on which accusations of their spying for America were written.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officials said that one of the bodies is probably that of the man who was kidnapped last week.</seg>
    <seg id="6">They said that the two remaining bullet-ridden bodies belonged to Afghani citizens.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Israeli attacks on Gaza continue for the 10th straight day.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A Palestinian child was injured in the Israel missile attack. The Israeli ground army is fighting with Hamas troops in the entire area of the Gaza strip whereas the Israeli air force continued attacks on the areas of militant groups on the tenth day.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The defense minister of Israel, Ehud Barack, said on Monday that they will continue the army operation until the people of Southern Israel are safe from the rocket attacks of Hamas.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, despite Israeli attacks, the rocket firing from Hamas's side has continued, due to which four people, including three civilians have died.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On Monday, Hamas leader Mahmood Zuhr pressured his companions to destroy the Israeli army and target Israeli civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But one official of Hamas said that they plan to send a delegation to Egypt on Monday to discuss the current violent situation of their party.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In Gaza one Palestinian woman was injured. Medical sources in Gaza said that during the last ten days almost 530 people have been killed including those 11 civilians; at least five were children.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Israel has reported one soldier killed and 10 more injured in a ground attack.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Israel has stopped journalists from entering Gaza to do reporting on the military action.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Elected American Vice President, Joseph Biden Reached Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Foreign Minister welcomed the American Vice President.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The elected Vice President of America along with his delegates  reached Islamabad on Friday for a tour of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Foreign Minister Shah Mehmood Qureshi and higher officials of the American consulate welcomed them.</seg>
    <seg id="5">American Senator Lindsy Graham is also with Biden on this trip.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Press Officer of the American Embassy, Lou Fintor told the Voice of America that the newly elected President, would talk to the Pakistani government about various regional issues during his tour. However, he avoided giving more details.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the sources of foreign office, Joseph Biden will also meet Army chief General Ashfaq Parvez Kiyani besides other high government officials.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is expected that during these meetings, war against terrorism will also be discussed besides important bilateral and international issues.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Joseph Biden was awarded the Hilal-e-Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After arriving in Islamabad, Joseph Biden met with President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="11">During the meeting, the president presented him with Hilal-e-Pakistan for playing an important role in forming close relations between Pakistan and America.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Joe Biden, head of the Foreign Relations Committee, along with Senator Richard Lugar introduced a bill indicating that the United States would increase defense to Pakistan to $5.7 billion in the next five years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Joe Biden played an important role in removing the previous president Parvez Musharaf, Prime Minister Gilani</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Yusuf Raza Gilani and Joe Biden ( File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="3">Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Gilani has stated that America's Vice Presidential candidate Joe Biden has played an important role in ending Parvez Musharaf's tenure as Army Chief of Staff. Biden has also done a great deal to promote democracy in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Yousaf Raza Gillani gave this statement while addressing reporters in a Karachi shipyard.</seg>
    <seg id="5">stated that Joe Biden supports Pakistan, and that he, as a chairperson of the Foreign Affairs Committee of the American Senate, presented a bill of 15 billion dollars aid for Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="6">About the missile attacks by American spy planes within Pakistani boundaries, the Pakistani Prime Minister once more derogated them saying that there is no agreement with the American government on allowing such attacks according to him, it was a matter of Pakistani sovereignty and hence by no means could they give permission for such attacks within their territory.</seg>
    <seg id="7">They also expressed the hope that after the new president came into power American policy would also be changed.</seg>
    <seg id="8">(File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="9">Yusuf Raza Gilani has said that the government has successfully separated the Taliban from ordinary tribesmen, but the drone attacks have proven to be very harmful to the efforts of the government as the terrorists once again join forces with the local tribes.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that the international community agrees with this stance of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The prime minister also said that if any trustful evidence is given, Pakistani forces will take action on there area by themselves.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Gilani reiterated his stance against the Mumbai attacks and said that if India provides evidence, then investigation will be carried out on that basis, and if there is any proof of someone's involvement, he will be dealt according to the laws of the country.</seg>
    <seg id="13">While answering a question about Rehman Malik's tour to Britain and his meeting with the MQM leader Altaf Hussain, the Prime Minister said that Rehman Malik went to London on his approval.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Four Quetta Policemen Killed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">File Photo</seg>
    <seg id="3">On an important highway in Quetta, Saryab road, firing by unknown people killed four policemen, including DSP "Deputy Superintendent of Police".</seg>
    <seg id="4">Wednesday morning in a Jeep two DSP, one sub inspector and two constables were on their way to the police training center. On Sariab Road near a college, an unknown rider on a motorcycle attacked the police Jeep and fired continuously. Sub Inspector Mehdi and Constable Sibgat ul llah and Nasr ul Ilah died on the scene but one DSP, Hasan Ali, died after reaching the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Hospital sources say that the other injured DSP Ghulam Muhammad's situation is also critical and he has been shot in the neck and the head.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After this incident police cordoned the entire area. As of now, no one has claimed the responsibility for the attack.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Another Indian software engineer dies in America</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Another software engineer belonging to Andhra Pradesh has been shot and killed by unknown attacker's.</seg>
    <seg id="3">26 year-old Akshay Vishal of Secunderanadwas was shot two days ago by unidentified assailants in the state of Arkansas. Vishal died in the hospital today while undergoing treatment for his injuries.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was an employee of Satyam Computers and was providing services for Falcon Jet Airways in America.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In the last year, seven students from Andhra Pradesh have been killed by American anti-social elements.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The rise in the deaths of those going to America for higher studies and employment has increased the worries of the thousands of families whose children are in America.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It should be known that America is preferred in Andhra Pradesh for higher studies and brighter future's.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to statistics from the American consulate in Chennai, one hundred thousand applications are received for visas every year, of which the most (40%) are from Andhra Pradesh.</seg>
    <seg id="9">During this time, the provincial government started trying to bring the dead body of the deceased to Hyderabad.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bush: America Should Be Vigilant for Enemy Attacks</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In his last weekly speech on the radio President Bush has insisted America be on the alert for enemy attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Bush said that the biggest threat to Americans is still the possibility of another terrorist attack. He stated that the enemies of the country are patiently waiting, and that they are bent on attacking again.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The retiring president has said that America should never be ignorant of its safety.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush has also expressed best wishes for the next President, Barrack Obama, who will take his oath of office on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In a radio broadcast on behalf of the Democratic party on Saturday, newly elected president Barack Obama spoke on the historical importance of the oath taking ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that this ceremony is a tradition in which the peaceful transfer of power from one leader to another is further evidence of the greatness of America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mr. Obama reminded listeners that around the world, many people can not even imagine the succession of a leader without blood and turbulence.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Meeting between sharifs and interior minister. Political and security affairs discussed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A meeting was convened in Raiwind between Interior Minister Rehman Malik and Nawaz Sharif, head of the PML-N, Pakistan's largest opposition party and ruling party in Punjab. Chief Minister Shehbaz Sharif also attended the meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to local media, Rehman Malik has brought a message from the PPP's top leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, Rehmand Malik did not give any details to the press. He told the media that national affairs were discussed during the meeting and he briefed the PML-N leadership about the post-Mumbai attack security situation.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words "I let them know about the action taken so far".</seg>
    <seg id="6">It should not be forgotten that a lot of action was taken by the Punjab government and that the team that I formed will need the help of the Punjab government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to Rehman Malik, although the media is not briefed, messages are exchanged among the leadership on a daily basis. Pervaiz Rashid Mir, the PML-N representative, was very careful not to disclose anything, saying that "Rehman Malik has said all that needs to be said."</seg>
    <seg id="8">It should be known that Pakistan Muslim League (n)'s leadership met the Internal Advisor at a time when the state was in a state of hot political activity with 20 or more leaders belonging to the opposition party. PML (q) held a press conference with the Governor of Punjab, Salman Taseer, rejecting the steps of the government in the state and opposing the inclusion of the Governor of Punjab, who is from the Pakistan Peoples Party in this matter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama's speech is good news for Pakistan, Zardari</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani president, Asif Ali Zardari, welcomed the opening speech of the new President of the United States, Barack Obama, saying that his statement that he would advance relationships with the Muslim world, based on mutual interests and mutual respect, is good news for Pakistan and its people.</seg>
    <seg id="3">in a statement issued on Wednesday, he said that reiteration of high moralities and values from the American president is a hope for a better future for the people of the world.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to the statement, President Zardari said that America, together with the international community, has a great responsibility of finding new ways of peace, success, and happiness in the 21st century.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Let it be clear that President Obama said in his opening speech on Tuesday after taking the oath, that America wants a new approach towards the Muslim world, based on mutual interests and mutual respect.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He told the people of poor countries that America will work with them so that there is social development and reduction poverty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Obama nominated a Special Representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Former Ambassador for United Nations Richard Holbrooke has been nominated as a Special Representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Holbrooke played a vital role in peace agreements in Bosnia Herzegovina.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Hall Brook said he is ready to advise President Obama on the matters of Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He added that this work is not easy.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that the histories of both countries were extremely different.</seg>
    <seg id="7">George Mitchell, who has been selected for the Middle East, will try to revive the Arab-Israeli dialogue.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mitchell is former minister and he played an important role in establishing peace in Northern Ireland.</seg>
    <seg id="9">While talking at the State Department today, he said that the situation in the Middle East is very vulnerable, complicated and dangerous.</seg>
    <seg id="10">But despite this, America will not step down from their efforts for peace over there.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghanistan Voter Registration in Peril</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Election commission of Afghanistan: due to concerns over security, it is delaying voter registration in some areas in the south.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Voter registration for the upcoming Presidential Election in Southern Afghanistan started this week.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, the commission was told that unless the security situation does not improve, voters in a few areas of the province Hilmand will not be able to get registered.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The rate of violence has been increased since last year in those southern areas where Taliban rebels have increased their attacks on Afghan Forces and International Forces.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Meanwhile, Afghan and international forces have said that between Wednesday and Thursday night, they have killed at least 28 militants during fights across Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">NATO said that their army has destroyed 22 fighters during air and land attacks on eastern province of Khost near the border of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Previously, the Afghan Defense Ministry had said that the Afghan army had killed eight rebels and injured two in the same province.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is not clear whether the Afghani officeholders are referring to the same incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090123.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Two missile attacks in Waziristan, at least 18 people killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistan Intelligence officials have said that at least 18 people were killed in two doubtful American missile attacks in North Waziristan .</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the officials, an American jet fired three missiles near a house in the area Mir Ali of north Waziristan, killing ten people in that house.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to local officials, five of the dead were non-national soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This region is considered the center of Taliban and Al-Qaidah activity.</seg>
    <seg id="6">A few hours after this incident, a missile attack was performed on south Waziristan as well, in which at least eight people died.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Despite the objections of the Pakistani government, about 30 missile attacks occurred in Pakistan since the middle of last year.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The present attacks were the first since President Barack Obama took office.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The Bush administration had refused to acknowledge responsibility for such attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="10">On Friday, suspected American spy planes dropped three missiles in the tribal region of North Waziristan. Until now, five people have died.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The dead victims have not been identified.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to initial reports, the missile attacks were on a house in the locality of Mir Ali.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It should be considered that this was the first attack after Barack Obama became president.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Sarhad Government Rejected the Question of Ban on Girls Education</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In Sarhad state, officials have rejected the Taliban's warning to restrict girls education, saying that this announcement is against both law and Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On Sunday, the education minister of Sarhad state, Sardar Husain Babar, added that the government will never allow such efforts to succeed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said the extremists want the children in our areas to remain uneducated.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words, "These people try to secretly blow up schools and frighten the boys and girls".</seg>
    <seg id="6">Talking about the environment of fear and insecurity, he said that the local government knows well and wants it to be known that no force can stop the spread of education in the land of the Pukhtons.</seg>
    <seg id="7">One day ago, the Taliban soldiers, led by Moulana Fazlullah demanded the banning of girls from studying in Swat's educational institutions from the 15th of January.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Despite the military activity going on in Swat during the last one and a half years, about 150 educational institutions were destroyed by the militants by the use of explosives and arson.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Due to the destruction of these educational institutions; thousands of girls and boys were deprived of the facility of education.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Strict security arrangements in India on Republic Day.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The 60th Republic Day is being celebrated in India on Monday. On this occasion, strict security measures are being taken and thousands of soldiers were posted throughout the country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On the occasion of Republic Day, during the army parade in New Delhi, weapons, planes and other military equipment is displayed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According to officials, to strengthen the security arrangements, air guns and 'sharp shooter' have been deployed. Police will monitor the routes used for the Parade. The American president congratulated India on this occasion</seg>
    <seg id="5">He also wished Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh a speedy recovery; who had undergone a heart operation on Saturday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It should be remembered that yesterday the Indian police claimed to have killed two suspected Pakistani militants after a shootout in the outskirts of New Delhi.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to the local authorities, police exported 47 rifles, grenades, and some papers from these two persons, which show that these two are Pakistani.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Police are also investigating whether these two individuals belonged to the banned organization 'Lashkar-e-Taiba' which was involved in last November's Mumbai attacks.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tea: an Effective Cure for Breast Cancer</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a new research, three cups of tea a day</seg>
    <seg id="3">can decrease the risk of cancer in women below 50 years of age, by more than a third.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Research at the Moffitt Cancer Center in the American State of Florida, has showed that chances of getting chest cancer in those women under 50 years of age</seg>
    <seg id="5">who drink at least three cups of tea a day is reduced by up to 37%.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The research study also claims that it does not help older women even if they drink three or more cups of tea daily.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Specialists think that this is because of the presence of such components in tea that are more effective against the types of cancer tumors which usually target women under 50 years of age.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In Moffitt Cancer Center, in the city of Tampa, Florida state, a research was conducted on over 5000 women, who had undergone treatment for breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Their ages were between 20 and 74 years.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Experts compared their medical records and lifestyles with women who were safe from breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The experts also found out that on a particular type of cancer, Lobular, tea had shown a great effect and it reduced by 66 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Almost every tenth patient of breast cancer suffers from this type of it.</seg>
    <seg id="13">This type of cancer is more dangerous because it originates deep inside the breast tissue, and is usually diagnosed when it has already spread to a great extent.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Experts say that by drinking at least three cups of tea a day, the danger of breast cancer can be reduced in young women.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They say that incorporating tea as a regular drink in your daily routine helps create immunity against the cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="16">In Britain every year almost 40,000 women are diagnosed with breast cancer.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Afghan war is the greatest challenge faced by America : Gates.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">American defense minister Robert Gates has said that the war in Afghanistan is the biggest military challenge faced by America.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Today Gates was briefing the senate and the house of representatives of the strategy adopted by the Obama administration on the Afghan, and Iraq war.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Gates told the Armed Services Senate Committee that war is not the only solution to the Afghan problem, but he further stated that, in order to make many areas secure, Army Personell are not available,taking the advantage of it the Taliban carry out actions.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Why Reduce Exercise With Age?</seg>
     <seg id="2">New research</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="3">Exercise at any age is good for health.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It energizes your heart, reduces cholesterol levels, helps in keeping weight low, helps to prevent diabetes and slows down the process of Alzheimer's or dementia.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Unfortunately the ability to exercise reduces in many people with the age.</seg>
    <seg id="6">experts say that exercise keeps our body and brain active, however, age can affect it.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The American Medical Association says that Many health problems can occur if exercise is not carried out.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Dr. Patricia Palecca of Mayo Clinic, Minnesota says that an increase in age is a major cause of inability to excercise and lack of bodily activity.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Dr. Patricia teaches medicine at the Mayo Clinic.</seg>
    <seg id="10">She headed a research trial regarding heart diseases and the ability to participate in exercise in older age.</seg>
    <seg id="11">A team of doctors used high frequency sound waves to observe the performance of heart</seg>
    <seg id="12">The pumping of the blood by the heart, its contraction and relaxation was studied.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The experts focused on the left part of the heart, which is the main part for pumping blood.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They came to know ,that with increase in age, problems increase in the relaxation action of heart.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Dr. Patricia says that as age increases the faults in the relaxation of the heart begin to appear and this affects the ability to exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Dr. Garwin  Cain was also a part of this study.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He says that they were surprised to see that it has an effect, as it confirmed that poor exercising ability is closely related to the heart's relaxation phase.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Sometimes blood pressure can cause faults in the working of the heart and can become a cause of heart diseases.</seg>
    <seg id="19">If the doctor and the patient work together on the faults of the heart they can achieve the benefits of exercise, despite the increase in age.</seg>
    <seg id="20">A detailed report of this has been published in the magazine of the American Medical Association.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">No Chances of an Immediate War with Pakistan: Indian Army Chief</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The chief of the Indian Army, General Deepak Kapoor has stated that there are no chances of immediate war with Pakistan. However, to serve the country and protect its interests, the Indian Army is always ready.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He has stated that despite the commitments and international pressure on Pakistan as a result of the attacks in Mumbai, the infrastructure of terrorism not only exists but is also proactive in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said this while talking to correspondents in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The Indian Army Chief was on a one day tour of the valley of Kashmir in order to analyze both the overall security situation in New Delhi administered Kashmir and the preparation of armed forces on the borders.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He was asked his thoughts on media reports that Pakistan has rejected the evidence provided from India regarding the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="7">General Kapoor said that decisions in matters of peace or war are made by the political leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Talking about terrorism in the land of Pakistan, he allegedly said that India will fight against the forces that are trying to destroy peace and weaken India.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He said that there are around 700 to 800 fighters present in Indian Kashmir, of whom almost 50% are foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="10">General Deepak Kapoor said that only with the betterment in the weather, the efforts of encroachment between Pakistan and Kashmir under its government can be increased.  Although India has increased security on the borders.</seg>
    <seg id="11">They have refused the possibility of reduction in the number of army soldiers in Indian Kashmir by stating that one can't compromise over the country's security.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah bless the tongues of the world and may Barack become a blessing for the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Though there is not much hope, we shall see how the relationship between America and Pakistan are effected by this change.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We shall also see what Barack Obama, who is the result of Martin Luther King's dreams, gives to the world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Obama, part of whose name is Husain, taking the oath today, as the American President, is not only a matter of all sorts of historic importance, but also a historic test.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Not only for himself, but also for all the people who supported him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It will even be a test for the white majority, as for them to accept from their hearts, a black governing over them is no easy task.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Those here in South Asia, especially the Muslims, who have hopes about him should remember that he was elected the president of America, and Obama should remember that the president of America is actually the president of the world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After a moment, a man whose brothers and sisters from his generation were brought to America from their countries as slaves and whose sweat and blood have strengthened the roots of the most powerful country of the new era, today a representative of this racially discrete nation will be called the 40th president of this very America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have expectations from this one man.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is necessary for those who admire him not to have unrealistic expectations for him.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If Obama becomes successful in decreasing the religious and racial acrimony, it will be a victory for his fans.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What effect will this change have on South Asia, and what considerable change can be expected in the American policy in this regard?</seg>
     <seg id="2">How will this change affect the relationship between America and Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="3">image not available</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sir, whether it be Obama or someone else, the type of policies with regards to the whole world are decided by the multi-billionaire, influential, strong Jewish lobby.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And as far as Pakistan is concerned, after the series of recent Bombay blasts, the offensive reaction of India, America and Israel is obvious to everyone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the creation of Pakistan, the administration of Swat remained with the Ruler of Swat that had a regular Army and Law.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They surrendered their rule to the government of Pakistan, according to a treaty.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But it's sad that our governments have treated Swat like a step mother.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the end of the governance of the King, there were no more schools founded in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Also, the areas development was not given any notice either.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Currently, the number of girls acquiring education is far less than in previous years.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Taliban continue their attacks on educational institutions in the NWFP.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The largest number of schools destroyed has been in the district of Swat, and the majority of those are girls schools.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Not only this, but the Taliban have announced the prohibition of girls education in Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thousands of male and female students have been deprived from getting education.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you think the goal of the Taliban is by wanting to end the education of women?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Why has the government been unsuccessful in stopping these illegal steps?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What actions do you think the government should take to stop these illegal activities.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The question should be, what do the ISI and Pakistani agencies get?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Because the people of Swat have realized this was a game and that the army was there to serve the Taliban and not to kill them. Otherwise, how could five schools be blown up in a single curfew night? How could people be slaughtered during curfew and hung in the center of the town?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When the government is not being allowed to have any say in Swat, how can the government be successful in stopping these illegal steps?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, the question arises as to how, when the government has an armed military, new and dangerous weapons, new technology and spy system etc., these four Taliban elements are not being controlled?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The answer is they have the hand of some secret power, which is why their weapons never run out and they are never arrested.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The conclusion is that the Taliban, through their dark activities, are making the work of the global leadership easier.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fifteen years ago, the war was on in Afghanistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The ISI was controlling the Taliban while on the opposing side the Northern Coalition was being aided by Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Then, suddenly, the situation changed and the Taliban's works came to light.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And ISI also got an offer of Dollars from America, so the previous friend became an enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now the scenario is that the war is still raging but the supporters in Pakistan are still the same Iran, India, and Russia.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Until mankind can understand the difference between whats right and whats wrong he will always make the wrong decision.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For example, if a thief intends to commit a crime, realizes it's wrong he will also fear his Lord and then he will not commit the crime.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Likewise, unless Israel inderstand it is wrong for it to drain the blood of innocents, and that there will be  punishment for this, it will keep playing Holi with the innocent blood of Gaza.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Greetings!</seg>
     <seg id="2">The question is whether war and terrorism are solutions to the problem?</seg>
     <seg id="3">If not, then what is the solution?</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is true that war and extremism do not solve problems, but adds 'blessings' to them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Palestine, Afghanistan and Iraq should adopt the same model for their development that Nelson Mandela used in South Africa.</seg>
     <seg id="6">That is, to struggle character wise and politically, more than in an armed manner.</seg>
     <seg id="7">kashmiri's participation in election shows that they have accepted his point.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Israeli attacks have gone on in Gaza for 3 weeks, and the death toll has reached 1000.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Despite worldwide diplomatic efforts, to date, a ceasefire was not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And according to a guess 9000 Falatinis have been left their homes and gone to save places after the attacks  starting in December.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Charitable organizations blame Israel for failing to care for the mental and emotional problems caused to Palistinian children.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What are you saying?</seg>
     <seg id="6">what do you think should to be done?</seg>
     <seg id="7">How is permanent peace possible in Gaza?</seg>
     <seg id="8">For details, click here.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Kindly note, due to increase in comments, only Urdu written suggestions will publish.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Press Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard to select Urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Taliban should be given a chance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Basit, Peshawar</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wake up! If the Taliban starts the real Jihad, who will slaughter innocent people?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Who will burn down the girls schools?</seg>
     <seg id="5">If kidnap for ransom, or not getting ransom so who will hang people on the pole by called them American spy?</seg>
     <seg id="6">These Taliban members have brought more damage to Islam than any nation or religion has ever brought.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pashtoon Roar</seg>
     <seg id="8">Kohat, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If the whole Muslim world just give a joint threat to attack Israel, you will see  how upset its father, America, will be.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And immediately not only talks on ceasefire but ceasefire will really happen as well.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But what can be done, where can our leaders get so much courage?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Someone should tell Ahmed Nayad to take the first step since he is very popular for his bravery at the BBC forums.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The responsibility for establishing peace and human rights falls not only upon the Arabs or the Muslims of the world, but rather it is the duty of all the nations in the world to speak up against oppression.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This sad incident is the worst crime committed by Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Just like in Pakistan and India, before the 30th of June or the end of the fiscal year the government institutions are looted. The American regime, just before its end, had given a green light to Israel to do whatever it wants.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">On one hand, America says that efforts will be made for a ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, the United Nation is passing one resolution after another but both have done nothing practically. This means that united nation is also working  to crush the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the Islamic Countries should cancel their membership in United Nations and lay the foundation of their own international organization.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We have many examples of where only promises and resolutions of America and the United Nations are seen, but the harm is only done to the Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What is the use of these vain efforts if the BBC does not want to publish anything?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Where have all the rules of journalism been buried? When blood, specifically of Muslims, is spilled, the monster of unbiasedness gets onto BBC's back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">by the way is a flag bearer of rights</seg>
     <seg id="4">Saying something from their side is a far away thing when they do not even want comments.</seg>
     <seg id="5">For the Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The only difference between you and the Jews is that they call themselves Jews and martyr the Muslims, while you stay among Muslims, call yourselves Muslims and cause Muslims..</seg>
     <seg id="2">[syja786]</seg>
     <seg id="3">For a long time, BBC forums have been using a certain word, sometimes while discussing suicide attacks and other times, while discussing terrorism in India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Extremism is the favorite word for those anti-islamic comments.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But who is the extremist? That you can easily figure out from the above comment.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When will our Muslims understand that Dajjal cannot be fought with the sword?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Looking at unarmed people in the bombing of Israel, what can one do other than cry?</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the most basic mistake behind this destruction and killing is that we try to use the name of Jihad to disfigure the beautiful face of Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When majority of the Palestinians have accepted the existence of Israel, what need does Hamas have to send rockets into Israel or conduct suicide attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">The conduct of both sides is misanthropic.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The role of the UN and the USA was again seen as favoring the injustice of Israel.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah allow the Muslim nation to unite. Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And we should think about giving the real terrorists an anti-terrorism Nobel prize for their painstaking efforts against terrorism, as after all, they are doing the real work.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise, would it be possible for terrorism to take place at such a large scale without the support of some big leader? And everyone knows who is controlling the strings.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In easy words, such gangsters are told to do whatever they want.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It hits you hard on the head and does not even let you cry.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Arab rulers are giving medicines for the injured, funeral clothings for the dead and money and they are asking</seg>
     <seg id="2">Israeli attacks, what should happen?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The actual problem is that the leaders of all the Muslim countries, including the Saudi king, are in a deep sleep. They neither have an army nor any protective plans. They think they can support and fulfill their responsibility.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They should immediately take practical steps against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="5">For example, stopping the supplies of petrol to European countries and America but alas they</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salam to all brothers and sisters!</seg>
     <seg id="2">I believe that in this time of difficulty, telling Hamas to stop their struggle for the sake of peace is an injustice to thousands of widows and hundreds of thousands orphans, and it is similar to considering them defeated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If Israel and its supporters are at the height of their Pharoahism, soon Moses will be born within their house, as this is the rule of nature. The steps taken by America and Israel have acted like a fertilizer in growing suicide bombers among the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Which these power intoxicated elephants are not realizing.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Abu Abdullah, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now Hamas and Israel should cease fire to stop bloodshed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Muhammad Sarfaraz, Paris, France.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rightly said.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Suppose that Hamas is 100% truthful, and they are struggling against oppression, to become successful in the eyes of Allah.  Even then, they should know that if a good deed results in the destruction of an established house, it is no longer a good deed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">For those who claim to love God, love the messenger, and love their religion, loving mankind is a part of their faith.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As if it is the order of Allah to evacuate all the people of the Book from the face of the earth, other than the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najibur Rehman Psycho, *Lahore* [P@KI@N]</seg>
     <seg id="3">The order is not to kill them but to invite them to Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jihad is ordered against those who do conspiracies against the religion.</seg>
     <seg id="5">These people should be fought against unless they stop these conspiracies. This doesn't mean that one should wear a jacket and blast himself at a gathering.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Brothers, the end result of killing innocent children is destruction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But I say to my friends that yesterday Israelis did not have a roof over their heads and today they are so strong that they do not listen to anyone because all Jews are one.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There are no Sheas and Sunnis. There are all just Jews and they have developed everything in every field.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In contrast, what is the condition of 55 Islamic countries?</seg>
     <seg id="5">They are behind in every field, and now the situation is that they have become so helpless that the enemy is killing them and they are waiting to die.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is essential that all Muslim countries unite and prepare a strategy against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Feroz Magsi, Jhang, Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">There is no better strategy than to recognize Israel, learn modern education and means of progress, and let the world live in peace and harmony.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Muslims have great land and resources.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The need is for proper usage.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The first and most disappointing factor is that Hamas and Alfateh could not unite.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Great leaders like Yasir Arafat and Sheikh Yasin were killed in an organized manner to weaken this brave nation which is doing Jihad for the Aqsa Mosque.  This was impossible without getting Yasin and Arafat out of the way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The world is witnessing how Palestine has been scattered  after the death of these two leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and how the Jewish lobby gradually kept strengthening its grip.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In 1974, a Pakistani Prime minister was in such world power that he led all the Muslim leaders under one roof with 100% attendance for the first time in history.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today on his 81st birthday, is it a very difficult task for the whole nation to promise to keep unity in its lines.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Also, while eradicating the differences between other Muslims,  its (The formation of Islamic common wealth) mission will be carried forward</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a Jinn, which has been inside Palestine for half a century.</seg>
     <seg id="2">this jinn have many face.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Many times this monster criticizes itself from a different mouth, to divert the attention of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and this jinn other face eating peoples in Iraq, Afghanistan, Iran and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This Jinn fears Islam the most, as it knows that only Muslims following the complete religion of Islam practically can remove it. History proves that Islam has brought many Abu Jahls to the path.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Israels fighter jets start bombarding on Gaza and launched missile attacks on the 27th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In this attack, more than three hundred residents have died.</seg>
     <seg id="3">After the air attacks, Israeli tanks and bulletproof vehicles prepared for war via land and reached Gaza.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Through a unanimous resolution in an emergency meeting of the security council, the United Nations has demanded Israel and the Palestinian authorities to ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Israel official said that they will continue action in Gaza until the rocket attacks on Israel end.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What should Israel do in order to defend them self? Will their action work?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is the international community to do?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Does this intense action link to Israels upcoming next election?</seg>
     <seg id="9">What does newly elected President Barack Obama say after his past position on the middle east?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Kindly note down that due to increase in the number of comments only Urdu suggestions will publish.</seg>
     <seg id="11">For this, hit Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard and select Urdu.)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Palestine will forever remain a sacred place for Muslims and its protection is a must for us.</seg>
     <seg id="2">and we should remember that it is also our Qibla e Awwal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel and India have to vanish one day since these countries are made to be broken. God will surely torment these disbelievers. Sajid Sadiq, Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When has the night of loneliness been spent shedding tears?</seg>
     <seg id="5">When has misfortune departed by praying only?" (Nawabzada Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC searches for such comments and publishes them.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After all, they have to maintain the illusion of neutrality.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Although the news from BBC is usually correct but the real thing is the style of the news.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Which news to be made prominent and which news to be considered as insignificant.</seg>
     <seg id="5">etc. etc.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="7">In this art now a days; the Pakistani electronic and print media, especially some Urdu newspapers and columnists, are no more behind anyone who cheat in the coverage of the increasing extremism and terrorism, or in the ""grudge of Muavia"" written on them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It has been said that the United Nations seemingly supports human rights and peace but actually the Muslims are being subjected to extreme levels of cruelty and brutality. And what we hear from the United Nations is that Hamas should stop the attacks. How long will this hypocrisy carry on?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why there is so much atrocity committed on Muslims. If people like Americans are backing up the Jews then Allah Almighty had said that this nation will live a shabby life and this nation can never live a right life. So, Americans, if you have courage then stop supporting them and see then what their fate is.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The just people of the world and those that kill people in the name of peace should understand that peace will only be prevalent through administering justice, and not by being unjust and killing people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If any tribe could be finished by killing their people, and if the required results could be obtained, then after Hitler's steps, not only the presence but the rise that the Jews are enjoying today, could not have been possible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the words of a poet</seg>
     <seg id="4">Atrocity is atrocity, it vanishes when it rises.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Blood is blood and it clots when it drops.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now who will tell whom what is terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Is all this not included in terrorism? Why does everybody worry only about their own pain?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are others not human? Or is it that the blood of Muslims has become so cheap? Was the blood of this many innocents not red?</seg>
     <seg id="4">And now why there is no condolence message coming from anywhere?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I watched the Mumbai incident, and felt as if my own house was on fire. The sorrow of those affected was overwhelming. If only there was a solution to this war.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I see dead bodies on the road, helpless injured and innocent faces soaked in blood. How shall we condemn? I can not find words!</seg>
     <seg id="2">I feel like crying about the helplessness of Muslims, that on one side, people are dying in India, and the whole world is climbing onto Pakistan, without any proof and saying, take action or else we will.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And on the other side, Israel is ruthlessly killing Muslims and the whole world is silent. This is unbearable.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is delay but not ever in the house of God. Only then will this darkness shed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the presence of America, danger to the integrity of Israel is a joke.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Concerning elections, the rulers should do such things to gain people's support. There is no doubt about this especially when countries like Israel exist. Stop talking about Barrack Obama. History is a witness that no American leader has gone against this policy. They will not do it. A regime, whether black or white, is a regime.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">From the discussions going on in the forum, it seems that everyone is hurt over her death, but as a politician, her mistakes have not been ignored.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This issue is debatable, as to whether Benazir gave her life for democracy or for power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If democracy was dearer, why did she leave the republic for ten years in the control of Musharraf, waiting for American clearance and deal?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir did not come to Pakistan when the people needed her the most.  Unfortunately, she came to Pakistan when she had to deal with cases and was promised a seat of power.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no one remaining to say about the criticism and accusations of a historical personality.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="3">Some things should be ignored because nothing can be done about them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Another reader.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Ladies and gentlemen, maybe due to studying the history, in not only Pakistan, but its four friend-nations and seven other nations, you find the arguments of Mr Psycho more appealing.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tariq Ayaz.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Those who don't deserve such education shouldn't get it either.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The reflection of the pine in water never got to be green.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Britains never let them unite and established the Hindu-Muslim conflict, which was later on brought up by Sir Syed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Psycho</seg>
     <seg id="3">How merciless is our nation? We are blind when writing in favor of ourselves and our party, but now when every historical intellectual is being blamed and critiqued, no one is saying a word.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We have achieved lot of success.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="6">Some things are ignored, thinking that nothing can be done about them. Just like a donkey does not become a scholar if you en wreathe him with books.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Although the ongoing talks between Pakistan and India were interrupted after the Bombay attacks, Pakistan and India should continue these meetings.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If we talk of war then it will bring loss of life on both sides.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India says that the man caught in the Mumbai attacks is a Pakistani citizen and he has also written a letter to Pakistan in Urdu but on the other hand when India initially apprehended this extremist, they said he is a great engineer and afterwards he was declared as a 4th grader, point to be noted.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First of all, Merry Christmas to Mr. Bhana and all our Christian friends of the forum.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Friends of the forum: Greetings Mr. Psycho, A. Raza, Sister Sana, Sister Shahida Akram and all.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We do not want the flames of war, we want the flowers of peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">War itself is a problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What problems can war solve?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Today it will give fire and blood.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Tomorrow it will give hunger and privation.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Therefore, O intelligent people,</seg>
     <seg id="9">It is better that war is postponed.</seg>
     <seg id="10">In your and our garden</seg>
     <seg id="11">It's better that the glim keeps lightened</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The India-America relations have deepened and India knows that when the time comes, America will openly betray Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is that the old history of America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because in the case of an Indian attack, America's goals will also be fulfilled but the expenses will be India's.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan should make a clear statement that we shall not attack first but if we are invaded then there will be no peace, reconciliation or ceasefire until India is completely destroyed or occupied, even if we ourselves get destroyed in doing so.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is Islamic history.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even before this resolution, the Pakistani public and army had given the message that they wanted to give.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In compensation for the Mumbai attacks, the abnormal diplomatic and military benefits that India tried to gain, made it more a victimizing party, than a victim. That is why, in contrast to the harsh initial global reactions, the world has now reduced their force on Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">While ignoring India's unnecessary bobbery, the satisfaction of the United Nations and the appreciation from the Interpol chief over Pakistan's efforts is a "Side Effect" of India's overwhelming diplomacy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There are no two opinions about this being a very beastly action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But the question is that when thousands of Taliban attacked the house of Pir Samiullah, where and what was the Pakistani army doing at that time?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Should the army not held accountable for what they did there for one year?</seg>
     <seg id="4">How many Taliban are killed by the thousands of shells fired by mortars and cannons everyday?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I appeal to the I.S.I, that for God's sake, stop monitoring the Taliban and let us live in peace in our heavenly hometown Sawat.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And stop this fake Operation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The day is not far when a resolution will be passed in the United Nations against army intervention in Pakistan, the same way as it was passed against Jama'athud-Da'wah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Riyaz Ahmed Farooqui</seg>
     <seg id="3">The extremists of our country and their supporters are constantly providing all the evidence and justification required for the instigation of action against them.  God forbid that the day when such a resolution is passed, in all likelihood not a single voice will be raised in the United Nations in our favor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And supposing there is a delay in the enactment of this resolution, then considering the example of America, a superpower will come forward to take over on its own resources.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We do not know about the personality and works of Pir Samiullah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Probably he was not a revolutionary.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The bodies of Comrade Che Guevara, Nawab Akbar Khan Bagti, Dr. Najibullah, and thousands of other revolutionists were dishonored at the hands of the enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are eternal even after death.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But here, an international game is being played. Here ferociousness  and animosity are created to do the ruling.</seg>
     <seg id="6">So that license can be created that if we are not here than these ferocious and barbaric will clutch the government.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the name of religion, activities of these so-called Islam lovers is highly condemned.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The supporters of these fundamentalists can see the oppression of America, but instead of being sorry about such beastly actions, they give it the name of tribal traditions and clearly avoid it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No person with a heart can accept these beastly actions, which are done sometimes in the name of tribal traditions and sometimes in the name of Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, people of our army are with these people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">That is because when they change destination, it takes time. But to catch them, forget about getting there on time, even if they are on the spot, they leave from there.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are they so clever that they keep 50-70 people hostage and our army just watches it as spectators?</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are servants of Allah and so is the army.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is very clear that there is something fishy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Instead of promoting God's blessing and merciful nature, discussing various disastrous and punitive occurrences to create an air of fear and terror in the name of religion, was seen. And besides the event of hanging the dead body, their literature and books like "what will happen after death" also create fear and terror.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And these people are using this fear and terror as a shield for the purpose of world power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Wiso!</seg>
     <seg id="4">You have scared the world with the fire of hell.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You became the image of fright.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is surprising when it is said that this cannot be the work of a Muslim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We are either unaware of our history or we choose to not know about it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Upon the death of the Prophet, upon refusing to pledge alliegance, who burned the door of the daughter of the Messenger and pulled her husband out with a rope around his neck?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Had they come from somewhere outside?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Was the strike on Madeena and Great Karbala the work of Hindus and Jews?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Without accepting the facts, neither motives can be removed nor can they be corrected.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC people, stop this dual policy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The title for this incident: "Was it legal or illegal to hit Bush with the shoes?"</seg>
     <seg id="3">'should have been</seg>
     <seg id="4">Tahir Chaudhry, Japan</seg>
     <seg id="5">Please show some modesty. A human was pulled out of his grave and hanged over a pole just because he raised his voice against the oppression, and you are concerned about the topic of the box office?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the success of Operation Sherdil and Operation Lion Heart across the border depends on who is in the favor of public opinion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This step of American and Pakistani intelligence agencies and Pir Sahib is the victim of this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the comments on this forum would be against the Taliban because intelligence agents have successfully infiltrated the Taliban ranks and they are carrying out actions that can change the perception of the people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I only want to ask that while this body was hanging for a whole day, what was the army doing? Are they only there for targeting the public? They even report something like this: 'While bombing Taliban residences, a stray shell kills two children and their mother'.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Did they not know about this mistake?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Or were they watching the show?</seg>
     <seg id="4">We say it with excuse, stop this game for Allah's sake.</seg>
     <seg id="5">After all, there is a ruler above you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Whether the question asked by BBC is understandable or not, it is saddening to see the lack of perspective of the writer. For instance, no one asked what the army of 30,000 in Swat went there to do.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The army's assistants were hanging the bodies of those who resisted the Taliban on poles.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Whatever the green-footed Pakistani government did with the Swat public, the media, including BBC, did not do good by keeping the world ignorant about the reality.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Pakistani Army is putting up a drama.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Every child in Swat is saying that this is a bloody drama.</seg>
     <seg id="6">For God's sake, stop this drama.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Taliban has destroyed the name of Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If the real Muslims do not accept Taliban as Muslims, then why do they get a refuge in thier places?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The ones who are shameless and don't do hard work and labor take arms in their hands and join their group.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Islam has not came under the pressure of gun or sword.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Have shame.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It's baseless has no roots in any religion nor in family customs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All media including the BBC show different views on Taliban and tribals.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Infact nobody knows the actual situation except us, becuase we are the natives.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In short, its a game in which the CIA, RAW, MOSAD and our own ISI are invloved. No one is a talib or a tribal. Who made these institutions? Warmongers--who are against Islam, Taliban, Madrassa's, Pushtoon people, tribes and tribal traditions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The heads of Muslims have hung from shame over this action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I salute MQM's Altaf Hussain and the leadership of ANP and PPP who speak against this cancer that is the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This cancer is a product of Zia-ul-Haq who died but also destroyed Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But I am hopeful that the present leadership will end this cancer.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the Mumbai incident, India said that extremists were behind the attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan denies the blames and said it will give all possible assistance to India in interrogation.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India said that it has given a list to Pakistan of 20 suspected extremists wanted by India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now Pakistan has said that included in the list is Jaish-e-Muhammad's Molana Azhar Masood, who is not in custody and the government of Pakistan has no information about him.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Before that the president of Pakistan Asif Ali Zardari rejected the view that western spy agencies and the Indian government had provided evidence related to the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">President Zardari said, regarding Ajmal Kasab, that it is not yet proven that he is Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Meanwhile, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has warned Pakistan that its relationship with India cannot improve if it's land is being used for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="8">And in the latest development, the Indian cricket team has cancelled their tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should these political events affect sports?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What do you see in the future of Indo-Pakistani relations?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Neither America nor India will break Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan will be broken by Pakistanis themselves.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What do you expect after so much provincialism, sectarianism, and Mullaism.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It has been proven over time that Jinnah has not been good to the Muslims of India.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Yasmin, Chicago.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Madam, If  Mr. Jinnah's vision had been realized, neither the cancer of provincialism, sectarianism, and Mullaism would have  spread in Pakistan nor would the Muslims in India have displayed such behavior.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is our fault that we couldnt reproduce a leader of similar stature.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If we can't respect our leaders, then who can we respect?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This region has great capabilities.</seg>
     <seg id="2">God knows when we'll understand and the region will progress with the blessing of unity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In both countries the Mullahs, Pundits, Taliban, Shiv Sena, the RSS, etc have been established to oppose the progression of peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And the evil powers don't want this region to progress, therefore, these countries are controlled like puppets.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can you imagine what status this region of Pakistan, India and China will have in the world?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Pakistan is under persecution from God that these thieves, bandits and criminals have been imposed as leaders of the nation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May God protect Pakistan from any harm, Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But sir, open your eyes and look around and you will see the current situation and ground realities revealing the extent to which the American have progressed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Other than the national matter are not looking good as well, circumstances in Sarhad, Balochistan, Karachi in Sindh are in front of you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In this situation the country needs such a leader who can unite us as one nation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">O Allah, have mercy on us.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, there is no way other than a last war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Enough is enough.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now it should be do or die.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This problem will not be solved with hypocritical deceit.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And neither with small big terrorism in each other countries.</seg>
     <seg id="6">After all, Europe got settled after the final world war.</seg>
     <seg id="7">and if this world war had not taken place, then these countries, just like Pakistan and India, would have been clattering.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Almost all our political parties agree that terrorism and factionalism should be stopped.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But our army rulers don't seem sincere in this matter. On one hand, America and Europe thinks we are with them in this war against terrorism.  But, on the other hand, we also help secretly help the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We should think and fix our direction and choose only one side.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no doubt that the majority of the members of Jamaat-ud-Dawa are also members of Lashker-e-Tayyaba, who joined  the party named Jamaat-ud-Dawa Pakistan after Lashker-e-Tayyaba was invalidated.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Although these members only did subsidiary activities, after India's great insistence The United Nations has invalidated the group.  The government of Pakistan is also  continuing the crack down against them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, it's better if Jihadi groups leave religious extremism and continue religious and subsidiary activities.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Terrorist groups in Pakistan, support professional criminals and the heads of those are Mullahs who call Pakistan the land of destruction and what not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, they are trying their best to destroy Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In reality, they do not even deserve to be called human beings, let alone Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Without cleaning Pakistan of these evil doers, the country's existence will be in jeopardy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Can we still afford to think if we should ban these mutinous persons or not?</seg>
     <seg id="6">There is no place on earth for extremist Mullah's who only work to cause killings.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This news breaks my heart to pieces.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What type of world is this in which it is very difficult to follow the preachings of Allah's Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Non-Muslim can kill Muslims, but when Muslims try to take revenge then all non-Muslims along with the whole world think that Islamic preaching is done with Hafiz Sayeed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the Mumbai attacks, Indo-Pak relationships turned sour, for the first time suffering a severe setback.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After the Mumbai attacks, Indo-Pak relationships turned sour, for the first time suffering a severe setback.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India has always claimed that militant and non-militant groups which are active in Pakistan are responsible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The up coming problems on the taluk ,has  been stoped.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian security centers have blamed them for the attack on Mumbai, saying the Lashkar-e-tayab is responsible.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this case, the name Jamat-ud-Dawa has popped up many times.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the first time that relationship between both the countries has worsened due to terrorist activity in India.</seg>
     <seg id="8">In December 2001, after the attack on the parliament, the two neighbors were prepared to go to war.</seg>
     <seg id="9">After that, in 2002, Lashker-e-Tayyaba was banned and included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="10">On Jamat-UL-Dawa, on which a security analyst said that this is new face of Lashkar-e-Taiba asking for sanctions.</seg>
     <seg id="11">In your opinion, should this group be banned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Should Pakistan take action against terrorist group on its land?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Can putting a ban on Jama'athud Da'wah help the present Indo-</seg>
     <seg id="14">Pak crisis could resolve and for real peace in between two countries how important is that to finished groups who have weapons?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Security Council of the United Nations has banned Jamat-ud-Dawa. After all, what proof does the Security Council have to decide this so quickly?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Does the Security Council always show urgency against the Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is what they call a slow complaint and a fast witness.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If you see India has made itself as a Disappointed Country</seg>
     <seg id="5">whose intelligence, army and security institutes failed, and were brought to their knees by a few terrorists for three days. And India wants to put the blame for its inability on Pakistan, to fool the whole world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When one disbeliever dies, there is hue and cry in the whole world. Why these double standards?</seg>
     <seg id="2">To a non political, religious and social organisation of our dear country---</seg>
     <seg id="3">Furqan Farooq, Faisalabad</seg>
     <seg id="4">As long as our Prophet (PBUH), the Awliya Kiram and the Sufis continued to teach people the lesson of love and respect, the religion of Islam would spread and prosper with peace.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Muslims have had success in every land.</seg>
     <seg id="6">When this beautiful religion came to ordinary people, then divisions arose between Muslims and non Muslims and a new era of tumults and quarrel began. Previously the world was not aware of this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salam: Please do it with pleasure but act on your own.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Do not do it because of American pressure.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If India is aggrieved, it should provide the evidence.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why doesn't it give evidence?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And why does it accuse us of everything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">There are extremist groups and organizations in India as well. Why don't they put sanctions on them?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are we the only terrorists in the world?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What is it that India is doing in Kashmir?</seg>
     <seg id="9">What is it that Israel is doing?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The truth is that we are the first Islamic Nuclear State. Is this what the fight is about?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is now in the last stages.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Kamranhassan, ABU DHABI</seg>
     <seg id="3">Your speech is from the heart  like the situation calls for.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now American magazines are very boldly printing the new map of Pakistan and all of these sanctions seem to be part of this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Americans are now not slowly but very swiftly tightening their grip over Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">We must remember that in these circumstances,if we as a nation do not display unity and solidarity and if Bangladesh can be created, then anything can happen.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Terrorism is condemned, whether it is in a hotel in Mumbai or in a Marriott Hotel in Islamabad or in Palestine.</seg>
     <seg id="2">These terorrists should be punished whether they are from Pakistan, India, America or Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now the question is that why the whole world, including Pakistani officials, are silent on the terrorist attacks that are conducted daily in Pakistan, resulting in the death of hundreds of people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Was the attack on the Mariat hotel a terrorist attack?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Then why?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Praise the worthy Advisor interior,Mister Rehman Malik,by the grace of God, how brave he has become!</seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">not only this, but according to BBC Mr. Malik has denied this impression with intensity that the arresting of the terrorists have been carried out under 'someones's pressure'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Brother, Subhanallah!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Having this capability or not, that I don't want to say.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We, i.e. Pakistan, are fighting somebody else's war.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We have our own interests that we shall do our best to protect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Nobody has the authority to interfere with any other country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This does not seem to be the era of new populations.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If people expect justice or demand that an external united court be established to respect democratic institutions, and not help any dictator or military regime, there could be peace in the Third World, including Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">For example, Pakistan is always following the goals set by Europe and America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan is forced to be so, despite the opposition from the majority of its populace.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This enhances the opposition viewpoint and anti-American sentiment.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If America and its Allies believe in Democracy, they should give up their colonial behavior and leave this region</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan has the ability to arm and disarm.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistani forces occupying Kashmir raided one of the camps of Lashkar-e-Tayyaba.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Since the Mumbai attacks, pressure is increasing on Pakistan to act against the extremist organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India claims that the Lashkar-e-Tayyaba was involved in the  Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
     <seg id="5">He said that the extremists whom attacked Mambae used Pakistani earth.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Meanwhile, Pashawar commanders say that unknown soldiers fired and destroyed 50 miltary trucks.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the second attack in Peshawar on NATO and American supplies in the last 48 hours.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Meanwhile, Pakistan made the show of distinctive party Lashkar-e-Taiba and before this was tried to make military persons nonmilitary and military weapons were changed with money and certainly no any action without it.</seg>
     <seg id="9">It is clear from the circumstances that efforts remain unsuccessful to dislodge the armed groups funded by Americans and Saudis during afghan war. It means efforts to restore Pre-80's Pakistan are fruitless.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The question is, is this what Pakistan really wants to do?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Does Pakistan have the ability to do so?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What is your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Click here for details.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Please note that only urges typed in urdu are published due to large number of urges.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Press alt+shift to select Urdu on screen.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I ask only one question from the flag holders of humanity.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If you kill their children, will they come to praise you? It is impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4">And question from you that from islamic studies to western eastern studies, say any logic, argument and philosophy give permission to kill innocent civilians including praying men, laborers and poor workers of different occupations, in revenge of American attack?</seg>
     <seg id="5">If your answer is no, then you need to correct your point of view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">People were armed, at that time it was dangerous that Russia will turn toward Pakistan after Afghanistan, therefore people were armed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, when there is the fear that America will capture Pakistan via Afghanistan,as the American president  mentioned in his presidential address, why should we disarm them now?</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is because America and India will not have to face any public resistance after defeating the Pakistan army.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Yes, if any of them are involved in terrorist activities, then only Pakistan should take action against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">But this is more, that government against Lashkar-e-Taiba proves correct by India that Pakistan is involve in that.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeeb Ul Rehman Saico, *Lahore* [P@KI@N]</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even if we accept that Lashkar-e-Taiba is guilty, it is still not correct to blame the Pakistani government.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And another question arises, "did these terrorists not have the aid of some government or non-government employee of India"?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are the terrorists born or made only in Pakistan, and not in India or other nations of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post63" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As far as Lashkar-e-Tayyaba is concerned, it has no involvement in the recent incidents.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It should be kept in mind that Hafiz Saeed was the first Jihadi leader who claimed that the actions of the Taliban were a Fitna.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I am sure that the Taliban effect is an inseparable result of American plans. Hence, every person who can stand in the way of the Taliban must be removed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">even support by whole nation, take action against Lashkar due to Indian pressure indicate Zardindco frustration and butter up nature.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The operations started with American and Saudi funding, and has to come to an end. To do so, it should be requested of them to wipe out this filth that is consistently polluting our society.</seg>
     <seg id="2">One should also protest against them that according to ethics, America and Saudi Arabia distributed dangerous weapons and named Jihadis, but in reality spread the virus of hateful literature and culture due to which slaughter houses were opened in our country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the threat of attack from India, the announcement of the Pakistani Army that they will divert their attention to India by removing the army from Afghanistan, and the announcement of Taliban that they will take care of the Afghan border, America stumbled badly and tried its best to convince India that she should attack Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This showed the strength of America in the region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Although India did not even threaten nor does it have the guts to.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And the rest was taken care of by the attacks of the Taliban on American posts.</seg>
     <seg id="5">That proves that without the Pakistani Army and the Pakistani government, America is nothing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Karachi is Pakistan's business and economic center, and Dubai of the less privileged areas.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Hundreds of thousands do not return empty-handed from here. But since the law was enforced on the western borders, Karachi has taken all the attention.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now they are looking to kidnap this city.</seg>
     <seg id="4">For the first time, Pathans began to be called Pukhtons, and the people of a single town are made foreigners and are being made to fight, while the need is for unity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One solution to the problem is that the Urdu speakers learn Pashto, or the Pashto speakers learn Urdu, or maybe it's better for everybody to learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You will surely think this as a ridiculous suggestion but do you think that the reason for this conflict is not ridiculous?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The reason of violence is language?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir, I actually shared this proposal many times in my childhood with my friends, which included people from all religious and linguistic groups, but these people used to laugh at me.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At that time, the religious and linguistic hate which was not as lively and strong as they are today were still developing within.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I don't understand what is happening or why.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are these the signs of the Day of Judgement?</seg>
     <seg id="3">For what crime are innocent people being killed?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The reasons are in front of everybody, those who want to break up Pakistan are the active ones and those who do such things have neither religion nor country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Be it Karachi or Mumbai, the houses were set on fire by its own residents.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Whichever government comes, it only changes the names of the places and starts working for fame, just like how nowadays, the airports, roads and buildings are all Benazir.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Does Benazir mean that is what is happening to the public of Karachi and Pakistan?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When Bombay attacks were at their peak, the failure of efforts of the RA to initiate turmoil in Karachi proves this that in the past political elements working on the payroll of RA have now resigned from their posts.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The unjustified killing of Pashto-speaking hard workers and Indian threats have awakened sleeping Pakistanis from Karachi to Khyber.</seg>
     <seg id="3">While the patriotism of all political, religious, lingual and national parties has taught diplomatic manners to India, at the same time it has also given American planners one more chance to think.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The MQM and the ANP are responsible for the turmoil in Karachi, and the government is only interested in itself.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The government can control the situation in one hour, but it is purposely allowing it to grow.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Pressure of political parties on police and rangers keep them from doing the operation.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The talk of uniting is only restricted to speeches. The political parties should leave their interests and work for the interest of the common man.</seg>
     <seg id="5">These kinds of incidents will keep taking place until there is pressure on the administration.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To me, these people are the biggest terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Foreign powers are definitely involved in this, but no one knows who they are.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And the sad thing is that if such a situation was prevalent in any border town, the government would take care of that place. But since this is far from the border, the government looks helpless.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government should set up an operation here, and save a big and important town from terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Otherwise Pakistan will face a huge financial crisis.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even BBC Urdu is not writing the truth due to fear, and as for the local media, it is even thinner.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The whole truth is available on BBC English.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One solution to the problem is this that Urdu speaking people should learn Pashto or Pashto speaking people should learn Urdu. It would be even better if everyone learned English.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You will definitely take this as a funny suggestion, but don't you think the cause of the conflict is also funny?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Was language the reason for violence?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There was another story of cruelty recorded in Karachi, the terror of which was being felt by every citizen for a long time.</seg>
     <seg id="2">No one left any stone unturned.  The reports that surfaced in the media only told 50% of what actually happened here in four days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I have spent the last three nights sleepless and the fear is still there.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Those who make the people evacuate hotels, those who kill the shoe-makers and the peanut-sellers.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The people who looted the super highway and cut the ears off of innocent people are all unaware of Allah's punishment, which can catch them anytime.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In your opinion, what are the reasons for this sudden disturbance?</seg>
     <seg id="2">(BBC)</seg>
     <seg id="3">Keeping in mind the gruesome bloodshed event in Mumbai we do not need to delve deep into the matter to find the reason of disorder in Karachi. It is simple and easy to guess that the turmoil is just due to an unconscious trade of blood.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is obvious that if someone mistreats the father, it is no surprise if the son becomes out of control.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The blood of the loyalists of Liaqat Ali Khan also belonged to the same place. To eliminate Mr. Psycho's misunderstanding I am writing this verse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We will also repeat the traditions of the elders.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We made it by sacrificing lives, and will save it by doing the same.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Faizan Tauseef Siddiqui</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is very disappointing that the whole country is at stake and we are fighting with each other.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mr. Siddiqui, I request if wikipedia.</seg>
     <seg id="7">See Liaqat Ali Khan, you will find out that he belonged to a noble Punjabi family from Karnal, in Punjab.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Because of his efforts for immigrants, today the immigrants call him on of their own.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Every action has a reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="2">One can bear one's self, but...</seg>
     <seg id="3">Ijaz Awan</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sir, before you gather a huge crowd very quickly, I should tell you that you are finding the graffiti of real gangsters these days on the walls of Karachi in the form of wall chalking and posters.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We have been seeing both types of mischief.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mischief mongers did not leave Pakistan or the founder of Pakistan alone. They did not have to face any reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Quite the opposite, they are pecking at the heart of Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One Muslim League N was left. Even they made a draft of the 18th amendment and gave it to the People's Party.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Before this, MQM and Muslim League Q made and submitted a draft of the 18th amendment to the National Assembly and the Senate.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Until now it seems that drafts of the 18th amendment are a political trick and no one is sincere in getting this amendment approved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the reason why  no one has made a fuss in the assembly or senate floor in the favor of this amendment nor has forced the assembly to approve this change.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It seems like that after submitting the drafts of 18th amendment, these parties have done their part. They will be able to say this tomorrow that we submitted the draft and that the government speaker did not take any action.</seg>
     <seg id="6">MQM is a coalation with the government. Muslim League(N) is a secret partnership with the government. The Muslim League(Q) is the party that passed the 17th amendment. Now, how it is possible that these parties are sincere in abolishing the 17th Amendment?</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is called getting credit for nothing.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The People's Party is not in a hurry to dismiss the seventeenth amendment anyways.</seg>
     <seg id="9">How can anyone think of getting his own hands cut?</seg>
     <seg id="10">As long as Zardari is the president, the seventeenth amendment is not going to be repealed.</seg>
     <seg id="11">This was the opinion of the majority in one of our surveys and it is correct.</seg>
     <seg id="12">If the seventeenth amendment had been canceled then Zardari would never had become the president.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Now he is even more powerful than President Musharaf because along with being the president he is also the chairman of the People's party.</seg>
     <seg id="14">As long as he is the president, the seventeenth amendment will remain intact.</seg>
     <seg id="15">In order to finish the 17th amendment, the political parties will have to bid Zardari farewell from the presidential house.</seg>
     <seg id="16">Neither MQM nor other parties want this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Most of the elders in our family belonged to the working class.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In our childhood, when we used to see our uncles doing labor work, we used to pray to Allah to save us from this hard work.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To avoid this we wrote a letter to the editor of the daily Amroz and asked him what we should do after matriculation so that we don't have to do labor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The editor wrote in reply to become a doctor or engineer and study Science and Math subjects.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We were inclined towards engineering and in matriculation we studied Technical drawing instead of Biology.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But at the time of admission in F.Sc. my elder brother forced me to become a doctor after doing F.Sc. in medical.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We hardly studied biology for a month before we started studying math.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Fear of labor made me an engineer and now I am in a better position than my fellows in the family for which I am always thankful to God.</seg>
     <seg id="9">I remembered this when I was trying to lift the carpet with my two young sons at our old house.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It was not half an hour since we started working, and the younger son said, "Dad, it looks as if I was not made for this job."</seg>
     <seg id="11">We said, "If that is true, then study a lot like us, and free yourself from bodily pain."</seg>
     <seg id="12">The son said, "I am studying and will continue studying, but I cannot do this work."</seg>
     <seg id="13">Anyway, the three of us finished that work in three hours and returned.</seg>
     <seg id="14">My purpose of saying this is that if a person has set a goal, whatever be the reason behind it, no one can stop him from achieving his goal.</seg>
     <seg id="15">But if you do not even know what you have to do, then Allah alone is your protector.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is said that you should not say bad things about the dead, but what shall we do? We see only bad things in Benazir, even on the anniversary of her first death.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir, for her selfish purpose, crushed the independence movement of the Sikhs after giving the list of the names of those who were fighting for freedom. On the other hand, she gave India the chance to keep its full attention on Kashmir after helping to suppress the Punjab movement.</seg>
     <seg id="3">A tug-of-war between Benazir and Nawaz Sharif rule is part of the history and has pushed the country back many years.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even after her exile, Benazir continued to make negative comments about Kashmir and the nuclear program.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Benazir violated the London agreement with Nawaz Sharif and made a deal with General Musharaf.</seg>
     <seg id="6">During the rule of Benazir, she gave her husband the freedom to make as much money as possible, which is why he is known as Mr. Ten Percent.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In Benazir's era, her brother was killed, and his killer has still not been punished.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Despite being a woman, Benazir avoided fighting for women's rights.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Just as Benazir did her politics over her father's dead body, similarly her widower is doing the same over her dead body.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Benazir came into power twice, but she could not punish the culprits of her father's political murder, as even she couldn't register a case against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It has been 37 years since East Pakistan separated from us, but look at the extreme of senselessness of our people and leaders that we never celebrate the mourning day.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We should have been observing December 16 as a day of reflection and making plans to prevent the reoccurrence of such incidents.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We should have been sending greetings to the people of Bangladesh on this day and been trying to bring them closer to ourselves.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The rulers should reopen the Hamudur Rehman commission reports and discuss the reasons for the separation of East Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They used to make arrangements to bring back the Biharis trapped in Bangladesh and send them presents to raise their spirits.</seg>
     <seg id="6">We have become so insensitive that if someone dies in our neighborhood, we're not even aware of it.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We don't care for our brothers and sisters because we have become selfish.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Even if a great accident occurs, we are busy in our daily routines.</seg>
     <seg id="9">As East and West Germany reunite, I wish East and West Pakistan would follow suit.</seg>
     <seg id="10">We can be one again if we both sacrifice for each other and come out of the hole of selfishness.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But this wish does not seem likely to be granted in the near future.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It was announced in the news today that the Governor of the American State Illinois had been arrested on corruption charges.</seg>
     <seg id="2">to remove him from the office of Governor, State Congress is preparing to start trial against him as soon as possible. One of our friend who has keen eye on the current affairs of Pakistan proudly said that this is democracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In America, even the higher level people are not above the law.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And the other is your country, Pakistan, where even the president was chosen after the corruption charges against him were dropped.</seg>
     <seg id="5">My vein of loyalty throbbed and I said what is the big deal if a governor was arrested in America? In Pakistan, once the prime minister was arrested and hanged overnight, and another time sent into exile.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tell me, when did this happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan awarded the person who broke the law with a guard of honor from the presidency. When did this happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="8">In Pakistan, the Chief Justice was suspended, and, besides public support, he has yet to be restored. Has that ever happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="9">A holder of a falsified degree was made the Minster of Health in Pakistan, did this ever happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="10">After listening to this, the poor American could not stop laughing and also accepted defeat.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In this picture, President Zardari is smiling, despite being surrounded on all four sides by Americans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It seems from his smile</seg>
     <seg id="3">The America is with his government, but he is forgetting that last year the same people were with Parvez Musharaf.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This picture was passed on as if it showed a family.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Previously such a photo, one president with three American agents, has never been printed in newspapers before.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It seems as if America's work in Pakistan has increased and now more than one agent is needed to complete it, or that they did not trust the new slave as they trusted the first one.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is also possible that this was done by keeping in mind the notoriety of President Zardari breaking his promises.</seg>
     <seg id="8">If he was a smart ruler, at least he would not have shown his teeth in this photo, and he would have at least seemed ashamed of the neckband of slavery that he was sporting.</seg>
     <seg id="9">If the Principle of Democracy is applied to this picture then President Zardari is in the minority.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The majority rules the country according to democracy, yet who is in this majority according to the photo?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There are enough opportunities in the fields of counseling and psychotherapy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to the government, tactics along with force, and discussions have been going on.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Research has revealed that there are conditions which can be cured without medication.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government must, instead of using the power, eliminate the causes of the issue.</seg>
     <seg id="5">By finishing the causes, Fazlullah and the Taliban will be finished themselves.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The Sharia bill proposed by ANP will solve the problems in Swat to a great extent.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In addition to the observance of the Shariat law, the administration will take care of the well being of the people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At the beginning of General Musharaf rise, it looked like the nation had rid itself of the incompetent politicians, but the lust for power changed all his plans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Whatever expectations were, after joining the 'war of terror', he began to consider himself irremovable.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The next logical and expected steps never happened.</seg>
     <seg id="4">As soon as Bush's era was near its end he started worrying about the end of his rule. In his panic, he made a deal with thieves.</seg>
     <seg id="5">General Musharaf was in a position to control the army, but the present administration doesn't know what is happening.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The army could not put down the terror in Baajodoh and Swat. The commoners are subjected to "bombardments and enmity", creating great loss to lives and properties, and launching them into psychological disorder.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Despite the military operation in Swat, a war-torn area of NWFP, things are getting worse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On one hand the writ of GOVT is limited to a resolution of condemnation passed by National assembly while on other hand the influence of Taliban's FM channel is increasing in swat.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the third side, the common folk consider it safe to listen to those who are in control of the area.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Security forces in swat have used lethal weapons and claim to have killed many extremists. Despite these causalities, the Taliban's power is rising and they control nearly 80% of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a result, GOVT is not accepting its failure and the Taliban is getting stronger.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The poor citizen is the only loser.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Someone in Swat asked, "How are the Talibans?"  The answer is, "They are very good; they are fighting the war against the enemies of God."</seg>
     <seg id="8">A question about the army was answered, "Very good, it is fighting against the enemies of our country."</seg>
     <seg id="9">Then it was asked, "who are the enemies of religion and the country" and the answer was, "the citizens."</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I am astonished how the Pakistani Army will fight with the Indian Army, while it is unable to control a small group of Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They could not track down Taliban's illegally operated FM channel, which in my opinion is very easy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But still, FM was spreading hatred in full swing.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First the girls schools and now the boys schools are being destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">A curfew is imposed so that Talibans can move around easily.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tonight eight trucks entered the suburbs of Mingora during curfew and created bunkers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The question is that how could they reach there during curfew?</seg>
     <seg id="8">The army could kill Akbar Bugti in his house, but salutes the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="9">For God's sake, someone tell this army to protect the helpless people of Sawat from the Taliban and prove that the Pakistan army can overcome any enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">He says that most of the blood is spilled in the name of religion. Tell me, if there was no religion, would blood not have spilled?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are Punjabi, Pathan, White, Black, Mahsood and other tribes the result of religion?</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, sir, no way! Only religion teaches that there is no black and white, there is no Punjabi and no immigrant. If it were not for religion, then half of the world would have been destroyed in fights between the white and the black, and the rest of the people would have drowned in tribe-brotherhood hatred.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Actually, religion gives moral teachings to the man. And binds him that he is not here on his own choice but the creator of the universe has sent him here. And he should spend his life according to his rules.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a Muslim, I am completely convinced that Islam is a complete way of life and the true religion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After settling down in London, every morning I would first call my relatives and ask them how they were. Most of them had never called me to find out how I was doing, and I then realized that they do not like me calling them either, so I stopped calling them.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Living here in France for two years I also felt the same way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I do not know why people only expect us to call.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A resolution about Iraq passed in a few hours to send a "peace" force to Darfur was not a problem at all.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Immediately criticizing the Mumbai attacks and restricting suspected groups is a matter of a few hours.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And where death is dancing, we are consenting.</seg>
     <seg id="4">O upholders of world peace, life is finishing over here.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are people really waiting for it to finish?</seg>
     <seg id="6">So that no other victim will even think about using a great damage causing weapon like a gun to fight for his rights?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Even when a father is holding the corpse of his son, an ounce of sorrow does not arise from any part of your heart?</seg>
     <seg id="8">If not, then you don't even deserve to be called a human being.</seg>
     <seg id="9">rather, you are a blemish on the name of humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">OK, it was proven that this area was also the home of the Israelis for thousands of years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ideally, these two tribes should have lived happily together with love and affection, but since their strings are in the hands of the western and Arab countries, peace is not possible without their will.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now even Iran wants to fight its proxy war from here.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even if operations in Israel are stopped for the time being, they will start again after some other incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The owner of the BBC is interested in serving America and Israel, and this is why in the name of 'enlightenment' it has come out with a series of Zionist favoring blogs, and is seeding biased and blind propaganda.</seg>
     <seg id="2">BBC is only completing a formality, and its goal and intent is to gather well wishes.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I request the moderator to publish this comment from Fidwi, so that some truth may still remain on BBC.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thanks.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I don't know who wrote this story or how this story came to being, but one thing is for sure, in every age, draculas have been drinking the blood of innocent people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In every age, wars have been fought and blood has been spilled.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the surprising thing is that this 21st century man, who considers himself civilized, is quiet over this ruthless open massacre.</seg>
     <seg id="4">How can he not realize that whatever is happening is showing the ugliest face of humanity</seg>
     <seg id="5"></seg>
     <seg id="6">Well wisher, Sajjad Alhasnain, Hyderabad, Deccan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At this time along with Dera Ghazi Khan, in whole country winter rains are going on.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Here is a poem for the season. Enjoy the rain with this poem.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even these rains are from you</seg>
     <seg id="4">If it rains, it is spring.</seg>
     <seg id="5">If it stays, then it is peace.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Sometimes it comes without a reason.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Sometimes it spreads day and night.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Sometimes, it is very noisy, and sometimes it is very quiet.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Even these rains are  from you</seg>
     <seg id="10">in some remembrance some night</seg>
     <seg id="11">to a buried ash</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sometimes the wind put it out.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Sometimes it burned itself.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Sometimes every drop is painful.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Even these rains are from you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All these leaders are about to run holding a very sensitive case. Little do they care if the country survives or not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Let the population sell toothpaste or clean the bells of the Mandir with the peels of lemons.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Like our leaders, our media is corrupted as well.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Its sole purpose is to extract money from the government.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As for the public, they are ignorant. To speak about them is the biggest ignorance.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Yesterday afternoon something surprising happened.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All around police are running here and there but not asking about illegal parking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Moreover, the NYPD was not in a mood to look at illegally parked cars.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It happened that a plane of US Air really became a plane and landed in the Hudson River.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Till today only this much is known, that the ""terrorist"" belonged to the family of birds called goose.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Yesterday was perhaps historically cold in New York.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The temperature does not fall this much.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Even my jaw started hurting from my half an hour walk outside.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Imagine what would have happened to those people who jumped from the plane into the river.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Happy news is that the people all stayed safe.</seg>
     <seg id="11">The sad news is that the ship of company sank in this financial crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="12">I went by West Side Highway to New Jersey, watching all this, and I saw that Southbound was blocked, but what did I do?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Yes, I got stuck in the same rush on the way back.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Thankfully, during my one-hour trip the way had opened at least a bit, so I was able to use the 56th street exit.</seg>
     <seg id="15">I had not taken the previous two exits, seeing the lines of traffic there.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Makki, My Pakistan: Well, congratulations. Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ammaar: Of course, with faith.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Shaguftah: Well, Congratulations, Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sarah: I had two chickens. It's a sacrifice. Janzeb will tell you how it was.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Besides this, there is no other way.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At this farm, one has to process his own meat, including removing the skin.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Basim.net might take some time to repair.</seg>
     <seg id="8">What happened on the forum?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Linko</seg>
     <seg id="10">To fight with "listen to the blog", use Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Duffer: Khair Mubarak! Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sir, please use Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="13">The snow will vanish.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We considered the Taliban group of Swat nonreligious, and they were only against education of women.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They were expressing this irritation by demolishing schools and colleges for women every day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Like the majority of the ideas, this was not proven right. According to CNN news, on the lucky day of Monday, a group of Taliban demolished a boys school with gunpowder.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Swat: The Taliban has destroyed a boys' school.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The girls schools were already destroyed, acting according to the famous English saying "Ladies First".  I do not know why people are still bent on calling the Taliban uncultured and barbaric.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Another thing that becomes clear from this is that the accusation of the Taliban being against girls education is not true.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Rather, Masha Allah, they are against education altogether.</seg>
     <seg id="8">May Allah give these Mujahideen more power, and the evil government</seg>
     <seg id="9">which is let loose on us, may He help them in uprooting them.</seg>
     <seg id="10"></seg>
     <seg id="11"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1"></seg>
     <seg id="2"></seg>
     <seg id="3">Some days go, a girl's marriage with a dog become fresh.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Look at that groom.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Humanity is rare in the 21st century.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the age of the computer. The computer occupies a place in every walk of life.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have reservations over this increasing involvement of the computer in financial matters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Where use of credit cards bring ease to life, it also gives better control to law enforcement agencies over your private life.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now, with just a look at the credit card transaction record, your whereabouts can be traced.</seg>
     <seg id="5">and in future, when use of real currency will reduce to a great extent, its benefits will increase more and more.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Similarly, in the world of crimes, instead of playing with the dangers of robbing a bank, the credit card information is stolen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Similarly friends are also made through computers.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Social networking sites such as Orkut, Facebook and Myspace have achieved an initial level of acceptance.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But don't you feel that psychologically, the more we accustome ourselves to social networks, the more we are physically getting away from people.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Also consider match-making websites, where your preferences are matched to a list of people with similar desires as you.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Now can you spend your life with a person like you?</seg>
     <seg id="12">I can not. That is why a spouse is called the better half.</seg>
     <seg id="13">He/she will help eliminate my faults.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I guess I got a lesser part of intelligence.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Since childhood, whenever an elder said anything to me that was the truth for me.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And so I had assurance that my father knew the answer to every question in the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I was laughed at because of it.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But only that saying seemed true which could be possible.</seg>
     <seg id="6">It is very troubling that there is the need to tell lies.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Even at this age, he was harmed by this.</seg>
     <seg id="8">That is why I try to lie as little as possible.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Don't tell lies, especially in the name of God.</seg>
     <seg id="10">and Allah willing say only when there is pray to Allah that work completes.</seg>
     <seg id="11">As for the intentions, only Allah knows best.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a disgusting problem that results from a distancing from religion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to our religion and the law of Pakistan, a minor should stay with their mother.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Their expenses are the responsibility the father when the father can meet them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Then when the kids mature, they can live with anyone they want.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You are right that the actual problem is the relatives who misguide.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Possessiveness is present in all of our actions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Even here, thinking is prevailing that there will be more partners in father's property so it is resisted, although this act of the father is commendable should be imitated.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Here these restriction regarding relations have created many evils in the society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The concept of remarriage of a divorce or a widow is getting rare.</seg>
     <seg id="5">These absurd beliefs and baseless traditions are the reason for family breakups.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Why is it In our society, if the spouse of a 50-55 year person passes away,  they not looked at in a nice manner?</seg>
     <seg id="2">A Pakistani uncle near us whose wife died a good 10 or 12 years ago,  had all his children married, but when he married a widow, his own children went against him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion, this is due to religion, is it not?</seg>
     <seg id="4">They said: "How could he consider having someone else take the place of our mother?"</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I believe that this person's children should have thought what is wrong if he married a widow, after he married off all his children?</seg>
     <seg id="2">This widow also got support and the uncle also got someone to look after the house.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The children would definitely have gotten busy in their own worlds and would not be able to give time to him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The reason for this is ignorance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If their wives deny to serve him tomorrow, then what will he do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is a result of pressure from society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When people begin to make fun of such a family for doing something like that, children start to feel ashamed of their father's second marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Though they should face the environment and say that their father's action is in perfect accordance with Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is the curse of our society, which have been facing for the last 40-50 years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A wife can accept her husband going around having illicit relations, but she can't stand him having a second wife.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If it's in her power, she will not let him do so even after she dies.</seg>
     <seg id="4">She destroys her husband and her own hereafter, and becomes a cause for spreading filthiness in society.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Nothing happens with the singing about Islam. We actually like what our traditions and cultures are.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For example, keeping girls from getting education and fear of love marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As for your question, the old man was going to the widow's house instead of bringing the widow to his house, so that the children could make some fuss and then become quiet and relax (though the stomach of the widow's children would hurt).</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Indo-Pak subcontinent, Islam was accepted centuries ago, but it could not yet leave its' ignorant mentality and has always kept culture and tradition above Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Thinking of a man's second marriage as an innovation, divorce as a clinical rest, divorced woman as untouchable, love marriage as a mark on honor and a man marrying a woman elder to him as a deception on the part of the wife, is all a part of this mentality.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Over all, by copying the western world, we are declaring the religious veil as old fashioned.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Accepting Islam was easy, getting rid of this way of thinking is very hard.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Allah grant us all spirit and courage for this.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Writing Urdu was never so difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="8">It took centuries to write this little.</seg>
     <seg id="9">consider more to less.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Allah Hafiz</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Ameer Taimoor in his book "I am Taimoor" writes, "I found this secret in my life that if the leader of any army is in the front line then that army will never lose."</seg>
     <seg id="2">But here, the situation is different.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They say that common people are there to die for us and they die as martyrs.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Yet, if a common person dies it should be considered murder.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May peace and blessing of Almighty be upon you.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today, as I was returning to my shop after Isha prayer, a man sitting in a car at the circle raised his hand and drew my attention towards him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I thought maybe this man has forgotten his way or maybe he wants to ask me something. I stopped and saw his whole family was in the car.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He asked whether I could understand Arabic well or not. I said, no problem, tell me what you want.</seg>
     <seg id="5">He started saying I have come from Riyadh but someone in Medina picked my pocket, if you could please help me? I said forget about it, because this has happened to me earlier. In return I gave this man 20 riyals to pay for gas and to go back to Riyadh. In stead he started doing the same thing after moving forward a little.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Angrily, I cursed at him and threatened to call the police, so he ran away.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Now the situation has become that we Muslims come in cars with our families to beg all day, and gain at least two or three thousand illegally.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Whereas there is a clear Hadith of the Prophet (SAWS) that says that the upper hand is better than the lower hand; the lower hand being the begging hand and the upper hand being the giving one.</seg>
     <seg id="9">May Allah bless us and make us true Muslims (Amen)</seg>
     <seg id="10">Wassalam</seg>
     <seg id="11">Javed Iqbal</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Famous singer Adnan Sami's wife reached a police station in Mumbai, accusing him of torturing her.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The police station advised her to contact a court.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Adnan Sami's wife, Saba Guladari, submitted a plea against her husband stating that Adnan Sami tortures her continuously.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and treats her inhumanely.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now this thing has gone out of her tolerance, therefore, a case may be registered against Adnan Sami.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The police, instead of filing a case, told her to contact a court, saying that this matter was not one which the police could touch.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In your opinion, is the accusation of Adnan Sami's wife on him correct?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Could this accusation be an attempt of India to defame Adnan Sami?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Let us know your opinion on this issue.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Adam Sanghar, Mehr.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As far as allegations are concerned, anyone can accuse someone else.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There's nothing more important than respect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Whatever be the case between Adnan Sami and his present wife, he left his honorable life and went to India to earn money. Now that fame has fallen around his neck.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is a consequence of his own deeds.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Washington...</seg>
     <seg id="2">Top American officials say that president Obama will take a strict stance over Afghan president Hamid Karzai.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In America's new policy for Afghanistan war has been given more importance than development.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Officials say that Hamid Karzai is considered to be a hurdle in achievement of American goals.  In his government there is corruption, drug business has increased, and Taliban are regaining their power.</seg>
     <seg id="5">American officials say that the people who are putting more pressure on Hamid Karzai to do more include Vice President Joe Biden and President Obama's representative for Afhanistan and Pakistan Richard Holbrooke.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He claimed this policy arose after the end of the administration of President Bush, who used to video conference with Hamid Karzai every two weeks. Bush used to stress the American role in rebuilding Afghanistan and its civilian institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Officials say that the Obama administration will work with state leaders as a backup to the main government.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Officials say that they plan to join Hamid Karzai in the fight against corruption.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Hamid Karzai is facing fresh elections this year and it is not yet clear whether Obama and his group will support Karzai for presidency or not.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Is this statement, of the American officials, a forecast of change in American policy regarding Afghanistan?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Is Hamid Karzai's rule coming to an end?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What is your opinion about this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In a series of three one-day matches between Pakistan and Sri Lanka, Sri Lanka defeated Pakistan 2-1.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In the first one-day match, Pakistan defeated Sri Lanka. However, Sri Lanka won the remaining two matches.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the third match, the national cricket team's performance was very poor. In response to Sri Lanka's 309 runs, it only managed to hit 75 runs in 23 overs before going all out and suffering a humiliating defeat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The result of the series proves that the national team has no consistency in its performance.</seg>
     <seg id="5">besides the home ground and all claims, the national team was defeated, what are the reasons of this in your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Which aspects of the game should experts focus on?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are you satisfied with the selection of the team?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Which department will you blame for the defeat: fielding, batting or bowling?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Kindly share your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Babar Husain, Jeddah. It is very sad that even in todays modern age, such ignorant traditions are prevalent. If the landlord or the property owner targets innocent people with his harsh dictatorship, who will call them Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="2">A Sardar, himself should walk over these embers. Why doesn't the present government act against them?</seg>
     <seg id="3">When will we find justice through the courts?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370243-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Sri Lankan team has arrived in Pakistan to play a one-day series.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Besides the Indo-Pak sullenness, a visit by a foreign team to Pakistan is very pleasing.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On reaching the Karachi Airport, the Sirilankan team was given a warm welcome.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Two days between Pakistan and Sri Lanka will be played in Karachi whereas the third day will be played in Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Both teams are claiming assurance regarding bowling, batting, and fielding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">While the Sri Lankans are proud of their spinners, Pakistan has its fast bowlers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Srilankan Captain, Mahela Jaywardena, has said that not one player on the Pakistan team, but rather the whole Pakistan team is dangerous.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Murli dharan and Mendis will be the trump cards whereas the Pakistan Captain says that it will be a tough competition.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Shoaib Malik has said that we have played Murlidharn and will see Mendas as well.  They have developed a secret game plan which they will show at the ground.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Will the Pak-Sri Lanka series be really as interesting and exciting as the claims are?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Who will dominate the series between Pakistan and Sri Lanka?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Who will win the series?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Who will be the man of the series?</seg>
     <seg id="14">Give your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Gulpham, London, publishes his own views and you also prefer these views. I wish you would also write some truth, and not change your words like Mukherjee, because the order is to speak the truth in front of a tyrant king, and this is equivalent to Jihad. What should be said of Mukherjee, he tries to change his statements and stay in the news.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Yousuf, Dubai</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is all these people's doing Kashmiris are fighting war of independence for the past sixty years.</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, no one  asked, now that they are caught in a war of extremism and terrorism so they have started talking about peace and settlement.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First they killed Muslims brutally, and now they are trying to resolve issues.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In a way, Pakistan has to understand their own duplicitous policies.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Asad Khan, London.</seg>
     <seg id="2">India creates situations that make people all over the world focus their attention on Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Pakistan always shows the truth of India to the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now the British government has realized that the Indian government is maligning Pakistan for terrorism so that it can occupy Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They are unwilling to talk with Pakistan on this matter.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">British Foreign minister David Milliband said that by resolving Kashmir issue terrorism will be reduced and the government of Pakistan can handle new challenges impressively on its border.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The President of the United States Barack Obama expressed a similar opinion.</seg>
     <seg id="3">British foreign minster has said that even though the fight against terrorism is dangerous, for their own safety they chose to fight.</seg>
     <seg id="4">David Miliband has said that Pakistan should show leniency towards extremist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Under pressure from major world powers to resolve the Kashmir issue, India is creating unrest in the region to distract world from this issue.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Terrorist attack in Mumbai is also a part of this strategy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Does India want to the allegations of terrorism its escape goat to avoid peace talks?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Let us know about your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Usman Aftab</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think the big powers do not want to harm Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They in fact are thinking of ways to control Pakistan because they know Pakistan is an atomic power.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They want to create an environment for revolution.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Foreign countries are thinking that if Pakistan is cornered that will pose more political and geographical problems. They want to help Pakistan so they can achieve their vested interests.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A citizen, USA</seg>
     <seg id="2">It has always been a Hindu tradition; walking stick in arm and name of Ram on lips.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I think that they get nervous over small issues and then warn Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are ready in all ways, the Indian Chief of Army should keep his mouth shut or else, we know how to give mouth breaking anwers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Faheem Siddiqi</seg>
     <seg id="2">This conversation is going on due to American mischief. America's mind was already spoiled, but we know India is also becoming like that. Let them attack, and they will see the reality, as to who is in hot water.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel is attacking Hamas, but no one has the courage to stop it. Watching Israel, India also wants to do all that.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Prime Minister, Syed Raza Yusuf Geelani said that the newly elected American vice president, Joe Biden, played an important role in removing the ex-president Musharraf's uniform and replacing it with a lame democracy, which is why the Pakistani government has honored him with a special star.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The credit for removing the uniform and replacing the democracy should not go to any political party. The Parliament is not a rubber stamp.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All decisions will be made in the Parliament.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Prime Minister said that Dr. Qadir's chapter had been closed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Does public protest against dictatorship have no significance to you?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Has the lawyers movement not played any role?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you have to say about this statement from the Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Let us know what you think.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American President George W Bush, in his last Press conference, advised newly elected President Barack Obama that he made many mistakes in his tenure, and Barack Obama should do what he thinks is right.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As President, I did whatever I felt was appropriate in accordance to the situation, American law, and Constitution by often allowing the American interest reign over my own acceptance.</seg>
     <seg id="3">He said that the enemies of America are still planning to attack, and that the biggest challenge for Barack Obama would be to stop it.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He said that, unable to find the weapon of mass destruction from Iraq was his major dissapointment and to announce the mission completed in Iraq was his big mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Speaking at his last press conference at the White House, the American President said that this was his last press conference, and he thanked the journalists and other friends who are present.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you believe that Obama will not repeat the same mistakes that Bush made?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Was it too late for Bush to admit to his mistakes?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Will Obama be able to follow Bush's advice?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Give us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American Vice President Dick Cheney said, "I want to see Osama Bin Laden alive or dead."</seg>
     <seg id="2">He said that Osama Bin Laden is hiding in some hard to reach area and is of no use to his organization, and if Osama Bin Laden is arrested alive or dead then his organization must be destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">America intends to arrest Osama and the search for Osama is on.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Will Dick Cheney's goal to arrest Osama be accomplished?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Give us your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At the end of the first day match of Habib Bank Shahid Afridi, a cricketer in Qaiud-e-Aazam trophy  PIA, fought with a spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="2">When Shahid Affridi came out of the drawing room after playing the match on the UBL ground, a large number of fans gathered around him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In one situation a fan held his hand and asked to take a photo with him; Shahid Affridi removed his hand and said that he can take the photo tomorrow. On the fan's insistence, Affridi became angry and slapped him, before they start a quarrel the crowd quelled the situation.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After that Shahid Affridi said that without any reason he was made an issue therefore at that time he was in a hurry to attend the Prayer.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Nevertheless, I shall apologize to that spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What would you say about this behavior of Shahid Afridi?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Let us know about your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian Prime Minister, Manmohan Singh, has once again accused Pakistan of provoking a war.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan is using terrorism as a state policy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">while addressing a Chief Ministers conference in New Delhi, Manmohan Singh said that the terrorist elements are backed by neighboring countries, especially Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The terrorists behind the Mumbai attacks used the pelagic route and were safe from the Indian Coast Guard.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian Prime Minister said that the Mumbai attacks of November were carried out by Lashkar-e-Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that the terrorists were using new techniques and modern communication systems. We will have to step up the forces at the line of control as well, from where there is infiltration. He said that terrorism will not be accepted in any form, and this is our policy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">How do you see this allegation from the Indian Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Does not the internal chaos and separation movements in India show India's anxiety?</seg>
     <seg id="9">On whose orders is India taking this warning stance?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Let us know of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Zubeer Khan, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is very hurtful incident that Israel is publicly massacring the Palestinians, same situation is here in Kashmir but Security Council do not even bother about it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Associations in Kashmir and Palestian have to fight for their freedom, and they must unite and struggle with dangerous situations. One day their struggle will result in good. Insha Allah</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Ghaza, the Israeli air force attacks Palestine and many people have died.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The important Political Person of HAMAS Nazariyan has killed along with his family.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the other side the functions of the peace councils were closed, without any conclusion.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The meeting saw American opposition to the resolutions passed criticizing Israel by Libya and other Arab countries.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Israel's jet planes have been bombarding the residential areas of Palestine for last many days.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Each country around the world began to protest against the Mumbai attacks but can no one see this brutality?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Why are the leading Muslim countries silent?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What is your opinion on these double standards of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Saeed, New York.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think the problem lies in the illiteracy of our nation. People do not know how their money is spent. The government is solving its problems by introducing new taxes. The power and Gas crisis will remain unsolved.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Everybody knows the real faces of the elected representatives of the people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The power crisis has become worse in Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, the price of gas has been increased by 18%. Due to unavailability of petrol, people are facing severe difficulties.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The business and industrial communities of Pakistan are violently protesting the power and gas crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The producers have given the ultimatum to close the factories.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Here in Karachi, the public is annoyed over the 8-10 hour load shedding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Production has become practically paralyzed.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The government institutions are blaming each other to express their positions.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Are the talks of increasing the prices of electricity and gas a joke against the nation?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Why is attention not being given in resolving the issues?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The government is not working to improve the situation.</seg>
     <seg id="11">To solve these problems in the short term, what suggestions do you have?</seg>
     <seg id="12">I am aware of your opionion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Imran Khokhar, Madina Munawwarah, I want to say that, as the people, the rulers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I am surprised that government is carrying slogan of public service is itself hurting them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The unavailability of electricity, gas and petrol has become a persecution.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The government has no control over the institutions.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The law and order situation is getting worse, day to day. May Allah have mercy on this country.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The new year has started.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Last year was a year of outbreaks and political ups and downs. It will also be remembered for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We will also remember the removal of President Musharraf from power, the end of President Bush's eight-year regime, Bush having shoes thrown at him, the establishment of a democratic government in Pakistan, sudden calamities, the earthquake of Balochistan, and the terrible global financial crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now that the new year has arrived, how do you think it will go?</seg>
     <seg id="5">In your opinion, what will be the result of the political or geographical situation? What will be Obama's strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is there any hope of moving towards the eradication of terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Will the judicial crisis in Pakistan come to an end?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What direction will Indo-Pak relations take?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is there a chance of a surgical strike or full scale war?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What expectations do you have for the new year?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Share your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370256-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The first anniversary of Benazir Bhutto's death is being observed. She was martyred in an election rally at Liaquat Garden Rawalpindi on December 27, 2007.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir is not among us today. She was a thoughtful politician and a world reknowned figure. She held a special status in national politics.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One year has gone by but the mystery of her martyrdom has not yet been resolved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Her efforts to bring democracy to Pakistan were not in vain.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Today, Pakistan has a democratic government and her husband, Asif Ali Zardari, is holding the chair of the president.</seg>
     <seg id="6">How do you see the role of Shaheed Benazir Bhutto in Pakistan politics?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Who can be behind her martyrdom?</seg>
     <seg id="8">She was recently awarded the global award for human rights. What would you like to say about her political and democratic services?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After ruling over America for eight years, President Bush left the White House, for presidential camp office, Camp David, so that the White House can be decorated and prepared for new President Barack Obama, according to his wishes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During Bush's eight years rule, the historical attacks and destruction of the World Trade Center, attack on Pentagon and then in the name of war against terror, attacking Afghanistan and Iraq and involving forces from other countries into the war and use of American resources in it have become memorable examples of his time.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As a result of this war, America had to face the worst economic and financial crisis in history.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What do you think the world achieved and lost as a result of this war?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Were the policies of President Bush successful?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What is your opinion on President Bush's tenure?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian Government has stopped the Indian cricket team from visiting Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Indian cricket team was supposed to play three tests, five one-day matches and one 20-20, during the tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Vice President of the Indian Cricket Board, Mr. Ragiv Shukla, told Geo News that he has sought permission for the tour of Pakistan from the Indian government, but due to current tensions between the two countries the tour has been canceled.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Is the Indian government's decision to cancel the trip in view of the present political situation a proper step? Should sports not be separated from politics?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Is the Indian government's decision harmful for cricket?</seg>
     <seg id="6">If an English team visited India Despite security concerns then why can't the Indian team continue its tour of Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion on this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salman, Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Those people who feel proud of visiting India</seg>
     <seg id="3">and who make their films and videos over there, should now have their eyes opened as to how much the people of India respect them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I remember an interview of Adnan Sami in which he said that he is not a Pakistani national but a British subject.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan Sami should come back to Pakistan at the first opportunity, because he did not get honor over there either.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Farid Ahmad</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="3">India's attitude has changed after the Bombay Attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jagjit Singh has shown by his reaction that he hates Pakistan and the Pakistanis.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It should be known that Adnan Sami has sung with Asha Bhonsle. How has he become helpless now? Adnan Sami should stay in India. There is no need for him to come here.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muhammad Shamshad Alam</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi. I will only say this about Jagjit Singh: he changes color like a chameleon.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who gives statements in relation to the circumstances. Pakistanis! Open your eyes to how much value you are given in India. Understand their mentality.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the Mumbai incident, their hateful statements have increased, and now they are spitting poison against popular singer Adnan Sami.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">According to a foreign news agency, during his final visit to Iraq when American president Bush along with Iraqi president Noori Almaliki were in a press conference in his office, the situation went ludicrous when an Iraqi journalist while addressing President Bush said ""You dog this is a farewell kiss""</seg>
     <seg id="2">After this, the journalist took his shoe off and threw it at Bush. President Bush ducked with expertise and saved himself from getting hit by the shoe.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The second shoe hit the American flag.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Security personnels dragged the journalist away from there.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On this occasion, President Bush said that he did not know why he did that.  The shoe was size ten, he was not bothered.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Do you think this reaction of the journalist was an expression of deprecation for President Bush from the Iraqi people?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What do you think about this incident?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The tension between Pakistan and India's relations after the terrorism in Mumbai got further intense when the fighter planes from the Indian Air force violated the Pakistani airspace in Lahore and Kashmir sectors.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Due to the reaction of the Pakistani Air Force, the Indian planes were forced to go back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">According to sources, both Indian planes were full of weapons and ammunition.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the first incident of its kind in the current situation.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan Air Force says that it is ready to defend the country.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Information Minister Sherry Rahman says that Indian officials have accepted that aerial boundaries have been crossed, although this happened by mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pakistan military sources have declared this incident felonious.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Do you think India really intends to launch an air raid on Pakistan?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is this statement of India correct? Was this violation  a mistake or was this to find out the ability of Pakistan Air force?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Will this incident cause an increase in tension between the two countries?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Share your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Respected martyr Benazir Bhutto was given the International Award for Human Rights after her death, which was received by her son and chairperson of the People's Party Bilawal Bhutto Zardari.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This award was given to the former Prime Minister of Pakistan, slain Benazir Bhutto, in acknowledgment of her contribution towards human rights, in a function held during one of the meetings of the General Assembly in UN Headquarters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The 60th anniversary of the passing of the human rights resolution by the United Nations was celebrated on the 10th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Among those people and institutes being recognized for their human rights work, apart from Benazir Bhutto, were former American Attorney General, Louis Ramsey Clark and Human Rights Watch, an organisation that works around the world for human rights.</seg>
     <seg id="5">On this occasion, the Pakistani Ambassador to the United Nations, Abdullah Husain Harun, and other senior embassy agents were present.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you say about the former martyr Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto receiving this award?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Samir.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Chicago.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is true that she was martyred, but we also remember that she killed many innocent people in Karachi and that she was proud that Naiseer Ullah Baber had done a great job.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But later, she completely changed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is also true that she ignored the senior members of her party and made her son the representative of Peoples Party. What kind of democracy is that?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Juma Noor,Karachi,It proved this Quranic saying that unbelievers help unbelievers.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Until the metal of the axe has a grip attached to it, it cannot chop off the wings.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our leaders have a idea of this, which they are using to make secret plans.</seg>
     <seg id="4">God help our leaders.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The United Nations security council added the names of Hafiz Saeed and 3 other Pakistani's and Jamat Al Dawa and 5 other groups to the terrorist list.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Pakistanis whose names were included in the terrorist list by the Al-Qaidah and Taliban Sanctions Committee of the Security Council included Jama'athud Da'ah chief, Hafiz Mohammad Saeed, practically non-existent organisation Lashkar-e-Taiba Operation Chief, Zakiur Rahman Lakhwi and Financial Chief Haji Mohammad Ashraf.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In addition, a Saudi named Mehmood Ahmed Bazeek was also added to the terrorist list.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jamat-ul-dawa, Passban-i-kashmir and Alrashid trusts are included in these organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The allied nations will freeze their accounts and funds, restrict their travel and they will be arrested.</seg>
     <seg id="6">They will have to face charges.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are these sanctions the result of Indian propaganda?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Why does India make claims about this agency for the Mumbai blast without any proof?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Are the terrorism agencies not in India?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Does UNO, have the knowledge for these occurrence of blasts in India?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please provide us your suggestion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Occasionally Eid represents happiness and joy, and monotheists sacrifice animals following the tradition of Ibrahim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During this turbulent time when inflation is at its peak, the political situation is not promising, even after this rich and poor prepare for Eid within their means and wish their relatives a happy Eid in different ways.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We are also giving you an opportunity to wish your loved ones Eid greetings through our blog in the form of short messages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You can also send Eid wishes in the form of short Eid poems.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Murtaza Jilani.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Our leaders in Karachi should understand this-that the people they are doing the operation against are the true valuers of Pakistan. They are tolerating all kinds of tortures but they love Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>

