<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "ftp://jaguar.ncsl.nist.gov/mt/resources/mteval-xml-v1.3.dtd">
<mteval>
<tstset setid="mt09_urdu_evalset_current_v0" srclang="Urdu" trglang="English" sysid="mturk">
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090102.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">France  suggestion was appriciatable.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When commity's meeting was set up in the parliment house the chairman Mushahid  hussain syeed of the commity in his presence the   suggestion was given to the government,not only with the help of donating thinks but also  with all the political group to send to the parliment of Paliestien.</seg>
    <seg id="3">After the meeting while talking to one of the   member Mushahid hussain sayeed told  by the side of France  suggestion was accepted,in which it is said that the Israial's should stop the war immediatly,besides all this   the people who are in the cave should be permitted to do some work.</seg>
    <seg id="4">On behalf of Israil  the attack on paliestien was declared as the crime on humanity, they said that all the countries should help.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mushahid hussain said that all the countries gives their opinion on terraisiom  but attack of Israil on paliestien why all are quiet.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The chairman of the commiety  said the paliestien's matter  Saddam's brother Tanfeed was made target.</seg>
    <seg id="7">They said that the commiety has said that America's prime minister Barack Obama before100 days his government of set up,  he will speak to the muslim people to erase  and end the misunderstanding between muslim  people and America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mushahid hussain sayeed said that the arising misunderstanding between  muslim and western people will be seen and decided.Kashmir and paliestien problem will be solved.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Malik imdad khan the ex minister said to the commiety that he will be attending the confrence of  THE Islamic countries which is held at Saudi Arabia.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Failiour of the meeting Israil's attack on paliestien has requested that the peliestien's matter are unknown and the other country is trying to be in contact.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The prime minister of external affairs said that the issue of Falastin should be solved according to the planning of The United States.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Two generalists belonging Arab countries also attended the meeting and told about the fresh situation of Falastin.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Here the students of International University in Islamabad made strike against Islaean attacks against Falastin.</seg>
    <seg id="14">The strikers hold banners and pads containing slogans against Israel.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Abstain from decrease eating in order to escape from flue.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This research of American scientists was shown after many experiments on mouses.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It was proved by experiments the low calories eaters mouses had low defending power for flue in ratio.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The research proved this old talk that decrease eating is useful in fever.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Eat and drink more in fever according to scientists.</seg>
    <seg id="6">It is the saying of the researchers of Machigan State university that the low eater mouses had the low defending power against infection and their death chances decreased although the more eaters mouses had the high power against flue virus.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Professor Elizabeth Gardner said that those who are dieting are not only sooner affected by the flu, but also take longer to recover.</seg>
    <seg id="8">She also said that those who have taken flu vaccines should also avoid dieting for a few months during the winter.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">First nuclear test was done in 1990</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Thomas Reid, who worked in the Leur National Laboratory as a weapon designer had written this book with the help of Los Alamos National Laboratory's former Technical Intelligence Director, Danny Staleman.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this book, called 'Nuclear Express', the political history of the bomb and its spread, both the authors claim that whichever country made an atom bomb either stole the nuclear secrets from another country or they got help from a nuclear power.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Thomas Reid said in an interview with US News, that China tested Pakistan's first atom bomb in 1990, during the term of the Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Thomas Reid said that due to many factors, he is certain that China tested Pakistan's first nuclear bomb.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Among the factors are the design of the bomb, and information he gathered from Chinese scientists.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He further added that that was the reason that Pakistan was able to reply to India's Nuclear test with a nuclear test in just 2 weeks and 3 days.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Thomas Reid reminded that in 1961, Russia suddenly performed a nuclear test, in response to which America took 17 days to preform a test, despite having this bomb for a long time.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He added that the atom bomb that was tested on May 19th 1998 by Pakistan was made very carefully and that Pakistani scientists had complete reliance on it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">When Thomas Reid was asked whether China provided nuclear technology to Pakistan, he said because India was the common enemy of both China and Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that there was proof available that Dr. Abdul Qadeer Khan used the Chinese design, and later on the documents which were received from Libya also verify this fact.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Upon another question, as to whether joint nuclear testing was common, he said that America had openly performed nuclear tests for England in the deserts of Nevada in 1990.</seg>
    <seg id="13">He said that we also believe that Israel also has access to the results of this testing.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Thomas Reid was also asked about China's nuclear distribution program which is going on.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Upon that Thomas Reid said that China has been providing raw material, guidance and design for the nuclear setup in Asfahan, Iran since 1991.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Apart from this, China provided Iran with the nuclear enrichment plant in Kheraj.</seg>
    <seg id="17">He said that China has been providing Iran, Syria, Pakistan, Egypt and Libya with nuclear technology through North Korea.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090103.0024" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The year 2008 was excellent for the media.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The business man travels throughout his normal day when he discovers a flaw in his work, and fixes it and goes about his day</seg>
    <seg id="3">the male student walks along the long road</seg>
    <seg id="4">the puppy and the children play non-stop until the mother calls them all in to play.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The business man travels throughout his normal day when he discovers a flaw in his work, and fixes it and goes about his day</seg>
    <seg id="6">the puppy and the children play non-stop until the mother calls them all in to play.</seg>
    <seg id="7">the male student walks along the long road</seg>
    <seg id="8">The business man travels throughout his normal day when he discovers a flaw in his work, and fixes it and goes about his day</seg>
    <seg id="9">the male student walks along the long road</seg>
    <seg id="10">the puppy and the children play non-stop until the mother calls them all in to play.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The business man travels throughout his normal day when he discovers a flaw in his work, and fixes it and goes about his day</seg>
    <seg id="12">In America, there was an average increase of eight percent in the price of one ticket. In Madonna's show, the most expensive ticket sold was of 350 Dollars.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The editor of Pollstar magazine, Gary Bongiovanni, said that given the economic environment, the year 2008 was a good year for musicians.</seg>
    <seg id="14">He predicted that the year 2009 would be a good year for Springsteen and U2, whose albums were to be released this year.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0004" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ban on Joint Education: Taliban</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The local Taliban of the Hafiz Gul Bahadur faction, in the chief province, Miran Shah and other provinces of North Waziristan have distributed a pamphlet in which the government and semi-government institutes in which boys and girl are given joint education were warned.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the pamphlet, it was stated that if the joint educational institutes were not closed by the 5th of January, action will be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It was stated in the pamphlet that making identification cards for women, either for government aid or for other educational reasons would be forbidden, and that women would be disallowed from going to identification offices in all provinces.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The local Taliban's announcement of the forbidding of women from making identification cards was made at a time when about 200 women had submitted their forms in North Waziristan for identification cards in the identification offices for the sake of the Benazir Income Support Program.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to the locals, the pamphlets issued by the local Taliban was read out loud on the loudspeakers of all the mosques in North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="7">However, the letter did not state whether there would be a ban on separate girls educational institutions or not.</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to this pamphlet if any women goes to school or any government office to get education or make the Identity car then there would be strict punishment for her and her family when she is caught.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Apart from this the Police has also reported that on Sunday, in the District of Banu, Meeran Shah Road there was a nuclear Blast at the tunnel.As a result of which a road passer was killed and one man is injured.</seg>
    <seg id="10">The injured was admitted to the Banu Soul Hospital.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090104.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Target Cling- "More dead bodies are discovered".</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police two dead bodies were discovered on Sunday, from the areas of Green Chowk and Saharab Khan Chowk (Mingora).The heads of these bodies were separated from their necks of the bodies.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The information about the killed are being said through the Front-air core and police.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The investigation team has reported that a letter was found near the killed bodies warning that whoever attend or shift these killed bodies before the morning 11. am will be responsible for his destruction.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The local people of that area has said that no dead body was touched till the 11. am in the morning. Later we security guards lifted these bodies and shifted to the hospital.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The head place Mingora and the nearby places of this area has been experiencing lot of new dangerous incidents during the Target Cling, from the past few weeks. There is increase in these incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="7">It has been showed that among the killed there include the local area people, women and security guards.</seg>
    <seg id="8">according to local sources, more than thirty people have been killed to date in these kind of incidents.</seg>
    <seg id="9">so far no organization has taken responsibility of these killings.</seg>
    <seg id="10">the spokesman of the local Taliban in Swat Muslim Khan told on Saturday that the dead bodies found on Friday included those of his fellows and also included the dead body of the Taliban commander in Deolai, Rafiullah.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Muslim Khan said that Rafiullah was under custody of the security forces for the past one and half month.</seg>
    <seg id="12">he had said that the local taliban send notice before killing any one. On the other hand common citizens are worried about these incidents in Mengora.</seg>
    <seg id="13">according to the local people, a large number of security forces are deployed in Mengora but despite of this the attacks on the citizens are ever increasing.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090106.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Musical tribute to Benazir from Bakhtawar.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">A rap song (a modern style of music) in Bakhtawar's voice has been posted on youtube as well.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This 5 minutes long song contains pictures and video clips of Benazir.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Eighteen years old Bakhtawar is a student at the Edinburgh University.</seg>
    <seg id="5">she has great interest in poetry and singing.</seg>
    <seg id="6">it is said that apparently after the appreciation from her mother she had started singing songs as a hobby.</seg>
    <seg id="7">while paying a tribute to her mother she has said that she was an intelligent and beautiful lady, she did every thing with style.</seg>
    <seg id="8">regarding the 27th December incident she said that she the bullet was fired at her temple, she left us at the age of 54 and left three children amongst residuals.</seg>
    <seg id="9">the whole nation is hopeless without her and she is still in everyone's heart.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Bakhtawar is the second amongst Benazir's children after 20 years old Bilawal.</seg>
    <seg id="11">she has been taking interest in music from early days.</seg>
    <seg id="12">it is said that before her mothers return to the country with reference to a journalist friend she has expressed a will to meet the Grammy award winner music director and rapper Puff DD. but this meeting could not take place.</seg>
    <seg id="13">translation of Bakhtawar's poetry was published by some Sindhi news papers as well but her voice is being heard for the first time through You Tube.</seg>
    <seg id="14">some workers and followers of Benazir Bhutto have started preparing CDs of Bakhtawar's rap song.</seg>
    <seg id="15">On the other hand, Pakistan Peoples Party spokesperson, Farhatullah Babar confirmed that the song and voice present on YouTube is that of Bukhtawar.</seg>
    <seg id="16">He said on phone from Islamabad that this was the salutation of a brave mother by a sad daughter, which even started to play on Pakistan's government TV network.</seg>
    <seg id="17">Farhatullah Babar said that the party had no present plan to distribute CD's of her song.</seg>
    <seg id="18">He said that a few months ago, a fake page belonging to their party's young chairman, Bilawal Bhutto Zardari was created on Facebook which was later removed.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090107.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani: Minister for Media</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The joint minister of media and publishing, Sherry Rehman told BBC Urdu in an SMS message that he sent, confirming Ajmal Qasab's citizenship as a Pakistani, only that more investigations were going on.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Before this, the internal advisor to the Prime Minister, Rahman Malik had denied his Pakistani citizenship.</seg>
    <seg id="4">It was his saying that the record keeping offices do not have any record of him.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Regarding this new standpoint, it could not be cleared as to on what basis the Pakistani government changes their stand.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, according to the Foreign Ministry, the confirmation of Ajmal Qasab's citizenship was done by the Home Ministry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">before that BBC Urdu service and some other news papers and TV channels shows Ajamal Qasab belongs to Okara's district Faridcoat village of province Punjab.</seg>
    <seg id="8">all government kept deny of that.</seg>
    <seg id="9">still it is not clear that either Ajmal Qasaab belongs to Faridcort or some other area.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090108.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Rockets fired from Lebanon, give fire back bombarding.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Israels solders and police personals told to news agencies representative that there were four rockets fired from Lebanon to Israel in which one laid on North district of Nahriya due to that two person received very minor injuries.</seg>
    <seg id="3">in reply of Lebanon rockets attack Israeli tanks bombarded on Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="4">this is not clear that this attack made by Hezbollah or either behind that there is a hand of Palestinian activists group in Lebanon.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Lebanon government said that they are also trying to know that who is behind that rockets attack.</seg>
    <seg id="6">BBC analyst considered that this is very dangerous turn of intense situation in this region at the present time.</seg>
    <seg id="7">BBC correspondent for middle east Jeremy Boin according to him this rocket attack give more danger to separate war.</seg>
    <seg id="8">A threat is being expressed for the last few days that what if the current proceedings in Gaza spread to the borders of Israel along with Lebanon in the North.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Here, on night between Wednesday and Thursday, Israel's air force did  7 aerial attacks on the Gaza strip.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the Israel army, police stations of Hammas, tunnels, stock of weapons, rocket firing points and weapon workers of Hammas were made targets during these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Besides the aerial attacks, Israel army and marine artillery men continued bombing on Gaza through out the night.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to the Palestine sources, a mosque was destroyed in one of the aerial attacks in the city of Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="13">According to unauthentic sources, tanks of Israel army, which were supported by helicopters, moved towards the area of Khan Yunus.</seg>
    <seg id="14">In the fight going on for the last 12 days,almost 700 Palestinians have died including women and children in a large number.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Although on the other hand 11 men of the Israel army were also killed.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Security forces of Israel has confirmed that high defense official Amoos Gilad is going to Qahir to discuss the conditions of the cease fire.</seg>
    <seg id="17">One delegation of Hammas is also about to leave for Qahir to talk to the ambassadors of Egypt.</seg>
    <seg id="18">With this, the director of Falastin authority abbas Mahmood is also reaching Qahira at Friday.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090109.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">My heart has been broken, return my kidney.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Doctor Richard Batista told that he donated his kidney to her wife in order to save his life before 8 years ago.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the saying of news reporter institute A.F. the wife of Doctor Richard Batista gave the reward of that donation and deceived him and made belongings with another person and get divorce.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Doctor Richard Batista told in an interview to an national news Daily News that the lover of my wife made a hole in my heart and that is still in my heart.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the barrister of Doctor Richard Batista that the Doctor is saying the returning of his kidney but infect he wants to return the money of that kidney.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to his wife saying he will show his saying in the front of a judge after some coming days.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Nine k.g. labister freed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Jarj The Joint Labister was caught from a sea before two weeks.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The company of sea food purchased it in 100 dolors.</seg>
    <seg id="4">and they started lobster pictures for their marketing</seg>
    <seg id="5">working for All Animal protection Organization PETA demanded to release Lobster which result in releasing the lobster in sea</seg>
    <seg id="6">George was caught in the sea near Canada from where he spent 10 days in City Crab and Sea food Company</seg>
    <seg id="7">Lobster age can be calculated through his weight</seg>
    <seg id="8">Restaurant Manager Keth Walnti says that his Intentions was not to harm but to place in the tank so that people can take interest.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Wallay Ingrid newkrk, a member of Animal Protection Organization PETA say that restaurant decision is appreciatable and is an example for those who think to keep this precious Animal in to tank or to cook them in water.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090110.0032" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">cell phone helped to find the baby</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">authorities when came to know about Nitali Maltis, Massachusetts city Police officer and Agarbijhon forces came into action.</seg>
    <seg id="3">authorities finds the exact location of the baby with the help of GPRS installed in her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="4">But Google Street view help to locate baby that she was in Hotel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">a week ago Natalie's grandmother Rose Maltois Natalie took her from her legal parents' custody.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Ethol's police chief Timothy Anderson told BBC that she said she would never give Natalie back and then she left the state.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Police contacted Miss Maltois but when as per promise she did not send Natalie back, the Police decided to search for Natalie through her cell phone.</seg>
    <seg id="8">since 2005 there is a regulation in America that the cellular companies will provide location for 67 percent people in a range of 100 meters and 95 percent callers in a range of 300 meters.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090112.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Hamid Karzai on a visit to India.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">this is Hamid Karzai's second Indian tour in last five months.</seg>
    <seg id="3">it is expected that during his meeting with Prime minister Manmohan Singh he will discuss after effects of the terrorist attacks in Mumbai.</seg>
    <seg id="4">during this visit he wants to express the feeling of his people and solidarity with India over the Mumbai terrorists attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">during Karzai's visit, besides extremism, bilateral trade will also be discussed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">discussion on bilateral cooperation to counter extremism between both countries is also expected.</seg>
    <seg id="7">during his last visit to India, president Hamid Karzai said that terrorism will not be let into the relations between India and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">he also said that both India and Afghanistan are facing challenges of terrorism and merciless killings.</seg>
    <seg id="9">peace and stability in both countries, region and whole world is beneficial for everyone.</seg>
    <seg id="10">we understand this reality that both countries and the whole world can only join hands to face this curse of terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="11">it should be clear that for attacks on Indian embassy in Kabul in July last year, Karzai held Pakistani intelligence agency ISI responsible for it.</seg>
    <seg id="12">in that attack, including a senior member of IFC, four Indians were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="13">after the attack on the embassy, during Karzai's visit to India, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh said that this attack was on the India and Afghanistan friendship. We have agreed that terrorism will not be let into our relations.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0015" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Mumbai attacks, special judge for hearing.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Mumbai police commissioner Hassan Ghafoor has told that the hearing for the case registered against the only living accused from the Mumbai terrorist attacks will be carried under supervision of M.L. Tehliani.</seg>
    <seg id="3">earlier in this case, Ajol Nikum has been appointed as the public prosecutor.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Ajmal Qasab is now in police custody, and it is being hoped that the police will file a charge sheet against him before January 24th.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ajmal Qasab does not have any lawyer to defend him.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In a letter written to the Pakistani government, Qasab asked for legal aid.</seg>
    <seg id="7">India has give Pakistan proof of the involvement of Pakistani extremists in the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Pakistan has accepted that Ajmal Qasab is a Pakistani civilian.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to the police case, Ajmal Qasab and his partner Abu Ismail killed 6 police officers including ATS chief Hemant Karkare, Additional Police Commissioner Ashok Kamte and Encounter specialist Police Inspector Vijay Salaskar, after which they fled with their squad car, which was later recovered near DB Marg, Gurgam Choupati.</seg>
    <seg id="10">During police action, Ismail Khan died and the police captured Ajmal alive.</seg>
    <seg id="11">No lawyer was appointed yet, to follow Ajmal's case.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The lawyer chosen by the government, from the legal aid cell, Dinesh Mota refused to accept the case on moral reasons.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Two lawyers pulled out their names after protests and opposition by the people of a political group.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0021" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Constitutional Amendment; Committee to be formed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After addressing a seminar on environment change, he told media representatives that for this sake, the parliamentary meeting will take place in which a committee will be formed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that until now, to complete the 17th amendment, the constitutional amendment bill was presented by the Joint National Movement to the National Assembly, whereas other political parties have also presented their constitutional bills in this regard to the parliament.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the Pakistan Peoples Party has also send all the political parties a rough version of the 17th amendment and the committee would analyze their version.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In answer to a question, he said that the parliament would decide the balance of power between the President and the Prime Minister.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Prime Minister said that the Parliament has the complete right to take any decision.</seg>
    <seg id="7">In answer to another question, he said that in getting the former President retired General Pervez Musharraf to leave his post, apart from the role of political parties, the former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Pakistan Peoples Party, Benazir Bhutto also played an important role, by forcing the global brotherhood to remove the uniform of President Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that the elected Vice President of America, Joe Biden was a supporter of Pakistan and democracy, and that the president honored him in return for his services with the Pakistani Crescent.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Replying to a question about the Indian governments warning of breaking all ties with Pakistan, after the Mumbai incident, the Prime Minister Yusuf Raza Geelani said that the leaders are under extreme pressure from the public, which is why they issue such statements.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090113.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Protest against the removal of journalists</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Many of print and electronic media journalists held protest demonstration under the backing of RIUJ against the downsizing in different media organizations. They were shouting slogans against media owners and government</seg>
    <seg id="3">CR Shamsi, a senior member RIUJ, addressed the gathering. He said the same politicians who were protesting on roads with us, now are ruling this country. They have not enough courage to take actions against some power media owners</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said how the owners of media groups talked about human rights; they are exploiting the poor journalists by killing them financially.</seg>
    <seg id="5">One example of the exploitation is the suicide of a reporter of Lahore based Private TV channel. He was not having his due salary for four months. The media workers are living hand to mouth under the constant stress of downsizing and under payment.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He supported a decisive action against media owners. A camp should be installed before the National assembly to show anger and protest.</seg>
    <seg id="7">CR Shamsi criticized Salman taseer and blamed that Govers newspaper aaj Kaal is sacking its employees without any prior notice.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Daily Jinnah, daily khabrain, Channel 5, business plus and Aaj news have sacked dozens of their employees.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Mazhar Abbas, General Secretary RIUJ, also addressed. He said that all journalists associations are observing black day today to protest anganist forced abdications of journalists. He said that journalists will cover the parliaments session with black strips to protest.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Mazhar Abbas said that 50% TV channels and newspapers of Pakistan are exploiting media workers. Journalists are working there without any formal agreement</seg>
    <seg id="11">He said that more than 200 journalists and media workers are being sacked from TV channels and newspapers. More workers can be sacked by using economic crisis as a possible reason.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Mazhar Abbas said that movement of journalists will remain active till restoration of dismissed employees, implementation of 7th wage board and payment of pending salaries to employees of newspapers and TV channels.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090114.0019" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Cabinet of 11 members took its oath.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">New cabinet consists of a Far-ward block of former PM Sardar Attique's Muslim conference, 2 members of PPP, 2 members of People's Muslim League and one member of MQM.</seg>
    <seg id="3">A female member is also a part of the cabinet. She belongs to the far-ward block of Muslim conference.</seg>
    <seg id="4">According ruling  alliance, the cabinet will be enhanced during next week. 12 more ministers will be included in the cabinet. Earlier this month Sardar Attique Khan lost his position because of vote of no confidence. He was replaced by Sardar yaqoob khan.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The departments of these ministers will be announced later.</seg>
    <seg id="6">During oath taking ceremony, PPP workers raised slogans in support of Benazir bhutto, Former Prime Minister of Pakistan.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090116.0025" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">3.5 million users infected by Virus.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Conficker was first time identified in October 2008. It is also named as Downup, Downadup and Kido</seg>
    <seg id="3">A patch is offered by Microsoft to remove this virus but still almost 3.5 computers and memory sticks have been infected by this.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Experts say that the number of affected computers might be quite large.</seg>
    <seg id="5">To get rid of this, dealers will have to use Microsoft's MS08-067 patch.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Microsoft says that the virus which has affected thousands of computers searches for the Windows file 'services.exe' and injects its code into that.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Then, this virus becomes a DLL type of file, in the Windows system folder.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This virus also creates the name of the file.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It then changes the Windows registration details.</seg>
    <seg id="10">After this virus is activated, it creates a problem, which appears as an HTTP server, and changes the restore point of the machine.</seg>
    <seg id="11">It then downloads files from hackers' websites.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Microsoft claims that this virus has affected computers in various countries.</seg>
    <seg id="13">China, Brazil, Russia, India, America and England are some of those countries.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090117.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">ask for urgent report on Indian information.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">on Monday after meeting in ministry of foreign affairs while talking to the media representative he said that information given from India</seg>
    <seg id="3">information help for to investigate this matter.</seg>
    <seg id="4">they said Pakistan is an independent country and do investigation on information provided by India from any country</seg>
    <seg id="5">will not accept any dictation.</seg>
    <seg id="6">they said also collecting other information in addition information getting form India</seg>
    <seg id="7">Adviser of foreign minter said that organization who control law and order arrested 124 member of blacklist organization for the risk of peace threat.</seg>
    <seg id="8">and if found some evidence against some of them will take an action against them although innocent will be free.</seg>
    <seg id="9">he replies on one question that no one prison can send to India  and take an action against them as according to Pakistani Law.</seg>
    <seg id="10">he said takes an action against them as on F.I.A law.</seg>
    <seg id="11">while answering a question he said that the Indian law enforcement agencies have collected information about people involved in Mumbai attacks in 42 days therefore the world community including India will give some time to Pakistan to investigate on these informations.</seg>
    <seg id="12">He reiterated this offer from the government that a joint investigation team be made to investigate the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="13">it should be clear that a 3 membered investigation team led by additional director general FIA which is   of Mumbai attacks from India.</seg>
    <seg id="14">investigating on informations provided to Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Pakistani High commissioner in India Shahid Malik has met president Asif Ali Zardari in which it was cleared that if any person or group from Pakistan is found involved in Mumbai attacks, he will be dealt in accordance with the national laws and no one will be handed over to India. whereas the Indian leadership is putting pressure on Pakistan to extradite the people involved in the incident to India.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090119.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'Any thing is possible in America'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mr. Obama will take oath as the 44th president of America on 20th January.</seg>
    <seg id="3">while standing on the stairs of the building built in memory of 16th American president Abraham Lincoln and addressing a musical concert</seg>
    <seg id="4">Mr. Obama said that America is facing the most bitter challenges since many generations and he is hopeful that America will take care of it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Abraham Lincoln put an end to slavery in America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">But along with that Mr. Obama also stated that solving the problems faced by the country would take time and that the path would be a very difficult one.</seg>
    <seg id="7">"But despite this Im hopeful that the vision of the founders of this Nation will stay alive.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Besides being involved in the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, America is in the grip of a severe economic crisis.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Extra ordinary preparations are on the way for the oath taking ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Observers believe that around two million people will attend the ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Tuesday is a national holiday because on that day the great American visionary, Martin Luther King, was assassinated.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Martin Luther King was an African American.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Commitment to work was promised in honor of the memory of Martin Luther King.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Dr Martin Luther King was killed in the year 1968.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Barak Obama paid his respects to Dr King and told his fellow Americans to work together to achieve what was promised to this country.</seg>
    <seg id="4">There in Washington there are preparations going on towards the oath ceremony that is going to take place on Tuesday. the preparations include the preparation for the big public meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is expected that nearly twenty-Lakh people will gather in Washington for the first time in the American history, to see this American oath leadership ceremony.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Barack Obama has made the beginning of Monday by his visit to the TB center in the North America.In in the later part of the day he visited the injured American soldiers. After this he went to visit the house of those who were homeless and painted something on the wall.</seg>
    <seg id="7">While talking to the correspondents Barack Obama has said that - " the problems and troubles in which we are bounded and people who are homeless and troubled by the present circumstances require us to take actions to come out of these problems.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He has also said that King Martin Luther had spent most of his life by serving the nation and its people.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Barack Obama was also saying that when we are respecting the memories of King Martin Luther then we should not just stand in his respect instead adopt his sayings in our practice.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He has said that the Tuesday's function in which thousands of people gathered to hear the dream of King Martin Luther. People heard my speech which who were also gathered to hear the same dream in the year 1970.</seg>
    <seg id="11">King Martin Luther has also said in the same function that " that day would come when people would take inspiration from his color.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to the BBC's reporter Mathew Pres in the history of the American oath taking ceremony, the King Martin Luther has come for the oath taking ceremony before 24 hours while the other American leaders would take the oath on the blue form.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The leadership of Obama in the various states of South America would prove to be the implementation of the dream of the King Martin Luther.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090120.0027" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Was the Additional Political Agent.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Additional Political Agent was kidnapped by the unknown masked men on the first ten days from Southern Wazeerastan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Sources said that the member was kidnapped by the Mulla Nazeer Group's local Taaliban.</seg>
    <seg id="4">On the basis of the local organization on Tuesday at nearly four o'clock in the evening the Additional Political Agent of Wazeerastan Aamir Lateef had reached the Wana Scout Camp by a tribal group.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But they didn't say that who kidnapped the Additional Political Agent.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Therefore local people say that the local Taaliban had kidnapped the Political Agent.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Aamir Lateef was kidnapped at that time when he was going to Tank from Wana Camp.</seg>
    <seg id="8">On the eleventh of January 2009 in the tribal locality of Karkandra seven armed masked men had kidnapped the Additional Political Agent Aamir Lateef along with his driver.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Official members say that the kidnappers first unarmed the security available in the cars and then made the Additional Political Agent to sit in another car and took him away.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According to the Local Organization after the kidnap of the Additional Political Agent security forces blockaded all the check posts of the Southern Wazeerastan and the tribal area and every passerby was checked thoroughly and from about a week the officials had ordered economical restrictions on Wana.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the eight of December 2008, Northern Wazeerastan's Assistant Political Agent Asmattullah was kidnapped at that time when he was traveling from Meer Ali to Banu on Eid Vacation.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">British Hacker's win in the court.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Forty Two years old British citizen had confessed that he had hacked the American Army's website.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gerry is patient of Esperanza Syndrome. It is clear that Esperanza Syndrome patient does only one type of work.</seg>
    <seg id="4">His advocates say that if he was submitted to America then they fear that may be he will try to convict suicide.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Therefore the government's advocates say that on the basis of Gerry's health condition the possibility is very low.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Lord justice Morris K and Mister justice Simon had declared that Gerry has the permission to apply for the appeal in the British court.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Gerry's advocates had put this point that if Gerry was taken away from his house and family the he will try to commit suicide.</seg>
    <seg id="8">They also said that on this situation even the Secretarial Department didn't took any interest.</seg>
    <seg id="9">But the Government's advocates said that the secretarial department has used their options.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Gerry never denied the hacking of American Military website.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Gerry In year 2001, hacked two American system which resulting  in a loss of 0.8 million Dollar to American Government.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Gerry has hacked 97 Computers Including American Navy and Nasa.</seg>
    <seg id="13">But Gerry has said that his intentions was not wrong he was only looking for the information related to Alien which he think that American Government has kept secret.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Gerry's Father Janes Sharp he is happy with the decision.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Gerry's Lawyer has said that the verdict is correct.</seg>
    <seg id="16">this case is under proceeding since 2002 and finally the decision came correct</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090123.0030" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Kashmir: Two Hizb Commander are killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Lieutenant Kernel Achari, Indian solider of East Frontier which is posted in Jammu has said in to BBC that 24 Rachtri Rifles and Jammu Kashmir Policeman has covered a area of Gindo Destrict in DoDuk where militant were hiding</seg>
    <seg id="3">they fired at military and in return fire two militant were killed</seg>
    <seg id="4">The spokesperson said that among the two killed extremists was the district commander of the 12 year banned organisation, Hizbul Mujahideen, which is active in the region, Zuhoorud Deen Khande, who was an expert at gunpowder blasts.</seg>
    <seg id="5">His companion was identified as Sajjad Husain who joint the extremists last year, according to the army.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to Acharya, operations are still continuing in the mentioned jungle region, as according to him, there is the possibility of more extremists being present there. According to the army, two Kalashnikov rifles were also recovered during the first stage of the operation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Yesterday, state police chief, Kuldeep Kumar Khudda released the stats for 2008, saying that this was the most peaceful year so far.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is worth mentioning that no violence was reported in the seven stage assembly elections that took place in November and December.</seg>
    <seg id="9">More than 1350 contestants took part in these elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It should be known that Hizbul Mujahideen is active in Jammu and Kashmir for the last 18 years.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Hizb called a one sided ceasefire for the first time in July 2000, after which the Indian government and Hizb commanders held dialogs.</seg>
    <seg id="12">However, the ceasefire came to an end within 15 days.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Since then, many Hizbul Mujahideen commanders were killed in operations.</seg>
    <seg id="14">On Thursday in the reputed daily newspaper of Pakistan "The News", it was written about the residing terrorist groups in Pakistani Kashmir that Lashker-e-Tayyaba and Hizb-ul-Mujahideen has made the decision about considering the Kashmir policy.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Be clear that the policy of both groups until now was that Kashmir problem can be solved with the armed opposition.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Dera Bugti: Blast on the gas pipe line.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the police officials, 18 inch Qatar pipe line going from Loti gas field was destroyed in a bomb blast on Monday.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This pipe line goes towards the Sui plant.</seg>
    <seg id="4">A man named Sarbaz Baloch representing himself as a represtor of his invalidate party "Baloch republican army" has accepted the responsibility for this attack on the telephone on behalf of his party.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In four days, fourth gas pipe line was destroyed in a bomb blast.</seg>
    <seg id="6">On Friday, in Dera Allah Yar, an 18 inch Qatar pipe line was destroyed whose maintenance was continued until Sunday morning.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The general manager Mushtaq Siddiqui of the Sui Southern Gas company in Quetta said that gas supply through this pipeline would begin after noon.</seg>
    <seg id="8">This pipeline comes to Quetta through Sibbi.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In Quetta, Ziyarath and other far off regions, there is an acute shortage of gas for the last three days. On one hand, it is continuously snowing and the temperature has fallen below freezing point and on the other hand, the heaters and stoves have gone cold.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Apart from this, in Derahbagti town, there was a motorcycle blast in the market, but according to the police, there was no loss of life in the blast.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090125.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Administrator for Jamaa'athud Da'wah</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The central headquarters of Jamaa'athud Da'wah is in Taibah, about 25  kilometers from Karachi.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This center includes a hospital, a school and a hostel for students.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The law minister of Punjab, Rana Sanaullah Khan says that supervisors were appointed in the center of Jamaa'athud Da'wah, so that the work of social institutes there goes on unaffected.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Khalid Waleed, son in law of the Jamaa'athud Da'wah chief, Hafiz Saeed, a high ranking government officer, Khaqan Babar, was appointed for the supervision of the hospital, school and other social institutes, based in the center, as the administrator, while according to him, the posting of police at the center was also increased.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Security Council has passed a ban on Jamaa'athud Da'wah, after which the Pakistani government has started taking action against Jamaa'athud Da'wah across the country, and has put the chief of the Jamaa'ath, Hafiz Saeed along with other leaders under house arrest. The appointment of the administrator in the Taibah center by the Punjab government was also a part of the action being taken against Jamaa'athud Da'wah by the joint government.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Khaqan Babar belongs to the DMG, i.e. District Management Group.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Hafiz Khalid Waleed said that the Commissioner of Lahore division, Khusroe Pervez Khan along with police and the civil government came on Sunday and inspected the Taibah center. Khalid Waleed spoke ill about the appointment of an administrator, by the government in Jamaa'athud Da'wah, and he said that the number of patients in the hospital and children in the school had already dropped due to government actions.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Here according to a press release by Jamat-ud-Dawa, party's chief Hafiz Saeed has written a letter for the General Secretary of United Nations, Ban Ki Mon, and Committee for Taliban, in a reques is made to cancel the restrictions on the party made by the Security Council.</seg>
    <seg id="10">It says in the letter that the one sided decision of the Security Council on banning Jamat-ud-Dawa is unfair. And Jamat-ud-Dawa has no relation with terrorism but it is busy in the activities of charity.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Edhi on the aid mission of Gaza.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">After going through many steps of receiving permission required to enter Gaza, he has only been successful in reaching Egypt from New york.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said while talking to BBC Urdu service from Qahira that he has still not reached Gaza because Egypt and Israel has created many obstacles.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that it has been 8 days since I am here but I still have not received the permission to enter Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I am currently in Qahira and hopefully will get permission to go to Gaza</seg>
    <seg id="6">He told explaining that: "First I was given only 7 days visa to go to Gaza and later on my insisting, Pakistani officials helped me and had it extended for one month but on this condition that I will go to Gaza only once that is single entry.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that he has his son and daughters with him and they want to do charity work in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">I have brought some money.</seg>
    <seg id="9">$100,000 Cheque has been given to Egypt Red-cross and $10,000 cash Amount is also donated to for Aid supply to Ghaza.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090126.0028" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">four more minister the cabinet raised to 64 Ministers.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Among Four New Federal Minister, 2 Member are from Mutihida Qaumi Moment and 2 are from Jamiat Ulmai Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">New Ministers took Oath from President Asif Ali Zardari.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During the Oath Ceremony Prime Minister Yuosaf Raza Gillani and Federal Cabinet Members were also present.</seg>
    <seg id="5">With Four New Federal Minister the total strength of Cabinet with Ministers, Federal Ministers and Advisors reached to 63.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Farooq Sattar and babar Ghuari are two minister from MQM while Azam Swati and Mulana Atta ur Rehman are from Jamiat e Ulami Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The department of Ministries are not announced till now.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Faroo Sattar is Convener and Babar Ghauri is Senator from MQM whose term is ending on 10th of March.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Azam Swati is Selected as Independent Senator and he is considered to be richest Senator.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Member of national Molana Ata-ur-Rehman is the younger brother of Molana Fazal-ur-Rehman</seg>
    <seg id="11">It should be noted that four important advisors are not members of national assembly.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It should be noted that when on November 3rd 2008 22 new ministers and 18 state ministers were added in the cabinet it was thought that MQM would be added in the cabinet however due to disagreement over division of ministries MQA was not included.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090128.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Baluchistan, pipe line was destroyed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to Police, 18 inch diameter pipe line that goes to different wells in Pee Koh was destroyed in the morning by unidentified people.</seg>
    <seg id="3">A part from this yesterday well number 3 in Sui was completely destroyed and a gas pipe line was damaged near Dera Illa Yar.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Sirbaz Khan who is the representative of Disbanded organization Baloch Republican Army has claimed the responsibility of the attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Violent incidents has increased in Balochistan since the start of year 2009.</seg>
    <seg id="6">This month dozens of gas pipe lines have been destroyed and the attacks have increased on trains and people from Punjab.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Although Chief Minister Balochistan Nawab Aslam Raeesaani has expressed his concerns and ordered Police to exchange information with the secret agencies however it has been impossible to stop these incidents</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090129.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">819 billion dollar economic package approved.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">No republican member voted in support of President Obama's  Plan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to Republicans, this economic package would not prove a failure</seg>
    <seg id="4">In the House, this economic package is passed on a 244 to 188 vote</seg>
    <seg id="5">This package will be presented in the senate during next week. In the senate, the democrats are in a slight majority.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Because of the strong criticism from republics, approval of this package would not be easy</seg>
    <seg id="7">Obama has asked the parliamentarians to support this economic package by putting aside their political associations.</seg>
    <seg id="8">President is very optimistic about his Economic plan which is going to become a law next month. President hopes this economic plan will be useful for American economy and trade.</seg>
    <seg id="9">According to this economic plan, a handsome amount has been dedicated to general public and business community. 540 billion dollar will be spent on communication, education and modern technology.</seg>
    <seg id="10">According Richard Listern, A BBC correspondent in Washington, obama came in power with the motto to introduce new political culture but current debate on economic package has increased the political bitterness.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The Republican party members, among the representatives of the senate, called the proposed bill a waste of government money, and they said that it will not help in creating new employment opportunities.</seg>
    <seg id="12">They stressed upon the bill passed by their party, in which more importance was given to tax cuts.</seg>
    <seg id="13">They said that more employment opportunities could be formed with less capital through their bill.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They said that compared to constructive plans, more employment opportunities could be formed through tax cuts.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bitterness between Israeli President and Turkish Prime Minister</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Recep Tayyip Erdogan told the Israeli president, almost screaming, that the blood of many humans were spilled in Gaza, and it saddened him to see that people could watch this armed killing from Israel and clap in agreement.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Erdogan said that "I believe that you are using such words to erase your guilty feeling, and outloud, that too. But you killed those people, and I am remembering those children who were killed near the shore."</seg>
    <seg id="4">Simon said that Gaza's calamity is not Israel, but Hamas, who have established a dangerous dictatorship over there.</seg>
    <seg id="5">A BBC journalist from Davos said that he had never seen such a scene in an global economic forum before.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, Erdogan later stated that he respected the Israeli president and his age, which is why he did not scream at him, but whatever he was saying was very far from the truth</seg>
    <seg id="7">Turkey is one of the few Muslim countries which has diplomatic relationship with Israel. But displeasure has been materializing between the two recently.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090130.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">'The attack was not planned by Pakistan'</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">When talking to ND TV, an Indian channel, Wajid Shamsul Hassan stated that the Pakistani investigation report on Mumbai attack would be executed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">in the attack occurred in Mumbai last November, more than 120 people were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">India accused that  the extremist outfit Lashkar e Twaiba was behind the attack.</seg>
    <seg id="5">India also said that the 'political factors' in Pakistan also influenced the incident.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Mumbai attack has badly affected the relationship between the two countries.</seg>
    <seg id="7">When talking about the Pakistan investigation report on the incident, the high commissioner Wajid Shamsul Hassan has given out a hint about whereabouts of the report.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Wajid Shamsul Hassan said that in the light of investigation made so far, it is understood that Pak land had not been used for organizing the attack.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It might have been some other land; definitely, not Britain too.</seg>
    <seg id="10">these are the two places (Pakistan and Britain) about which I was worried.</seg>
    <seg id="11">India and the international community has created a lot of pressure on Pakistan to take actions against the culprits of the Mumbai attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Wajid Shamsul Haq said: we are not trying to cover it up.</seg>
    <seg id="13">we believe in taking action based on facts.</seg>
    <seg id="14">the world will accept our investigations.</seg>
    <seg id="15">we will try to satisfy India over the results (of the investigation)</seg>
    <seg id="16">while defending the delay in the investigation is Pakistan he said that it takes time to collect, understand and check these kind of stuffs.</seg>
    <seg id="17">The High Commissioner Wajid Shamsul Haq said that it took 45 days for India to present its dossier.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="BBC_URD_20090131.0009" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A black man elected as the republican leader too.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">in the sixth round of elections in the Republican party, Michael steel has won who received 91 votes out of 168.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In the selection for the post of Chairman, the candidate opposing Steele, Katon Dawson got 77 votes, whereas the ex-Chairman Duncan withdrew from the competition in the second stage.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Newspaper writers say that among the five candidates who stood for the chairmanship of the Republican Party, Michael Steele was considered the most moderate leader.</seg>
    <seg id="5">After winning, Michael Steele said in his speech, 'We are going to tell our friends and foes together, that you can join with us, but whoever wants to spoil this, they should be ready to be separated from us'. Michael Steele is from Maryland, where he was Deputy Governor.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He rose to fame in 2006, when he stood in the voting for a seat of the senate.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But after losing in the voting for the senate seat, he became the chairman of the Political Conservative Committee of the party.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Now, after being selected the chairman of the party, the country wide projects of the party will be under his supervision.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He fought in the election, promising that he would take the party in a new direction, and that he would use new techniques to join old-fashioned supporters with the party.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090104.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Indian claim of the presence of Lashkar-e-Taiba and Jaysh-e-Mohammad in Jammu</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">There are reports of the presence of militants in the Ponch province of Jammu</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to government sources, upon receiving secret reports, the police and the army have surrounded the region and have started searching.</seg>
    <seg id="4">During this a fight started in which four militants, two soldiers and one policeman were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to the sources, fights were going on until the last news. And in this area, militants associated with Lashker-e-Tayyaba and Josh-e-Muhammad are present, for which more army has been sent to fight them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">During this, chief minister, nominated by the involved officials, Omer Abdullah met with the governor and he directly gave the news of the selection of the Assembly leader from his party national conference.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Congress, the ally of the National conference also informed the governor of the advocacy of Omar Abdullah.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Omar Abdullah will take oath as the chief minister of teh sate.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Remember, national conference became the biggest party by gaining 28 seats in the assembly of 87 members in the current state elections. Keep in mind that separatist parties boycotted the elections.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Congress, which secured 17 seats, accepted to form coailition government with the national conference.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Today party workers welcomed Omar Abdullah with great fanfare on his arrival in Srinagar.</seg>
    <seg id="12">On this occasion, Omar Abdullah says that he will play his role in making the talks possible between Indian government and separatists. Although this is not possible until the elections in India and formation of the new government.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090106.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The Role of EU for peace in the Middle east.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">from official point of view, the role of European Union is decisive in the peace efforts to stop the war in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">according to Brussels' official stance, the efforts of Schwarzenberg delegation or Sarkozy were equally helpful in this regard.</seg>
    <seg id="4">European Union's spokesman Amadeu Altafaj has said that every such effort is adorable which is helpful in sending the European Union's message to the opponents of the war.</seg>
    <seg id="5">it seems alright as far as the official statement is concerned.</seg>
    <seg id="6">but in reality the European Union is portraying a very disappointing picture of the internal tensions.</seg>
    <seg id="7">as the head of the Union, Czech republic's role is even weaker than before.</seg>
    <seg id="8">an on top of that the internal issues have made is helpless.</seg>
    <seg id="9">on the other hand the French president Sarkozy is behaving like if he is still the president of the European Union.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Whereas France has completed its presidential tenure of six months.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Sarkozy wants to play a leading role and he is capable of it but he does not have the permission to do it.</seg>
    <seg id="12">The most comedy situation is for the Ambassdor of France Mr. Bernard Kouchner</seg>
    <seg id="13">He is also involved in this, with the guidance from the Ambassador of czech republic Mr. Schwarzenberg</seg>
    <seg id="14">not only this they had different opinion about, they might has to face a battle with the western world</seg>
    <seg id="15">they said that for the defence the Isreal they might has to face the war, even though it doesn't appear like that,  on the other side Germany also posted a person towards the east side. till Europeoan Union come to an conclusion, they wont win the battle</seg>
    <seg id="16">This is the proof of Isreal, which is doesn't provide any response to the European Countries.</seg>
    <seg id="17">this is best time for the European Union to perform, because America has failed in the western side by the law of Goerge W bush</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090108.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Capitalism Revolution: Death of the German millionare</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In the south of German, the place by name Subia, Adolf Miracle has lefted a big business people behind him</seg>
    <seg id="3">But, before some time they german people dont know him</seg>
    <seg id="4">After which the business people found difficulities to raise fund from 30 bank, then only he was in the headlines of the newspaper. which reflects a bad future for the mircale group</seg>
    <seg id="5">The aim of advertising is always to sell the product or let the people know the various facilities made available to them either at the market or at their doorstep.</seg>
    <seg id="6">When a product is being advertised we are able to gather more information such as its name, price,benefits and availability in short, it is a brief actual account of itself.</seg>
    <seg id="7">But sometime the drafted messages tend to be fictional too, owing to either exaggeration or to false claims made by the advertiser. Viewed objectively, the advertising message must act as a salesperson and do its best to convinced consumer of the merits of the product.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The words used in advertisements are typical of a salespersons' language and this is how he would like to convince his prospective buyer,should they come face to face.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The name of this advertisements is Ratiopharm. The words used by the salesperson, definitely praise the product or service that is available.</seg>
    <seg id="10">More often, they are colorful and catchy words as they persuade the customer to respond favorably and force him to purchase the product. Unless cosmetics and other like Kassbohrer products are heavily promoted, they will languish unsold on the shelves of this stores for a long time.</seg>
    <seg id="11">So, advertising always puts forward the best points of the product. Advertisement can be educative, entertaining, informative handy and surely interesting.</seg>
    <seg id="12">At times, however, they tend to be boring, irritating, incredible and embarrassing.</seg>
    <seg id="13">Another category of advertisements tends to brag so as to tempt the buyers.</seg>
    <seg id="14">But whatever it be, advertisements have a two-fold purpose to serve. They have a message to convey and they attempt to evoke a desirable response in the buyer. As a result 400 VEM product becomes a popular ones; the demand increases.</seg>
    <seg id="15">this way Merchlay group will stay as it has always been after the death of Adolph Merchley</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090112.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The rate of crime among immigrants in Germany.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to latest statistics the rate of crime among immigrants from 2004 till 2007 is 22%.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Decline from 9 to 0.21%</seg>
    <seg id="4">has reached 4%</seg>
    <seg id="5">According to Interior minister Joachim Herrmann of province Bavaria this is a superficial positive change.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said "this should be noted that the number of outsiders seeking immigration of Germany is increasing"</seg>
    <seg id="7">Hence, this should also be stated in statistics that the criminal is a German citizen but his background is non-immigrant.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He said that his province will also consider this while collecting statistics</seg>
    <seg id="9">A part from Bavaria the same is being planned in Hamburg.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Senator for foreign affairs from CDU, Christoph Ahlhaus has said: "When research is done in a scientific manner, the man can not pre-decide its results but it is based on the facts and figures that come out as a result of the research.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Ahlhaus diverted the attention to a research report from the anti crime's provincial office which was prepared in 2006 and according to this report in Bergdorf, a part of Hamberg, it was investigated that out of all crimes happening there what percentage have the involvement of foreigners.</seg>
    <seg id="12">results showed that the foreigners here have</seg>
    <seg id="13">the crime rate was less as compared to the crimes allover the province.</seg>
    <seg id="14">in contrast when in 2006 a survey was done on crimes in youth in Berlin, it came up that young people having foreign background had a percentage of .44</seg>
    <seg id="15">was 7 percent</seg>
    <seg id="16">However, other political parties of Germany for example, SPD, Environmentalists organization Greens, and leftist organization Linkspartei were against this proposal that while collecting facts and figures regarding crimes, this should also be inquired that which German citizen has a foreign background.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0006" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">We want quick evacuation of troops from Gaza: Olmert</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Ehud Olmert has stressed that for complete evacuation of the army, a future and permanent ceasefire agreement is inevitable.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Hamas and Israel declared ceasefire on Sunday.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Islamic militant group, Hamas has said, announcing a one week war break, that the Israeli army should evacuate the Gaza strip within one week and stop their guarding of the strip.</seg>
    <seg id="5">On the other side, Hamas leader Ismail Junaih has said that Israel has received victory in the Gaza war from God.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that Israel was unsuccessful in achieving their goals in the Gaza war.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Before that, in Sharm-el-Shaikh in Egypt, on Sunday, the leaders of Arab and European countries had a meeting in which there was a call for immediate evacuation of Israeli army from Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It was decided in the meeting, that soon, an international aid conference for Gaza would be held.</seg>
    <seg id="9">German Chancellor, Angela Merchel was also present in the mentioned meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="10">At least 1300 Palestinians including 10 soldiers as well as 13 Israelis were killed in the three week long war being fought between the Israeli and Hamas soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="11">On the other side, Palestinian President, Mahmood Abbas stressed upon an international rule in the Palestinian regions.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090119.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Al-Qaida's video message to Germany</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this thirty minute video, a man wearing a black turban, covering his face and holding a gun in his hand addresses the German government.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The same man is introducing himself as the Father of Talha and is talking in German language.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Arabic subtitles are also present in this video message.</seg>
    <seg id="5">There is a log of Al-Qaeda on the side of the screen and video has the date of October 2008.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In this message, it is said to the German Government that is the country expressing their belief that they will not be attacked on after assigning army in a great number in Afghanistan. If this is not innocence, what is it?</seg>
    <seg id="7">This man calling himself "Father of Talha" did not threaten about attack on Germany indirectly.</seg>
    <seg id="8">In Afghanistan, the number of German army soldiers included in the United army NATO is almost 3500 at this time.</seg>
    <seg id="9">In October last year, German Parliament has approved of sending 1000 more soldiers to Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="10">This is the first message received by Germany from Al-Qaeda.</seg>
    <seg id="11">Mikhael Luders, who keeps a close watch on the activities related to terrorism, says in relation to this message :" The suicide bombing outside German consulate recently has proved that we should take it seriously in every condition.</seg>
    <seg id="12">For the last few years, AL-Qaeda has been distributing messages over the internet and there have been attacks after such messages.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The responsibility for the terrorist attack outside the German Embassy at the weekend was taken by the militant group, the Taliban.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Most German papers and analyzers are linking this attack with the message of Al Qaeda.</seg>
    <seg id="15">"They are targeting Germany.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Muslim hard liners see the Germans Afghan policy in a negative and questionable light.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They blame the German government of adopting biased policies not just towards Afghanistan but the Middle East also.</seg>
    <seg id="18">And it is for this reason that they are increasingly finding Germany as their enemy.</seg>
    <seg id="19">Besides this the German Government stated that even before the video came out publically the German undercover agencies knew about it.</seg>
    <seg id="20">The German federal anti crime organization was occupied in investigating the contents of the video.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090120.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama took office as the President of America.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In this crisis the American people are on one side while the rest of the world is expecting different things form Obama.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Now when Barack Obama is receiving greetings from all over the world on becoming the president of America, the expectations from him are also rising.</seg>
    <seg id="4">in this reference, the German Chancellor Angela Merckle has expressed confidence in the American president.</seg>
    <seg id="5">"I am sure that based on the friendship between Federal Republic of Germany and the United States of America, we can resolve all the issues faced.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Russian prime minister Viladimir Putin has said that Obama appears to a serious and open hearted man this is really a good news.</seg>
    <seg id="7">although the policies of former American president George W. Bush have been facing criticism.</seg>
    <seg id="8">however, his regime is appreciated for promoting China to play a more constructive role internationally whereas China has said about the new American president that he will have to work for stronger military relations between both countries.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Active in German city of Bochum, Chinese political expert Kusuay Wu says:</seg>
    <seg id="10">"in this reference, I am sure that in coming weeks and months, Obama and his team of economists will put immense pressure on China to have a more flexible and competitive to market exchange rate for the Chinese currency.</seg>
    <seg id="11">former American regime has also improved on relations with India.</seg>
    <seg id="12">how far Obama can take these relations, Christopher Raj, Professor of American Studies in New Delhi says on this: "now we have come closer in strategic partnership, however, Obama can not bring an overnight change.</seg>
    <seg id="13">In a message sent to Obama by Pope Benedict, he also stressed upon the need to create an environment of peace and mutual help in the world.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="DEW_URD_20090131.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">State elections in Israel</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">This is the first important election in this war ridden country since 2005.</seg>
    <seg id="3">For the state elections, more than 14,400 contestants have entered the arena for 440 seats.</seg>
    <seg id="4">To maintain peace and safety during the elections, 800,000 police and soldiers were posted in Iraq.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Fearing that some bomb blast or terrorist attack might take place on this important day, all the borders of Iraq were sealed one day in advance, i.e. on Friday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Apart from this, the airport was closed and restrictions were placed on public trasnsport.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to reports, due to the restrictions on public transport, there was no traffic on the roads of Baghdad, and children were seen playing football on the roads.</seg>
    <seg id="8">During the present Iraqi elections, the security arrangements will tell, on one hand whether or not the local security agencies will be able to take over the country after the return of the American forces from Iraq in 2011, and on the other hand, political analysts are using this as a test as to what extent the public is prepared to bring change to the country in democratic ways.</seg>
    <seg id="9">The state elections are being held with help from the United Nations and almost 800 international supervisors are overlooking the elections.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090107.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Today is celebrated as Ashoora day all over Iran with high reverence and piety and with the remembrance of the Leader of martyrs Imam Hazrat Husaian.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to Mahar news agency,in all small and big cities including Tehran, the capital of Iran, people mourned the sacrifice of Hazrat Imam Husain (Peace be upon him), the leader of martyrs. Huge crowds attended the mourning processions and meetings. Due respects and condolence were given to the Ahlu Baith (the Prophet's (PBUH) inheritors).The whole Iran observed with great sorrow and lamentation the supreme martyrdom in the Karbala battleground of the Prophet's grandson, Imam Hazrat Husain (PBUH).The true believers cherished the memory of the unique sacrifice of Hazrat Imam Husain in Karbala. Large crowds attended the condolence meetings and processions.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090111.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Israeli troops' retreat from Gaza Corridor. Stern defense put up by Palestine fighters.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to Mahar news reports of Urdu service,even on the 16th day of the battle between good and evil, the Israeli troops showered bombs on the city dwellers. 880 people have so far martyred in the land-sky-sea attack of the Israeli troops and 3700 Palestines have been severely injured.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The martyrs include 275 innocent children. They embraced death smiling at the faces of deceitful Arab leaders and the organizations pretending to be working for international human rights.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The Israeli troops were forced to leave Ujain in Gaza today because of the strong resistance of the masked Palestine soldiers. They exhibited magnificent defense with the help of their strong faith and desire for sacrifice. They engage in a do or die battle against the Zionist enemies.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But for the treacherous stand of the Egyptian President Husni Mubarak, the brave and solid fighters of Hamas would have thrown the Israeli troops into the pit of shameful defeat. Unfortunately, the Egyptian Muslims also keep the Palestines under siege along with the Israeli troops. It is the most tragic incident in the history of Arabia.</seg>
    <seg id="6">There can be seen that Saudi Arabia and Udar government extends political as well as financial assistance to Israel. Similarly, they join hands with Israel to deceive the Musalmans of Gaza who are put in unending miseries.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090112.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barak Obama and America weave new evil strategies against Iran.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to Mahar news agency, the elected President of America Barak Obama, while talking to ABC news channel, said that new and modern strategies would be adopted in dealing with the Iran affairs.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Bark Obama said that Iran will be the big challenge for American Government.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Bark Obama said that he afraid about the Iranic help to Falastini Islamic organization Hammas and Hizbullah and Iranic item program.</seg>
    <seg id="5">But he will not continue the running policy of American president Bush about Iran and start relationship with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Bark Obama said that he will stress on talking and respecting showing his real aim.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Bark Obama said it in past also that there will be no conditions to talk with Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="8">He showed in interview that the management will work on this new policy rapidly about Iran.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Bark Obama said about the problem of middle East that he will make a special team for it.</seg>
    <seg id="10">That will start work after 20 January for the peace of middle East.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090113.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The president Jarj Bush declared his mistakes and criminals in his last speech.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The expert News agency said about the Associate Press that American president Bush declared his mistakes and criminals in last press conference.</seg>
    <seg id="3">During his press conference at White House President Bush offered his best wishes to newly elected President Obama and said that the biggest challenge would be to protect America from every possible attack.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He said that the completion of Iraq mission and improvements in social security are his mistakes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush said that he did everything for the protection of America.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In response to several questions asked about Israeli aggression in Gaza President Bush replied that Israel has the right to protect herself but Hamas does not and Hamas should not attack Israel and like America the whole world should strangle the oppressed instead of the oppressor.</seg>
    <seg id="7">America's most incompetent and ineligible president said that Hamas should not be provided arms however America is giving the most devastating weapons to Israel who are using these weapons in the genocide of Palestinians. Also criticized pro Israeli Arabs and declared them friends of Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Bush was embarrassed about the crimes committed in Abu Garib and Guantanamo bay prisons.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Experts say that Bush should be trialled for war crimes and the organizations who will do this will do great benefit to mankind.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Iranian President Ahmedi Nizad regretted the silence of Arab countries.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to all news agencies Iranian president Doctor Ahmedi Nizad has strongly criticized silence of Arab leaders on the Israeli aggression and oppression.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmedi Nizad is shocked on the silence of Arab countries and their leaders on the Israeli aggression on Gaza and said that Israel is doing Holocaust of Palestinians, terrorizing Palestinian children, women and ordinary citizens.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmede Nejad has called upon all the Arab countries to unite against Israel and to save the oppressed Muslims of Gaza Israel's harm and tyranny.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090115.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Ahmade Nejad; Saudi King should clarify his stance on the  genocide being done in Gaza by Israel.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to the report by MAHAR/MEHR news agency, President Ahmede Nejad in his message to the Saudi King Malik Abdullah declared that the silence on the human genocide in Gaza and muteness on the murder of innocent children and women by  the Muslim King of Saudi Arabia is a reason that  is encouraging of the enemies of Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">President Ahmede Nejad has said in his message; You should show your true stance on Gaza and declare support for the oppressed, so that the enemy's efforts of planting differences in the Islamic block should fail.</seg>
    <seg id="4">President Ahmede Nejad has said in his message; You know that for the last 19 days Israel is bent upon human genocide, murdering innocent children, subjecting homes, mosques, schools and hospitals to barbaric bombing. The Zonist Regime is brutally murdering the unarmed Muslims in Gaza. In situations like these, silence on the part of leaders like you is only encouraging Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Ahmede Nejad has told Malik Abdullah that even non- Muslim countries like Valenzuela and Bolivia have taken concrete steps against Israel and that he is expected to take better steps.</seg>
    <seg id="6">President Ahmede Nejad told the Palestinians that success will be at their feet in Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">and Oppressed will win over the oppressors and thats Allah's promise.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090116.0010" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President George Bush; Terrorism is still a threat to USA.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">MEHER/MAHAR news agency has copied with reference from the German news agency that the US President while addressing his successor Barak Obama and the nation in his farewell speech, said that though the US is safer than it was seven years ago but the threat of terrorism still looms over USA.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Bush said that the enemy terrorists are waiting patiently to attack America, and they have a strong determination to attack America so America should never be unaware about its security.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The American President ignored the hurts and suffering of the hundreds of thousands of Palestinians in Gaza, and defended his policies saying that America is still the biggest supporter country of independence. However commentators do not accept the reality of the unpopular president's remarks, as America is neither a supporter of freedom, nor a supporter of human rights, but rather it is the most mischievous country in the world, which not only supports a blood thirsty country like Israel, but is also directly involved in its crimes.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Israel, openly kills children, women and civilians and the American president is congratulating them. This is the American humanity and freedom which the world is seeing in Gaza and other places.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090117.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Usama Hamdan: Presence of army in Palestine continues</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a report by Mehr News Agency, the Hamas leader in Lebanon, Usamah Hamdan told French News Agency, during an interview, that the one sided ceasefire from Israels side is against the comprehensive international efforts for a ceasefire. He said that as long as Israel is present in Gaza, a one sided ceasefire is meaningless.</seg>
    <seg id="3">He said that the one sided ceasefire was an unsuccessful effort of Israel to escape defeat. Hamdan said that if Israel wants long term peace, it will have to accept Hamas's conditions as well as end this siege.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The Hamas leader in Lebanon made it clear that if Israel tries a one sided ceasefire with its army remaining in the Gaza belt, there will be resistance against it.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Addressing a one way conference from Beirut, the Usamah Hamdan called for the European countries to break ties with Israel.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Hamas leader said that the increasing numbers of the martyred and injured will only increase our determination.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He told the Palestinian public to stay firmly rooted and resist the enemy like a boulder.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090120.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Taliban have killed six people in Pakistan's tribal area of north Wazirastan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">meher reporting agency copied with reference to rueters that taliban have killed 2 Afghans and 4 Pakistanis over accusation of espionage in Pakistan's tribal area of north Wazirastan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">according to reports, on Tuesday morning locals found four dead bodies from tehsil chowk in Tehsil Mir Ali, who were shot dead.</seg>
    <seg id="4">whereas two dead bodies were found in capital Miranshah who were thrown in the market of a Bazaar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Letters written in Urdu have also been found near the dead bodies in which it is claimed that the dead were involved in espionage.</seg>
    <seg id="6">also, two weeks earlier, in Miranshah, capital of north Wazirastan, two Afghanis were killed over accusations of espionage.</seg>
    <seg id="7">over last twelve days, fifteen people have been killed over charges of espionage for America.</seg>
    <seg id="8">it should be clear that during last six years more than a hundred people have been killed in South and north Wazirastan on accusations of espionage. Taliban are accused of being involved in these murder cases.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090122.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Barak Obama is expected to undersign the closure orders of the infamous Guantanamo bay prison.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr reporting agency has copied through sources that today the American president will sing the orders of the closure of the infamous Guantanamo bay prison.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The new American president, Barack Husain Obama started working on his campaign promises at the surface level.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In this regards, President Obama called for making a plan on calling the army back from Iraq, while the American president will sign an order today, to close the notorious Guatenamo Bay jail.</seg>
    <seg id="5">It is being expected that President Barack Obama will probably sign on the order today, through which the Guatenamo prison will be closed within one year.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Apart from this, the White House is expected to revise suspected terrorism investigation methods and ban ill treatment of prisoners during interrogation.</seg>
    <seg id="7">President Barack Obama started to fulfill his election campaign promises from his first day in office, and first of all started by taking steps towards making the actions and working of the government transparent.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Experts say that the American president has started making efforts to save the falling image of America throughout the world, but that would be difficult for it, because as long as it will keep supporting the blood thirsty Israeli government, it can not be expected to do anything good. Therefore if America wants to save its image, it will have to stop its support of Israel and have to disassociate itself from Israel's crimes.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="MHR_URD_20090131.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tony Blair stresses upon the need to include Islamic organization, Hamas in the talks</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Mehr news agency quoted from the Britain newspaper, The Times, that former Prime Minister Tony Blair stressed upon the need to include Hamas in the talks, to bring about peace in the Middle East.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the newspaper, Tony Blair said that it is important that a path be found for bringing Hamas into the Middle East peace process. Blair criticized the Bush administration for speaking only to Mahmood Abbas and ignoring Hamas. It should be clear that the western countries have realized the democratic and organizational powers of Hamas and are calling for bringing them into the talks, whereas previously they used to consider it a terrorist organization. A terrorist organization which is trying to defend its country and struggling to save its own house from the clutches of others. Whose house and country have been in the hand of the occupying Israeli government for 60 years.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090101.0016" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Murder of Balochistan merchants in Karachi, Complete strike in Quetta</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Due to the death of four merchants from Balochistan in Karachi, a complete strike was in effect on Thursday against it, in Quetta and some other places.</seg>
    <seg id="3">In this period all business centers remained closed, whereas traffic was also less than normal.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The protesting strike was called by the 'Anjuman Tajiran Balochistan' (Balochistan Trade Union), Pushtunkhwah Milli Awami Party and the Jamiat-e-Ulama-e-Islam. They accused the Karachi police of having openly fired at these merchants, when they were going by car to their vehicle showroom on Tariq road.</seg>
    <seg id="5">The president of the Anjuman Tajiran, Abdur Raheem Kakad demanded that the guilty police agents should be arrested and action should be taken against them.</seg>
    <seg id="6">However, the stand of the Karachi police about this incident was not immediately clear.</seg>
    <seg id="7">All four of the dead merchants were from the border city of Chaman.</seg>
    <seg id="8">A large amount of security was provided by the government during the strike, and police officers were posted throughout the city, at important locations.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090103.0018" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">A senior commander of Hamas was killed in Israeli attack.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In an air attack by Israel, a senior Hamas commander was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="3">This is the second death of an important Hamas figure, in the week long Israeli attacks on the Gaza belt.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Hamas officeholders said that Abu Zakariyya AlJamaal was killed in Shujaaiyah palace in the east of Gaza city, on Saturday.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In another air attack by Israel, on Thursday, Aalam Nazar Ra'iyan was killed.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Hamas's evacuated leader, who stays in Syria, Khalid Mushil has promised to take revenge and warned Israel of launching a land attack on Gaza.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Thousands of Israeli tanks and soldiers are posted at the Gaza border, and they are waiting for orders to attack.</seg>
    <seg id="8">America has called for a ceasefire, but said that it is up to Israel, whether to attack Gaza or not.</seg>
    <seg id="9">American President, George Bush said on his weekly speech on radio, that Hamas was escalating the situation, and he said that their attacks on Israel amounted to terrorism.</seg>
    <seg id="10">He said that America would work for a ceasefire, but any one sided settlement would not be acceptable.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0011" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Bodies found in North Waziristan</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistani Security officials said that the bodies of three people were found in the tribal regions of North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">It is suspected that Taliban gave them the death penalty and killed them.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Two dead bodies were found new Miran shah with letters. They were blamed as spying for US.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Officials said that one dead body might be of a local person  kidnapped last week.</seg>
    <seg id="6">They disclosed that the other two dead bodies were of afghan citizens.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090105.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">10th day of Israel attack on Ghaza.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The philistine child that was wounded by Israel missile attack.  Israeli army is fighting against the armed men of Hamas in Ghaza. Israeli air force is striking against the shelters of Philistine fighters.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Israeli defense minister said that operation will remain till south Israel is not made safe from the rocket attacks of Hamas.</seg>
    <seg id="4">However, Hamas firing rocket despite Israeli attacks. 4 casualties have reported, 3 of them are civilians.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Mehmood Zafar, a Hamas leader asks his soldiers to crush Israeli soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="6">According to an official of hamas, Hamas is planning to send a envoy to Egypt to discuss the latest situation</seg>
    <seg id="7">A wounded woman in ghaza. According to medical staff during last 10 days nearly 530 people have lost their lives. 11 civilians, including 5 young children were killed on Monday.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Israel has reported the death of one soldier and the injury of 30 others in land attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Israel has stopped other-national journalists from entering Gaza, for investigating military action.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090109.0007" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The elected American Vice President, Joseph Biden reached Pakistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The foreign minister received the elected American Vice President.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The elected American Vice President, Joseph Biden reached Islamabad on Friday, along with his group, for his tour of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">The foreign minister, Shah Mahmood Qureishi and the high ambassadors of the American Embassy received him.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Ameican senator Lindsy Graham is also with Biden on this trip.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Press Officer of the American Embassy, Lou Fintor told the Voice of America that the newly elected President, would talk to the Pakistani government about various regional issues during his tour. However, he avoided giving more detail.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to sources in the Office of the External Ministry, Joseph Biden would meet with various officeholders in the government, as well as with Army Chief Ashfaq Pervez Kiyani.</seg>
    <seg id="8">It is expected that apart from important bilateral and global issues, matters related to the war against terrorism will also be discussed in these meetings.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Joseph Biden awarded the Pakistan Crescent</seg>
    <seg id="10">After reaching Islamabad, Joseph Biden met President Asif Ali Zardari</seg>
    <seg id="11">During their meeting, in recognition of his efforts in increasing ties between Pakistan and America, the President awarded him with the Pakistan Crescent.</seg>
    <seg id="12">It should be clear that Joseph Biden had introduced a bill along with Senator Richard Logger as the chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee of the American Senate, in which it was proposed that during the next five years there is a tripling in the amount of military aid given to Pakistan, making it 15.7 Billion Dollars.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090112.0023" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Joe Biden played an important role in removing Musharraf's uniform, Prime Minister Geelani.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Yusuf Riza Geelani and Joe Biden (File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="3">The Prime Miniter, Yusuf Riza Geelani said that the American newly elected Vice President played an important role in removing former President Pervez Musharraf from the position of Army Chief, and that Joe Biden helped Democracy in Pakistan considerably.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Yusuf Raza Geelani gave this statement, speaking to journalists in the Karachi shipyard.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He said that Joseph Biden was a Pro-Pakistan leader and as chairman of the committee for foreign relations of the American Senate, he passed a bill for aiding Pakistan with 15 Billion dollars</seg>
    <seg id="6">About the missile attacks by American spy planes within Pakistani boundaries, the Pakistani Prime Minister once more derogated them saying that there is no agreement with the American government about allowing such attacks as according to him, it was a matter of Pakistani sovereignty and hence by no means could they give permission for such attacks within their territory.</seg>
    <seg id="7">They have also showed hope that after coming to the leadership of the new government in America there will be changes in the American policy.</seg>
    <seg id="8">(File Photo)</seg>
    <seg id="9">Yousef Raza Geelani had said that the government had divided the terrorism from the general tribes was successful but the missile attack from the spy air crafts had caused disaster to the governments efforts and the terrorists again get included with the tribal area.</seg>
    <seg id="10">They had said that the United Nations members accepts the situation with Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The Vice President had said that if anyone from the tribes testifies then the Pakistan Forces themselves will do the investigations in their areas.</seg>
    <seg id="12">Over the attacks on Mumbai the Vice President Yousef Raza Geelani had repeated his opinion that if India sends the witness then they will investigate on that basis and if there is anyone involved then there will be an investigation against them in the National Law.</seg>
    <seg id="13">On behalf of the tour of Rahman Malik to Britain and meeting with his MQM leader Altaaf Hussain, answering a question the Vice President said that Rahman Malik went to London on his permission.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090114.0020" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Qwetta, with the DSP four police members killed</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">File photo</seg>
    <seg id="3">On Qwettta's one important Shah Rah Saryab Road by the unknown persons firing with one DSP 'Deputy Superintendent of Police' four police members were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Wednesday Morning in 1 jeep 2 DSP, 1 Sub Inspector and 2 Constable were on the way to Police Training Center, on Sariab Road near Degree College an unknown rider on motor cycle has attacked on police jeep and was firing continuously, in this attack Sub Inspector Mehdi and Constable Sibgat ul llah and nasr ul llah has died on spot but 1 DSP Hasan Ali has died after reaching hospital</seg>
    <seg id="5">From Source of Hospital they said that the second DSP Ghulam Mohammed is very serious as he is severely injured and he got a bullet shot in his head and Neck</seg>
    <seg id="6">After this incident police has besiege that area, till now no one has accepted the Responsibility of this Attack</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090116.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">In America one more Indian Software Engineer has been murdered</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In America an unknown person has killed a software engineer who belongs to Andhra Pradesh</seg>
    <seg id="3">2 days before an unknown person has bullet shot to Akshya Vishal who is 26 Years old and he belongs to Andhra Pradesh, and in hospital while under Treatment Vishal has died</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was an Employee of Satyam Computers and in America he was working with Falcon Jet Airways</seg>
    <seg id="5">Last Year from Andhra Pradesh there were 7 students who were killed in non society elements in America</seg>
    <seg id="6">The Students who are going for higher education and employment to America has been murdered so the Family, Friends and Relatives are Concerned about there children who are Residing in America</seg>
    <seg id="7">To clarify that for higher studies and for better future in Andhra Pradesh they prefer America</seg>
    <seg id="8">According to the statistics of American consulate in Chennai, 100,000 American visa applications are received from India, from which the majority i.e. 40% is from Andra Pardes.</seg>
    <seg id="9">During this time, the provincial government started trying to bring the dead body of the deceased to Hyderabad.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090117.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">America should stay alert for Enemy's attack: Bush.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">President Bush has insisted America on being alert for enemy's attack in his last weekly speech on radio.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Mr. Bush has that even today, America's biggest threat is another attack from the terrorists. He has warned that enemies of the country are waiting patiently and are ready to attack again.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Retiring president has said that America should never be ignorant of its safety.</seg>
    <seg id="5">President Bush has also expressed best wishes for the next President Barrack Obama, who will take his oath on Tuesday.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Newly elected President Barrack Obama shed light on the historical importance of his oath taking ceremony in his speech on radio on Saturday.</seg>
    <seg id="7">He said that this ceremony is a tradition in which transfer of the power from one leader to another in a peaceful way is also highly related to the American greatness.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mr. Obama reminded that in the entire world, there are many who can not even imagine that their leaders will retire from their positions without violence and shedding of blood.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090118.0002" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Meeting between sharifs and interior minister. Political and security affairs discussed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">In Raiwind, a meeting held between the interior minister Rehman malik and Nawaz sharif, head of PMLN; the largest opposition party in center and ruling party in punjab. The CM, Shehbaz sharif was also present in the meeting.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to local media, Rehman Malik has brought some message from top PPP leadership.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Howver, Rehmand Malik did not give an detail in press. He told the media that national affairs were discussed during the meeting and he briefed the PMLN leadership about the post Mumbai attacks situation.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words: "he briefed about all the steps taken"</seg>
    <seg id="6">one should not forget the most lethal terrorism occurred in Punjab and PMLN is ruling Party in Punjab. And my established team needs the cooperation of the government of Punjab.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to Rehman Malik, media is not briefed but messages are exchanged with the Leadership on daily basis. Pervaiz Rashid Mir, the representative of PMLN was very cautious to disclose any thing. He said, "rehman malik has told what is required to be told"</seg>
    <seg id="8">This meeting held when the political temperature is on rise in Punjab. The major cause of this rise is the joint conference of Governor punjab Salman Taseer and more than 20 Nazims of PMLQ. The policies of Punjab Govt came under criticism during this press conference.PMLN has rejected the allegations and criticized the Governor's participation in the press conference.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090121.0017" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Obama's speech is a good news for Pakistan, Zardari</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">President of Pakistan welcome the Obama's speech and said that American intent to have a respectful a balanced relationships with Muslim world is a good news for Pakistan and its people</seg>
    <seg id="3">in a statement issued on Wednesday, he said that reiteration of high moralities and values from the American president is a hope for a better future for the people of the world.</seg>
    <seg id="4">president Zardari stated that there is no doubt that there is a great pressure on America to join the world community to find ways of peace, prosperity and complacency.</seg>
    <seg id="5">it should be clear that president Obama after taking the oath for his designation said on Tuesday in his opening speech that  America wants development in relations with the Islamic world which should be based on mutual benefits and respect for each other.</seg>
    <seg id="6">he told the people of poor countries that America will work with them so that there is social development and reduction poverty.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">President Obama nominated a special representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">former ambassador for United Nations Richard Holbrooke has been nominated as a special representative for Pakistan and Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">Holbrooke played a vital role in peace agreements in Bosnia Herzegovina.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Holbrooke said that he is ready to be an advisor to president Obama on Afghanistan and Pakistan issues.</seg>
    <seg id="5">He clearly said that this is not an easy task.</seg>
    <seg id="6">He said that both countries have entirely different history.</seg>
    <seg id="7">George Mitchell was chosen for the Middle East, who will try to blow life into Arab Israeli peace discussions.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Mitchell is an ex-senator and he has played a role in establishing peace in Ireland.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Speaking in the State Department today, Mitchell said that the Middle East situation is unstable, confusing and dangerous.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Nevertheless, America will not step back on efforts to establish peace over there.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090122.0022" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Afghanistan: Voter registration in danger.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The Afghanistan Election Commission has said that due to a doubt in safety, it is delaying the voter registration in some of the southern regions.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The voter registration for the upcoming presidential elections had started this week in South Afghanistan.</seg>
    <seg id="4">But the commission has declared that as long as the security conditions do not improve, the voters in some parts of Halmand state will not be able to register themselves.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Extremism has been on the rise in those regions of the south, where Taliban rebels have increased attacks on Afghani and international governments.</seg>
    <seg id="6">In the meanwhile, the Afghani army and the international armies are claiming that during the night between Wednesday and Thursday, during small fights, they killed at least 28 soldiers.</seg>
    <seg id="7">NATO has said that their army has destroyed 22 fighters during air and land attacks on Eastern province Khost near the border of Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Before that, Afghan Ministry of Defense stated that in the same province, Afghan army killed 8 rebels and injured two.</seg>
    <seg id="9">It is not clear whether Afghan officials have mentioned the same incident.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090123.0014" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Two missile attacks in Waziristan, at least 18 people killed.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Pakistan authority has said that at least 18 are dead in the 2 ambiguous American missile attacks in the North Waziristan.</seg>
    <seg id="3">According to the officials, American jet fired three missiles near a house in the area Mir Ali of north Waziristan, killing 10 people in that house.</seg>
    <seg id="4">according to the local officials, there were 5 foreign fighters in those who were killed.</seg>
    <seg id="5">This area is considered the center of the Taliban and Alqaida's fighters.</seg>
    <seg id="6">After a few hours of this incident, southern waziristan was also attacked with a missile, in which at least 8 people died.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Apart from disagreement of Pakistani government, after the mid of the last year, there have been almost 30 missile attacks in Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">The attacks in these days are not after the American president Prak Obama in control.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Bush management has been abstain from accepting or rejecting these attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="10">In tribal areas of Pakistan Wazeerastan, three mezayles were placed by suspected American spy aeroplane ata Friday in which 5 men dead in this report.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The dead persons have not been acquainted yet.</seg>
    <seg id="12">According to primary knowings these mezile attacks were under taken at the house in Meer Ali area.</seg>
    <seg id="13">It should be in mind that that was the first attack after the being Brak Obama the president.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090125.0005" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Province Sarhad government rejected the question of ban on girls education.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Province Sarhad rejected the threat by Taliban soldiers in Swat by saying that this announcement is against law and Islam.</seg>
    <seg id="3">The education prime minister of province Sarhad Sardar Hussain Babur said more that the government will not made these efforts possible.</seg>
    <seg id="4">His saying is that the extremists want that the children in our areas left free from education.</seg>
    <seg id="5">In his words: "These people try to secretly blow up schools and frighten the boys and girls"</seg>
    <seg id="6">Talking about the environment of fear and insecurity, he said that the local government knows well and wants it to be known that no force can stop the spread of education in the land of the Pukhtons.</seg>
    <seg id="7">One day ago, the Taliban soldiers, led by Moulana Fazlullah had demanded the banning of girls from studying in Swat's educational institutions from the 15th of January.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Despite the military activity going on in Swat, during the last one and a half years, about 150 educational institutions were destroyed by the militants by the use of explosives and arson.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Due to the destruction of these educational institutions, thousands of girls and boys were deprived of the facility of education.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0003" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Strict security arrangements in India on Republic Day.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">The 60th Republic Day is being celebrated in India on Monday. On this occasion, strict security measures are being taken and thousands of soldiers were posted throughout the country.</seg>
    <seg id="3">On the occcasion of Republic Day, during the army parade in New Delhi, weapons, planes and other military equipment is displayed.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Officials are saying that the security arrangements include anti aircraft missiles and sharpshooters and that police will be deployed to watch the roads of the parade. American President Barack Obama congratulated India on the occasion.</seg>
    <seg id="5">And he also wished Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, who had undergone a heart operation on Saturday, a speedy recovery.</seg>
    <seg id="6">Please note that yesterday Indian police had claimed to kill two suspected Pakistani fighters near New Delhi after an encounter.</seg>
    <seg id="7">According to local government police had recovered AK47 rifles, grenade an some papers from both persons. Which indicates that they were probably from Pakistan.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Police is also investigating this matter that whether these two persons belong to the banned organization 'Lashkar-e-Taiba' which was involved in last November year's Mumbai attacks.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090126.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Tea: A good cure for breast cancer</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">According to a new research, drinking three cups of tea every day</seg>
    <seg id="3">the chances of breast cancer is reduced by more then one third  in women less then 50 years old.</seg>
    <seg id="4">In a research conducted in MOFT center of Florida America, it has been told that women with less then 50 years age that have breast cancel onco</seg>
    <seg id="5">gets the chances of breast cancer reduced by 37 percent who drink tea three cups a day.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The research shows that the aged women dont get any effect from drinking three or more cups of tea a day.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The researchers think that the tea contains such elements that are effective against the special type of onco in the breast cancer (that effect the women younger then 50 years age)</seg>
    <seg id="8">In Moffitt Cancer Center, in the city of Tampa, Florida state, a research was conducted on over 5000 women, who had undergone treatment for breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Their ages were between 20 and 74 years.</seg>
    <seg id="10">Experts compared their medical records and lifestyles with women who were safe from breast cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="11">The experts also found out that on a specific type of cancer called lobular cancer, the drinking of tea has shown clear effects, and has decreased its occurrence by 66 percent.</seg>
    <seg id="12">A tenth of every breast cancer patient suffers this type of cancer.</seg>
    <seg id="13">This type of cancer is more dangerous because it is deeper and is usually only known after it spreads quite a bit.</seg>
    <seg id="14">Experts say that regular tea consumption, at least three cups a day, can drastically reduce the occurrence of breast cancer in young women.</seg>
    <seg id="15">They say that making tea a regular beverage taken on a daily basis and included in ones daily activities causes the suitable defense required against cancer in the body.</seg>
    <seg id="16">In Britain, every year, approximately 40,000 women are diagnosed with breast cancer.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090127.0008" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">The biggest military challenge facing the American war in Afghanistan is gas.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">American Defence Minister Robert Gates has said that the biggest  Military challenge to America is  the war in Afghanistan</seg>
    <seg id="3">Gates is today giving a briefing to American Senate and representatives of the Congress on the Obama Administrations policy on Afghanistan and Iraq wars.</seg>
    <seg id="4">Gates told the Armed Services Senate Committee that the war is not the only solution to Afghan problem but he further said that in order to make many areas secure, Army Personal are not available,taking the advantage of it the Taliban carry out actions.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090129.0012" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">Why reduction in exercise with increase in the age</seg>
     <seg id="2">New Research</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="3">Exercise is good for health in every age</seg>
    <seg id="4">This keeps the heart healthy,reduces the level of cholesterol,Helps in keeping the weight low, helps in reduction of sugar and reduces Alzheimer meaning decreases the speed of dementia.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Unfortunately, in many people with the increase in the age, the capability to carryout exercise also decreases.</seg>
    <seg id="6">The specialists say that with exercise our body and brain remain active but age can have effect on it.</seg>
    <seg id="7">The American Medical Association says that Many health problems can occur if exercise is not carried out.</seg>
    <seg id="8">Doctor Patrisha Pae Leka of the Meo Clinic in Mani Sotta says that the reason for the addition in the age is from inability of exercise and less functionality in the body.</seg>
    <seg id="9">Doctor Patrisha teaches medicine in the Meo Clinic.</seg>
    <seg id="10">She did the research on the heart illnesses in old age people and the the benefits of doing exercises.</seg>
    <seg id="11">A team of doctors used the high frequency layers of sound to test the functioning of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="12">In which they studied the work of blood pump in the heart, its squeezes and the resting of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="13">The experts had given full attention on the left side of the heart which is the important part where the blood is pumped.</seg>
    <seg id="14">They came to know that with the growing age the grievousness is added in the respiration work of the heart.</seg>
    <seg id="15">Doctor Patrisha says that with the growing age the grievousness is added in the respiration work of the heart and with the growing age the effect grows with the exercise.</seg>
    <seg id="16">Doctor Garven Ken was included in this study.</seg>
    <seg id="17">They say that we were surprised to see that this thing is effected necessarily and with this it has been clear that bad exercise functionality has an affect on the heart's respiration work.</seg>
    <seg id="18">Blood Pressure can cause a cardiovascular diseases and dysfunction.</seg>
    <seg id="19">If Doctor and Patient cooperate each other then exercise can be beneficial even in old age.</seg>
    <seg id="20">A detailed report has been published in the Journal of American Medical Association.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="VOA_URD_20090131.0013" genre="nw">
   <hl>
     <seg id="1">There are no chances of War with Pakistan in near future, Indian Army Chief.</seg>
   </hl>
    <seg id="2">Indian Army chief Gen. Depak Kapoor said that there is a fat chance of war with Pakistan. "However, we are ready to protect our national interests at any cost", he said</seg>
    <seg id="3">General kapoor blames that despite international pressure terrorists' network still exists and active on Pakistani soil.</seg>
    <seg id="4">He was talking with journalists in Sri Nagar.</seg>
    <seg id="5">Indian Army Chief is on one day visit to Kashmir Valley to observe the  activities of Armed forces on the boundaries.</seg>
    <seg id="6">When he was asked to comment about the Pakistan's rejection of Indian proofs about Mumbai Attacks.</seg>
    <seg id="7">Gen. kapoor said that political leadership is responsible to deal with issues relevant to peace or war</seg>
    <seg id="8">Commonly  there are many structures of riots and protests  on the land of Pakistan. He has also reported that there would be tremendous battle between India and Pakistan. Pakistan has aimed to weaken the Indian Army.</seg>
    <seg id="9">He has also reported that there are about 700-800 army men on the land of Kashmir out of which about 50% of the army men are non-country men.</seg>
    <seg id="10">General Deepak Kapoor has reported that there is some improvement in the K.I.K atmosphere. he has also said that he has increased that Pakistan has increased the efforts of battle on the Pakistan Dependent Kashmir. therefore we have increased the Army camps at the Indian borders.</seg>
    <seg id="11">He has also reported that he has increased the number of army in the India Dependent Kashmir. He has clearly mentioned from the symptoms that there cannot be any compromise with regard to the protection of the country.</seg>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post123" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Oh God, Please accept our prayers. Please prove Barack Obama to be good for this world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is evident from the present situation that there are very less chances of getting a positive response, but still we will wait and see to what extent the Pakistan-American Relationship changes and what benefit it can give to us.</seg>
     <seg id="3">what inspiration does Mr.K Barack gives to this world with regard to the inspiration and aims of the King Martin Luther.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post124" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Obama whose part of the name is also Hussein is going to take the oath as an American Leader.He is going to be a protector of the country and the History. This is an exam for the American history.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Not only for the sake of their community but also for all those who have supported him with their heart and soul.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This test will happen on the extreme white paper.it is not easy for him to write on the blue paper whole-heartedly that he would rule the country with justice.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Here, South Asia, specially Muslims who have expectations from them, should remember that he has been elected as the president of America. And Obama should remember that President of America is actually the President of the entire world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post93" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After a moment, a man whose brothers and sisters from his generation were brought to America from their countries as slaves and whose sweat and blood have strengthened the roots of the most powerful country of the new era, today a representative of this racially discrete nation will be called the 40th President of this very America.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have expectations from this one man.</seg>
     <seg id="3">People who love him, have to have unreal expectations from him.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If Obama succeeds to an extent in reducing the hatred among races and religion in the world, so this will be a win for people who love him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516101-post94" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What will be its effect on South Asia and can a meaningful change be expected in the American policy regarding this matter?</seg>
     <seg id="2">How will this change effect the relationship between America and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4">Dear, whether it is Obama or some one else, the decision of the policy of the entire world is done by Jews lobby of  billionaires, influencing, powerful and effective people.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And as far as Pakistan is concerned, after the series of recent Bombay blasts,the offensive reaction of India, America and Israel is in front of everyone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post18" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the creation of Pakistan, the administration of Swat remained with the Ruler of Swat, who had a regular Army and Law.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He handed over administration of Swat to Pakistan under a  pact</seg>
     <seg id="3">but it is matter of sorrow that our government treated Swat like a step mother.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There was no increase in the number of schools after the end of the government of the ruler of Swat.</seg>
     <seg id="5">and no interest was taken in the building and development works</seg>
     <seg id="6">The girls who are getting education today are much lesser in number than  those who used to get educated in the previous era.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Frontier Province, there is a continuous targeting of educational institutions by Taliban's.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The maximum number of schools have been destroyed in district Swat in which majority are the girls schools.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is not just this, the Taliban has imposed a ban on girl education.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thousands of male and female students have been deprived from getting education.</seg>
     <seg id="5">what do you think what are the objectives of Taliban to end women education ?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Why Government is unable to stop these unlawful act.</seg>
     <seg id="7">what do you think what Government should do</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">question is that what are the benefits for ISI and Pakistani Agencies.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, people of Swat can understand the game that Military is there to support Taliban not to kill them because how is this possible that in karfuo 5 schools were exploded and people were slaughter and where hanged at the road</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post37" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When there is no Authority of Government left than how come government can stop these unlawful acts?</seg>
     <seg id="2">now question arises that with all the advance technology, destructive weapons, and an effective spy system why these Taliban are still not in control ?</seg>
     <seg id="3">the answer is that there is hand  on them of some secret Power thats why there weapons never ended and they are never arrested</seg>
     <seg id="4">the conclusion is that Taliban with there deeds making the work easier for World Power</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516103-post40" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">war in Afghanistan is  going from past 15 years</seg>
     <seg id="2">ISI is controlling Taliban when at that time opponent was north coalition who was supported by Russia, India and Iran.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Then suddenly situation changed, actions of Taliban began to appear.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And ISI was also offered Dollars from America so past friends became enemies.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now situation is this that war continues but helping in Pakistan are still those Iran, India and Russia.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Unless this feeling does not emerge in Human that what is right and wrong till then Human will keep doing mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As an example a thief when goes to steal if he at that time gets this thought that stealing is not a good thing and theft is a curse, there is also punishment in it and he fears from God then that Human will not steal.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Same like this that unless Israel do not gets this apprehension that i am doing wrong and draining blood of innocents and i will get punishment for this, he will keep playing Holi with the blood innocents of Gaza till then.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Respects!</seg>
     <seg id="2">Question is that is war, armed movement, terrorism is solution to problems?</seg>
     <seg id="3">If not then what is the specific prescription which takes to the solution of the problems?</seg>
     <seg id="4">It is right that the war is the way that does not solve the problem but make it more difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Falastin,Afghanistan and Iraq should adopt the way which adopted Nalis Mandaila in South Africa to make their movements success.</seg>
     <seg id="6">That mean there should be behaver and politics efforts in more then force.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The participating of Kashmirian public in election tells that they accepted this view.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The third week is continue of Israel attacks on Ghaza and dead persons are about 1000.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The war could not stopped until this time with world ambassador efforts.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And according to a guess 9000 Falatinis have been left their homes and gone to save places after the attacks  starting in December.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And here helpful institutions blamed Israel that he did not care the Falastini children and there will be one total posterity in hard mental and emotional problems.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is it should be?</seg>
     <seg id="7">how could it long term peace possible in Gaza?</seg>
     <seg id="8">for detail click here.</seg>
     <seg id="9">kindly note that due to increase in comments only Urdu written suggestions will publish.</seg>
     <seg id="10">for that while pressing Alt+Shift select Urdu.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">give a chance to Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Basit, Peshawar.</seg>
     <seg id="3">wake up if Taliban will do real Jihad so who sacrifice innocent people.</seg>
     <seg id="4">who burnt out Girls School?</seg>
     <seg id="5">and if kidnap for ransom or not get ransom so who will hang people on the pole by called them American spy?</seg>
     <seg id="6">those Taliban give very damage to Islam that no other nation or religion have done.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Pashtoon roar</seg>
     <seg id="8">Kohat Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post28" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If all Muslim world attack Israel or just give a threat to do so then see how painful this for America, the God Father of Israel</seg>
     <seg id="2">Then a true seize fire will be observed</seg>
     <seg id="3">But what shoud we do about the cowardice of Muslim rulers.</seg>
     <seg id="4">someone should ask the Ahmadi Nejad to become the first to attack as he is popular for his bravery.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516107-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Struggle for Peace and human rights is not the solo responsibility of Arabs or Muslim world. It is the duty of whole world to raise voice against cruelty.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This sad incident the worst crime committed by Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In India and Pakistan, the financial corruption becomes higher at the end of fiscal year, similarly Bush administration has permitted the Israel to do what she wants</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">On one hand America demands the seize fire</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand, the United Nations is passing resolution after resolution, but action-wise, neither have done anything. There is only one meaning of this, and that is that the even the United Nations is openly in favor of destroying the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All Muslim countries should immediately end their membership in the United Nations, and should establish their own global organisation.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We have many examples of where only promises and resolutions of America and the United Nations are seen, but the harm is only done to the Muslims.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What is the use of these vain efforts if BBC does not want to publish anything?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Where have all the rules of journalism been buried? When blood, specifically of Muslims, is spilled, the monster of unbiasedness gets onto BBC's back.</seg>
     <seg id="3">which considers itself the standard bearer of truth.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Forget about breaking something on its own, the height of heartlessness is that it does not even publish comments</seg>
     <seg id="5">from Muslims</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post211" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The only difference between you and the Jews is that they call themselves Jews and martyr the Muslims, and the likes of you stay among Muslims, call yourselves Muslims and cause Muslims..</seg>
     <seg id="2">[syja786]</seg>
     <seg id="3">For a long time on BBC forums, sometimes suicide bombing and other times terrorism in India was used to target a certain sect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The favorite word of these Anti-Islamic discussions was Extremism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You can get a very good idea, about who an extremist is, from the above discussion in which, writing against Iran was almost considered blasphemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post213" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When will our muslims understand that Anti Christ can not be fought with swords.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Looking at unarmed people in the bombing of Israel, what shall one do other than crying?</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the basic fault is of this turmoil and massacre which by naming Jihad, we try to blacken the beautiful face of Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When majority of Palestinians accepted the existence of Israel then why did Hammas need to fire those rockets on Israel and made suicide attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Attitude of the both the sides is against humanity.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The role of UN and the USA was again seen as favoring towards the injustice of Israel.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post214" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May Allah give muslim nation the understanding of becoming  united. Ameen!</seg>
     <seg id="2">As a matter of fact,think about giving Noble Prise to terrorists for carrying out this painful terrorist activity, as a campaign against terrorism, eventually the actual work is being done by them.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Otherwise, is it possible to carryout terrorist activity on such a massive scale without the assistance of Chiefs and  every one knows who are pulling their strings.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In such a situation it can be termed as high handedness "Do what ever you can".</seg>
     <seg id="5">The strong mans fist,it beats over the head and do not let one cry.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post215" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Arab rulers are giving medicines for the injured,Funeral clothing's for the dead and money and they are asking</seg>
     <seg id="2">should the Israelis continue attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="3">The actual problem is that the rulers of Islamic countries including Saudi Arabia are dreaming undutiful while asleep,Neither they have army nor they have defence plans,they just think that by providing aid they have done their duty.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They should immediately take practical steps against the Israel</seg>
     <seg id="5">like cutting of oil supply to European countries and America, but sorry for them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post217" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Regards to all brothers and sisters</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think asking Hamas to give up their struggle for the sake of peace is unfair to millions of widows and orphans. It is similar to prove them unsuccessful.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If the  Pharaoh-ism of US and Israel is on rise then Moses will come to counter them because every Pharaoh has a Moses.The American and Israelis actions are producing suicide bombers among Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Power has abandoned their ability to think and understand.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Abu Abdullah, Pakistan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post230" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now Hamas and Israel should seize fire to stop bloodshed.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Mohammad Sarfraz, Paris, France</seg>
     <seg id="3">rightly said</seg>
     <seg id="4">Suppose Hamas is on right path and struggling against cruelty for the sake of God's will; they should know that an act of goodness does not remain good if it causes harms to others.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Love for humanity is the precondition for God and his prophet's love.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It seems God has asked to annihilate all others than Muslims</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeeb-ur-Rahman Psycho *Lahore* [Pakian]</seg>
     <seg id="3">No! It is not decreed to annihilate but it is decreed to invite people to Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But people who do conspiracies against the religion, it is decreed to do Jihad against them.</seg>
     <seg id="5">One should fight with them until they finish their conspiracies. But this certainly does not mean that they can wear a jacket and blow up in a crowd.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post39" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Brothers, the consequence of a murderer of children is disaster.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But its a request to my friends that yesterday Israelis did not have a roof over their heads and today they are so strong that they do not listen to anyone because all Jews are one.</seg>
     <seg id="3">They do not have Shiite nor Sunni, all are just Jews. And they have succeeded in every field and made everything.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Opposite to this, what is the condition of 55 Islamic Countries?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Lagging in every field and now the condition is this that they are so helpless that enemies are killing them and they are waiting for their death.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Point required is that all Muslim countries should get together and should make a plan against Israel.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Feroz Magsi, Jhang, Pakistan</seg>
     <seg id="3">And there is no better action plan than this, to accept Israel and to learn modern science and developmental ways from it, and allow the world to live in peace and calm.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Muslims have a lot of land and resources.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The need is for proper utilisation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post59" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">First, the part that hurts the most is that there could not be unity between Hamas and Al-Fath.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Great leader like Yasir Arafat and Sheikh Yasin were systematically killed to weaken the brave nation of the only region which is still fighting for Masjid Aqsa, and this was not possible as long as Yasin and Arafat were in the way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The world is watching how Palestine is getting scattered, second by second, after the death of these two leaders.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And how the Jewish lobby is increasing its reach, second by second.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516120-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In 1974, Pakistan had a Prime Minister of such global credentials that for the first time in the history of the country, he gathered all the Muslims leaders, with a 100% attendance, under a single roof.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today on his 81st birth anniversary, is it a very difficult task for the people to pledge to keep unity, not only within their ranks,</seg>
     <seg id="3">also, while eradicating the differences between other Muslims,  its (The formation of Islamic common wealth) mission will be carried forward</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">its a monster that has gripped Palestine for half a century.</seg>
     <seg id="2">this monster has many faces.</seg>
     <seg id="3">many times this monster criticizes itself from its own but different mouth to divert the pressure and attention of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and its other mouths are eating humans in Iraq, Afghanistan, Iran and Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">this monster is most unhappy with Islam because it knows that whenever it will be kicked out that will be through Islam, Muslims, the perfect religion of Muslim and Practical Islam as the history tells that Islam has put giants like Abu Jehl on the right path.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">bombing from Israeli fighter planes on Gaza has continued  since 27th of December.</seg>
     <seg id="2">more that 3 hundred Palestinians have been killed in these attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="3">after the Arial attacks, Israeli tanks and armed vehicles have reached the Gaza border with complete preparation for a ground attack.</seg>
     <seg id="4">through a unanimous resolution in an emergency meeting of the security council, the United Nations has demanded Israel and the Palestinian authorities to ceasefire.</seg>
     <seg id="5">However, Israeli officials claim that they will continue their action in Gaza until they are convinced that Israel will be safe from rocket attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In your opinion, is the statement by Israel, that this is an Israeli struggle for safety, acceptable?</seg>
     <seg id="7">In this situation, is the global brotherhood doing its job?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Can this inhumane action have a direct relation with the upcoming elections in Israel?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Can there be any expectation of improvement in the Middle East situation, after newly elected president Barack Obama takes office?</seg>
     <seg id="10">(Please note that due to an increase in the number of comments, only comments typed in Urdu will be published.</seg>
     <seg id="11">For this, hit Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard and select Urdu.)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Palestine is a holy land for the Muslims, all over the world, and protecting it is a necessary duty for us.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We should also remember that it was our first Qiblah.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And Israel, America and India have to disappear one day, as they are made only to be destroyed, and Allah will definitely destroy the disbelievers. Sajid Sadiq, Lahore.</seg>
     <seg id="4">"when the night of loneliness can be passed by tearing down</seg>
     <seg id="5">when an affliction can be avoided with only prayers" (Nawabzadah Nasrullah Khan)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post27" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC publishes these kind of comments after deep search.</seg>
     <seg id="2">after all a neutral impression is to be maintained.</seg>
     <seg id="3">although the news from BBC are usually correct but the real thing is the style of the news.</seg>
     <seg id="4">what should be pointed out and what news should be given less importance.</seg>
     <seg id="5">etc. etc.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="7">in this art now a days the Pakistani electronic and print media, specially some Urdu newspapers and columnists are no more behind anyone, who cheat in the coverage of the increasing extremism and terrorism or in the "grudge of Muavia" written on them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post29" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">has said that the United Nations which apparently talks of Human rights and peace, but when it comes to grimness and coercion over Muslims the only words coming out of its mouth are that Hamas should stop the attacks. how long this hypocrisy will continue.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why is so much oppression being done on the Muslims? If people such as America stop supporting these Jews, then Allah has declared that they will live the life of a disgraced people, and such people can never lead a proper life. So if the Americans have courage, let them stop their support, and then see what kind of life they get.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post45" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The famous just people of the world and those that kill people in the name of peace should understand that peace will only be prevalent through administering justice, and not by being unjust and killing people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If any tribe could be finished by killing their people, and if the required results could be obtained, then after Hitler's steps, not only the presence but the rise that the Jews are enjoying today, could not have been possible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the words of a poet</seg>
     <seg id="4">Oppression is oppression, that the more it's done the more it is erased.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Blood is blood, that the more it falls, the more it gathers.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post49" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Now who can tell who did terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Is all this not included in terrorism? Why does everybody worry only about their own pain?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are others not human? Or is it that the blood of Muslims has become so cheap? Was the blood of this many innocent not red?</seg>
     <seg id="4">And why is there no one to send a mourning message from anywhere?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I saw Bombay blasts operation like this fire was in my own house. Can not see the sorrow of mankind. And can anyone not see this sorrow? Alas if Muslims would think as one.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Dead bodies on the road, helpless injured and innocent faces soaked in blood, how shall we condemn, I can not find words!</seg>
     <seg id="2">I feel like crying over the helplessness of the Muslims that on one side people are being killed in India so the rest of the world comes over Pakistan without any proof and asks to perform operations otherwise we will do it ourselves!</seg>
     <seg id="3">And on the other side, Israel is killing generations of muslims in front of everyone and the world is silent. This is unbearable!</seg>
     <seg id="4">There is delay but not NEVER in the house of God and only then will this darkness shed. Then</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516125-post95" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the presence of America, danger to the integrity of Israel is a joke.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Considering elections, the rulers should do such activities for people's support. There is no doubt in this specially when countries like Israel exist. Rest talking about Barrack Obama, then history is the witness that no American leader has gone against the policy and nor will do it. Regime, whether black or white, is a regime.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516128-post30" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The debate going on in the forum makes it clear that every one is sad on Benazir's death but as a politician, one can not ignore her mistakes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">This talk requires debate that whether Benazir gave her life for democracy or for power.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If democracy was so dear then  why was it left in 10 year dictatorship of Musharaf until American clearance and the deal.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Benazir did not come to Pakistan when people affected by dictatorship needed her. Unfortunately she came to Pakistan when she assured about government and that she will be freed from trails.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post17" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no one remaining to say about the criticism and accusations of a historical personality.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="3">Somethings should be ignored because nothing can be done about them.</seg>
     <seg id="4">One more reader</seg>
     <seg id="5">Ladies and gentlemen probably you will understand My Syco because you have not only read history of Pakistan  but you have also read about Sir in 4 friendly countries and 7 others</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tariq Ayaz</seg>
     <seg id="7">Neither was given nature that can be improved with education</seg>
     <seg id="8">Remain green in water</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post26" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">England did not let them come close and created Hindu-Muslim conflict that was pampered by Sir Syed</seg>
     <seg id="2">Psycho</seg>
     <seg id="3">How bloody is our Nation and in our parties excitement while writing the Epode they will be blind but now every historic people is trying to pinpoint an accusation and criticize the judious, but on this there is no one is tell any thing</seg>
     <seg id="4">We people have achieved lot of success</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sana Khan</seg>
     <seg id="6">Few things can be avoided by thinking that nothing can be done for this in the same way as if we put books on donkey he will not become a professor</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post34" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If after the attack on Mumbai, if there is a problem got created between Pakistan and India in there regular activities but still India and Pakistan has to continue there regular activities</seg>
     <seg id="2">If we talk about War then at the both end there will be a loss of human being</seg>
     <seg id="3">India is telling that the person got arrested at the time of Mumbai attack is a Pakistan citizen and he has written a letter in Urdu and sent to Pakistan, but the other end India has first said after arresting him that he is a big Engineer but after that they have proved that he is just 4th standard Pass, point to be observed</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">first of all to Mr bhana and all western friends of this forum  a happy Christmas</seg>
     <seg id="2">Colleagues of the forum: Mr psycho, a raza, sister sana, sister shahedah akram and to all Adaab (salaam, greeting)</seg>
     <seg id="3">We do not want the flames of war, we want the flowers of peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">War is in itself, a problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">What problems can war solve?</seg>
     <seg id="6">It will give fire and blood today.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It will give hunger and need tomorrow.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Therefore, O intelligent people,</seg>
     <seg id="9">If war keeps getting postponed, it's better.</seg>
     <seg id="10">In your and our porch,</seg>
     <seg id="11">If the candle keeps burning, it's better.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Indo-American relations have now gotten quite deep, and India knows with certainty, that America will openly betray Pakistan, when the time comes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">this is also the old history of America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">in case of and Indian attack, America would get its goals and the expense would be on India as well.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan should make a clear statement that we shall not attack first but if we are invaded then there will be no peace, reconciliation and ceasefire until India is completely destroyed or occupied even if we ourselves get destroyed in doing so.</seg>
     <seg id="5">this is the Islamic history.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516135-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">even before this resolution the Pakistani public and army had given the message that they wanted to give.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Indian efforts for achieving diplomatic and military benefits as a ransom for the Mumbai attacks are making it more clever that effected and that is why in contrast to the initial strict reaction the world community has relaxed its pressure now.</seg>
     <seg id="3">while ignoring India's unnecessary bobbery, the satisfaction of the United Nations and the appreciation from the Interpol chief over Pakistan's efforts is a "Side Effect" of India's overwhelming diplomacy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post137" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">there are no two opinions over this that it is a heinous act.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But the question is that when thousands of Taliban attacked the house of Pir Samiullah, where and what was the Pakistani army doing at that time?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Should the army not be accountable for what they have done over the past one year?</seg>
     <seg id="4">How many Taliban are killed by the thousands of shells fired by mortars and cannons everyday?</seg>
     <seg id="5">I appeal to the I.S.I that for God's sake, stop monitoring the Taliban and let us live in peace in our heavenly hometown Sawat.</seg>
     <seg id="6">And stop this phony operation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post139" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">That day is not far when a resolution about Pakistan's military intervention will be passed by United Nations just like the bill which was passed against Jamat-ud-Dawah.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Riaz Ahmad Farooqi</seg>
     <seg id="3">The extremists of our country and their supporters themselves are constantly providing all evidences and justifications required for instigation of action against them, and God forbid, the day when such a resolution is passed, in all likelihood not a single voice would be raised in United Nations, in our favour.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And supposing there is a delay in the enactment of this resolution, then considering the example of America, a superpower will come forward to take over on its own resources.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post144" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We are not aware and familiar with the character and achievements of Pir Sami-ullah and what his activities were.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Maybe he was not a revolutionist.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Like the deadbodies of Comrade Che Guevara, Nawab Akbar Khan Bugti, Doctor Najeebullah and thousands of other revolutionists have been subjected to dishonour at the hands of the enemy.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are immortal even after they die.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But there is a international game being played here in which place public is ruled by frightening through barbarism and ferociousness.</seg>
     <seg id="6">So that license can be created that if we are not here than these ferocious and barbaric will clutch the government.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post161" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These acts of so called Islamic activists on the name of religion is without limit worthy of condemnation.</seg>
     <seg id="2">These supporters of extremists can see the injustice of America but instead of expressing grieve on those dishonest acts they clearly shun them by giving them name of tribal traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Sometimes by cloaking in tribal traditions, sometimes on the name of Islam, any pious man cannot give reason for such dishonest acts.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post164" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my view, our Army people are associated with theses people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">As such that when these people move from a place then it takes such time that they can be caught, there should be time for that but its a stretch that they get there on time even if they are there, they are long gone.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Are they so merciless that they kidnap fifty seventy men and our Army putting hand on hand looks at them like a spectator.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They are servant of Allah and  so is Army.</seg>
     <seg id="5">All in seeing that there is something wrong at the bottom.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post52" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malaiat, In the period of The dictator of the time Zia-u-Lhaq he did not show good characteristics of sympathies of Allah but there is various tortures at the name of religion and more it his writing "What will be done after death."</seg>
     <seg id="2">And such persons use this fright as a way to get only this world respect.</seg>
     <seg id="3">O Speakers                                                                                                                                                              "preachers"</seg>
     <seg id="4">You frightened the world form fire of Hell.</seg>
     <seg id="5">That you became the image of fright.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Upon it wondered that when it is said that it cannot be a Muslim action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We are ourself do not know this history or cover it for any purpose.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
     <seg id="5">was the attack of Yazid's forces on Medina not the act of Christians and the Jews?</seg>
     <seg id="6">without accepting reality neither the motives can be diminished nor correction can be made.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post60" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">O' BBC please stop this dual-headed policy.</seg>
     <seg id="2">better than this topic the super hit title: Shoe-ing of Bush fair or unfair?</seg>
     <seg id="3">'should have been</seg>
     <seg id="4">Tahir Choudhry, Japan</seg>
     <seg id="5">please show some modesty, a human pulled out of his grave and hanged over a pole just because he raised his voice against the oppression, and you are concerned about the topic of the box office.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post73" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the success of, operation Sherdil and across the border operation Lion heart, depends on the fact that in whose favor is the opinion of general public.</seg>
     <seg id="2">this act is of American and Pakistani agencies and Peer Sahab is a victim of this conspiracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">all discussions on this forum will now be anti Taliban since the secret agents have successfully joined Taliban and they are doing what can change the public opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post77" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I would like to ask only this. What were the soldiers doing when the corpse was kept hanging throughout a day? were they sitting there to aim only the common people? It is said that Taliban hideouts were bombed and a woman and two kids were killed when a house was attacked.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Why? Didn't they come to know about this great tragedy?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Were they leisurely having fun, or not?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Let us fold our hands to you in a request. For God's sake, stop this game.</seg>
     <seg id="5">After all, there is a ruler who watches over all of us.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post79" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Though the question raised from the B.B.C. is substandard, it could only be felt pity at the poor quality of the writers. For instance, nobody asked this. What were the 3000 soldiers camping at Swat doing ?</seg>
     <seg id="2">The helpers of the army were hanging on poles the dead bodies of those who fought Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The cheating done to the commoners by the Pakistani soldiers is done, but, it is not right that the medias including B.B.C. has concealed the fact from the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The Pak soldiers are playing drama.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Every child in Swat whispers that it is a bloody drama.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Stop this drama for Godsake!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post84" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">These Talibans have destroyed the image of muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If the real muslims dont accept Taliban as muslims then why they get a refuge in thier places.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The one who are shameless and dont do hardwork and labour, take arms in their hands and join thier group.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Islam doesnt spread through sword and guns.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Have shame.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post88" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Its baseless and has no roots in any religion nor in family customs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All media including BBC show different views on Taliban and Tribals.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Infact nobody knows the actual situation except us, becuase we are the natives.</seg>
     <seg id="4">(  sorry was pretty hard to translate)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516146-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This move has ashamed all the Muslims.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I salute MQM's Altaf Hussain and the leadership of ANP and PPP who speak against this cancer that is Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This cancer is a product of Zia-ul-Haq who died but also destroyed Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But I am hopeful that current leadership will end this  cancer.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After Mumbai attacks India said that some extremists are behind the attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan rejecting the accusations said that it will help India in investigation in every possible way.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India said that it has given a list to Pakistan that has 20 suspected extremists required by India.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now Pakistan has said that included in the list Jaish-e-Muhammad's Molana Azhar Masood is not in custody and government of Pakistan has no information about him.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Before that the president of Pakistan Asif Ali Zardari refuted the view that west's secret agencies and Indian government has given evidence related to Mumbai attachs.</seg>
     <seg id="6">President Zardari has said that it has not been proved that Ajmal Kasab is a Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="7">During this, Prime Minister Manmohan Singh warned Pakistan that the its relations with India are not going to improve until its land is continued to be used for terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="8">And in latest development, Indian Cricket team has cancelled their tour of Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Should sports be effected due to these political events?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What future to you see of India Pakistan Relationship?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post22" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Neither America, nor India would break Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan would be broken by the Pakistanis themselves.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What do you expect after such regionalism, communalism and vandalism.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Even Jinnah too did not do good towards the Muslim's of India. Time has proved this.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Yasmin, Chicago</seg>
     <seg id="6">Madam, if we kep working on the vision of Jinnah, the cancer of Communalism, Regionalism and Vandalism would not have spread in Pakistan. And also the Muslims of India would not have been treated this way.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is our mistake of not producing a leader of his caliber</seg>
     <seg id="8">If we could pay the due respect to our heroes</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post33" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This region has great potential.</seg>
     <seg id="2">God knows when this region will learn its lesson and its unity will bring regional development/prosperity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Both countries have extremist forces like Taliban, Shiv sina and RSS etc... These extremist forces are enemies of the regional peace.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The imperial powers do not want peace and stability in this region.They are controlling these countries like puppets.</seg>
     <seg id="5">can you imagine the international influence of Pakistan, China and India, if they are united</seg>
     <seg id="6">Pakistan is under the occupation of corrupt and opportunist leadership.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post42" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">May God protect our country, Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But being a Pakistani we should not neglect the ground realities/threats. American forces have been deployed very near to our afghan borders.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Besides this the situation in the country doesnt seem to be stable, like in the NWFP, Baluchistan and Sindh, and the problems in Karachi are also evident.</seg>
     <seg id="4">In this atmosphere we need a leader that can unite the people of this country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">O God please show us some mercy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516154-post58" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I believe we have no other option but to go to war one last time.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Enough is enough.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It's now or never.</seg>
     <seg id="4">These fraudulent dialogues and pointless meetings are not the solution to the problems.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Neither is by committing small scale terrorist acts in each others territories.</seg>
     <seg id="6">After all it was only after waging the Second World War that Europe managed to sort its problems out.</seg>
     <seg id="7">And if it wasn't for this World War then they'd still be arguing and nagging each other over small things.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post112" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Almost all of our political parties are unified to the topic that terrorism and sectarian violence shall be eradicated from the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But own military leadership does not seem to be sincere on this topic. At one side Europe and America are assured that the military is sincere in achieving a terror free state but on the other hand helps the Taliban in disguise.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Now we have to think and define our path and select one path to focus on, Thank you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is no doubt that the elements of Jamat-ud-dawa include majority of those people who belong to Lashkar-e-Taiba which is a banned organization, is now established and operating with a new name Jamat-ud-dawa Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">However after that more focus was diverted towards humanitarian activities and now on India's strong request , the United Nations has also banned it and the government of Pakistan has also implemented a crack down on this organization.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In my opinion if these Jihadi groups leave religious extremism and get focused towards religion and humanitarian assistance then it is much better.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post150" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The terrorist organizations present in Pakistan which have used the name of Jihad to induct and nurture professional killers and criminals and their molana's are the same people who called Pakistan 'Plaeedistan' meaning un clean land. These are the people who use bad named for Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now they are trying their best to destroy Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In reality they don't even get close to be called a Muslin, in fact they deserve to be called animals or barbarians</seg>
     <seg id="4">Pakistan security will stay at risk until these extremists are not eradicated from Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Should we still  think that the innocent people will be charged with rules and regulation?</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this feurious world the job is war,their work is only to kill.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">With this news my heart is broken.</seg>
     <seg id="2">What type of world is this in which  it is very difficult to follow and live with the preachings of Allah's islam .</seg>
     <seg id="3">Non muslim can kill muslim but when the muslim try to take revenge then all non muslim  with the whole world brother's  together think ,that the islamic preaching's are done with Hafiz Sayeed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">India is very upset on the attack on Mumbai.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Citizen of pakistan  has created the misunderstanding between two countries and in the up coming days the sitiuation will be  more worst.</seg>
     <seg id="3">India alway's blames the pakistan's terror group.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The up coming problems on the taluk ,has  been stoped.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian security centres  has blamed the attack on Mumbai the Lashkar-e-tayab is responsible.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this case, name of Jamat-ud-Dawa has come in the front many times.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is the first time that relation between both the countries have worsen due to a terrorist activity in India</seg>
     <seg id="8">In December 2001, after the attacks on Indian Parliament, these two neighbors were on the brink of war.</seg>
     <seg id="9">After that, in 2002 Lashker-e-Tayyaba was banned and included in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Now Jamat-ud-Dawa, about which Security analysts say that it is in reality a new face of Lashker-e-Tayyaba. Restrictions on the party are being requested.</seg>
     <seg id="11">In your opinion, should this group be banned or not?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Should Pakistan do decisive operations against extreme activists on its land?</seg>
     <seg id="13">By banning Jamat-ud-Dawa, can  current Pak-India crisis be over?</seg>
     <seg id="14">crisis be over? and how important is it to close down the armed groups to keep constant peace between both countries?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post36" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Security Council of the United Nations has banned Jamat-ud-Dawa. After all what proof does the security council have to decide this so quickly?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Will the Peace Council never show any alertness against the Muslims every time?</seg>
     <seg id="3">For this it is said that when the accuser is lazy the witness is active.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If seen India itself has become one useless realm.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whose intelligence, army and other security officials has become useless, who for 72 hours have danced the dance of mole with terrorists and India is cheating the world by blaming Pakistan over its uselessness.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post51" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">If one disbeliever dies then the whole world knows about it- why is this double accuracy?</seg>
     <seg id="2">To the dear nation of one nonpolitical, religious, farming organization...</seg>
     <seg id="3">Farqaan Farooq, Faisalabad</seg>
     <seg id="4">Until our Prophet(Peace be upon Him), great ancestors and Sufism gave the human beings the love and respect, religion Islam was more vast growing and ripening from peace and sparkle.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Muslims also got promoted in every field.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But when this beautiful Religion rose to the hands of distillation then within the human beings began the difference of religious and disbeliever and the new gateways of pride and prejudice began to open by which the world was unknown before.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post53" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salute, sir, salute happily, but get your work done on your own.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Do not do it under the pressure from America.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If India is in difficulty, let them prove it, no?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Why does it not give?</seg>
     <seg id="5">And why do they accuse us with everything?</seg>
     <seg id="6">There are fundamentalist groups and organisations, even in India. Why does no one put any restrictions on them?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are we the only terrorist in the whole world?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What is it that India is doing in Kashmir?</seg>
     <seg id="9">What is it that Israel is doing?</seg>
     <seg id="10">The truth is that we are the first Islamic Nuclear State. Why, is what the fight is about.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is on the verge of break up.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Kamranhassan, ABU DHABI</seg>
     <seg id="3">You are right, circumstances are supporting your argument.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now even American magazines are publishing new maps of pakistan. These sanctions are the part of greater game plan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Gradually,USA is making its grip stronger on Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In this situation, if we'd not become a united nation then history of Bangladesh's creation can be repeated.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post69" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Terrorists' attack should be condemned, whether these are committed in Mumbai, Islamabad or in Philistine.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Terrorists should be uprooted without any discrimination of nationality.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The question arises, why Pakistan and other world is silent on the terror attacks in Pakistan, killing hundreds of innocent people?</seg>
     <seg id="4">if attack on Marriott was not act of terror?</seg>
     <seg id="5">then why-</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516161-post91" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">hale to the advisor for interior Rehman Malik, how brave and bold has the gentleman become.</seg>
     <seg id="2">no imgage</seg>
     <seg id="3">not only this, but according to BBC Mr. Malik has denied this impression with intensity that the arresting of the terrorists have been carried out under 'someones's pressure'.</seg>
     <seg id="4">wow, all praise to the Almighty!</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post13" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">whether having the ability or not or to say that I don't want.</seg>
     <seg id="2">We, the Pakistanis are fighting whose war.</seg>
     <seg id="3">and why we have our own interests which we shall do our best to protect.</seg>
     <seg id="4">No one has  a right to interfere anyone's national affairs.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The colonial system is apparently not there.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If people are sure to have justice or Allies support the importance of free judiciary and give respect to democratic institutes and dont support the dictatorial governments; peace can be achieved in third world countries including Pakistan. But this is not acceptable for allies</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Pakistan is always in line with European and American interests.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan is forced to do so despite a majority of its population oppose it.</seg>
     <seg id="3">This enhances the opposite or anti sentiments.</seg>
     <seg id="4">If America and its Allies believe in Democracy, they should give up their colonial behavior and leave this region</seg>
     <seg id="5">Pakistan has ability to arm or disarm.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Security forces searched a camp of Lashar-i-tayba in Pakistan administered Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="2">After Mumbai attacks, Pressure is being increased on Pakistan to take actions against extreme outfits</seg>
     <seg id="3">India blames that Lashar-i-tayba has role in Mumbai Attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Condalisa rice, American foreign minister asked Pakistani leadership to take practical and transparent actions against those responsible for Mumbai attacks.</seg>
     <seg id="5">he believed the terrorists involved in Mumbai Attacks used the Pakistani soil.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Meanwhile, the officials in Peshawar has told that more than 50 trucks have been burnt by some unknown armed persons. These trucks were going to Afghanistan with goods for NATO forces.</seg>
     <seg id="7">These was the second attack on American supply during the last 48 hours.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Meanwhile Pakistani police cracked down a camp of Lashkar i Taiba, a banned outfit. Already many efforts have been made to disarmed the extremists, even money and indemnity was offered.</seg>
     <seg id="9">It is clear from the circumstances that efforts remain unsuccessful to dislodge the armed groups funded by Americans and Saudis during afghan war. It means efforts to restore Pre-80's Pakistan are fruitless.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Question arises, whether Pakistan wants to do so?</seg>
     <seg id="11">If Pakistan has an ability to do this?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What is your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="13">For details please click here</seg>
     <seg id="14">Note: due to higher numbers, only comments typed in Urdu will be published</seg>
     <seg id="15">For this, click Alt+Shift on the on-screen keyboard and select Urdu)</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post32" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I have only one question for the standard bearers of the world.</seg>
     <seg id="2">If you kill their children, will they come to garland you? It is impossible.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Saeed, Multan</seg>
     <seg id="4">And I ask you, does any science, from Islamic sciences to the sciences of the East and the West, any logic or philosophy, anywhere, give the permission to kill innocent public, including worshipers, laborers, and poor workers, in revenge for the American attacks?</seg>
     <seg id="5">If your answer is in negative, then you really need to fix your viewpoint.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post35" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The people were armed when there was the fear that Russia would head towards Pakistan after finishing Afghanistan, and that is why they were supplied arms.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Now, when there is the fear that America will capture Pakistan, via Afghanistan, as the president American president has clearly mentioned in his presidential mission, why should we disarm them now?</seg>
     <seg id="3">Only so that after defeating the American or Indian army, it does not have to face any resistance from the public?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Yes, if any of them are guilty of being involved in any destructive work, Pakistan can take action against them alone.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post46" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">But it is sad that the fact that Lashkar-e-Taiba is involved proves India's claim that Pakistan is guilty in this.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Najeebur Rahman Syco, Lahore</seg>
     <seg id="3">Even if we accept that Lashkar-e-Taiba is guilty, it is still not correct to blame the Pakistani government.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And another question is that were these terrorists not supported by an Indian governmental or non-governmental agent?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Are terrorists only born or prepared in Pakistan, and not in any other country of the world?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post63" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">As for Lashkar-e-Taiba, the present terrorism is in no way connected to it.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It must be remembered that Hafiz Saeed is the first 'Jehadi leader' who called the Taliban actions 'mischief'.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I am sure that the Taliban effect is a inseparable result of American plans, and hence every person who can stand in the way of Taliban must be removed.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Despite the support of the whole nation, the fact that Zardari and co. took action against the Lashkar is a clear sign of their frigid and kiss-up nature.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post64" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">To stop the project that is running on Saudi-American funding, they must be requested themselves to regather, for God's sake, the filth that has polluted our society.</seg>
     <seg id="2">we will protest against them that in which ethical way America and Saudia has distributed Dangerous weapons and so called Jihad but actually they have distributed hatred literature and cultural virus which has created a human slaughter houses.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516165-post71" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">after the threat from India to attack Pakistan, Pakistan Military announces that he will pull his forces from Afghan border and put it towards India. Taliban also announces that they will take care of the Afghan border which resulted in a chaos In America and he Forced India not to do war with Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In this Letter all the musket of American Power was exposed</seg>
     <seg id="3">in contrast India has never threatened nor he has the power to attack</seg>
     <seg id="4">the remaining damage is done by the Taliban by attacking the American convoy</seg>
     <seg id="5">this proved that without Pakistan Military and Government Of Pakistan support America is Nothing</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post109" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Karachi, Pakistan's Main Business and Finance City which is Dubai of all the rural areas</seg>
     <seg id="2">Million never returned from here with empty hands, but when western areas law and order situation is worsen all attention is directed towards Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="3">now they want to hijack this city</seg>
     <seg id="4">for the first time Pathans are called by Pakhtuns,which is making city's people as stranger and fighting among each other, but to be united is necessity of time</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post117" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One solution to this problem is that either the Urdu speaking people learn Pushtun or the Pushtun speaking people learn Urdu, or better yet, both learn English.</seg>
     <seg id="2">You might think that this is a funny proposal, but does the cause of the conflict not seem funny?</seg>
     <seg id="3">That the cause of extremism be language?</seg>
     <seg id="4">Zaheer Chughtai</seg>
     <seg id="5">Sir, I actually shared this proposal many times in my childhood with my friends, which included people from all religious and linguistic groups, but these people used to laugh at me.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At that time, the religious and linguistic hate, which was not as lively and strong as they are today, were still developing within.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post120" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I can never understand what is happening and why?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Are these the signs of the Day of Judgement?</seg>
     <seg id="3">For what crime are innocent people being killed?</seg>
     <seg id="4">The reasons are in front of everybody. Those who want to break up Pakistan are the active ones, and those who do such things, have neither religion, nor country.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Whether it be Karachi or Mumbai, the house was burnt by the houses own lanterns</seg>
     <seg id="6">Whichever government comes, it only changes the names of the places and starts working for fame, just like how nowadays, the airports, roads and buildings are all Benazir.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Does Benazir mean that which is happening to the public of Karachi and Pakistan?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post127" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At the height of the Mumbai attacks, the fact that the efforts to cause mischief on linguistic and racial lines in Karachi failed is proof that those politicians working on racial parole have resigned from their jobs.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The taking of the lives of innocent Pushtu speaking labourers and the Indian warnings have awakened the sleeping Pakistani feelings from Karachi to Khyber.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The identical country loving reaction of all the political, religious, linguistic and national parties has not only taught India the manners of diplomacy but it has also given the American policy makers a chance to think again.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post131" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The responsible parties for the worsening situation in Karachi are the United and the ANP, and the government is taking sides.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The government can control the situation in one hour, but it is purposely allowing it to grow.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The police and rangers are avoiding action because of the pressure on them by the political parties.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The talk of uniting is only restricted to speeches. The political parties should leave their interests and work for the interest of the common man.</seg>
     <seg id="5">These kinds of situations will happen until political pressure stays on the management. Allah keep Pakistan safe.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post135" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In my opinion, they are the biggest terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">And of course there are external powers active in this. But no one knows who they are?</seg>
     <seg id="3">But what is sad the most is if this kind of situation occurred in some city of Sarhad, government would have done what not but now when it is not in Sarhad, the government is so helpless.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Government should do an operation here and save country's big and an important city.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Otherwise, Pakistan will face a big economic setback.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post136" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even BBC Urdu is not writing the truth being scared. On the other hand Pakistan's media's condition is even worse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The complete truth is available on BBC English.</seg>
     <seg id="3">One solution to the problem is this that Urdu speaking people should learn Pashto or Pashto speaking people should learn Urdu or it is even better if everyone learns English.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You will obviously consider this suggestion as ridiculous but don't you think the reason for collision is ridiculous?</seg>
     <seg id="5">The reason for persecution may be language ?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post145" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Another story of murder has finally been published in Karachi, which was being dreaded by all the citizens for a long time.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The criminals do not let go any opputunity of a crime. The news reports and the media are only telling 50% of what actually happened here in 4 days.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Have spent the last three nights without sleeping, and the fear is still there.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Those who make the people evacuate hotels, those who kill the shoe-makers and the peanut-sellers.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Those who rob and kill at the Super Highway, and cut off the ears of innocent citizens, they are ignorant of the wrath of Allah which will eventually entrap them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post149" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">What could be the reasons of this sudden turmoil in your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="2">(B.B.C)</seg>
     <seg id="3">Keeping in view, the gruesome bloodshed event in Mumbai, we do not need to delve deep into the matter to find the reason of disorder in Karachi. It is simple and easy to guess that the turmoil is just due to an unconcious trade of blood.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Obviously if somebody infuriates a father, it would not be surprising if the son reacts violently.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the blood of the loyalists of Liaqat Ali Khan also belonged to the same place but to eliminate Mr. Psycho's misunderstanding I am writing this verse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">we will also repeat our elders' traditions</seg>
     <seg id="3">we made it by sacrificing lives and will save it by doing the same</seg>
     <seg id="4">Faizan Tauseef Siddiqui</seg>
     <seg id="5">it is very disappointing that whole country is at stake and we are fighting with each other.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Mr. Siddiqui, I request if wikipedia.</seg>
     <seg id="7">see Liaqat Ali Khan, you will will find out that he belonged to a noble Punjabi family from Karnal in Punjab.</seg>
     <seg id="8">due to his steps for the migrants, today the migrants consider him as one of them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-NG-102-174502-11516169-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">there is always a reaction to every action.</seg>
     <seg id="2">one can afford on oneself but.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Ejaz Aiwan</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sir, before you gather a huge crowd very quickly, I should tell you that you are finding the open memento of the real gangster activities these days on the walls of Karachi in the form of wall chalking and posters.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We have been tolerating both kinds of actions.</seg>
     <seg id="6">These thugs did not even forgive Pakistan and the founder of Pakistan, they did not face any reaction.</seg>
     <seg id="7">On the contrary, we are writing our hearts on the chest of Pakistan.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359731-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">One Muslim League N was left, even they made a draft of the 18th amendment and gave it to People's Party.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Before this, MQM and Muslim League Q have made and submitted a draft of the 18th amendment in the National Assembly and the Senate.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Till now it seems that drafts of the 18th amendment is a political trick and no one is sincere in getting this amendment approved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">This is the reason why  no one has made a fuss in the assembly or senate floor in the favor of this amendment nor has forced the assembly to approve this change.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It seems like that after submitting the drafts of 18th amendment, these parties have done their part that is they will be able to say this tomorrow that we submitted the draft, government speaker did not take any action.</seg>
     <seg id="6">MQM the government, Muslim League N in the opposition and Muslim League Q was the party who passed 17th amendment so how is it possible that these parties will be sincere in finishing the 17th amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="7">This is what is called getting credit for nothing.</seg>
     <seg id="8">People's party is already not in a hurry about finishing 17th amendment.</seg>
     <seg id="9">How can someone think of cutting their own hands?</seg>
     <seg id="10">17th amendment will not be canceled until Zardari is the President.</seg>
     <seg id="11">This was the opinion of the majority in our survey and it is also true.</seg>
     <seg id="12">If 17th amendment was to be discarded then Zardari would have never become the president.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Now he is even more powerful than President Parvez Musharaf. Because with being the president, he is also the chairman of the People's Party.</seg>
     <seg id="14">17th amendment is valid until he is the president.</seg>
     <seg id="15">In order to finish the 17th amendment, the political parties will have to bid Zardari farewell from the president house.</seg>
     <seg id="16">Neither MQM nor other parties want this.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359750-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Most of the elders in our family belong to labor class.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During your childhood when we our uncles doing their work we prayed Allah to protect us from physical labor.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To avoid this we wrote to the editor of monthly Amroz to ask him what to do after matriculation so that we would not have to do physical labor.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Editor in reply wrote that we should become Doctor or Engineer and study these courses.</seg>
     <seg id="5">We were inclined towards engineering and in matriculation we studied Technical drawing instead of Biology.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But at the time of admissions in FSc the elder brother forced us to study medical in FSc.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We hardly studied biology for a month before we started studying maths.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Means that to avoid physical labour we became engineer and we are in better position than many friends in our family and we thank Allah for it.</seg>
     <seg id="9">We remembered this when with out 2 young sons we were trying to lift carpets of old hour.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Now it hasn't been half an hour while we were working that the small son said "Daddy it seems that I am not born for this job"</seg>
     <seg id="11">We said that if so study good like us and build up your body.</seg>
     <seg id="12">The son started saying I am studying already, will be studying more but this work is not done by me.</seg>
     <seg id="13">Any how we three managed to complete the work within three hours and returned home.</seg>
     <seg id="14">The meaning of saying this is that if a man decides on one destiny then whatever comes afterward will not stop him to accomplish his destination.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Yes and if you don't really know what you have to do then Allah is the only protector for you.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359766-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">There is a saying that never say bad for a dead but what to do, also at the first death anniversary of Benazeer we only see bad in her.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazeer for her own benefit forwarded to India the Sikhs' army, who were to fight the war of independent. On one side the independent movement of the Sikhs was collapsed and on the other side gave chance for India to concentrate on Kashmir after pushing down the Punjab movement.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is the part of the distraction from the leadership of Benazeer and Nawaz Sharif which have pushed the country to many years backwards.</seg>
     <seg id="4">During exile Benazeer continued on keeping the series beneficiary information of Kashmir and Atomic Program.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Benazir violated the London agreement with Nawaz Sharif and made a deal with General Musharaf.</seg>
     <seg id="6">during her rule, Benazir gave a free hand to her husband to make as much money that is why he is known as Mr. Ten percent.</seg>
     <seg id="7">during Benazir's rule his brother got killed but his murderers are still safe from any punishment.</seg>
     <seg id="8">besides being a woman herself, Benazir avoided fighting for women's rights.</seg>
     <seg id="9">just like Benazir did her politics over her fathers dead body, similarly her widower is doing the same over her dead body.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Benazir came into power twice but she could not punish her the culprits of her father's political murder even she couldn't register a case against them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359779-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">it has been 37 years since East Pakistan separated from us but look at the extreme of senselessness of our people and leaders that we never celebrate the mourning day.</seg>
     <seg id="2">what should have happened instead is that we should have celebrated 16th December as a didactic day and take such measures that this kind of incident don't take place again.</seg>
     <seg id="3">on this day we could send greeting to the people of Bangladesh and try to bring them closer to ourselves again.</seg>
     <seg id="4">the rulers would reopen the Hamudur Rehman commission reports and discuss the reasons for the separation of East Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="5">They used to make arrangements to bring back the Bahari's stuck in Bangladesh and send them presents to raise their spirits.</seg>
     <seg id="6">But we lack feelings now. We are not even aware if someone dies in our neighborhood.</seg>
     <seg id="7">We do not care about our brothers and sisters because we have become selfish.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Even if a great accident occurs, we are busy in our daily routines of life from the next day.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Only if East and West Pakistan could be one together just like East and West Germany was united once again.</seg>
     <seg id="10">We can be one again if we both sacrifice for each other and come out of the hole of selfishness.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But this wish does not seem to be granted in the near future.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359785-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">When it was announced in the news today that the Governor of the American State Illinois was arrested for corruption charges</seg>
     <seg id="2">and when the State Congress started getting ready to remove him from the position of the governor as soon as possible, then there is this one American companion who has a close watch on the circumstances of Pakistan, boastfully claimed to us that this is what we call democracy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In America, even the higher level people can not transcendence the law.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And the other is your country, Pakistan, where even the President was chosen after the corruption charges against him were dropped.</seg>
     <seg id="5">My vein of loyalty throbbed and I said what is the big deal if a governor was arrested in America. In our Pakistan, once the Prime Minister was arrested and hanged overnight, and another time sent into exile.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tell me, when did this happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="7">In Pakistan, those who broke the law were sent out of the presidential palace with a guard of honor. Tell me when this happened in America.</seg>
     <seg id="8">The Chief Justice of Pakistan was removed in such a manner, that despite having public support, he could not be replaced until now. Has this happened in America?</seg>
     <seg id="9">In Pakistan, a fake-degree holder was made the Minister of Health. Did this happen in America?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Hearing this, the American laughed till he was tired and conceded defeat.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-72-174253-11359789-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In this picture, President Zardari is smiling, despite being surrounded on all four sides by Americans.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It seems from his smile that</seg>
     <seg id="3">he thinks that America is with his government. He is forgetting that one year ago, they were with Pervez Musharraf.</seg>
     <seg id="4">the picture look like a picture of Family</seg>
     <seg id="5">before that no picture as such has been published in which President is with 3 American authorities</seg>
     <seg id="6">Look like that America's work has been increased in Pakistan and one and more Authorities are working on it or they might not believe that person as compared to the first one.</seg>
     <seg id="7">it might possible that they have planned also this, keeping in mind the nature of President Zardari promise fulfillment.</seg>
     <seg id="8">if there would any intelligent Politician than there would be atleast not smiling in this picture and his face should show some Embarcement</seg>
     <seg id="9">if Democracy principle applied on this picture than President Zardari is in Minority</seg>
     <seg id="10">According to Democracy, Majority is the ruler of Nation and who are they picture is showing</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Heaven like Swat of Pakistan is also known as Switzerland.</seg>
     <seg id="2">till now, according to Government Policy, cross talks are also going along with the power use</seg>
     <seg id="3">but power use is resulting in increase power of Taliban and increasing sympathy for Taliban among people beside that it is not providing any benefits</seg>
     <seg id="4">Instead of using power, government should find out the real causes of the problem.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Fazalullah and Taliban will dissolve into nothingness if the root causes are terminated.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The Shariat bill suggested by the                                                                 The Shariat bill suggested by the ANP administration will, to a great extent, bring a solution for the problems in Swat.              a</seg>
     <seg id="7">But, in addition to the observance of the Shariat law, the administration will take care of the well being of the people.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post19" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The actions of General Musharaf made us believe that we had been made free from the unqualified politicians of the land. But, his ambition for more power changed everything.</seg>
     <seg id="2">How many expectations were there! He lost all hopes in "war and terror".</seg>
     <seg id="3">Hopes of taking actions were lost.</seg>
     <seg id="4">It seemed that he understood that the end of his reign was imminent along with the end of Bush administration. As a result, thieves were recruited to power centres.</seg>
     <seg id="5">General Musharaf was in a position to control the army. But the present administration does no know what is happening.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The army could not put down the terror in Baajodoh and Swat. The commoners are subjected to "bombardments and enmity" i.e, creating great loss to lives and properties. It also puts them into psychological disorder.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In Swat, the strongly affected part of Sarhad state, despite the continuity of military action for over one year, the situation is still going from bad to worse.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On one side, the government is only reiterating the passing of a reproachful resolution in the national assembly. On the other side, the Taliban's illegal radio FM channel is having much more influence in the region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On the third side, the common man considers it safest to listen to the one who actually has control over the region.</seg>
     <seg id="4">During the action of the security forces, there were claims of destroying the fundamentalists by the bombing of gun ship helicopters and cannon houses, but despite these destructions, the Taliban only became more powerful, and according to an estimation, their control over Swat increased that much percent more.</seg>
     <seg id="5">As a result, on the one hand the government is not ready to accept defeat, and on the other hand the Taliban is stronger.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Who is stuck in  between? The poor civilians.</seg>
     <seg id="7">It is said in Swat, that someone asked what kind of people are the Taliban were, so he got the answer, 'They are very good, as they are protectors of the religion and they fight against the enemies of Allah and the religion'.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Then he asked how the army was, so he got the answer, 'They are very good, as they are the protectors of the country and they fight against the enemies of the country'.</seg>
     <seg id="9">He then asked who the enemies of the religion and the country were, so he got the answer, 'We civilians'.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358562-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I am wondering how the Pakistani Army will fight the Indian Army, when they couldn't control a small faction of the Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Could not track down Taliban's illegally operated FM channel which in my opinion is very easy.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But still FM was spreading hatred in full swing.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After girls schools now boys schools are being destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Curfew is imposed so that tablibans can move around easily.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Tonight 8 trucks entered the suburbs of Mingora during curfew and created bunkers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The question is that how could they reach there during curfew.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Army could kill Akbar Bugti in his house and salutes Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="9">For God sake someone tells this Army to protect helpless people of Sawat from Taliban and prove that Pakistan army can overcome any enemy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358578-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">He says that most of the blood is spilt in the name of religion, tell me that if religion was not then blood wouldnt have spilt?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Punjabi, Pathan, White and Blank, Mehsood and other tribes, are these the products of religion?</seg>
     <seg id="3">No not at all.A religion teaches that there is no white no black, there is no Punjabi no immigrant.If there was no religion then people would have destroyed each other and other things in the battle of black and white.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The religion only teaches the man how to be disciplined and mannered.Religion only shows the man that he has not come by himself instead he has been created by the Supreme Power God and He has sent you in this world to lead a life as per His orders.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Being a Muslim iam very sure that Islam is a complete religion  and moreover it is a true religion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358583-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Even after the time i acquired the luxuries in London, I continued to call up my relatives on every morning to find out about their good and bad.Even though my relatives never bothered to call me ever in my life. But still i continued to do so. But the time when i felt that my relatives dont even like my calling them, i stopped making calls to them ever after.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Even i have felt the same here since i have spent my two years of life in France.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Why people keep expectation only from us to make a phone call to them in Patna.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358596-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">About Iraq, within a few hours there would be an Army sent for the "peace" in the Darfar. This is not a problem for them.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The post action after the Mumbai Blasts and the security in the areas are a matter of few hours.</seg>
     <seg id="3">There are discussions and opinions on the matter where there are more risk to death in the areas of Mumbai through any sources.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Hey you the Protectors and leaders of the Peaceful world the life is being ended here only in the discussions.</seg>
     <seg id="5">is it really being waited to diminish.</seg>
     <seg id="6">so that any again no aggrieved could even think about using a weapon of mass destruction like the stonebow to gain his own rights.</seg>
     <seg id="7">when a father is running carrying his beloved sons dead body, even then your hearts don't pinch you with pain?</seg>
     <seg id="8">If not then you don't even deserve to be called human being.</seg>
     <seg id="9">but you are a black mottle over the name of humanity.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post14" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">so atleast this has been proven that this region has also been a homeland for Jews for centuries.</seg>
     <seg id="2">ideally these two nations should have lived in harmony but since their strings are in Western and Arab hands, so without their will peace can not prevail in this region.</seg>
     <seg id="3">and now even Iran wants to fight its proxy war from here.</seg>
     <seg id="4">even if the Israeli operation stops temporarily, it will start again any moment after any incident.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">BBC's own country has its interests related to America and Israel and this is why while taking cover of enlightened moderation, it has started a series of blogs or Jewism and doing a biased propaganda.</seg>
     <seg id="2">BBC is only completing a formality, and its goal and intent is only to gather well wishes.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I request the moderator to publish this comment of Fidwi, so it be known that at least a little bit of affinity towards truth is still remaining in BBC</seg>
     <seg id="4">Thank You.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-77-174260-11358605-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I don't know who wrote this story or how this story came to being, but one thing is for sure, in every age, draculas have been drinking the blood of innocent people.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In every age, wars have been fought and blood has been spilled.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But the surprising thing is that this 21st century man, who considers himself civilized, is quiet over this ruthless open massacre.</seg>
     <seg id="4">How could I not feel that whatever is happening is presenting a very ugly picture of mankind.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The most disturbing and sad part, is what kind of picture will this dark side of cultured man present to another man coming in the next century.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Well wisher, Sajjad Alhasnain, Hyderabad, Deccan</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377684-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">At this time, including Derah Gahzi Khan, summer showers are taking place throughout the country.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A poem on climate is presented to you. May you enjoy the sweet rain when you read this poem.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It rains just because of you</seg>
     <seg id="4">whatever rains is the spring</seg>
     <seg id="5">whichever comes to a standstill is tranquility</seg>
     <seg id="6">Sometimes comes, with no reason</seg>
     <seg id="7">Often spreads wide in the night hours</seg>
     <seg id="8">Often quite noisily, often silently</seg>
     <seg id="9">It rains.. but just because of you</seg>
     <seg id="10">whichever cherishing memory, whichever night</seg>
     <seg id="11">A suppressed music!</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sometimes he put it out</seg>
     <seg id="13">sometimes he lit himself up</seg>
     <seg id="14">sometimes every drop carries sorrow</seg>
     <seg id="15">These rains are quite like you</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-78-174262-11377692-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">All these leaders are about to run holding a very sensitive case, little do they care if the country survives or not.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The people should they sell their possessions or be wiping clean the temples with lemon peals.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And like our leaders our media is corrupted as well</seg>
     <seg id="4">Its sole purpose is to extract money from the government.</seg>
     <seg id="5">And the people are oblivious about this,</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11377995-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">An odd incident took place yesterday noon.</seg>
     <seg id="2">All police are running here and there, but don't ask about illegal parking.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What's more, NYPD traffic was not in the state where it could look at illegally parked vehicles.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Something like this happened, that a plane of the US Air really became a ship and landed in the Hudson river.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Until now, we only now that terrorists are of the descendants of geese.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Yesterday was perhaps historic cold, in New York.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The temperature does not fall this much.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Even my jaws started hurting from my half an hour walk outside.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Imagine, how the people who jumped from the plane into the river would have felt.</seg>
     <seg id="10">It is a matter of happiness that all people were safe.</seg>
     <seg id="11">And it was sad that the companies plane drowned during this financial crisis.</seg>
     <seg id="12">I went by West Side Highway to New Jersey, watching all this, and I saw that Southbound was blocked, but what did I still do?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Yes, I got stuck in the same rush on the way back.</seg>
     <seg id="14">Thankfully, in my one hour trip, the way had opened at least a bit, so I was able to get the 56th street exit.</seg>
     <seg id="15">Otherwise, I had not taken the previous two exits, seeing the lines waiting at them.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-79-174263-11378012-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Makki, My Pakistan: Well, Congratulations, Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Ammar: Of course, believing women</seg>
     <seg id="3">Shaguftah: Well, Congratulations, Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Sarah: I have slaughtered two chickens and how they are slaughtered, Jahanzeb has already mentioned.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Apart from this, there is no other way.</seg>
     <seg id="6">At this farm, one has to get his own meat done,, including removing the skin.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Bossom:It may take some time for the Dot Net to get fixed</seg>
     <seg id="8">What happened on the forum?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Linko</seg>
     <seg id="10">To fight with the "listen to the blog", use Firefox.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Duffer: Khair Mubarak! Eid Mubarak to you too.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Sir use Firefox</seg>
     <seg id="13">Snow till disappear</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364077-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">For no reason, we thought that the Taliban group from Sawat was non religious, who were only against women education.</seg>
     <seg id="2">They were expressing this irritation by demolishing schools and colleges for women every day.</seg>
     <seg id="3">But like majority of the ideas, this was not proven right also. According to this news of CNN, on the lucky day of Monday, a group of Taliban demolished a Boys school with gunpowder.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Swat, The Taliban has destroyed a boys school.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The girls schools were already destroyed, acting according to the famous English saying "Ladies First". I do not know why people are still bent on calling the Taliban uncultured and barbaric.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Another thing that becomes clear from this is that the accusation against the Taliban, that they are against girls education, is not true.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Rather, Masha Allah, they are against education altogether.</seg>
     <seg id="8">May Allah give these Mujahideen more power, and the evil government</seg>
     <seg id="9">which is let loose on us, may He help them in uprooting them.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Amen, then Amen.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Masha Allah, up till now, 182 schools have been destroyed.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364081-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The custom of fixing marriages before birth among Muslims, marrying with the Qur'an to collect property, and the statement by many Muftis that the girl becomes intelligent and reaches puberty at the age of eight was not little, that there was the news from India, that a girl was married with a frog.</seg>
     <seg id="2">See a picture of the bride, taken at the marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Some days go, a girl's marriage with a dog become fresh.</seg>
     <seg id="4">see that now</seg>
     <seg id="5">Humanity is rare in 21st century.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364084-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the age of computer. computer has occupied its space in every walk of life.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Many people have objections over interference of computer as its role in financial matters.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Although credit card users have facility but their personal life is under more control of law enforcement agencies.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now the record of financial matters can easily be tracked by using credit card.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In future when usage of currency will become lesser, its importance will increase.</seg>
     <seg id="6">In crime world risk is not taken to rob banks. Now credit card information is stolen.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Similarly friends are also made through computers.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Social networking sites, like Orkut, Facebook and Myspace are at first level of acceptance.</seg>
     <seg id="9">But do you not think that the more we are following these social networking sites, the further we are getting from people in real life?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Similar are the match making websites, where your desires are matched with others desires and you are shown a list of the people who match with you.</seg>
     <seg id="11">But can you lead a life with a person who is just like you?</seg>
     <seg id="12">I can not, and that is why the spouse is called the better half,</seg>
     <seg id="13">because he/she will get rid of the faults within me.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364087-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Perhaps I have got a small share of sense.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I used to believe everything someone elder says.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In the same way, I thought that my father knew the answer to every question on earth.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I used to get laughed at a lot for this.</seg>
     <seg id="5">But only that saying seemed true which could be possible.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Become much irritation because what was the reason to tell lie?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Bore loss on that saying even at this age</seg>
     <seg id="8">So it is my effort to say lie the very least.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Do not misguide someone by lieing and that also by attaching Allah's name.</seg>
     <seg id="10">and Allah willing say only when there is pray to Allah that work completes.</seg>
     <seg id="11">Remaining Allah knows better the state of intention.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364089-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is a disgusting problem which is created due to reason of distance from religion.</seg>
     <seg id="2">According to law of both our Pakistan and religion, minor child should stay with mother.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Their expense is due to their father and father can meet with children.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Then when the child becomes of age, he or she can stay with whomever they will.</seg>
     <seg id="5">You rightly mentioned that the actual problem is that of the relatives who mislead.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Possessiveness is present in all our actions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It is this very factor in effect over here, that there will be new shareholders in the father's property born, and they will go against him. Otherwise his fathers action is commendable.</seg>
     <seg id="3">These restrictions have caused social evils, even in our marriages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The concept of the marriage of a divorced woman or a widow has become obscure.</seg>
     <seg id="5">It is these wasteful ideologies and baseless traditions that have made the family structure a mess.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In our society, if the wife of a 50-55 year old man or the husband of such a wife passes away, why are they not looked at in a nice manner?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Near us, there is a Pakistani uncle, whose wife passed away 10-12 years ago. Now, after marrying off all his children, he has married a widow, so even his children have gone against him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I believe this is his legitimate right. What do you say?</seg>
     <seg id="4">What type of mentality is the 'while we are there, no one can take our mother's place', kind of mentality?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">I believe that this persons children should have thought what is wrong if he married a widow, after he married off all his children?</seg>
     <seg id="2">Thereby, this widow also got support and the uncle also got someone to look after the house.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As the children would definitely have gotten busy in their own worlds and would not be able to give time to him.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post4" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The reason for this is ignorance.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Tomorrow if their wives refuse to look after them, when they are old, what will they do?</seg>
     <seg id="3">This is a result of the force of society.</seg>
     <seg id="4">When people begin to make fun of such a family for doing something like that, children start to feel ashamed of their father's second marriage.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Though they should face the environment and say that their father's action is in perfect accordance with Islam.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">This is the curse of our society, which we are facing for the last 40-50 years.</seg>
     <seg id="2">A wife can accept her husband going around having illicit relations, but she cannot stand him having a second wife.</seg>
     <seg id="3">If possible, stop him from doing so, even after you die.</seg>
     <seg id="4">She destroys her husband and her own hereafter, and becomes a cause for spreading filthiness in the society.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post7" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Chanting Islam, Islam does not mean anything. In reality, we like only our culture and traditions.</seg>
     <seg id="2">For instance keeping girls  from gaining education and fearing marrying the girl of ones choice.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As for your question about the old man going to the widows house instead of bringing the widow to his house, so that the children could make some fuss and then become quiet and relax, (though the stomach of the widows children would hurt).</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-83-174268-11364090-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the Indo Pak subcontinent, Islam was accepted centuries ago, but it could not yet leave its ignorant mentality and has always kept culture and tradition above Islam.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Thinking of a man's second marriage as an innovation, divorce as a clinical rest, divorced woman as untouchable, love marriage as a mark on honor and a man marrying a woman elder to him as a deception on the part of the wife, is all a part of this mentality.</seg>
     <seg id="3">What's more, in mimicry of the western countries, we have started to consider piety and veil as old fashioned.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Accepting Islam is easy, but leaving this mentality is very tough.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Allah grant us all spirit and courage for this.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Amen</seg>
     <seg id="7">Writing Urdu was never so difficult.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Century passed writing such little writing</seg>
     <seg id="9">Know that little is much.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Allah Hafiz</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Ameer Taimoor in his book "I am Taimoor" writes that i found this secret in my life that if leader of any Army is in front line then that Army will never lose.</seg>
     <seg id="2">But here situation is else.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To say that Common people are there to die for us if we die then martyr</seg>
     <seg id="4">if someone from common people dies then murder</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-84-174269-11325249-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">AsSalaamu Alaikum wa Rahmatullahi wa Barakatuhu (greeting)</seg>
     <seg id="2">Today, as I was returning to my shop, after Isha prayer, when a man sitting in a car at the circle raised his hand and diverted my attention towards him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I thought this man might have lost his way, or he might want to ask something, so I stopped, and his whole family was sitting in the car.</seg>
     <seg id="4">He asked whether I could understand Arabic well or not. I said no problem, tell me what you want.</seg>
     <seg id="5">He started to say that I have come from Riyadh, to Madinah, but someone has pick-pocketed me, so please help me out. I asked him to excuse me, as such an incident had taken place with me previously, that I had given the person 20 Riyals to buy petrol to reach Riyadh, but he went a little ahead and started to ask somebody else.</seg>
     <seg id="6">I got very angry and scolded him and warned him that I would call the soldiers, so he got very frightened.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Now the situation  has become, that we Muslims come on cars, with our families to beg throughout the day and gain at least two or three thousand illegally.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Whereas there is a clear Hadith of the Prophet (SAWS) that says that the upper hand is better than the lower hand; the lower hand being the begging hand and the upper hand being the giving one.</seg>
     <seg id="9">May Allah have mercy on us and make us true Muslims (Amen, Amen)</seg>
     <seg id="10">WasSalam</seg>
     <seg id="11">Jawed Iqbal</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Famous singer Adnan Sami's wife reached a police station in Mumbai, accusing him of torturing her.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Police station advised her to contact a court.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Adnan Sami's wife Saba Giladari gave a complaint against her husband saying that he continuously tortures her.</seg>
     <seg id="4">and that he treats her in a non-human manner.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Now, it has become difficult for her to bear, and that is why she has filed a case against him.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The police, instead of filing a case, told her to contact a court, saying that this matter was not one in which the police could put their hands.</seg>
     <seg id="7">In your opinion, is the accusation against Adnan Sami, by his wife proper?</seg>
     <seg id="8">This is not an Indian effort to disgrace Adnan Sami, is it?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Let us know about your opinion on this issue.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370234-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Adam, Sanghad, Mehr</seg>
     <seg id="2">As far as accusations go, any person can accuse the other.</seg>
     <seg id="3">To get enraged for honor is not sensible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Whatever be the case between Adnan Sami and his present wife, he had left his honorable life and went to India to earn money. Now that fame has fallen around his neck.</seg>
     <seg id="5">This is the result of his own actions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370236-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Washington...</seg>
     <seg id="2">High ambassadors of America say that President Obama will take a strong stand against Afghan President Hamid Karzai.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In America's new policy for Afghanistan, instead of development, war has been given more importance.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The envoys say that Hamid Karzai is being considered a barrier in the achievement of American goals in Afghanistan, as there is corruption in the government and the business of middlemen has increased and the Taliban are once more gathering strength.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The American envoys say that among the people in the American government who are stressing upon Hamid Karzai to do something more are Vice President Joseph Biden and President Obama's representative to Afghanistan and Pakistan, Richard Hallbrooke.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that this good administration was noticed after the President Bush left, who used to have a video conference with Hamid Karzai after every 2 weeks and used to emphasize on the role of America in Afghanistan and the development of its city departments.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Officials say that Obama management will work with the state leaders as a backup with the main government.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Officials say that they will emphasize Hamid Karzai on fighting against corruption</seg>
     <seg id="9">Hamid Karzai faces new elections this year. And it is not clear as yet that Obama and his companions will favor his presidency or not.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Is this statement, of the American officials, a forecast of change in American policy regarding Afghanistan?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Is this era of Hamid Karzai ending?</seg>
     <seg id="12">What are your thoughts in this matter?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370238-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">In the series of three one-day matches between Pakistan and SriLanka, Srilanka defeated Pakistan with 2-1.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Pakistan defeated Srilanka in the first one-day match although Srilanka won in the next two matches.</seg>
     <seg id="3">In this third one-day match, the nation's team performance was very poor. They worn out in only 75 runs in 23 overs against 309 runs made by the national team of Srilanka.And this is how we faced a lesson learning defeat.</seg>
     <seg id="4">the result of the series proves that the National team has no consistency in its performance.</seg>
     <seg id="5">besides the home ground and all claims, the national team was defeated, what are the reasons of this in your opinion?</seg>
     <seg id="6">which departments of the game should be addressed more by the authorities?</seg>
     <seg id="7">are you satisfied with the selection of the team?</seg>
     <seg id="8">which department you will hold responsible for the defeat, fielding, batting or bowling?</seg>
     <seg id="9">please provide your feedback.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370242-post6" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Babar Hussain, Judah, it is very disappointing that even today these kind of heathenish  traditions continue. these feudal lords target innocent people with their feudal rule, who would call them Muslims?</seg>
     <seg id="2">a Sardar should walk himself over these embers. why the present government do not act against them?</seg>
     <seg id="3">when the judicial justice will come in handy.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370243-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">the Srilankan cricket team has arrived Karachi to play One Day internationals.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Despite the tensions between Pakistan and India it is nice to see a foreign team visit Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On reaching the Karachi airport the Sirilankan team was given a warm welcome.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There will be two one day matches in Karachi and one in Lahore between Pakistan and Sirilanka.</seg>
     <seg id="5">There have been bold statements from both sides regarding their bowling, batting and fielding.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If the Sirilankans are proud of their spinners than Pakistan has its fast bowlers.</seg>
     <seg id="7">The Sirilankan captain Mahela Jayawardene has said that no one player of the Pakistan team can be singled out as a threat, the whole team is dangerous.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Muralitharan and Mendis are said to be trump cards while the Pakistani captain has said that the competition will be a tough one.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Shoaib Malik said that they've already played Muralitharan and that they'll see off Mendis as well, he also said that they've got a secret game plan that they'll reveal on the pitch.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Can it really be that according to the Pakistani and Sirilankan claims the contest will be a gripping one?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Who will have the upper hand when the series between Pakistan and Sirilanka gets underway?</seg>
     <seg id="12">Who will win the series?</seg>
     <seg id="13">Who will be the man of the series?</seg>
     <seg id="14">Give your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370244-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Gulpham, London, publishes his own views and you also prefer these views. I wish you would also write some truth, and not change your words like Mukherjee, because the order is to speak the truth in front of a tyrant king, and this is equivalent to Jihad. What should be said of Mukherjee, he tries to change his statements and stay in the news.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Malik Yusuf, Dubai.</seg>
     <seg id="2">How is all this is double for these people, when the Kashmiri people have been fighting for independence for the last 60 years?</seg>
     <seg id="3">No, no one asked, and they are now stuck in their war of extremism and terrorism, so they start talking about making up.</seg>
     <seg id="4">First they openly killed the Muslims, now they are in the efforts of setting things right.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Anyway, Pakistan will have to understand their double edged policies.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post15" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Asad Khan, London.</seg>
     <seg id="2">India is creating such a situation that the world's attention can be diverted from Kashmir.</seg>
     <seg id="3">but Pakistan has always shown the real face of India to the world.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Now the British Government is also understanding that the Indians are taking cover from their occupation over Kashmir by blaming Pakistan of terrorism.</seg>
     <seg id="5">and they hesitate to talk to Pakistan over this issue.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">British foreign minister David Milliband has said that by resolving the issue of Kashmir will bring an end to extremism, the government of Pakistan will effectively handle the threats rising on the borders.</seg>
     <seg id="2">it should be clear that the newly elected American president Obama has also expressed similar views over the Kashmir dispute.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The British foreign minister while talking to media in Mumbai and has written in an article that the idea of the war against terror is wrong and killing people just for the threats to one self was the policy of president Bush.</seg>
     <seg id="4">David Milliband has said that Pakistan should not be lenient with the extremist groups.</seg>
     <seg id="5">due to the stress over the need for resolution of the Kashmir dispute from the major powers, isn't India trying to divert the attention from this issue by creating unrest in the region?</seg>
     <seg id="6">isn't the terrorism in Mumbai a part of this strategy?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Is India using terrorism as a base to escape from comprehensive dialog?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Let us know of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370245-post2" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Usman Aftab,</seg>
     <seg id="2">I think the big powers do not want to harm Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Rather it wants to keep it in check, and hence is thinking of taking certain steps. They know that Pakistan is a nuclear state.</seg>
     <seg id="4">They want to bring about some kind of revolution here.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Foreign countries are only thinking that if they corner Pakistan, they would face some political and geographic problems. They want to help Pakistan, but also want to be successful in their goal.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A citizen, USA.</seg>
     <seg id="2">It has always been a Hindu tradition, that in the side is a knife and on the mouth is Ram.</seg>
     <seg id="3">I think that they get stomach aches over small issues and begin to warn Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">We are ready by all means. Indian Army chief should keep his mouth shut.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370246-post9" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">F.M. siddique</seg>
     <seg id="2">Political statements are coming under the mischievous support of America. America is crazy and now Indians are going on the same pattern. if India has courage to attack, it should to know the ground reality.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Israel is attacking Hamas and no one has courage to stop Israel. Following Israel, Indian also wants to do some adventure.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370247-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">PM said that Byden had a great role in shedding Musharraf's uniform and restoring the democracy. That is why he has awarded SI.</seg>
     <seg id="2">No political party can get the credit of uniform shedding and the restoration of democracy. Parliament is not a rubber stamp.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All decisions will be made in Parliament.</seg>
     <seg id="4">PM said that Dr. Qadir's chapter had closed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">If public protest against dictatorship has no significance to you?.</seg>
     <seg id="6">If lawyers movement did not play any role?</seg>
     <seg id="7">what will you going to do at Prime Minister's statement</seg>
     <seg id="8">please give us your opinion</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370248-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">American President George W Bush in his last Press conference advises newly elected President that he did many mistakes in his tenure and Barack Obama should do what he think is right</seg>
     <seg id="2">I as the President and according with the constitution of USA and law i did the developments, i put forward American interest on my own popularity.</seg>
     <seg id="3">he said that America's Enemy are still planning to attack America. the biggest challenge for Barack Obama is to prevent from these attacks</seg>
     <seg id="4">he said that , unable to find the weapon of mass destruction from Iraq was his major dissapointment and to announce the mission completed in Iraq was his big mistake.</seg>
     <seg id="5">In last press conference from white house American president has said that this is my last press conference i thank u all news reporter and my colleague who attended this conference</seg>
     <seg id="6">do you think Obama will not do that mistake which bush did?</seg>
     <seg id="7">don't you think bush was late in accepting his mistakes?</seg>
     <seg id="8">will Obama be able to follow the advice of Bush?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Inform us of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370250-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The American Vice President Dick Cheney says I want to see Usama Bin Laden alive or dead.</seg>
     <seg id="2">He says that Usama Bin Laden is hiding in some hard to reach area and is of no use to his organization, if Usama Bin Laden is arrested alive or dead then his organization must be destroyed.</seg>
     <seg id="3">America is ambitious on the arrest of Usama and the search of Usama is on.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Will Dick Cheney's wish of arresting Usama be accomplished?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Inform us of your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370251-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the completion of Qaide Aazam Trophy match between PIA and Habeeb bank the all rounder cricketer Shahid Affridi had quarrel with one fan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">When Shahid Affridi came out of the drawing room after playing the match on the UBL ground then a big number of fans gathered him.</seg>
     <seg id="3">On one situation a fan held the hand and asked to take a photo with him on which Shahid Affridi removing his hand said that he can take the photo tomorrow but on fan's insistence Affridi became angry and slapped him, before they start a quarrel the gathering people just dismissed the matter there itself.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After that Shahid Affridi said that without any reason he was made an issue therefore at that time he was in a hurry to attend the Prayer.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Any way, I beg pardon for this drama.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you say about Shahid Afridi's actions?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Let us know about your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370252-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Manmohan Singh once again accused Pakistan of creating a war-like atmosphere.</seg>
     <seg id="2">and that Pakistan is using terrorism as a policy of state.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Speaking to a meeting of the cabinet of ministers, Manmohan Singh said that terrorist factions are being supported by neighbouring countries, especially Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="4">And that the terrorists who attacked Mumbai used the sea way and remained safe from the coastal guard.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The Indian Prime Minister said that the Mumbai attacks of November were carried out by Lashkar-e-Taiba.</seg>
     <seg id="6">He said that the terrorists were using new techniques and modern communication systems. We will have to step up the forces at the line of control as well, from where there is infiltration. He said that terrorism will not be accepted in any form, and this is our policy.</seg>
     <seg id="7">How do you see this accusation of the Indian Prime Minister?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Do the internally opposed and separatist movements of India show the disturbed situation n India?</seg>
     <seg id="9">On whose orders is India taking this warning stance?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Give us your views.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post10" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Zubair Khan, Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="2">This is a sad calamity that Israeli is massacring the Palestinians and the same situation is prevalent in Kashmir, but there is no effect on the Security Council.</seg>
     <seg id="3">All the organisations present in Palestine and Kashmir should keep their war going until they gain independence, and they should form unity among themselves and keep facing any type of harm, and one day or the other their martyrdom will give fruit, God Willing.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370253-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The air attacks by Israel on Gaza are continuing, just the same. Until now, hundreds of Palestinian men, women and children have been martyred.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Important Hamas leader Nazariyan was killed along with hwife and children.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Here the Security Council meeting concluded without any decision.</seg>
     <seg id="4">The meeting saw American opposition to the derogatory resolutions passed against Israel by Libya and other Arab countries.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Israel's jet planes have been bombarding on the residential areas of Palestine for last many days.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Every country around the world began to protest against the Mumbai attacks but can't anyone see this brutality including America and Britain?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Why are the major Muslim countries quiet?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What is your opinion on these double standards of the world.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post12" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Saeed, New York.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In my opinion, the basic fact is that most of our people are uneducated and they don't even know where their money is actually going. Government is interested in doing it's job properly by applying and collecting taxes. Shortfall of electricity and gas will continue in the same manner.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Because everyone knows about the character of those who have been elected by our own nation.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Crisis of electricity and gas all over Pakistan has become a critical state.</seg>
     <seg id="2">On the other hand the GAS tariff has been raised to 8% where as in some cities due to the non availability of the petrol is increasing the difficulties and miseries of the masses.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Due to the long load shedding of electricity and gas crisis in Pakistan's industrial and business sector, there is a severe reaction. Riots and violent protests are taking place.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Industry holders gave ultimatem to stop mills.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Here there is unbelivable situation in cities by the load shedding of light in Karachi from 8 to 10 hours.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The industrial became aproximatly hand less and feet less.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Government institutes are showing their openions by blaming one another.</seg>
     <seg id="8">Talks with nation of increase the prices of electric and gas in not a jok.</seg>
     <seg id="9">Why did not pay attention to solve these problems.</seg>
     <seg id="10">The government is not going to work for upwards.</seg>
     <seg id="11">What will you suggest about the control this big problem.</seg>
     <seg id="12">Aware me about your openion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370254-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After the loss of Imram, that as there are people as there are commonders.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I wonder those who shout slogans for an administration of the public create nuisance to the public.</seg>
     <seg id="3">It is torture not to get jelly, petroleum and gas.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Government departments have lost control.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Law and order has been degenerated. May Allah show his mercy  on this country of ours.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370255-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A new year has begun.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Last year was a year of political turmoil and chaos. The year will be remembered for terrorism too.</seg>
     <seg id="3">President Musharaf's stepping down from power, the end of President Bush's eight years' reign, the slinging of chappals to Bush, the rethroning of democracy in Pakistan,the unexpected disasters, the earthquake in Baloochistan, the financial melt down all over the world,the depression in the market</seg>
     <seg id="4">The new year has set in. How do you feel now at the new year's arrival?</seg>
     <seg id="5">In your opinion, What colour will the political and geographical situations in the country take? What tricks will Obama adopt?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Is it possible to predict an end to the threatening terrorism?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Will the judicial crisis in Pakistan come to an end?</seg>
     <seg id="8">What turn will the Indo-Pak relations take?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Is there any chance of a surgical strike or a full-fledged war?</seg>
     <seg id="10">What are your expectations for the new year?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Share your opinion.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370256-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">It is the first death anniversary of Benazir Bhutto. She was slain after an election rally in Liaqat Bagh, Rawalpindi on 27th December 2007.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Benazir is not among us today. She was a thoughtful politician and a world reknowned figure. She held a special status in national politics.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Although it's been a year now yet the enigma of her death remains unsolved.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Her efforts to bring democracy to Pakistan were not in vain.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Today a democratic government exists in Pakistan and her husband Asif Zardari currently holds the position of Pakistan President.</seg>
     <seg id="6">What do you think is the role of martyr Benazir Bhutto in Pakistani politics?</seg>
     <seg id="7">Who can be behind murdering her?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Recently,, she was given the global human rights award. What would you like to say about her democratic and political services?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370257-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">After ruling over America for eight years, President Bush left the White House, for presidential camp office, Camp David, so that the White House can be decorated and prepared for new President Barack Obama, according to his wishes.</seg>
     <seg id="2">In Bush's eight year presidency, the historic World Trade Center attack, the attack on the Pentagon, the action against Afghanistan and Iraq in the name of a global war against terrorism, in which armies of many countries were pulled into the war, and American resources were completely exhausted, were some of the memorable events of the Bush era.</seg>
     <seg id="3">As a result of this war, America had to face the worst economic and financial crisis in history.</seg>
     <seg id="4">What do you think the world got and what do you think they lost, as a result of this war?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Were the policies of President Bush successful?</seg>
     <seg id="6">What are your views of the Bush era?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370259-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">The Indian government has stopped the Indian cricket team from touring Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The Indian Cricket Team had to play three tests, five one day matches and one 20 twenty on Pakistan Tour.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The Vice-President of the Indian Cricket Board Rajeev Shukla who spoke to the news said that the board has asked the Government to allow the Pakistan Tour but because of the serious matters between the two countries this tour is not possible.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Is it right to use available political issue of the Indian government as the passport to cancel the cricket tour, the games must not be kept away from politics?</seg>
     <seg id="5">Isn't the decision of the Indian Government towards cricket a loss?</seg>
     <seg id="6">Even though the security in India was poor, the English Cricket Team tour was going on, so why don't the Indian team do the Pakistan Tour?</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion in this regard?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Salman, Karachi.</seg>
     <seg id="2">People who feel proud on going to India.</seg>
     <seg id="3">And their films and videos which are made there, now their eyes must open to see that how much the Indian people respect you.</seg>
     <seg id="4">I remember one interview of Adnan Samee where he said I am not a Pakistani, my popularity is British.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Adnan Sami needs that he should come to Pakistan at first opportunity because respect did not suited him even there.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post16" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Fareed Ahmad</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi</seg>
     <seg id="3">Indians attitude have changed after Mumbai attack.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jagjit showed his reaction in this form that he hates Pakistan and Pakistani.</seg>
     <seg id="5">it should be known that Adnan Sami sung seven songs of Asha Bhosla, now how can he be out of tune, Adnan Sami should stay in India, no need to come here.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370261-post3" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Muhammad Shamshad Alam</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi, i will only say this on the statement of Jagjit Singh that he changes color like a chameleon.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Who gives statements suitable to situation Pakistanis open your eyes that how much you are given worth in India, understand the thinking of Hindu.</seg>
     <seg id="4">After the Mumbai incident, their hateful statements have increased now they are spitting poison against popular singer Adnan Sami.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370262-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Without my permission at all, a dream takes place in my mind. I must have a house in a beautiful evergreen valley. There must be flowering trees on top of the hill.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Each morning at least one among the flowers that fall from the trees should reach the valley, where my small nest-like house situates.</seg>
     <seg id="3">The second thing was that about your future.</seg>
     <seg id="4">At night, while sleeping on the terrace, I must be able to view the whole star bloomed sky.</seg>
     <seg id="5">Seeing the melting mist in the valley, seeing the gold- bangled hands working in the tiled kitchen, watching my hard work blooming up in the compound.</seg>
     <seg id="6">Looking at the twinkling stars, feeling the softness of fondling fingers, inhaling the fragrance of night jasmine.</seg>
     <seg id="7">What is your opinion about this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370263-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">By wearing a mask repeatedly, you have lost your face. You have developed the art of having the brightness of truth even while uttering point blank lies.</seg>
     <seg id="2">I was always dominated by an uncontrollable thirst for affection.</seg>
     <seg id="3">When my problem is something concerned with money.</seg>
     <seg id="4">There are many problems faced the people in the world. It is not under the control of human beings.</seg>
     <seg id="5">I think it is mainly by people not think properly, what is the real cause.</seg>
     <seg id="6">The consequence of the fact that it is very dangerous to face the problems that arise in the world future.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Today itself start for the well beings of the people</seg>
     <seg id="8">What did the people seriously think about that?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Poverty, financial crisis, diseases are the main challenges that people going to face in the world in future.</seg>
     <seg id="10">Why did the people think about the consequences of the dangerous calamities affected the people?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Start today for that. Are you ready.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">We are firmly take a decision today. How to solve the problems. It is not merely easy. It is very risk task. First of all we have the good mind and attitude towards that.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The world faced many calamities such as earthquake. flood, Tsunami etc. But we have not known yet to take precautionary measures to overcome that. We have taken after the calamities. Our scientists to find necessary steps for that</seg>
     <seg id="3">from United Nation side made a 60 birthday on 10/December for Human Rights resolution.</seg>
     <seg id="4">at his oucation to accept work for human rights personalities and organization have been awarded in which Benazir Bhutto and also America ex-Attorney Cornall Lewis Rams Clark and international organization work for Human Rights Human Rights Watch included.</seg>
     <seg id="5">at that time Pakistani Diplomat in United Nation Abdullah Hussain Haroon and some other Senior diplomats also present .</seg>
     <seg id="6">what you say about Ex-prime minster Benazir Bhuto Martyr   received this Award</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370264-post8" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">September.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Chicago.</seg>
     <seg id="3">this is true that she has martyred but we also remember that she killed many innocent in Karachi that she proud of that Naiseer Ullah Baber has done a great job.</seg>
     <seg id="4">But than she totally changed.</seg>
     <seg id="5">but this is also true that he neglect senior people in his party and chose his son as a party leader what Democracy is this?</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post11" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Jimmy Noor, Karachi, this news proved Quran that said that Non-believer will support only Non-Believer.</seg>
     <seg id="2">An axe cant cut the wood until it does not have wooden handle</seg>
     <seg id="3">Our rulers are responsible for the hardships and problems our country is in.</seg>
     <seg id="4">May God bless our rulers with rightness</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370265-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">A panel of UN's Security council has included the names of Hafaiz Saeed and three other Pakistanis in the list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="2">The names of Hafiz Mohammad saeed (the chief jamat-ul-dawa),Rehman Lakhvi (Lashkar-i-taiba's chief of Operations), and haji Mohammad Ashraf (Lashar-i-taiba's Head of finance) have been included in the list of terrorists. This list approved by the Security Council's committee on Alqaida and Taliban.</seg>
     <seg id="3">Beside these, a saudi citizen Mehmood Ahmed's name is also part of the this list of terrorists.</seg>
     <seg id="4">Jamat-ul-dawa, passban-i-kashmir and Alrashid trusts are included in these organizations.</seg>
     <seg id="5">The member countries will freeze the assets of these personalities and organizations.These persons will not allow to travel and they will be arrested if travel led.</seg>
     <seg id="6">They have to face the cases.</seg>
     <seg id="7">Are not these sanctions  made under the influence of Indian propaganda?</seg>
     <seg id="8">Why is India blaming these parties for the Bombay attacks without any proof?</seg>
     <seg id="9">Aren't there any terrorist groups in India?</seg>
     <seg id="10">Are International groups not aware of the tortures being done on the minorities in India?</seg>
     <seg id="11">Please inform us with your suggestions.</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370266-post1" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Occasion of Eid represents happiness and joy and monotheists sacrifice animals following the tradition of Ibrahim.</seg>
     <seg id="2">During this turbulent time when inflation is at its peak, political situation is not promising, even after this rich and poor prepare for Eid within their means and wish their relatives a happy Eid in different ways.</seg>
     <seg id="3">We are also providing you with the chance through this blog to wish your loved ones a happy Eid through short messages.</seg>
     <seg id="4">You can also wish by writing verses with reference to Eid</seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
 <doc docid="urd-WL-86-174276-11370267-post5" genre="wb">
   <p>
     <seg id="1">Murtaza Jilani.</seg>
     <seg id="2">Karachi, our leaders should understand this that people, they are doing the operation against, are the true valuers of Pakistan, who are tolerating all kinds of tortures but they love Pakistan.</seg>
     <seg id="3"></seg>
     <seg id="4"></seg>
   </p>
 </doc>
</tstset>
</mteval>

